<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1331_nm.4427" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4427" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4427" rank="species">Selenomonas infelix</organism><reference id="rid.1331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas noxia sp. nov., Selenomonas flueggei sp. nov., Selenomonas infelix sp. nov., Selenomonas dianae sp. nov., and Selenomonas artemidis sp. nov., from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Selenomonas infelix</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas infelix</i> (in.fe'lix [pronounced in.fay'lix]. L. adj, <i>infelix</i> causing harm, unlucky [referring to its occurrence in periodontal disease]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved, crescent shaped, and 1.0 to 1.2 by 3.2 to 5.3 μm.</s><s>With Leifson flagellum stain, cells appear to have one or more central-to-polar flagella arising from the concave side.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On rabbit blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h, colonies are 0.5 to 1.0 mm, circular, entire, pulvinate, translucent, shiny, smooth, and white.</s><s>Sometimes growth is as a spreading film over the entire plate.</s><s>Strains produce moderate turbidity in PY broth and have abundant growth</s></p><p class="description"><s>that is turbid with a smooth sediment in PYG broth cultures.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 to 45°C.</s><s>Moderate growth occurs at 30°C; at 25°C there usually is no growth.</s><s>Slight ammonia is detected in PY, PYG, and chopped meat cultures.</s><s>Neutral red may be weakly reduced.</s><s>In PYG agar deep cultures, resazurin is not reduced and moderate-to-large amounts of gas are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml, erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation acids of the type strain, in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture, are 1.7 of acetic and 3.4 of propionic in <i>Selenomonas</i> D-6 and D-10 (in part) in previous publications.</s></p></content></protolog>