<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7007_nm.2684" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2684" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2684" rank="species">Pseudomonas salomonii</organism><reference id="rid.7007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bella</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rott</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Samson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas salomonii sp. nov., pathogenic on garlic, and Pseudomonas palleroniana sp. nov., isolated from rice.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2065</fpage><lpage>2074</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02225-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508870</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas salomonii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas salomonii</i> (sa.lo.mo'ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>salomonii</i> of Salomon, referring to Max Salomon, the agricultural technical advisor who first observed the symptoms of the new garlic disease `Café au lait')</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Forms typical white-cream, circular, smooth colonies, 3-4 mm in diameter after 48 h growth on YBGA at 28 °C.</s><s>A fluorescent pigment is produced on King's medium B.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Pectolytic on Hildebrand's medium (pH 8.3).</s><s>Oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, levan production and gelatinase reactions are positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and aesculin hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Growth is observed on D-xylose, D-glucose, trehalose, lyxose, malonate, DL-glycerate, D-malate, L-isoleucine, L-valine, L-tyrosine, L-ornithine, L-arginine, β-alanine, <i>p</i>-aminobenzoate, sarcosine, ethanolamine, diaminobutyrate and on the carbon sources listed as positive in Table 3.</s><s>There was no assimilation of L-rhamnose, arbutin, aesculin, melibiose, raffinose, butyrate, isovalerate, DL-2-aminobutyrate, L-methionine or the carbon sources mentioned as negative in Table 3.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain, CFBP 2022<sup>T</sup>, is 60.2 mol%.</s><s>The hypersensitive reaction on tobacco leaves is positive just after isolation and negative after subculturing several times.</s><s>Strains are pathogenic to <i>Allium sativum</i>, producing the typical symptoms of `Cafè au lait' disease.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Collection Française des Bactèries Phytopathogènes (CFBP), Angers, France, as CFBP 2022<sup>T</sup>, in the International Collection of Microorganisms from Plants (ICMP), Auckland, New Zealand, as ICMP 14252<sup>T</sup> and in the National Collection of Plant-Pathogenic Bacteria (NCPPB), Sand Hutton, York, UK, as NCPPB 4277<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>