<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5416_nm.3628" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3628" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3628" rank="species">Desulfuromusa bakii</organism><reference id="rid.5416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic Analysis of Five Strains of Gram-Negative, Obligately Anaerobic, Sulfur-Reducing Bacteria and Description of Desulfuromusa gen. nov., Including Desulfuromusa kysingii sp. nov., Desulfuromusa bakii sp. nov., and Desulfuromusa succinoxidans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>753</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-753</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfuromusa bakii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfuromusa bakii</i> (ba'ki.i. M. L. gen.n. <i>bakii</i>, of Bak, named in memory of Friedhelm Bak, who made important contributions to our knowledge of sulfur- and sulfate-reducing bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.5 to 0.6 μm wide and 2 to 4 μm long when they are grown with elemental sulfur as the electron acceptor, Nitrate, dimethyl sulfoxide and Fe(III)-citrate are not utilized as electron acceptors.</s><s>No growth occurs with aspartate or maleate without additional electron acceptors.</s><s>Citrate, acetate, pyruvate, lactate, propionate, oxalacetate, succinate, maleate, alanine, glutamate, aspartate, and yeast extract are used as electron donors.</s><s>Strains can be cultivated in defined medium without addition of complex nutrients like yeast extract or peptone.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of NaCl and MgCl<sub>2</sub> concentralions of 114 and 3.3 mM, respectively.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between 6.7 and 7.4, and the minimum and maximum pH values for growth are 6.2 and 7.8, respectively.</s><s>The minimum temperature for growth is 8°C; the maximum temperature for growth is 32°C; and the optimum temperature is between 25 and 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Desulfuromusa bakii</i> is strain Gyprop (= DSM 7345); the G+C content of its DNA is 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Desulfuromusa bakii</i> Gyprop<sup>T</sup> was isolated from an anoxic mud sample collected from Guayamas Basin (Gulf of California) at a depth of about 2,000 m.</s><s>The habitat of <i>Desulfuromusa bakii</i> Kyprop is the anoxic mud of the shallow Kysing Fjord south of Århus, Denmark.</s></p></content></protolog>