<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8820_nm.13737" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13737" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13737" rank="species">Luteolibacter pohnpeiensis</organism><reference id="rid.8820"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nozawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Persicirhabdus sediminis gen. nov., sp. nov., Roseibacillus ishigakijimensis gen. nov., sp. nov., Roseibacillus ponti sp. nov., Roseibacillus persicicus sp. nov., Luteolibacter pohnpeiensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Luteolibacter algae sp. nov., six marine members of the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia', and emended descriptions of the class Verrucomicrobiae, the order Verrucomicrobiales and the family Verrucomicrobiaceae.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>998</fpage><lpage>1007</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65520-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398209</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Luteolibacter pohnpeiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Luteolibacter pohnpeiensis</em> (poh.n.pe.i.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>pohnpeiensis</em> pertaining to Pohnpei Island, located in Micronesia, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are 0.5–0.8 μm wide and 1.5–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/10-strength MA are circular, convex and pale yellow in colour.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C, with optimal growth at 30–37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at either 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.5–9.0.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth and can be tolerated up to 6 % (w/v).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase tests are positive, but <em>α</em>-glucosidase, esterase (C4), lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase tests are negative.</s><s>Dextrin, l-arabinose, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, furanose, glycerol and glucose 6-phosphate are oxidized.</s><s>MK-10 is also present as a major respiratory menaquinone.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains muramic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (4.4 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (15.6 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (6.7 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (45.0 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14.8 %) and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (10.5 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 55.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A4T-83<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08322<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22041<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a piece of driftwood from a mangrove coast located on Pohnpei Island.</s></p></content></protolog>