<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4559_nm.4984" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4984" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4984" rank="species">Bacillus sonorensis</organism><reference id="rid.4559"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palmisano</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duncan</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Istock</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cohan</surname><given-names>F.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus sonorensis sp. nov., a close relative of Bacillus licheniformis, isolated from soil in the Sonoran Desert, Arizona.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1671</fpage><lpage>1679</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus sonorensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus sonorensis</i> (so.no.ren'sis. N.L. adj. <i>sonorensis</i> of the Sonoran, named after the Sonoran Desert, where the organism was collected)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rod-shaped and are 1.0 μm wide by 2-5 μm long, as determined by measurements of photomicrographs.</s><s>Cells often occur singly but a few chains of two to four cells are also seen.</s><s>Gram-positive, motile, catalase-positive, facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies on TBAB agar are a yellowish-cream colour, form mounds or lobes of amorphous slime and are approximately 2-4 mm in diameter after 2 d at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies are bright yellow on pH 5.6 agar, brown on tyrosine agar and pale yellowish-cream on glycerol/glutamate agar.</s><s>Spores are formed in unswollen sporangia and are slightly less than 1.0 μm wide and 1.5-2.0 μm long.</s><s>They are ellipsoidal in shape and their position within the sporangia appears to be generally subterminal.</s><s>The maximum growth temperature is about 55 °C and the minimum is about 15 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.7.</s><s>Growth occurs in 3% NaCl but not in 5, 7 or 10% NaCl.Growth is inhibited in 0.001% lysozyme.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, arabinose, xylose and mannitol.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is positive and the pH after 2 d at 28 °C ranges from 5.1 to 6.6.</s><s>The egg yolk reaction is negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch and decomposes casein.</s><s>Citrate and propionate are utilized.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Tyrosine is not degraded.</s><s>All of the characteristics described above are identical to those of <i>B. licheniformis</i> with these exceptions: growth of the <i>B. licheniformis</i> type strain occurs in 5, 7 and 10%NaCl; colonies of <i>B. licheniformis</i> are cream coloured on pH 5.6 and tyrosine agar and reddish-brown on glycerol/glutamate agar.</s><s>The thermal denaturation temperature for DNA of the type strain of <i>B. sonorensis</i> is 88.1 °C and the G+­C content determined from this value is 46 mol%, which does not distinguish this species from <i>B. licheniformis</i>.</s><s>A number of traits can be used to distinguish <i>B. sonorensis</i> from <i>B. licheniformis</i>.</s><s>Diagnostic phenotypic traits include pigmentation when cells are grown on tyrosine agar, pH 5.6 agar and glycerol/glutamate agar and differences in growth in 5, 7 and 10% NaCl.</s><s>Distinguishing genetic traits include DNA-DNA reassociation values, sequences of secY, rpoB and 16S rRNA genes and enzyme electrophoresis analysis of ten loci.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from desert soil.</s><s>The type strain is L87-10<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection as strain NRRL B-23154<sup>T</sup> and in the DSMZ as strain DSM 13779<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>