<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4895_nm.1806" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1806" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1806" rank="species">Diaphorobacter nitroreducens</organism><reference id="rid.4895"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Diaphorobacter nitroreducens gen. nov., sp. nov., a poly(3-hydroxybutyrate)-degrading denitrifying bacterium isolated from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>299</fpage><lpage>308</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2323/jgam.48.299</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12682868</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>iaphorobacter nitroreducens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>iaphorobacter nitroreducens</i> (nitro.re.du'cens. L. n. <i>nitrum</i> nitrate; L. part. adj. <i>reducens</i> converting to a different state; N. L. adj. <i>nitroreducens</i> reducing nitrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.7–0.9 μm wide and 1.0 to 1.8 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on agar media are rough with uneven margins or smooth and entire margins.</s><s>The color of the colonies is transparent in earlier stages and turns pale to beige after longer incubation.</s><s>Poly(3-hydroxybutyrate) and poly(3-hydroxybutyrate-co-hydroxyvalerate) are degraded under aerobic and anaerobic denitrifying conditions.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, casein, DNA, Tween 20 and Tween 80 is negative.</s><s>β-Galactosidase and β-xylosidase are absent.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 28 to 35°C.</s><s>The optimum pH ranges from 7.0 to 8.0.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized are ethanol, acetate, propionate, butyrate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, caproate, gluconate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, a -alanine, asparagine, glutamate, casamino acids, peptone, and yeast extract.</s><s>Not utilized are sugars, sugar alcohols, methanol, aminobutyrate, benzoate, caprylate, citrate, malonate, tartrate, histidine, leucine, serine, and 1-chloro-4-benzene.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA ranges from 64 to 65 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is activated sludge.</s><s>The type strain is strain NA10B, which has been deposited with the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (RIKEN), Wako, Japan, as JCM 11421 and with the Collection of Bacterial Strains of Institut Pasteur as CIP 107294.</s><s>The accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is AB064317.</s></p></content></protolog>