<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.597_nm.1293" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1293" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1293" rank="species">Rhizobium loti</organism><reference id="rid.597"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jarvis</surname><given-names>B.D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pankhurst</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium loti, a new species of legume root bacteria.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>378</fpage><lpage>380</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-378</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium loti</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium loti</i> (M.L. noun <i>Lotus</i> generic name; M.L. gen. noun <i>loti</i> of Lotus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods which are motile predominantly by means of one polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>In nodules the cells are bacteroids (i.e., club shaped and branched) and contain inclusion bodies composed of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>Other inclusions, such as polyphosphate bodies, glycogen granules, and lipid droplets, are not present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on Vincent yeast mannitol agar (30) are more than 1 .O mm in diameter after 7 days at 28"C, but growth is inhibited at 42°C.</s><s>Growth at 28°C on yeast mannitol agar is inhibited by 3% NaCl and by pH values of less than 4.0 or more than 10.0.</s><s>On Vincent medium without mannitol, all strains utilize one or more of the following carbohydrates and form acidic end products: glucose, galactose, fructose, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, mannitol, and dulcitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The electrophoretic patterns of the soluble proteins from strains of fast-growing Lotus rhizobia are similar to one another and are distinguishable from those of other species of fast-growing rhizobia.</s><s>All strains produce extracellular polysaccharides which contain uronic acid, galactose, and glucose.</s><s>Somatic antigens are highly strain specific, but internal antigens show a reaction of identity between strains and can be used to distinguish <i>R. loti</i> from slow-growing Lotus rhizobia and from other <i>Rhizobium</i> nomenspecies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells can be infected by bacteriophages belonging to Bradley morphological types B and C (3).</s><s>These phages are host range specific, and susceptibility to 4203711 may be used to distinguish <i>R. loti</i> from slow-growing Lotus rhizobia and from other <i>Rhizobium</i> nomenspecies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of <i>R. loti</i> is 59 to 64 mol%.</s><s>DNA-DNA hybridizations with reference DNAs from <i>R. trifolii</i> strain CC275e (5 to 13%; mean, 8%), <i>R. meliloti</i> strain SU47 ( 5 to 15%; mean, 10%), <i>Rhizobium</i> sp. strain CC811 from <i>Lotus corniculatus</i> (46 to 74%; mean, 60%), and <i>Rhizobium</i> sp. strain CC809a from Lotus maroccanus (32 to 59%; mean, 47%) indicate that <i>R. loti</i> can be clearly distinguished from other fast-growing rhizobia.</s><s>Strains of rhizobia from a variety of other plants have similar genetic relationships, indicating that <i>R. loti</i> forms part of a larger group of root nodule bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen-fixing (effective) nodules are normally formed on the roots of <i>Lotus corniculatus</i> (bird's-foot trefoil), <i>Lotus tenuis</i> (slender bird'sfoot trefoil), <i>Lupinus densgorus</i> (lupine), and <i>Anthyllis vulneraria</i> (kidney vetch).</s><s>A few strains nodulate effectively on <i>Lotus pedunculatus</i> (<i>Lotus uliginosus</i>; big trefoil) or <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>.</s><s>Ineffective nodules may be formed on <i>Lotus pedunculatus</i> (<i>Lotus uliginosus</i>), <i>Lotus angustissimus</i> (narrow-leaved Lotus), <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>, <i>Clianthus punicens</i> (red kowhai), <i>Acacia sophorea</i> (<i>Acacia longifolia</i>; sallow wattle), <i>Carmichaelia angustata</i> (large-flowered broom), <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> (kidney bean), <i>Macroptilium atropurpureum</i> (siratro), and <i>Ornithopus sativus</i> (serradella).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>R. loti</i> is NZP 2213, a culture of which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 33669.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above for the species with respect to morphology, physiology, antigenic relationships, and plant specificity.</s><s>It is lysed by bacteriophages 1 through 7 of the 2037 series and by ϕ2205 but not by any bacteriophage from slow-growing Lotus rhizobia (26).</s><s>The percent DNA-DNA homologies with <i>R. trifolii</i> CC275e, <i>R. meliloti</i> SU47, <i>R. loti</i> CC811, and <i>R. loti</i> CC809a are 10, 5, 60, and 47%, respectively.</s><s>Nitrogen-fixing nodules are formed on the roots of the following plants: <i>Lotus corniculatus</i>, <i>Lotus tenuis</i>, <i>Lotus japonicus</i>, <i>Lotus krylovii</i>, <i>Lotus filicalius</i>, and <i>Lotus schoelleri</i>.</s><s>Nodules which cannot fix nitrogen are formed on <i>Lotus pedunculatus</i>, <i>Lotus hispidus</i> (<i>Lotus suavedens</i>), and <i>Lotus angustissimus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>