<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7587_nm.6021" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6021" rank="species">Nostocoida limicola</organism><reference id="rid.7587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandford</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosetti</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tandoi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>'Candidatus Nostocoida limicola', a filamentous bacterium from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>703</fpage><lpage>709</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758878</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of '<i>Candidatus</i> Nostocoida limicola' sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Five `<i>N. limicola</i>' II filaments were isolated by micromanipulation (Skerman, 1968) from two activated sludge sewage treatment plants (Sunbury, Victoria, Australia and Verona, Italy) to plates of freshly prepared R2A (for isolates Ben17, Ben18, Ver1 and Ver2; Reasoner &#x0026; Geldreich, 1985) or glucose sulfide (GS) medium (for isolate Ben67; Williams &#x0026; Unz, 1985) and incubated at 20-22 °C for several weeks until visible colonies were apparent. A morphological variant of strain Ben67 was separately subcultured and called Ben68. When the strains grew on both R2A and GS media (22 °C for 4 d), they generally produced small, round, whitish, shiny colonies. However, the ability of the isolated filaments to be successfully subcultured was extremely erratic and there was no pattern to the growth either for media or strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Neisser stain (Jenkins et al., 1993) for polyphosphate, the Rees et al. (1992) stain for polyphosphate and lipophilic inclusions, and the Gram stain (Jenkins et al., 1993) were applied to all strains from both R2A and GS media.</s><s>Microscopic observations of stained and unstained preparations were carried out with a Zeiss Axioskop microscope equipped for phase-contrast, bright field and epifluorescence illumination.</s><s>A Zeiss MC 100 photo micrography system was used to obtain photomicrographs.</s><s>The filaments of the Ben strains were generally wider than those of the Ver strains (compare Fig. 1a and b with c; and Fig. 1d and e with f).</s><s>The Gram stain reaction for all strains was extremely variable, as exemplified by the presence of both Gram-positive and Gram-negative cells or parts of cells for strains growing on both media (examples of Gram-negative parts are shown by arrows in Fig. 1a, b and c).</s><s>Most often, the filaments were evenly positively Neisser stained on GS medium (Fig. 1d, e and f) ; on R2A, cells were either evenly positive (Fig. 1h) or contained positive granules.</s><s>Some strains produced lipophilic inclusions, but this feature was not consistent on the different media.</s><s>Themorphology of the strains was markedly affected by the different media.</s><s>On GS, they generally grew as regular long filaments and closely resembled the appearance (stained and unstained) of `<i>N. limicola</i>' II in activated sludge plants (Fig. 1a-f).</s><s>On R2A, the strains appeared generally as clumps of swollen cells with extremely short filaments (Fig. 1g and i) and at times, clusters of cocci (Fig. 1h).</s><s>Fig. 1(c) and (f) show the results for Ver2, but these were the same for Ver1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The methods used to determine the phenotypic attributes of `<i>N. limicola</i>' II were essentially the same as those reported in Blackall et al. (1997) and Smibert &#x0026; Krieg (1994).</s><s>Strains Ben17, Ben67 and Ver2 were cultured in mineral, salt and vitamins medium (MSV; Williams &#x0026; Unz, 1989) plus 0.5 g glucose l<sup>-1</sup>; the inoculum for all tests was 1%.</s><s>Briefly, the carbon substrate utilization tests were done in MSV plus 0±5 g carbon source l−" ; the nitrogen utilization tests were done in MSV with 0.5 g glucose l<sup>-1</sup> and 0.05 g N l<sup>-1</sup> of the different nitrogen sources (ammonium, nitrite, nitrate, urea); growth temperatures were determined in MSV plus 0.5 g glucose l<sup>-1</sup>; growth under anaerobic conditions was determined in serum bottles with liquid R2A medium; and denitrification ability was assessed in two basal media (liquid R2A and MSV plus 0.5 g glucose l<sup>-1</sup>) amended with 0.1% KNO<sub>3</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The majority of strains could grow on sucrose as the carbon source, nitrite as the nitrogen source and at 35 °C (two of the three strains).</s><s>However, most strains could not use ethanol as the carbon source or grow at 8 °C (two of the three strains).</s><s>All strains could grow on acetate, pyruvate, propionate, glucose, fructose, mannose, lactose, Tween 80, peptone and glycerol as sole carbon sources; none could grow on citrate, succinate, lactate, oleic acid, oleate or propanol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>All strains could use ammonium, nitrate and urea as their nitrogen source, but none could grow without added nitrogen to a mineral based medium.</s><s>All strains grew at 15, 20, 25 and 30 °C, but none could grow at 40 °C.</s><s>No strains could grow anaerobically or with nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor and none produced any reaction in either open or closed Hugh &#x0026; Leifson tubes.</s><s>However, they could all reduce nitrate to nitrite and produce catalase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The near complete 16S rDNA sequences were obtained for all five isolates of `<i>N. limicola</i>' II using methods previously described (Blackall, 1994; Blackall et al., 1994).</s><s>These data for `<i>N. limicola</i>' II were phylogenetically analysed in a dataset of 16S rDNA sequences from a small range of close and distant relatives according to basic local alignment search tool (blast; Altschul et al., 1990) analyses.</s><s>Methods for phylogenetic analysis included manual alignment of sequences in ae2 (Ribosomal Database Project), preparation of datasets masked according to the Lane (1991) mask and analysis by evolutionary distance and parsimony methods in phylip (Felsenstein, 1993).</s><s>A total of 100 bootstrap resamplings was carried out.</s><s>A phylogenetic tree of `<i>N. limicola</i>' II and other actinomycetes is presented in Fig. 2, which describes for the first time the phylogenetic position of `<i>N. limicola</i>' II in the domain Bacteria as a member of the actinomycetes division.</s><s>Our `<i>N. limicola</i>' II strains have <i>Terrabacter</i> and <i>Janibacter</i> species as their closest phylogenetic relatives.</s><s>The `<i>N. limicola</i>' II strains produced a tight cluster (97.4% identical; &#x003E;98% bootstrap value) divided into two well supported (100% bootstrap value) subgroups comprising the Ver strains (99.9% identical) and the Ben strains (99.4% identical).</s><s>A clear variability in the region from nucleotides 997-1043 (V6 region, <i>Escherichia coli</i> numbering; Brosius et al., 1978) was observed between the strains comprising the two subgroups in Fig. 2.</s><s>Potential secondary structural models for this variable V6 region for the two subgroups are presented in Fig. 3.</s><s>The sequence data for the different isolates were deposited in EMBL (Ben17, X85211; Ben18, X85212; Ben67, Y14597; Ver1, Y14595; Ver2, Y14596).</s><s>A comparison between signature nucleotides of the Ben and the Ver strains and their closest relatives (Table 2) highlights Ben and Ver strain signatures that can be used in determining the affiliation of new strains with one or the other of the `<i>N. limicola</i>' II subgroups.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both van Veen (1973) and Nowak &#x0026; Brown (1990) reported that their isolates were facultative anaerobes (Table 1), but our isolates could not grow anaerobically when tested in serum bottles or when tested for their mode of attack on glucose according to the Hugh &#x0026; Leifson test.</s><s>Nowak &#x0026; Brown (1990) reported fermentative growth (Table 1) which is not a characteristic of our strains.</s><s>In addition, our strains could not denitrify nitrate which could be a mechanism of anaerobic growth.</s><s>Phenotypic similarities between our strains and those in the Nowak &#x0026; Brown (1990) study were: the inability to reduce nitrate or utilize citrate; the ability to grow on glucose, lactose, sucrose, glycerol and Tween 80; and intracellular storage of lipophilic material.</s><s>Phenotypic anomalies between strains in the two studies were the result of the anaerobic} fermentative mode of growth (discussed above).</s></p></content></protolog>