<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3800_nm.5182" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5182" rank="genus">Thermicanus</organism><reference id="rid.3800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gößner</surname><given-names>A.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devereux</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohnemüller</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Acker</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drake</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermicanus aegyptius gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from oxic soil, a fermentative microaerophile that grows commensally with the thermophilic acetogen Moorella thermoacetica.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>65</volume><fpage>5124</fpage><lpage>5133</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10543831</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermicanus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermicanus</i> (therm.i.ca'nus. Gr adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. adj. <i>ikanos</i>, M.L. <i>icanus</i>, capable; M.L. <i>Thermicanus</i>, the capable thermophile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A motile, weakly gram-positive, thermophilic, facultative microaerophile isolated from Egyptian soil.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped and have an S-layer and outer and cytoplasmic membranes; spores not apparent.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 55 to 60°C and pH 6.5 to 7; doubling times are approximately 1.5 to 2 h.</s><s>High levels of O<sub>2</sub> impair growth; prefers anoxic or microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>Substrates include stachyose, raffinose, maltose, sucrose, cellobiose, lactose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, and xylose.</s><s>Acetate, formate, and succinate are utilized only under oxic conditions.</s><s>Does not grow on cellulose, arabinose, gluconate, glyoxylate, lactate, pyruvate, oxalate, ethanol, catechol, protocatechuate, vanillate, CO, and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Fermentation products are acetate, succinate, ethanol, formate, lactate, and H<sub>2</sub>; fermentation products are also formed under oxic conditions.</s><s>Nitrate, sulfate, and thiosulfate are not dissimilated; Fe<sup>3+</sup> is reduced to Fe<sup>2+</sup> as a side reaction.</s><s>Particulate and soluble fractions have <i>b</i>-type cytochrome(s).</s><s>G1C content is 50.3 mol%.</s><s>Most closely related to <i>Paenibacillus</i>, <i>Bacillus</i>, and <i>Oxalophagus</i>, with the nearest 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity value being approximately 88%.</s><s>The thermophilic acetogen <i>M. thermoacetica</i> ET-5a grows commensally with <i>T. aegyptius</i> ET-5b<sup>T</sup> on oligosaccharides via the interspecies transfer of H<sub>2</sub>, formate, and lactate.</s></p></content></protolog>