<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10565_nm.17805" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17805" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17805" rank="species">Pontibacillus litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.10565"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>L.-B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Q.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pontibacillus litoralis sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic bacterium isolated from a sea anemone, and emended description of the genus Pontibacillus</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>560</fpage><lpage>565</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009910-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654352</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pontibacillus litoralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pontibacillus litoralis</em> (li.to.ra′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>litoralis</em> of or belonging to the seashore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, moderately halophilic, catalase- and oxidase-positive, Gram-positive rods, approximately 0.4–0.8 μm wide and 3.5–5.0 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella and bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in subterminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are creamy white-pigmented, flat and non-translucent with glistening surfaces and circular/slightly irregular margins, 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation at 35 °C on MA for 2–5 days.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 7.5) and 15–50 °C (optimum, 35 °C).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.5–15 % (w/v) NaCl in complex medium [optimum, 2–5 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Does not grow with NaCl as a sole salt.</s><s>Positive for methyl red test, nitrate reduction and fermentation of glucose, but negative for H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production, nitrite reduction, Voges–Proskauer test, phenylalanine deaminase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Respiration on nitrate, nitrite and fumarate under anaerobic conditions is not observed.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and Tween 40 are hydrolysed, but casein, DNA, hypoxanthine, starch, Tweens 20, 60 and 80, urea and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, dulcitol, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose and d-mannitol as sole carbon sources and l-alanine and l-asparagine as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-arabitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, acetate, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative for acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidases.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to (μg per disc): ampicillin (30), carbenicillin (30), chloramphenicol (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), lincomycin (2), rifampicin (5) and streptomycin (10), but not to nalidixic acid (20), novobiocin (30), polymixin B (30) or tetracycline (30).</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.3 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 072002<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21186<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 13237<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from homogenates of a surface-sterilized sea anemone (<em>Anthopleura xanthogrammica</em>) collected from a tidal flat of a China island, Naozhou, located at the edge of the South China Sea, China.</s></p></content></protolog>