<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4256_nm.2032" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2032" rank="genus">Azospira</organism><reference id="rid.4256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold-Hurek</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the taxonomic structure of the diazotrophic genus Azoarcus sensu lato and description of three new genera and new species, Azovibrio restrictus gen. nov., sp. nov., Azospira oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Azonexus fungiphilus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>659</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azospira</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azospira</i> (A.zo'spi.ra. Fr. n. <i>azote</i> nitrogen; L. fem. n. <i>spira</i> winding, turn; M.L. fem. n. <i>Azospira</i> nitrogen-fixing spiral)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formerly <i>Azoarcus</i> sp. group D.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonspore-forming, curved rods; cells range from 0.4 to 0.6 μm in width and from 1.1 to 2.5 μm in length; elongated cells with one to several spiral windings of up to 8 μm cell length occur rarely in late-stationary phase, alkalinized, nitrogen-fixing cultures.</s><s>Highly motile with a corkscrew-like motion by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Microaerophilic growth as veil-like pellicles which move up to the surface in semi-solid N-free media.</s><s>Strictly respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen or nitrate as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Chemorganoheterotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>No dissimilatory nitrate reductase.</s><s>Growth factor requirement varies.</s><s>Capable of growth in atmospheric nitrogen (N<sub>2</sub>) and reduction of acetylene to ethylene.</s><s>Grow mostly on salts of organic acids, such as L-malate, DL-lactate, succinate, fumarate, acetate, 2-oxoglutarate, <i>n</i>-caproate and propionate, and on ethanol; no growth occurs on most amino acids, nor on any mono-or disaccharides (Table 2).</s><s>Grow well at 37 °C.</s><s>Not halophilic or NaCl-dependent: no growth at 2% NaCl.</s><s>Neutral pH optimal for growth.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are <i>cis</i>-9 16:1, 16: 0, 18:1 and 3-OH-10:1.</s><s>G­C content of DNA is 65-66 mol%.</s><s>Member of the β-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Characteristics differentiating them from other diazotrophs given in Table 2 and 3.</s><s>Type species is <i>Azospira oryzae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>