<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5994_nm.2985" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2985" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2985" rank="species">Vibrio mytili</organism><reference id="rid.5994"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ortigosa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urdaci</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio mytili sp. nov., from mussels.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>362</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio mytili</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio mytili</i> (my.ti'.li. L. gen. n. <i>mytili</i>, of mussels [the genus <i>Mytilus</i>])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative coccobacilli motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Grows readily on marine agar 2216 (Difco), yeast extract agar (1, 2), and tryptone soya agar (Oxoid) containing 1% NaCl and in semisolid seawater agar (stab cultures).</s><s>Colonies develop within 24 h at 28°C and are regular in shape and unpigmented.</s><s>Grows on thiosulfate-citrate-bile-sucrose agar (yellow colonies) but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Swarming has not been detected in any of the media used.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative, with production of gas.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase, and nitrate reduction to nitrite are positive.</s><s>No growth occurs without addition of NaCl to the culture medium.</s><s>The salt requirement is specific for sodium ions.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 1 to 10% (wt/vol) NaCl but not in the presence of 20% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to vibriostatic agent OD29 (150 μg per disc).</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 37°C, but not at 4 or 40°C.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer, indole, H<sub>2</sub>S, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, and β-glucuronidase negative.</s><s>Thornley's ADH positive.</s><s>The strains are not able to hydrolyze urea, DNA, gelatin, casein, starch, alginate, and xanthine but degrade Tween 80, esculin, and tyrosine.</s><s>Acid is produced from sucrose, L-arabinose, arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, maltose, D-trehalose, salicin, and D-xylose, but not from D-mannose, D-sorbitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, and adonitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>V. mytili</i>- strains utilize the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-acoaitate, malanine, L-alanine, L-aspartate, D-cellobiose, esculin, D-fructose, fumarate, D-galactose, gentibiose, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, L-glutamate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, 2-ketoglutarate, DL-lactate, L-malate, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, 1-O-methyl-β-D-glucoside, palatinose, L-proline, D-raffinose, D-ribose, L-serine, succinate, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-turanose, L-tyrosine, and D-xylose.</s><s>Four of the five strains use L-arabinose, betaine, citrate, lactose, D-malate, and D-melezitose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, 4-aminobutyrate, 5 -aminovalerate, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, benzoate, caprate, caprylate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, dulcitol, <i>i</i>-erythritol, ethanolamine, L-fucose, D-galacturonate, gentisate, D-glucuronate, glutarate, histamine, L-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, D-lyxose, malonate, D-mannose, D-melibiose, 1-O-methyl-α-galactoside, 3-O-methyl-D-glucose, 1-O-methyl-α-D-glucoside, mucate, phenylacetate, 3- phenylpropionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, Lrhamnose, D-saccharate, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, tryptophan, and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 45 to 46 mol% (as determined by the thermal method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from mussels (<i>Mytilus edulis</i>) commercialized in Valencia but harvested off the Atlantic Spanish coast (Galicia).</s><s>Not known to be pathogenic for humans or mussels.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 165.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain 165<sup>T</sup> has all of the properties given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, L-arabinose, betaine, citrate, lactose, lactulose, D-malate, D-melezitose, and 1-methyl-β-galactoside are utilized in 2 or 4 days and maltitol is not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45.6 mol%.</s><s>This strain has been deposited at the Coleccion Espaiiola de Cultivos Tipo (Valencia, Spain) as strain CECT 632.</s></p></content></protolog>