<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4760_nm.2803" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2803" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2803" rank="species">Enhydrobacter aerosaccus</organism><reference id="rid.4760"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Irgens</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enhydrobacter aerosaccus gen. nov., sp. nov., a gas-vacuolated, facultatively anaerobic, heterotrophic rod.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>291</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-289</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enhydrobacter aerosaccus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enhydrobacter aerosaccus</i> (aer'o.sac.cus Gr. n. <i>aer</i>, air; Gr. N. <i>sakkos</i>, sack; N.L. <i>aerosaccus</i>, gas vacuolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gas-vacuolated, nonflagellated rod.</s><s>Gas vacuoles are not produced when grown on sugars, but are produced when grown on certain organic acids such as pyruvate, acetate, and succinate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Best growth occurs microaerophilically .</s><s>Folic acid and biotin are required when grown on a defined mineral medium, Colonies on RM-2 agar are colorless with an entire margin and convex elevation and adhere to agar surface.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>No growth at 7 or 43°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20 to 41°C.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is between 37 and 39°C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0 to 9.5.</s><s>Grows on CLED medium (Oxoid, Basingstoke, England) with 0 and 1% NaCl.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole not produced.</s><s>No growth on Clark Lubs medium.</s><s>No hydrolysis of O-nitrate-β-D-galactopyranoside.</s><s>Tween 80 (1% in RM-2 medium with 0.01% CaCl<sub>2</sub>) hydrolyzed.</s><s>No growth on deoxyribonuclease medium (method 1 of Vera and Power [9]).</s><s>Lysine, ornithine, and arginine decarboxylated after 5 weeks at room temperature (Moller's medium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources were utilized after 60 days of incubation at 30°C: L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-fucose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-sorbose, D-galactose, D-xylose, sucrose, maltose, acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, glycerol, succinate, inulin, ethanol (all in CAAm medium [S]), pyruvate, lactate, <i>meso</i>-malate, oxaloacetate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate (all in DM medium [S]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources were not utilized: lactose, cellobiose, raffinose, trehalose, melezitose, melibiose, starch, salicin, pectin, amygdalin, dextrin, phthalate, methanol, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, erythritol, formate, butyrate (all in CAAm medium [S]), benzoate and malonate (in DM medium [S]), and cellulose, chitin, agar, and gelatin by the method of Skerman (5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (ATCC 27094) was isolated from the oxygen-depleted zone (4 mg of dissolved oxygen per liter) of a eutrophic lake.</s></p></content></protolog>