<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7875_nm.2818" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2818" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2818" rank="species">Alteromonas fuliginea</organism><reference id="rid.7875"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kurika</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of brown-pigmented agarolytic bacteria of the genus Alteromonas.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>63</volume><fpage>1081</fpage><lpage>1087</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas fuliginea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas fuliginea</i> (Fu. li. gi. nea. L. adj. <i>fuliginea</i> - black-brown)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells with rounded ends.</s><s>Dimensions: length 1.5-1.8 μm, diameter 0.5-0.8 μmm.</s><s>Flagellated, motile.</s><s>The cells occur singly, sometimes in pairs.</s><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic.</s><s>Do not produce spores or capsules.</s><s>On complex media containing sea water, they form black or brown smooth, convex, glossy colonies 3-5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Synthesis of melanin-like pigment is intensive at temperatures from 4 to 10°C.</s><s>The cells require sea water or 1-6% sodium chloride for growth.</s><s>They do not grow in the absence of Na ion.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells grow at pH values from 6.0 and 9.0, the optimum pH being 7.5 to 8.5.</s><s>Their growth temperature ranges from 4 to 35°e.</s><s>The cells do not grow at 40°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are chemoorganoheterotrophs.</s><s>They utilize citrate, caprate, phenylacetate, tyrosine, and arginine as a source of carbon and energy.</s><s>They also utilize yeast extract, caseine hydrolyzate, gelatin, Tween-80, and DNA.</s><s>They do not utilize alcohols or sugars.</s><s>The cells display catalase, oxidase, and β-galactosidase activities.</s><s>They digest agar, carrageenan, alginic acids, esculin, and starch.</s><s>They do not digest N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, chitin, or cellulose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The (G + C) content of their DNA ranges from 41.5 to 43.8 mole%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain KMM 216 is chosen as the type strain.</s><s>It is isolated from the homogenate of purple sea squirt <i>Halocynthia aurantium</i> inhabiting the coastal waters of Peter the Great Bay in the Sea of Japan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the strain corresponds to that of the type species.</s><s>The strain is deposited in the Collection of Marine Microorganisms (KMM) of the Pacific Ocean Institute of Bioorganic Chemistry, Far East Branch of Russian Academy of Sciences, Vladivostok.</s></p></content></protolog>