<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12588_nm.21847" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21847" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21847" rank="species">Fibrisoma limi</organism><reference id="rid.12588"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Filippini</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaech</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ziegler</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bagheri</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fibrisoma limi gen. nov., sp. nov., a filamentous bacterium isolated from tidal flats</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1418</fpage><lpage>1424</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025395-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601484</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fibrisoma limi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fibrisoma limi</em> (li′mi. L. gen. n. <em>limi</em> of/from mud).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>After 1 day of growth in SM, filaments are 1.1 µm in diameter and 6.9–86.2 µm in length (Fig. 2).</s><s>In the earlier exponential growth phase, lengths of up to 366 µm can be reached.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are orange, convex and circular with regular edges.</s><s>Flagellar and gliding motility are absent.</s><s>Growth occurs in R2A, SM, NB, 0.5 % yeast water and on YT but not on blood, MacConkey and TS agars or in peptone water.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–7.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth within 1 week is 10–40 °C (optimum 20–30 °C).</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth but tolerates up to 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Agar, agarose and amylopectin are hydrolysed and starch, casein and xylan are weakly hydrolysed (as shown by haloes around the colonies).</s><s>Pectin and CM-cellulose are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API ZYM strip, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase activities are present; lipase (C14), β-glucuronidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the API 20NE strip, positive reactions are observed for β-galactosidase, aesculin assimilation and gelatin hydrolysis; negative reactions for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities, and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, negative results are observed for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease activities, citrate utilization, and H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production.</s><s>In the API 50CH strip after 7 days of incubation, aesculin is the only substrate assimilated; all other substrates are not assimilated.</s><s>No growth on glucose, arabinose, lactose or maltose in BG 11 medium.</s><s>Resistant to amikacin (30 µg), colistin (30 U), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg) and polymyxin B (300 U).</s><s>Sensitive to amoxicillin (10 µg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (20/10 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), ciprofloxacin (5 µg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30 µg), streptomycin (30 µg) and tetracycline (30 µg).</s><s>Intermediate sensitivity to vancomycin (10 µg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular morphology of strain BUZ 3<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped and form filaments; light micrograph (a), scanning electron micrograph (b) and transmission electron micrograph (c).</s><s>Bars, 20 µm (a), 2 µm (b) and 0.5 µm (c).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BUZ 3<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22564<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 58137<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mud in a tidal flat on the North Sea Coast of Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>