<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8620_nm.13674" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13674" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13674" rank="species">Vibrio porteresiae</organism><reference id="rid.8620"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rameshkumar</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fukul</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nair</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio porteresiae sp. nov., a diazotrophic bacterium isolated from a mangrove-associated wild rice (Porteresia coarctata Tateoka).</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1608</fpage><lpage>1615</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65604-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599703</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio porteresiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio porteresiae</em> (por.te.re′si.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>porteresiae</em> of porteresia, because the organism was isolated from <em>Porteresia coarctata</em>, a wild relative of rice growing in mangroves).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight to slightly curved rods (0.9×1.0–2.0 μm) which occur singly or in pairs and are motile.</s><s>Colonies on TSA supplemented with 1.5 % (w/v) NaCl are circular, smooth, and white with exopolysaccharide production within 2 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Swarming is not detected.</s><s>Able to fix atmospheric nitrogen.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.4±3.1 mol%.</s><s>Positive result in the Voges–Proskauer reaction and in tests for aesculin hydrolysis and citrate utilization.</s><s>Negative result in tests for indole production, ONPG and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, caseinase or amylase.</s><s>Negative for the reduction of nitrate to nitrite and no growth is observed in TCBS.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl concentrations of up to 5 % (w/v), but not at 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs in the presence of 1–2 % (w/v) NaCl at 28 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed in 0 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–37 °C (optimal growth occurs at 28 °C), but no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C, and at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimal growth occurs at pH 7).</s><s>Resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (10 or 150 μg per disc).</s><s>Facultative anaerobe capable of both aerobic and anaerobic fermentative growth.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from fermentation of glucose.</s><s>Other carbohydrates such as lactose, maltose, fructose, glucose, cellobiose, galactose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, mannitol and salicin are also fermented.</s><s>Trehalose, dulcitol, raffinose, melibiose, sorbose, melezitose, inulin, glycerol, sorbitol, adonitol and inositol are not fermented.</s><s>Grows in a mineral medium containing glucose and NH<sub>4</sub>Cl.</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, mannitol, salicin, rhamnose, xylose, fructose, glucose, maltose, mannitol, l-serine, and l-proline as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilization of melibiose is weak.</s><s>Does not use inulin, trehalose, inositol, dulcitol, arabinose, raffinose, sorbitol, mannose, l-alanine, l-choline, l-ornithine, l-arginine, l-lysine, l-valine, l-methionine or l-threonine as carbon sources.</s><s>The most abundant fatty acids are summed feature 3 (27.53 %; comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (18.75 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (19.20 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8.15 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (6.84 %), summed feature 2 (6.81 %; comprising an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain-length of 10.928 and/or C<sub>12 : 0</sub> ALDE, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I and/or C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH) and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6.40 %).</s><s>The following fatty acids are detected in small amounts; C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0.08 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.49 %), C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.38 %), C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0.25 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.22 %), C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH (0.25 %), summed feature 1 (0.64 %; comprising C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or C<sub>15 : 1</sub> iso I/H), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (0.26 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (0.26 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (0.24 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (0.58 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (0.36 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0.58 %), 11 methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (0.82 %) and an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain-length of 12.484 (0.94 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSSRF30<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24061<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19223<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from <em>Porteresia coarctata</em>, a wild relative of rice growing in mangroves.</s></p></content></protolog>