<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5263_nm.230" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.230" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.230" rank="species">Methanosarcina acetivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5263"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sowers</surname><given-names>K.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baron</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferry</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanosarcina acetivorans sp. nov., an Acetotrophic Methane-Producing Bacterium Isolated from Marine Sediments.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>971</fpage><lpage>978</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16346552</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanosarcina acetivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanosarcina acetivorans</i> (a.ce.tivo.rans, L.n. <i>acetum</i>, vinegar; L. part. adj. <i>vorans</i>, consuming; N.L. mas. adj. <i>acetivorans</i>, consuming acetic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphovars of this species, when grown on acetate, occur as irregular cocci, septated cell aggregates, or communal cysts that contain several individual cocci within a common envelope.</s><s>Individual cocci are 1.9 μm in diameter and nonmotile.</s><s>Surface colonies are pale yellow, circular, and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are lysed by SDS and possess a thin (10-nm), gram-negative cell wall.</s><s>Acetate, methanol, methylamine, dimethylamine, and trimethylamine are growth substrates; H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> (80:20) and sodium formate are not; NaCl (0.2 M optimum) and Mg<sup>2+</sup> (0.05 to 1.0 M optimum) are required for growth; no exogenous growth factors are required; the optimum temperature is 35 to 40°C; the optimum pH is 6.5 to 7.0; it is a strict anaerobe.</s><s>The source is anaerobic sediments from the Sumner branch of Scripps Canyon located near La Jolla, California.</s><s>The type strain is C2A.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms, Göttingen, Germany, as DSM 2834 and in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as ATCC 35395.</s></p></content></protolog>