<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12120_nm.20114" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20114" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20114" rank="species">Alishewanella agri</organism><reference id="rid.12120"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jo</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alishewanella agri sp. nov., isolated from landfill soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2199</fpage><lpage>2203</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011684-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897613</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alishewanella agri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alishewanella agri</em> (a′gri. L. gen. n. <em>agri</em> of a field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, aerobic, rod-shaped, 1–2 μm long and 0.5 μm wide and exist as single cells after incubation on LA for 2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies are 1–3 mm in diameter, circular, raised and a light ivory colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–44 °C in 0–6 % NaCl, with optimal growth at 30 °C in 2 % NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5–12.0, with an optimum pH of 6.0–8.0.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase reactions are positive.</s><s>Positive for reduction of nitrates to nitrites, aesculin hydrolysis and gelatin hydrolysis, but negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Cannot produce indole and does not ferment glucose.</s><s>No arginine dihydrolase or urease activity.</s><s>Enzyme activities are present for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Enzyme activities are not present for lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>In API 20NE, d-glucose and maltose are assimilated, but l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid are not.</s><s>According to the API 50CH test, d-glucose, aesculin, maltose, sucrose and starch are assimilated, but not glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl d-mannopyranoside, methyl d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, trehalose, insulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Growth also occurs on TSA, R2A and MA.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 54.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BL06<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22400<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15597<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in Pohang, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>