<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9267_nm.14546" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14546" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14546" rank="species">Natranaerobius trueperi</organism><reference id="rid.9267"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mesbah</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Natronovirga wadinatrunensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Natranaerobius trueperi sp. nov., halophilic, alkalithermophilic micro-organisms from soda lakes of the Wadi An Natrun, Egypt</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2042</fpage><lpage>2048</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008151-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605718</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Natranaerobius trueperi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Natranaerobius trueperi</em> (true′pe.ri. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>trueperi</em> of Trüper, referring to Hans G. Trüper, in honour of his contributions to the field of physiology of halophiles and his earlier work on the microbial ecology of the Wadi An Natrun).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells form irregularly shaped to circular opaque colonies with a white colour (when grown inside 1 % agar).</s><s>Cells are 2–3×0.6 μm in size, non-motile and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Cells are Gram-staining and Gram-type positive (Wiegel, 1981).</s><s>Halophilic: optimal growth occurs at 3.7 M Na<sup>+</sup> (2.2 M added NaCl); no growth occurs at Na<sup>+</sup> concentrations below 3.1 M or above 5.4 M.</s><s>Obligately alkaliphilic, pH<sup>55 °C</sup> range, 8.0–10.8, with an optimum at pH<sup>55 °C</sup> 9.5; no growth occurs at pH<sup>55 °C</sup> 7.8 or below and at pH<sup>55 °C</sup> 11.0 or above.</s><s>Thermophilic: temperature range for growth is 26–55 °C, with an optimum at 52 °C (at pH<sup>55 °C</sup> 9.5).</s><s>No growth at or below 24 °C or at or above 57 °C.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>In the presence of 0.3 % (w/v) yeast extract and tryptone, glucose, ribose, acetate, sucrose, Casamino acids, cellobiose, pyruvate and trimethylamine are used as carbon and energy sources (0.5 % w/v, pH<sup>55 °C</sup> 9.5).</s><s>Fructose, trehalose, betaine, formate, ribitol, ethanol, n-propanol and benzoate are not utilized.</s><s>Organic fermentation products from pyruvate are acetate and lactate.</s><s>Nitrate is utilized as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Sulfate, MnO<sub>2</sub>,  and  are not reduced.</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and hydrogen sulfide in the presence of 0.3 % yeast extract/tryptone and 0.2 % glucose.</s><s>Does not utilize citrate or produce urease, indole or acetoin.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids include i15 : 0 and a15 : 0.</s><s>The type strain of the species lacks detectable amounts of murein and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the genomic DNA is 41 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JW/NM-WN-LU<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18760<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1443<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of Lake UmRisha, Wadi An Natrun, Egypt.</s><s>Strain JW/NM-WN-LB2 was isolated from sediment of Lake Baida and strains JW/NM-WN-LA1 and JW/NM-WN-LA3 were isolated from sediments of Lake Abu Dawood, Wadi An Natrun, Egypt.</s></p></content></protolog>