<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12453_nm.21280" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21280" rank="species">Pseudonocardia mongoliensis</organism><reference id="rid.12453"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsetseg</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daram</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ando</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia mongoliensis sp. nov. and Pseudonocardia khuvsgulensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>747</fpage><lpage>756</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019562-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20418406</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia mongoliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia mongoliensis</em> (mon.go.li.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>mongoliensis</em> of or belonging to Mongolia, referring to the isolation of the type strain from soil of Mongolia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive.</s><s>Cells grow well on Bennett’s, yeast-starch and ISP 2 agar at 28 °C, forming well-developed, extensively branched and non-fragmented substrate hyphae.</s><s>Extensive acropetal budding of the white aerial hyphae and the formation of blastospores are observed.</s><s>Very scanty aerial hyphae are formed, only on the surface of water agar.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is light to moderate yellowish brown to pale yellow on different agar media.</s><s>Optimal growth at 25–30 °C; no growth at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 4–11 and tolerates up to 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase is not produced, nitrate is not reduced and gelatin, starch and Tweens 20 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>Arbutin is decomposed but casein, tyrosine, calcium malate, adenine and hypoxanthine are not.</s><s>According to the API ZYM enzyme assay, positive for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase, weakly positive for lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for alkaline phosphatase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase and α-mannosidase.</s><s>According to the API Coryne enzyme assay, positive for pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, urease and hydrolysis of gelatin, weakly positive for utilization of d-glucose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose and sucrose and negative for nitrate reduction, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and catalase and utilization of lactose and glycogen.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid; diagnostic sugars are galactose, ribose, glucose, arabinose, mannose and rhamnose (trace).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The menaquinone system consists of MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>0</sub>).</s><s>Major fatty acid methyl esters are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, unknown ECL 16.05, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid profile of the type strain is given in Table 3.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MN08-A0270<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 105885<sup>T</sup>  = VTCC D9-25<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of Khuvsgul Lake, Khuvsgul province, Mongolia.</s></p></content></protolog>