<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3439_nm.7359" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7359" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7359" rank="species">Kitasatospora cheerisanensis</organism><reference id="rid.3439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sung</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mo</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Son</surname><given-names>D.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kitasatospora cheerisanensis sp. nov., a new species of the genus Kitasatospora that produces an antifungal agent</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>753</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-753</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319499</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kitasatospora cheerisanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kitasatospora cheerisanensis</i> (chee.ri.sanen'sis. M.L. masc. adj. <i>cheerisanensis</i> pertaining to Cheerisan, the name of a mountain in Korea where the species was originated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast actinomycete which produces a greenish-yellow substrate mycelium and a whitish-grey aerial mycelium on yeast extract-malt extract agar, inorganic salt-starch agar, tyrosine agar, Bennett's agar and starch agar.</s><s>Vegetative mycelia fragment into bacillary structures, Spore chains are rectiflexibiles, with 20 or more rod-shaped smooth-surfaced spores (0.75-0.90 by 1.2-1.5 μm) per chain.</s><s>Submerged spores are formed in liquid culture.</s><s>Soluble pigments including melanin are not produced.</s><s>Colonies lacking aerial mycelium during early growth stage were pasty, circular, convex and dull milky on 0.1 x TSA.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-DAP and LLDAP.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain glucose and mannose, but lack galactose.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol are contained in the polar lipid fraction.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are saturated iso- and anteisobranched as well as straight-chain fatty acids.</s><s>The major menaquinone type is MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>The strain is positive for catalase activity and reduction of nitrate.</s><s>Acids are produced from arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, maltose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Casein, chitin, chitosan, starch, aesculin, gelatin, hippurate and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are decomposed, but cellulose, hypoxanthine and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1% NaCl, but not in 3% NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs at pH 7-8, and the optimum temperature range is 25-30 °C.</s><s>Arabinose, azelate, cellobiose, cronate, fumarate, D-glucose, galactose, iso-butyrate, malonate, maltose, rhamnose, trehalose and xylose are utilized for growth, but adonitol, fructose, glycerol, mannitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, suberate, succinate and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>This strain is susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, oxytetracycline, rifampicin and streptomycin.</s><s>The type strain YC75<sup>T</sup> produced bafilomycin-C1-like antifungal compounds.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 75-8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Kitasatospora cheerisanensis</i> YC75<sup>T</sup> and has been deposited in Korean Collection for Type Cultures as KCTC 2395<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>