<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4057_nm.7754" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7754" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7754" rank="species">Planctomyces stranskae</organism><reference id="rid.4057"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Starr</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planctomyces stranskae (ex Wawrik 1952) sp. nov., nom. rev. and Planctomyces guttaeformis (ex Hortobágyi 1965) sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>477</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planctomyces stranskae</i> (ex Wawrik 1952) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planctomyces stranskae</i> (stran'skae. M.L. adj. <i>stranskae</i> of Stransky; named originally by F. Wawrik [24] in honor of her biology teacher, M. L. Stransky)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are relatively large (3.0 to 3.5 μm in length, 1.5 to 1.7 μm in diameter at the globose end, ca. 1.3 to 1.4 μm in initial diameter at the conical end, and 1.0 to 1.1 μm in diameter at the terminus of the cell) and bulbiform (i.e., bulb shaped; a truncated cone blending into a spherical terminal dilatation; shaped like a common screw-in incandescent light bulb).</s><s>Numerous multifibrillar appendages, termed bristles, extend from the globose (spherical) end of the cell.</s><s>Numerous bacteria are associated with the bristles, especially in preparations made directly from natural samples.</s><s>Division is by budding, with a mirror-image bud formed at the globose end of the cell.</s><s>Numerous crateriform surface structures are present on the globose end of the cell; the presence of pili is uncertain.</s><s>The fine structure is typically bacterial, except for the rather thin cell envelope, the crateriform surface structures, and the many multifibrillar bristles.</s><s>Resistant to betalactam antibiotics.</s><s>Occur in rosettes, consisting of as many as 12 cells attached via holdfasts at the narrower ends of the several cells.</s><s>Neither motility nor flagella have been observed.</s><s>Common in eutrophic freshwater habitats, usually accompanying phototrophs (algae and cyanobacteria).</s><s>Metallic oxide encrustations of the cells have been observed in material from Austria (24) and from San Carlos Reservoir in Ariz. (unpublished observations).</s><s>Has not been cultivated axenically , although blooms occur in laboratory enrichments.</s><s>The type material consists of the present description and illustrations (Ps in Fig. 1; Fig. 5 ; and Fig. 6).</s><s>The type locality is a eutrophic man-made pond in a residential district (The Lakes) in Tempe, Ariz.</s><s>Frequently confused with <i>Planctomyces guttaeformis</i> (ex Hortobiigyi 1965) sp. nov., nom. rev., from which it can be distinguished on the basis of cellular size and shape, the absence of a multifibrillar spike in <i>P. stranskae</i> and its presence in <i>P. guttaeformis</i>, and the presence of numerous multifibrillar bristles in <i>P. stranskae</i> and their absence in <i>P. guttaeformis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>