<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.321_nm.121" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.121" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.121" rank="species">Methanobrevibacter cuticularis</organism><reference id="rid.321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leadbetter</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Breznak</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Physiological ecology of Methanobrevibacter cuticularis sp. nov. and Mehanobrevibacter curvatus sp. nov., isolated from the hindgut of the termite Reticulitermes flavipes.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>62</volume><fpage>3620</fpage><lpage>3631</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanobrevibacter cuticularis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanobrevibacter cuticularis</i> (cu.tic'ul.ar'is. L. <i>cuticula</i>, dim. skin; L. adj. <i>cuticularis</i>, referring to the cuticular surface of the termite hindgut epithelium which is colonized by this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight short rods with slightly tapered ends, 0.4 by 1.2 μm in size, occurring singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Gram positive-like by staining and cell wall ultrastructure.</s><s>No endospores formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict anaerobe.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Metabolizes H<sub>2</sub> plus CO<sub>2</sub> and formate (the latter very poorly), yielding CH<sub>4</sub> as the sole product.</s><s>Methanol, methanol plus H<sub>2</sub>, CO, acetate, ethanol, isopropanol, trimethylamine, dimethylamine, theobromine, theophylline, trimethoxybenzoate, lactate, pyruvate, and glucose are not metabolized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH optimum, 7.7 (range, 6.5 to 8.5); temperature optimum, 37°C (range, 10 to 37°C).</s><s>Chemolithotrophic growth occurs very slowly.</s><s>Yeast extract, a source of amino acids (e.g., Casamino Acids), and ca. 2% clarified rumen fluid are markedly stimulatory to growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Hindgut contents of the termite <i>Reticulitermes flavipes</i> (Kollar) (Rhinotermitidae).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: RFM-1.</s><s>Deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, Germany (DSM number not yet assigned; culture currently available from the authors).</s></p></content></protolog>