<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5800_nm.6348" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6348" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6348" rank="subspecies">Mycobacterium fortuitum acetamidolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.5800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imaeda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium fortuitum subspecies acetamidolyticum, a new subspecies of Mycobacterium fortuitum</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>97</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><source id="128">Microbiology and Immunology</source><abbrev>Microbiol Immunol</abbrev><issn>0385-5600</issn><essn>1348-0421</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3713561</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium fortuitum</i> subsp. <i>acetamidolyticum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium fortuitum</i> subsp. <i>acetamidolyticum</i> (<i>acetamidolyticum</i>: Latin adj., digesting acetamide)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: sputum of a patient; probably a lung pathogen.</s><s>Type strain: ATCC 35931 (NCH E11620).</s><s>The type strain is deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., U.S.A.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are described below (unless specially noted, the other two isolates show the same characteristics).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Occur as acid-fast short or intermediate rods (2-6 μm in length and 0.5-1.0 μm in width); cord is not formed; form rough, nonphotochromogenic, white colonies on Ogawa egg medium (or Lowenstei<i>n</i>-Jensen medium); grow on Ogawa egg medium after incubation at 37C for 5 days (the growth rate is faster than that of slowly growing mycobacteria and slower than that of rapidly growing mycobacteria); grow at 28 C, 37 C, and 42 C, but do not grow at 45 C or more.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grow on Ogawa egg medium containing 0.2% sodium <i>p</i>-aminosalicylate, hydroxylaminehydrochloride (0.5 mg/ml), sodium salicylate (0.5mg/ml), <i>p</i>-nitro benzoicacid (0.5 mg/ml), rifampicin (25 μg/ml), ethambutol (5 μg/ml), isoniazid (10 μg/ml), streptomycin sulfate (20 μg/ml), kanamycin sulfate (100 μg/ml), ethio namide(40 μg/ml), or thiophene-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide (1 μg/ml); do not grow on Ogawa egg medium containing 5% NaCl or ofloxacin (1 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Do not grow on a modified Sauton agar medium, in which sodium glutamate is substituted for asparagine (strain E11593 shows scanty growth); do not grow on modified Sauton agar medium containing 0.1% and 0.2% picric acid, or containing 0.1% sodium salicylate; show scanty growth on modified Sauton agar medium con taining0.1% or 0.2% sodium nitrite or containing 1% Tween 80.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arylsulfatase activity (3 days) positive; catalase (semi-quantitative) positive (negative in the other two isolates); α-esterase negative; β-esterase positive; β-galactosidase negative; nitrate is reduced to nitrite (6hr); niacin is not produed; Tween 80 is not hydrolyzed even after 14 days; acetamidase, urease, nicotinamidase, and pyrazinamidase activites are present, while benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, salicylamidase, allantoinase, and succinamidase activities are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-Glutamate, L-serine, D-glucosamine hydrochloride, benzamide, monoetha nolamine,and trimethylene diamine are not utilized as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources, but acetamide is utilized as a source of these elements.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose, acetate, succinate, and pyruvate are not utilized as sources of carbon in the presence of glutamate nitrogen.</s><s>In the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen, however, acetate, malate, pyruvate, fumarate, glucose, fructose, D-mannose, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, and <i>iso</i>-butanol are utilized as sources of carbon, but benzoate, malonate, sucrose, D-galactose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, trehalose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, 1,3-butylene glycol, and 1,4-butylene glycol are not utilized as carbon sources in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen (the other two isolates show scanty growth in the presence of citrate, and do not utilize succinate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-Serine, benzamide, pyrazinamide, nicotinamide, succinamide, nitrate, and nitrite are not utilized as sole sources of nitrogen in the presence of glycerol carbon, but acetamide and urea are utilized as sources of nitrogen (the other two strains do not utilize urea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The number of carbon atoms of the α-mycolate ranges from 68 to 82, and the center peak is at carbon number 78.</s><s>The G+C content is 62-63%.</s></p></content></protolog>