<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5818_nm.10039" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10039" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10039" rank="species">Streptococcus massiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.5818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Glazunova</surname><given-names>O.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus massiliensis sp. nov., isolated from a patient blood culture.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1127</fpage><lpage>1131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64009-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627666</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus massiliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus massiliensis</em> (mas.si.li.en′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>massiliensis</em> of Massilia, the ancient Greek and Roman name for Marseille, France, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming cocci, arranged in pairs or short chains that are 0.3–0.7 μm in diameter.</s><s>Surface colonies on sheep-blood agar are circular, white to greyish, shiny, convex, non-haemolytic and 1–2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37 °C in CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere.</s><s>Growth also occurs in aerobic, microaerophilic and anaerobic atmospheres.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 37 °C but growth is observed at 25–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The type strain carries Lancefield G group antigen and is resistant to optochine.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Acetoin production is negative and hydrolysis of hippurate is positive.</s><s>Enzyme activity of arginine dihydrolase, leucine aminopeptidase, alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase and alkaline phosphatase is detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, urease, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase or <em>β</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Maltose is fermented.</s><s>The following sugars are not fermented: arabinose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, glycogen, sucrose, pullulan, tagatose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, melibiose, ribose, starch and melezitose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4401825<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108498<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49690<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human blood sample.</s></p></content></protolog>