<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1016_nm.6999" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6999" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6999" rank="species">Streptomyces flaviscleroticus</organism><reference id="rid.1016"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Chainia species to the genus Streptomyces with emended description of species</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>55</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces flaviscleroticus</i> (Pridham) nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces flaviscleroticus</i> (<i>fla. vi. scle.</i> rot'i. cus. L. adj. <i>flavus</i>, yellow; L. neut. n. <i>sclerotium</i>; M. L. adj. <i>flaviscleroticus</i>, yellow sclerotium, referring to yellow and ability to form sclerotia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from information derived from several sources (Thirmalachar and Sukapure, 1964; <i>Shirling</i> and <i>Gottlieb</i>, 1972; <i>Williams</i> et aI., 1983; <i>Collins</i> et al., 1984; <i>Ruan</i> et aI., 1985).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic organism with extensively branched substtate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Spiral spore chains of smooth surfaced spores borne on the aerial mycelium.</s><s>Yellow brown substrate mycelium.</s><s>Produces sclerotia.</s><s>Does not form melanin pigments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adenine, aesculin, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch and urea are degraded but allantoin, chitin, lecithin, pectin, testosterone, L-tyrosine, xanthine and xylan are not.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is produced but nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-lactose, maltose, D~mannitol, D-mannose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, trehalose and D-xylose are used a sole carbon sources but adonitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, sucrose and xylitol are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is formed from D-lactose, D-mannitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, sucrose and D-xylose but not from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-melibiose, raffinose and D-sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows on DL-α-amino-n-butyric acid, L-arginine, L-histidine, potassium nitrate, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine, but not on L-cysteine, L-hydroxyproline, L-methionine or L-phenylalanine as sole nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 37 and 45°C but not at 10°C.</s><s>Tolerant to sodium azide (0.01 %, w/v) and sodium chloride (4%, w/v) but not to phenol (0.1 %, w/v).</s><s>Sensitive to rifampicin and sodium chloride (7%, w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not show antimicrobial activity against <i>Aspergillus niger</i> LIV 131, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> NCIB 3610, <i>Candida albicans</i> CBS 562, <i>Escherichia coli</i> NCIB 9132, <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> NCIB 196, <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> NCIB 9046, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i> CBS 1171 or <i>Streptomyces murinus</i> ISP 5091.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism contains major amounts of octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil, Pimpri, Inclia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 19347 (= DSM 43152 = IFO 12998 = ISP 5270 = KCC 3100 = NCIB 11008 = RIA 833).</s></p></content></protolog>