<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3485_nm.15" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15" rank="species">Pyrobaculum arsenaticum</organism><reference id="rid.3485"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sacher</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vollmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Respiration of arsenate and selenate by hyperthermophilic archaea.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>305</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11108007</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pyrobaculum arsenaticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pyrobaculum arsenaticum</i> (ar.se.na'ti.cum M.L. neutr. adj. <i>arsenaticum</i>, describing the ability of the organism to grow autotrophically on arsenate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cylinder-shaped rods, usually between 3 and 7 μm long and 0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Motile by flagellation.</s><s>Rods often arranged in V-, X- and raft-shaped aggregates.</s><s>No true branching.</s><s>Cells with terminal spheres occur in the stationary phase.</s><s>When grown organotrophically on arsenate or on arsenate and thiosulfate with hydrogen, small black particles (width: 0.3-0.4 μm) occur on the cell surface in the stationary phase.</s><s>Packed cell masses exhibit a greyish-black colour.</s><s>Growth between 68 and 100°C and at 0 to 3.0% NaCl.</s><s>No growth at 65 and 102°C.</s><s>No growth at 3.3% NaCl.</s><s>Optimally doubling time, 81 min.</s><s>Organotrophic growth on a mixture of yeast extract, meat extract, peptone and brain heart infusion.</s><s>Organotrophically, hydrogen inhibits growth.</s><s>Hydrogen inhibition can be overcome by addition of arsenate, selenate, sulfur or thiosulfate.</s><s>Formation of realgar in the presence of arsenate and thiosulfate or arsenic and L-cysteine (H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> gas phase).</s><s>Formation of elemental selenium during organotrophic growth on selenate (H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> or N<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> gas phase).</s><s>Lithoautotrophic growth by reduction of arsenate, elemental sulfur or thiosulfate with hydrogen as electron donor.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is formed from elemental sulfur or thiosulfate, arsenite from arsenate.</s><s>DNA base composition, 58.3 mol% G+C.</s><s>By 16S rDNA gene sequence comparisons, 1.4% evolutionary distance to <i>P. islandicum</i>, 1.3% to <i>P. aerophilum</i>, 1.4% to <i>Pyrobaculum</i> sp. WIJ3 and 3.2% to <i>Thermoproteus tenax</i>.</s><s>Type strain: <i>Pyrobaculum arsenaticum</i> PZ6°, DSM 13514, Braunschweig, Germany and ATCC 700994, Maryland, USA (isolated from Pisciarelli Solfatara, Naples, Italy).</s></p></content></protolog>