<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2306_nm.9735" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9735" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9735" rank="species">Alteromonas hispanica</organism><reference id="rid.2306"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Del Moral</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alteromonas hispanica sp. nov., a polyunsaturated-fatty-acid-producing, halophilic bacterium isolated from Fuente de Piedra, southern Spain</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2385</fpage><lpage>2390</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63809-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280501</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alteromonas hispanica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alteromonas hispanica</em> (his.pa′ni.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>hispanica</em> Spanish).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are straight rods, 1–2 μm long and 0·75 μm wide, appearing either singly or in pairs.</s><s>They stain Gram-negative and are motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>They produce buds, prostheca and PHB.</s><s>No spores are observed under any conditions.</s><s>Colonies are cream coloured, round, convex and mucoid.</s><s>EPS is produced.</s><s>Growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>The bacterium is chemo-organotrophic and strictly aerobic, i.e. anaerobic respiration with nitrate, nitrite or fumarate is negative.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>It produces acids from maltose but not from any of the following carbohydrates: adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>It is moderately halophilic, capable of growing in NaCl concentrations of 7·5 to 15 % w/v (optimum 7·5–10 %).</s><s>It does not require additional magnesium or potassium salts.</s><s>It grows within the temperature range of 4 to 40 °C (optimum 32 °C) and at pH values between 5 and 10 (optimum 7–8).</s><s>It shows positive activity for ONPG, phosphatase, selenite reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production from cysteine and hydrolysis of aesculin, casein, gelatin, Tween 20, Tween 80, starch and DNA.</s><s>It is negative for nitrate and nitrite reduction, urease, lecithinase phenylalanine deaminase, gluconate oxidation, growth on cetrimide agar, growth on MacConkey agar, indole, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and haemolysis.</s><s>It grows in synthetic media supplemented with maltose and mannitol as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>It does not grow in synthetic media supplemented with the following sole sources of carbon and energy, or carbon, nitrogen and energy: aesculin, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, starch, d-trehalose, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, lactate, malonate, propionate, succinate, adonitol, ethanol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, dl-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>It is susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), polymyxin B (300 UI), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), sulphamide (250 μg), tobramycin (10 μg) and trimetroprim/sulphametoxazol (1·25/23·75 μg).</s><s>It is resistant to cefoxitin (30 μg).</s><s>The principal fatty acids are (%): 16 : 0 N alcohol (7·35), 15 : 0 iso 2-OH/16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (22·10), 16 : 0 (13·77), 17 : 0 10-methyl (15·63), 18 : 0 (5·89), 18 : 3<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (6, 9, 12) (5·01) and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (14·30).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 46·3 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, F-32<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7067<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22958<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hypersaline water sample taken at Fuente de Piedra (Málaga, southern Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>