<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7045_nm.4147" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4147" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4147" rank="species">Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7045"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kopecný</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zorec</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mrázek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marinšek-Logar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Butyrivibrio hungatei sp. nov. and Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans sp. nov., butyrate-producing bacteria from the rumen.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>209</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02345-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans</em> (xy.la.ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, digesting; N.L. part. adj. <em>xylanivorans</em> xylan-digesting).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight to slightly curved rods (0·4–0·6×1·5–3·0 μm) that do not form endospores.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum (Fig. 3).</s><s>Growth occurs anaerobically at 39 °C, but not at 25 or 45 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed in the presence of oxygen.</s><s>However, exposure of grown liquid culture to air for several hours does not destroy the ability of the species to recover under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Substrates that support growth of the type strain are cellobiose, aesculin, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melezitose, salicin, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Tryptophan, urea and gelatin are not utilized.</s><s>The following substrates do not support growth of the type strain: glycerol; mannitol; raffinose; sorbitol; rhamnose; trehalose.</s><s>Medium M10 with glucose (22 mM) is fermented to formate (15·1 mM), butyrate (17·6 mM), lactate (10·9 mM), succinate (0·3 mM) and ethanol (1·1 mM).</s><s>Acetate is utilized.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Strain Mz 5<sup>T</sup> does not liquefy gelatin or produce hydrogen sulfide; neither does it reduce nitrate, hydrolyse urea nor produce catalase.</s><s>It produces α-galactosidase, α-arabinosidase, xylanase, amylase, β-endoglucanase, pectin hydrolase, proteinase and DNase.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid components of strain Mz 5<sup>T</sup> grown in DSM medium no. 330 without rumen fluid are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (39·2 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> (6·4 %), followed by iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3·9 %) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (4·3 %).</s><s>This species is characterized by a higher content of straight-chain cellular fatty acids and a lower content of branched-chain fatty acids.</s><s>Produces high xylanase activity.</s><s>Most strains also produce amylase, proteinase and DNase.</s><s>Laminarinase is detected in some species.</s><s>Strains belonging to <em>Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans</em> are listed in the footnote of Table 3.</s><s>The most common butyrate-producing anaerobic bacterium in our set of bacteria isolated from the rumen of sheep and cow.</s><s>The type strain is Mz 5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14809<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-455<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42·1 mol% (as determined by the HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron micrograph of <em>Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans</em> Mz 5<sup>T</sup> cells showing (a) the size and arrangement (bar, 100 nm) and (b) flagellar basis (bar, 0·5 μm).</s></p></content></protolog>