<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1793_nm.12194" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12194" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3834" rank="species">Helicobacter acinonyx</organism><reference id="rid.1793"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Eaton</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Radin</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krakowka</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morgan</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter acinonyx sp. nov., isolated from cheetahs with gastritis.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>106</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-99</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8379970</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter acinonyx</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter acinonyx</i> (acinonyx, L. gen. n. of the species <i>Acinonyx jubilatus</i>, from which it was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Helicobacter acinonyx</i> is a short, spiral, gram-negative rod, 0.3 by 1.5 to 2.0 μm.</s><s>Cells are motile and possess tufts of two to five sheathed monopolar flagella.</s><s>No endospores are produced.</s><s>Microaerophilic growth occurs at 37°C but not at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur aerobically or anaerobically.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin, or arabinose.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase, urease, gamma-glutamyl, transpeptidase, and arginine beta-napthylamide aminopeptidase are produced.</s><s>Proline, pyroglutamic acid, tyrosine, alanine, phenylalanine, and glycine beta-naphthylamide aminopeptidase are not detected.</s><s>Hippurate and indoxyl acetate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the presence of 1.0% glycine or 1.5% NaCl. <i>H. acinonyx</i> is resistant to nalidixic acid and sensitive to cephalothin and metronidazole.</s><s>In addition, it is sensitive to penicillin, ampicillin, nitrofurazone, erythromycin, gentamicin, chlortetracycline, and chloramphenicol and resistant to sulfamethoxazole with trimethoprim and to vancomycin. <i>H. acinonyx</i> was isolated from the gastric mucosa of cheetahs.</s><s>Four strains (90-119, 90-548, 90-736, and 90-1908) have been isolated and are available from The American Type Culture Collection (ATCC 51101, 51102, 51103, and 51104, respectively).</s><s>The type strain, 90-119, has a G+C content of 30 mol%.</s><s>It is deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Goteborg, Goteborg, Sweden (CCUG 29263).</s></p></content></protolog>