<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12533_nm.21391" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21391" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21391" rank="species">Allobacillus halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.12533"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Allobacillus halotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov. isolated from shrimp paste</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1023</fpage><lpage>1027</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023341-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511460</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Allobacillus halotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Allobacillus halotolerans</em> (ha.lo.to′le.rans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> <em>halos</em> salt; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>halotolerans</em> salt-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Negative for DNase, lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of starch, casein, gelatin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>After 48 h of growth on MA agar at 25 °C, cells have a mean size of about 0.6 µm (width) by 2.0–3.0 µm (length) and are motile.</s><s>Colonies are round, entire, convex and white-transparent.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.6–0.8 mm in diameter on MA agar after 48 h of incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C, with 6 % NaCl and at pH 7.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, negative for nitrate and nitrite reduction, indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, β-glucosidase, protease, β-galactosidase, urease, and for assimilation of glucose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, malate, arabinose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenyl acetate.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive reactions for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase, trypsin and α-chymotrypsin and negative reactions for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GP2 test system: dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, d-galacturonic acid, d-fructose, α-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, 3-methyl-d-glucose, methyl α-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, lactose, methyl β-d-glucoside, α-ketoglutaric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid methyl ester, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid, l-alanine, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-serine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxy adenosine, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to gentamicin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, streptomycin, penicillin G, ampicillin, novobiocin, tetracycline and rifampicin but is resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>The fatty acid constituents are 16 : 0 iso, 15 : 0 anteiso, 14 : 0 iso, 17 : 1 anteiso ω9<em>c</em>, 17 : 0 anteiso, 15 : 0 iso, 16 : 1 ω7<em>c</em> alcohol, 16 : 0, 18 : 0 and 18 : 1 iso H.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B3A<sup>T</sup> ( = BCRC 17939<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24826<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shrimp paste.</s></p></content></protolog>