<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3837_nm.2026" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2026" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2026" rank="species">Azoarcus evansii</organism><reference id="rid.3837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anders</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaetzke</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuchs</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic position of aromatic-degrading denitrifying pseudomonad strains K 172 and KB 740 and their description as new members of the genera Thauera, as Thauera aromatica sp. nov., and Azoarcus, as Azoarcus evansii sp. nov., respectively, members of the beta subclass of the Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>333</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-327</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537067</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azoarcus evansii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azoarcus evansii</i> (e'van.si.i. L. gen. n. <i>evansii</i>, of Evans, in honor of the late W. C. Evans, a pioneer in studies of anaerobic aromatic metabolism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods with rounded ends and are 1.5 to 3 μm long and 0.6 to 0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Each cell is motile by means of one subpolarly inserted flagellum.</s><s>Gram negative and KOH positive.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Colonies on minimal media containing benzoate are 1 to 2 mm in diameter and white or beige after 3 to 4 days of incubation at 28°C.</s><s>Yeast extract (0.1%, wt/vol) inhibits growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is around 37°C, and the optimum pH is around 7.8.</s><s>No growth occurs at 41°C.</s><s>Strictly oxidative metabolism occurs with oxygen or nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>During growth with aromatic compounds nitrite is an intermediate and is reduced mainly to N<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>Positive in the oxidative oxidation-fermentation test with different sugars.</s><s>No fermentation occurs.</s><s>In the presence of nitrate a variety of aromatic substrates are used anaerobically as sole carbon sources as are some sugars, dicarboxylic acids, and cyclohexanecarboxylate.</s><s>Several L-amino acids are growth substrates for aerobic growth.</s><s>The major fatty acids are <i>cis</i>-9 16:1, 16:0, 12:0, 3-OH 10:0, and cis-9,11 18:1.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone 8. <i>A. evansi</i> is a member of the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The type strain is KB 740 (= DSM 6898).</s><s>Isolated by K Braun and D.</s><s>T.</s><s>Gibson from creek sediment in the United States with media containing 2-aminobenzoate and nitrate (4).</s><s>The base composition of the DNA is 67.5 mol% G+C.</s><s>Additional morphological, biochemical, and nutritional features are summarized above and in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>