<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4803_nm.4109" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4109" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4109" rank="species">Tepidibacter thalassicus</organism><reference id="rid.4803"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kostrikina</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chernyh</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonch-Osmolovskaya</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeanthon</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tepidibacter thalassicus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel moderately thermophilic, anaerobic, fermentative bacterium from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1131</fpage><lpage>1134</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02600-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892139</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tepidibacter thalassicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tepidibacter</em> <em>thalassicus</em> (tha.las′si.cus. M.L. masc. adj. <em>thalassicus</em> of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 0·7–0·9 μm in diameter and 3·5–6·0 μm in length, which form round, refractile endospores in terminally swollen sporangia.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in short chains and exhibit tumbling motility due to peritrichous flagellation.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 33–60 °C, with an optimum at 50 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 4·8–8·5, with an optimum at 6·5–6·8.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations in the range 1·5–6 % (w/v).</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Substrates utilized include casein, peptone, albumin, yeast extract, beef extract, alanine plus proline and starch.</s><s>Glucose, maltose, pyruvate, valine and arginine slightly stimulate growth in the presence of yeast extract.</s><s>Fructose, sucrose, xylose, cellobiose, l-arabinose, glycerol, sorbitol, acetate, butyrate, lactate, formate, methanol, fumarate, glycine, alanine, proline, alanine plus glycine, betaine, olive oil, xylan, carboxymethylcellulose, filter paper, chitin, keratin and H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> are not utilized.</s><s>The products of glucose fermentation are ethanol, acetate and molecular hydrogen.</s><s>Reduces elemental sulfur to hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Does not use nitrate, fumarate, sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, amorphous Fe(III) oxide, Fe(III) citrate or oxygen as electron acceptors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SC 562<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (DSM 15285<sup>T</sup>) and in the UNIQEM Collection of the Unique Micro-organism Classification and Storage Laboratory of Institute of Microbiology, Russian Academy of Sciences (UNIQEM 215<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of its genomic DNA is 24 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>Habitat is a deep-sea hydrothermal vent chimney located at 13° N on the East-Pacific Rise.</s></p></content></protolog>