<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7173_nm.3521" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3521" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3521" rank="species">Desulfomicrobium norvegicum</organism><reference id="rid.7173"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Genthner</surname><given-names>B.R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Friedman</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devereux</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Desulfovibrio desulfuricans Norway 4 as Desulfomicrobium norvegicum comb. nov. and confirmation of Desulfomicrobium escambiense (corrig., formerly "escambium") as a new species in the genus Desulfomicrobium.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>889</fpage><lpage>892</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-889</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfomicrobium norvegicum</i> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfomicrobium norvegicum</i> (nor.ve'gi.cum. M. L. adj. <i>norvegicum</i>, Norwegian)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from Oslo Harbor in 1949.</s><s>The type strain was originally designated <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> Norway 4 and was deposited in the National Collection of Industrial Bacteria as strain NCIB 8310.</s><s>Non-spore-forming, gram-negative, sulfate-reducing, obligately anaerobic rods (0.5 to 1.0 by 3.0 to 5.0 μm).</s><s>Uses lactate, pyruvate, ethanol, hydrogen, and formate but not acetate, propionate, butyrate, methanol, propanol, butanol, isobutanol, lactose, glucose, oxalate, or choline as electron donors for sulfate reduction.</s><s>Ferments pyruvate poorly, malate well, and fumarate very well, forming acetate, lactate, and succinate.</s><s>Does not ferment choline.</s><s>Preferentially reduces fumarate and malate to succinate over reduction of sulfate to sulfide.</s><s>Contains desulforubidin, but not desulfoviridin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 56.8 mol%.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology with <i>Desulfomicrobium apsheronum</i>, <i>Desulfomicrobium baculatum</i>, and <i>Desulfomicrobium escambiense</i> are 13.1, 27.4, and 13.0%, respectively, and the level of DNA-DNA homology with Desulfovibrio desulfiricans ATTC 27774 is 2.1%.</s><s>Exhibits 99.2, 99.3, and 97.6% 16s rRNA similarity with <i>Desulfomicrobium apsheronum</i>, <i>Desulfomicrobium baculatum</i>, and <i>Desulfomicrobium escambiense</i>, respectively, and 87.7% 16s rRNA similarity with <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> ATTC 27774.</s><s>The type strain is NCIMB 8310.</s></p></content></protolog>