<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1016_nm.7016" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7016" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7016" rank="species">Streptomyces fumigatiscleroticus</organism><reference id="rid.1016"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Chainia species to the genus Streptomyces with emended description of species</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>55</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces fumigatiscleroticus</i> (Pridham) nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces fumigatiscleroticus</i> (<i>fu. mi. ga'ti. scle. rot'i. cus.</i> L. masc. n. <i>fumus</i>, smoke, steam; L. suf. <i>atus</i>, provided with; L. part. adj. <i>fumigatus</i>, smoked; L. neut. n. <i>sclerotium</i>; M. L. adj. <i>fumigatiscleroticus</i>, smoked sclerotium, referring to smoke colour and ability to form sclerotia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from information derived from <i>Thirumalachar</i> et al. (1966) and Ruan et al. (1985).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive organism with extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Produces spiral spore chains and shows brownish-black crusty growth.</s><s>Produces sclerotia.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Degrades gelatin, starch, urea and xanthine.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced but hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, sucrose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources but dulcitol, galactose, glycerol, inulin, <i>meso</i>-inositol, L-rhamnose, salicin and sucrose are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol and D-xylose but not from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 42°C but not at 10°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows antimicrobial activity against <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>, <i>Escherichia coli</i> and <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> but not against <i>Candida albicans</i>, <i>Cryptococcus neoformans</i> or <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil, Pimpri, India.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 19345 (= DSM 43154 = IFO 12999 = KCC 3101 = RIA 884).</s></p></content></protolog>