<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2072_nm.6735" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6735" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6735" rank="subspecies">Kibdelosporangium aridum largum</organism><reference id="rid.2072"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shearer</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovenella</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grappel</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hedde</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mehta</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>Y.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitkin</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nisbet</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kibdelins, a novel glycopeptide, and biological evaluation.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>1386</fpage><lpage>1394</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kibdelosporangium aridum</i> subsp. <i>largum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kibdelosporangium aridum</i> subsp. <i>largum</i> (<i>largus</i>, L. adj., abundant, plentiful, numerous)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>K. aridum</i> subsp. <i>largum</i> (SK&#x0026;F AAD-609) has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, as the subspecies type, under the accession number ATCC 39922.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pure cell walls contained <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, alanine, glutamic acid, glucosamine, muramic acid, galactose and a minor amount of arabinose and a trace of madurose.</s><s>No mycolic acids of any type were present in the cell extracts.</s><s>Phospholipids present were phosphatidyl ethanolamine, phosphatidyl inositol, phosphatidyl inositol mannosides and diphosphatidyl glycerol.</s><s>Thus SK&#x0026;F AAD-609 has a type IV cell wall with a type A sugar pattern" plus traces of madurose and a phospholipid pattern of type PII.</s><s>SK&#x0026;F AAD-609 did not grow under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Temperature range for growth was 15°C to 42°C with a trace of growth at 45°C.</s><s>The following tests were positive: Hydrogen sulfide production; milk peptonization; melanin production; gelatin hydrolysis and liquefaction; hydrolysis of casein, L-tyrosine, hypoxanthine, guanine, elastin, urea, esculin and hippurate; catalase and phosphatase production.</s><s>Results were negative for hydrolysis of starch, adenine, xanthine and cellulose (Avicel).</s><s>Tests for allantoin decomposition were weakly positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction to nitrite was doubtful.</s><s>No growth occurred in lysozyme broth.</s><s>Growth in 2 % NaCl was consistently positive; no growth occurred in 8 % NaCl while growth in 3 % to 7 % NaCl was inconsistent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid was produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, glucose, D-fructose, glycerol, glycogen, D-galactose, <i>iso</i>-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, maltose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, melibiose, D-melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid was produced from dulcitol, <i>iso</i>-crythritol, inulin or L-sorbose and salicin was variable.</s><s>Citrate, malate, succinate, oxalate, lactate, acetate, pyruvate, formate and propionate were utilized; benzoate and tartrate were not.</s></p></content></protolog>