<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9711_nm.14862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14862" rank="species">Maritimimonas rapanae</organism><reference id="rid.9711"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Maritimimonas rapanae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from gut microflora of the veined rapa whelk, Rapana venosa</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2824</fpage><lpage>2829</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010504-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628599</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maritimimonas rapanae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maritimimonas rapanae</em> (ra.pa′na.e. N.L. gen. n. <em>rapanae</em> of <em>Rapana</em>, the generic name of the mollusc from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.3–0.4 μm wide and 0.8–1.2 μm long and sometimes show filamentous growth (Supplementary Fig. S2).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, yellow-pigmented and glistening with entire margins, do not adhere to the agar and are approximately 2.0 mm in diameter after 7 days at 30 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and pH 5–9 (optimum, pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs in media (ZoBell's, TSA, R2A and NA) containing 3–6 % sea salts (optimum, 4–5 %), but not in media supplemented with NaCl (1–12 %) alone.</s><s>Cells grow in the bottom of tubes as viscid sediments.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is degraded, but aesculin, DNA, agar, casein, CM-cellulose, crystalline cellulose (filter paper), chitin, starch and Tween 80 are not.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities are present, cystine arylamidase and trypsin activities are weakly positive and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>In GN2 MicroPlate (Biolog) tests, d-glucose, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-serine and l-threonine are utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc, unless indicated) chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30); resistant to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 31.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A31<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22186<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15075<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sample from a veined rapa whelk (<em>Rapana venosa</em>) collected from the South Sea, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>