<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.607_nm.8494" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8494" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8494" rank="species">Bacillus farraginis</organism><reference id="rid.607"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pil</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herman</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus farraginis sp. nov., Bacillus fortis sp. nov. and Bacillus fordii sp. nov., isolated at dairy farms</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1355</fpage><lpage>1364</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63095-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280314</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus farraginis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus farraginis</em> (far.ra.gin′is. L. gen. fem. n. <em>farraginis</em> from mixed fodder for cattle, referring to feed concentrate for dairy cattle as the principal isolation source).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are long, straight, round-ended, motile, strictly aerobic, Gram-negative rods, occurring singly, in pairs or filaments.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·5–0·8 μm and cell length 1·2–4 μm.</s><s>Spores are ellipsoidal and occur paracentrally or subterminally in occasionally slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies grown for 3 days at 30 °C on nutrient agar are cream coloured or translucent, slightly raised, with irregular margins and granular, glossy surfaces.</s><s>Colony diameter is no greater than 1 mm.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 and 45 °C and weak growth occurs at 20 °C.</s><s>Some strains are capable of growth at pH 9 but none grows at pH 5.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and casein is not observed within 7 days of incubation at 30 °C, and growth in casein agar is poor or negative.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>All strains are unreactive in the API 20E and API 50CHB test kits.</s><s>In the Biotype100 kit using the Biotype 2 medium, nearly all strains (&#x003E;83 %) belonging to the species are able to use the following substrates as sole carbon sources: 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, d- and l-alanine, fumarate, l-glutamate, glutarate, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, d- and l-malate, dl-lactate, l-proline, putrescine, succinate, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>Many strains (&#x003E;45 %) are able to use l-aspartate, dulcitol, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, d-mannitol, d-ribose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Other substrates are used less frequently (17–44 %): l-arabinose, d-galactose, gentisate, d-glucuronate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol and <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose.</s><s>The following substrates are seldom or never used as sole carbon sources: <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, benzoate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, d-cellobiose, citrate, <em>m</em>-coumarate, erythritol, aesculin, ethanolamine, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, d-galacturonate, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, dl-glycerate, glycerol, histamine, hydroxyquinoline <em>β</em>-glucuronide, itaconate, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, d-lyxose, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 3-methyl d-glucopyranose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, mucate, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, propionate, protocatechuate, quinate, d-raffinose, d-saccharate, sucrose, l-serine, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-, <em>meso</em>- and d-tartrate, d-trehalose, d-turanose, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, d-xylose and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R-6540<sup>T</sup> (=MB 1885<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22081<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16013<sup>T</sup>), utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon sources: 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, d- and l-alanine, l-aspartate, dulcitol, fumarate, d-glucosamine, l-glutamate, glutarate, histamine, l-histidine, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, d- and l-malate, malonate, dl-lactate, l-proline, putrescine, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, succinate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 % of total cellular fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol.</s><s>The DNA G+C composition of the type strain is 43·7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>