<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7143_nm.1538" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1538" rank="genus">Blastochloris</organism><reference id="rid.7143"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of the bacteriochlorophyll b-containing phototrophic bacteria Rhodopseudomonas viridis and Rhodopseudomonas sulfoviridis to the genus Blastochloris gen. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>217</fpage><lpage>219</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995826</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Blastochloris</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Blastochloris</i> (Blas.to. chlo'ris. Gr. n. <i>blustos</i>, bud shoot; Gr. adj. <i>chloros</i>, green; M. L. fem. n. <i>Blastochloris</i>, green bud shoot)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics described below are based on information from previous reports (3, 14, 20, 23, 29) and this study.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped to ovoid and exhibit polar growth, budding, and asymmetric cell division.</s><s>Rosette-like aggregates sometimes occur.</s><s>Motile by means of subpolar flagella.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Photoheterotrophic, growing anaerobically in the presence of light.</s><s>Microaerophilic growth in the dark is also possible.</s><s>Phototrophically growing cells contain intracytoplasmic membranes that are present as lamellae underlying and parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are BChl b and carotenoids.</s><s>The color of photosynthetic cultures is green to olive green.</s><s>Photoorganotrophy with a number of simple organic compounds as carbon and electron donors is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Both ubiquinones (Q-8 to Q-10) and menaquinones (MK-7 to MK-9) are present.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA ranges from 66 to 71 mol%. 16s rDNA sequence information places the genus in the alpha-2 subgroup of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, and the genus <i>Rhodoplanes</i> is the closest relative among the photosynthetic genera.</s><s>The type species is <i>Blastochloris viridis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>