<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8705_nm.13244" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13244" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13244" rank="species">Brevibacterium album</organism><reference id="rid.8705"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium album sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from a saline soil in China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>574</fpage><lpage>577</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65183-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium album</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium album</em> (al′bum. L. neut. adj. <em>album</em> white).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, motile, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 1.8×4.0–5.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies are white on most media tested.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular, opaque and approximately 1–2 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation at 37 °C on ISP medium 5 containing 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs in the temperature, pH and salt ranges of 28–45 °C, pH 6–8, 0–10 % NaCl (w/v), 0–20 % KCl (w/v) and 0–30 % MgCl<sub>2</sub> . 6H<sub>2</sub>O (w/v).</s><s>Good growth occurs at 37 °C, pH 7.5, 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl, 0–10 % KCl (w/v) and 0–15 % MgCl<sub>2</sub> . 6H<sub>2</sub>O (w/v).</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources for growth in Biolog GP2 microplates: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-fucose, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, l-mannose, salicin, trehalose, turanose, d-malic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, putrescine, uridine 5′-monophosphate and fructose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized in the Biolog GP2 system: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-ribose, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>In the API CORYNE system, tests for pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, gelatin hydrolysis and acid production from d-ribose are positive.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis), urease and acid production from d-glucose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-lactose, sucrose and glycogen are negative.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, acid and alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase tests are positive.</s><s>Lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase tests are negative.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is A1<em>γ</em>, <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid directly cross-linked.</s><s>Cell-wall sugar contains galactose.</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The menaquinones are MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-6(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8, MK-6 and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) (ratio of peak areas, 76 : 10 : 5 : 3 : 2 : 1).</s><s>The fatty acid profile contains anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (58.71 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (19.0 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (12.29 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (7.24 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 70.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 90718<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18261<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19173<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AB 206112<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a saline soil in the north-west of China.</s></p></content></protolog>