<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9165_nm.14363" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14363" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14363" rank="species">Pseudidiomarina maritima</organism><reference id="rid.9165"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudidiomarina donghaiensis sp. nov. and Pseudidiomarina maritima sp. nov., isolated from the East China Sea.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1321</fpage><lpage>1325</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005702-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudidiomarina maritima</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudidiomarina maritima</em> (ma.ri.ti′ma. L. fem. adj. <em>maritima</em> inhabiting marine environments).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, slightly curved rods, approximately 0.4–0.6 μm wide and 1.4–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on MA plates are 1–2 mm in diameter, non-pigmented, circular and smooth after 48 h at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–15.0 % (w/v) with optimum growth at 3.0 %.</s><s>The pH and temperature ranges for growth are pH 6.5–10.0 and 10–45 °C (optimum growth at pH 8.0–9.0 and 37 °C).</s><s>No growth is detected at 4 or 50 °C.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar.</s><s>Casein, DNA, gelatin and Tweens 20 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for selenite reduction.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, gluconate oxidation, indole production, lecithinase, lysine decarboxylase, methyl red, <em>ο</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not formed from thiosulfate.</s><s>No nitrate or nitrite reduction.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, adonitol, l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, d-cellobiose, citrate, l-cysteine, ethanol, formate, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, glucose, l-glutamate, glycerol, glycine, gluconate, l-glutamine, l-histidine, inositol, isoleucine, lactate, lactose, lysine, malate, malonate, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, l-methionine, l-proline, propionate, pyruvate, d-raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, l-serine, l-sorbitol, sorbose, succinate, sucrose, trehalose, l-valine, xylitol and xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from: adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, d-raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, l-sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, the type strain is not able to use any of the substrates provided with the kit except gelatin.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the type strain produces gelatinase, but cannot ferment glucose or other carbohydrates as substrates.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin (10 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (10 μg), minocycline (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg), but resistant to bacitracin (0.04 IU), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), nystatin (100 μg) and tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.2 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 908087<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7285<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15534<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a coastal seawater sample collected from the East China Sea, China.</s></p></content></protolog>