<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3591_nm.3047" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3047" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3047" rank="subspecies">Aeromonas hydrophila dhakensis</organism><reference id="rid.3591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Albert</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kühn</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denys</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas hydrophila subsp. dhakensis subsp. nov., isolated from children with diarrhoea in Bangladesh, and extended description of Aeromonas hydrophila subsp. hydrophila (Chester 1901) Stanier 1943 (approved lists 1980).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>705</fpage><lpage>712</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01844-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054229</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>dhakensis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>dhakensis</i> (dha.ken'sis. N.L. adj. <i>dhakensis</i> of Dhaka, Bangladesh)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Includes the 10 strains listed in Table 1.</s><s>All child patients from which these strains were isolated lived in the vicinity of Dhaka and were treated at the International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh (ICDDR, B), in Dhaka.</s><s>Strains display the following characteristics typical of the genus <i>Aeromonas</i>: Gram-negative, straight, motile rods, chemo-organotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism, cytochrome oxidase- and catalase- positive, reduction of nitrate to nitrite without the production of gas and resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 24 h at 28 °C on TSA medium, but all strains also grow at 42 °C after 24-48 h.</s><s>No brown, water-soluble pigment is produced on TSA medium.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-, lysine decarboxylase-, indole- and Voges-Proskauer-positive.</s><s>No production of urease, tryptophan deaminase, ornithine decarboxylase or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, N-acetyL-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate (except strain LMG 19559), L-alanine, arbutin, L-arginine, DL-aspartate, butyrate, caprate (except strain LMG 19559), D-fructose, fumarate, D-galactose, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, L-glutamine, glycerol, L-glycine, L-histidine, isobutyrate, DL-lactate, lactose, DL-malate, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-maltose, L-proline, putrescine, pyruvate, D-ribose, salicin, spermidine, succinate, L-serine, D-sucrose, D-trehalose and urocanic acid.</s><s>None of the strains uses <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adipate, adonitol, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, betaine, cadaverine, D-cellobiose, L-citrulline, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucuronate, glutarate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, inositol, isovalerate, itaconate, L-leucine, L-lysine, maltitol, α-D-melibiose, mesaconate, methyl α-dmannoside, phenylacetate, L-phenylalanine, draffinose, L-rhamnose, sorbate, D-sorbitol, spermine, suberate, L-tryptophan, L-valine, D-xylitol or D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is uniformly produced from D-galactose, D-glucose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, salicin, D-sucrose and D-trehalose, but not from adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, D-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, α-D-melibiose, methyl D-glucoside, lactose,  L-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol or D-xylose.</s><s>All strains hydrolyse the following substrates: L-alanine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide (pNA), 2-deoxythymidine-5'-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl (pNP) phosphate, aesculin, gelatin, bis-pNP phosphate, <i>ortho</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucopyranoside, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine and L-proline pNA.</s><s>None of the strains is able to hydrolyse L-glutamate-γ-3-carboxy pNA, pNP α-D-glucopyranoside or pNP β-D-glucuronide.</s><s>All strains are resistant to ampicillin and penicillin but sensitive to kanamycin.</s><s>For resistance to nalidixic acid, streptomycin and tetracycline, resistant (including strains LMG 19559, LMG 19561, LMG 19564, LMG 19566 and LMG 19567) and susceptible (LMG 19558,LMG19560,LMG19562T, LMG19563 and LMG 19565) subgroups were observed.</s><s>Isolated from stool samples of children (under the age of five) suffering from diarrhoea.</s><s>One strain (LMG 19560) originated from a healthy child (Table 1).</s><s>All isolates except strain LMG 19561 are strongly β-haemolytic to sheep erythrocytes.</s><s>Eight of the ten strains produce high (≥1/256) cytotoxin titres (Table 1).</s><s>The type strain is strain LMG 19562<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 45377<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>