<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1490_nm.9444" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9444" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9444" rank="species">Pleomorphomonas oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.1490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pleomorphomonas oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium isolated from paddy soil of Oryza sativa</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1233</fpage><lpage>1237</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63406-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879261</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pleomorphomonas oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pleomorphomonas oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, from which the strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are colourless on nitrogen-free agar medium.</s><s>Old cells became ovoid.</s><s>Cells are 0·5–1·0×1·0–5·0 μm.</s><s>Acids are produced from glucose by fermentative metabolism but the organism cannot grow on tellurite agar medium.</s><s>Indole production, nitrate reduction, urease and tyrosinase activities are positive.</s><s>Phosphatase, DNase, tetrazolium chloride reduction and hydrolysis of gelatin, starch and aesculin are negative.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, d-glucose, d-fructose, mannose, d-galactose, trehalose, sorbose, sucrose, lactose, cellobiose, raffinose, salicin, starch, acetate, oxalate, fumarate, dl-malate, pyruvate, gluconate, sorbitol, mannitol, inositol, glycerol, l-serine, l-glutamine, l-aspartate and l-proline as sole carbon sources, but does not utilize maltose, succinate, malonate, glutamate, 2-oxoglutarate, glyoxylate, citrate, dl-lactate, dl-mandelate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, n-propanol, methanol, ethanol, benzoate, betaine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-threonine, l-arginine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-methionine, l-valine, l-phenylalanine, <em>β</em>-aminobutyrate, l-histidine or l-cysteine.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 63·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, F-7<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15079<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-940<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16300<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from <em>Oryza sativa</em> in 1982.</s></p></content></protolog>