<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1453_nm.1783" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1783" rank="genus">Acidovorax</organism><reference id="rid.1453"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jantzen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidovorax, a new genus for Pseudomonas facilis, Pseudomonas delafieldii, E. Falsen (EF) group 13, EF group 16, and several clinical isolates, with the species Acidovorax facilis comb. nov., Acidovorax delafieldii comb. nov., and Acidovorax temperans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>384</fpage><lpage>398</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-384</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2275854</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidovorax</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidovorax</i> (A.ci.do´vo.rax. L. neut. n. <i>acidum</i>, acid; L. adj. <i>vorax</i>, voracious; M.L. masc. n. <i>Acidovorax</i>, acid devouring [bacteria])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 0.2 to 0.7 by 1.0 to 5.0 μm.</s><s>They occur singly or in short chains and are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Urease activity varies among strains.</s><s>Some strains grow on Christensen urea agar, but lack urease according to API 20NE tests.</s><s>No pigment is produced on nutrient agar.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic. <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> and several <i>Acidovorax delafieldii</i> strains are capable of lithoautotrophic growth by using hydrogen as an energy source.</s><s>Oxidative carbohydrate metabolism occurs with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor; alternatively, some strains of <i>Acidovorax delafieldii</i> and <i>Acidovorax temperans</i> are capable of heterotrophic denitrification of nitrate.</s><s>Good growth is obtained on media containing organic acids, amino acids, or peptone, but only a limited number of sugars are used for growth; but 54% of the acids are consumed, compared with about 22% of the carbohydrates (Table 6).</s><s>Two hydroxylated fatty acids, 3-hydroxyoctanoic acid (3-OH-8:0) and 3-hydroxydecanoic acid (3-OH-10:0), are always present, 2-hydroxylated fatty acids are absent, and a cyclopropane-substituted fatty acid (17:cyc) is present in most of the strains.</s><s>The mean G+C values of the DNAs range from 62 to 66 mol%.</s><s>In DNA-rRNA hybridizations all strains belonging to this new genus group in a <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> range from 77.2 to 80.6°C versus rRNA from <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> ATCC 11228<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The genus <i>Acidovorax</i> belongs to the acidovorans rRNA complex and is equidistantly related to the other taxa in this complex (e.g., <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, <i>Comamonas</i>, <i>Xylophilus</i>, [<i>Alcaligenes</i>] <i>paradoxus</i>, and [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>avenue</i>).</s><s>The type species is <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> (Schatz and Bovell 1952) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The descriptions of the morphological, biochemical, and nutritional features of the former species [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>facilis</i> and [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>delafieldii</i> given by Davis et al. (5) and by Palleroni (36) were verified and were found to correlate fairly well with our own findings.</s><s>However, because <i>Acidovorax delafieldii</i> contains considerably more strains than [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>delafieldii</i>, its description needs to be updated.</s><s>To facilitate comparison with the other two <i>Acidovorax</i> species described here, we also provide a detailed description of <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> below.</s><s>Of the three species which we included in the genus <i>Acidovorax</i>, <i>Acidovorax delafieldii</i> is metabolically the most versatile, and <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> is the least versatile.</s></p></content></protolog>