<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12876_nm.22686" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22686" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22686" rank="species">Weissella ceti</organism><reference id="rid.12876"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernaldo de Quirós</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herráez</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Weissella ceti sp. nov., isolated from beaked whales (Mesoplodon bidens)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2758</fpage><lpage>2762</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028522-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216921</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Weissella ceti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Weissella ceti</em> (ce.ti. L. gen. n. <em>ceti</em> of a whale).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, non-spore-forming, short rod-shaped or coccoid (0.2 µm wide and 1.5 µm long) and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small, circular and non-pigmented, 0.75–1.0 mm in diameter and are α-haemolytic at 37 °C.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, catalase-negative and non-motile.</s><s>Cells are able to grow at 22, 30 and 37 °C, but do not grow at 15 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in broth containing 3.0–6.5 % NaCl, but not at pH 3.9. d and l lactic acid (d : l, 80 : 20) are produced as end products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Gas is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Dextran is not formed from sucrose.</s><s>Cells are able to produce acid from d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, trehalose and maltose, but not from d-xylose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, pullulan, gentiobiose, methyl β-d-glucopyranoside, glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inositol, dulcitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, melezitose, turanose, d-lyxose, xylitol, d-fucose, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, cyclodextrin, l-arabinose, melibiose or tagatose.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and pyrazinamidase are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-mannosidase, leucine arylamidase, β-galactosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), lipase (C14), β-galactosidase, valine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but not hippurate, gelatin or urea.</s><s>Hydrolysis of arginine and production of alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase are variable (the type strain, 1119-1A-09<sup>T</sup> gives a positive result for both tests).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1119-1A-09<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7719<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 59653<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the spleen of a beaked whale (<em>Mesoplodon bidens</em>).</s><s>The full range of habitat is not known.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>