<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8362_nm.13323" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13323" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13323" rank="species">Filomicrobium insigne</organism><reference id="rid.8362"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chi</surname><given-names>C.Q.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Filomicrobium insigne sp. nov., isolated from an oil-polluted saline soil.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>300</fpage><lpage>305</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65758-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196769</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Filomicrobium insigne</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Filomicrobium insigne</em> (in.sig′ne. L. neut. adj. <em>insigne</em> distinguished by a mark, remarkable, extraordinary, referring to the remarkable phylogenetic relationship between the type strain and members of the genera <em>Hyphomicrobium</em> and <em>Filomicrobium</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, motile, non-pigmented, 0.5–1.0 μm in width and 1.0–2.5 μm long with monoprosthecae or bipolar prosthecae and buds on the prosthecal tips.</s><s>Colonies on LB agar are milky white and 0.1–0.2 mm in diameter after incubation at 30 °C for 5–7 days.</s><s>Accumulates PHB and produces clumps and pellicles with wall-growth, but does not produce EPS after incubation in medium 166 broth at 30 °C for 5–7 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5), at NaCl concentrations between 0 and 7 % (w/v) (optimum 1–2 %), and at 4–45 °C (optimum 28–30 °C).</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, nitrate reduction activity, PHB production, hydrolysis of aesculin and oxidation of d-glucose, but negative for hydrolysis of gelatin, Tween 80, starch, casein and DNA, urease, phenylalanine deaminase, nitrite reduction activity, indole production, lysine, ornithine and arginine decarboxylases, and the ONPG, Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests.</s><s>Grows on methanol, formate, methylamine . HCl, acetate, ethanol, d-fructose, cellobiose and trehalose as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The following organic compounds are not utilized as carbon sources: maltose, l-arginine, succinate, d-erythrose, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, malonate, sucrose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, pyruvate, d-ribose, propionate, glycine, l-alanine, d-arabinose, d-glucose, lactate, l-glutamic acid and dextrin.</s><s>The major quinone is Q-9 and the major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Inhibited by 5 μg rifampicin, 10 μg amoxicillin, kanamycin, carbenicillin, tobramycin and streptomycin, 15 μg erythromycin, 30 μg cefoxitin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol and kanamycin, and 300 μg polymyxin B and streptomycin, but resistant to 30 μg nalidixic acid, 300 μg nitrofurantoin and sulfamethoxazole, and 23.75/1.25 μg sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SLG5B-19<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6497<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23927<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an oil-polluted saline soil at Gudao Oil-Product in the coastal Shengli Oilfield, Shandong Province, eastern China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>