<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4420_nm.4325" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4325" rank="genus">Desulfosporosinus</organism><reference id="rid.4420"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mee</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfosporosinus meridiei sp. nov., a spore-forming sulfate-reducing bacterium isolated from gasolene-contaminated groundwater.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>133</fpage><lpage>140</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211250</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfosporosinus</i> (Stackebrandt et al. 1997) emend.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Desulfosporosinus (De.sul.fo.spo.ro.si«nus. L. pref. de from; L. n. sulfur sulfur; M.L. n. spora spore; L. n. sinus bend; N.L. masc. n. Desulfosporosinus a spore-forming curved (organism) that reduces sulfur compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, curved rods that have a multilayered cell wall structure.</s><s>Endospores are produced; they are oval and subterminal and cause the cells to swell slightly.</s><s>Motile, with lateral or peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>Desulfoviridin and cytochrome c<sub>3</sub> are absent; bisulfite reductase P<sub>582</sub> is present.</s><s>Sulfate and thiosulfate are reduced to sulfide in the presence of lactate, pyruvate and other carbon sources and electron donors.</s><s>Incomplete oxidation of organic compounds to acetate occurs.</s><s>Fumarate is sometimes used as a carbon and energy source for sulfate reduction.</s><s>Nitrate is sometimes reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Autotrophic growth occurs with hydrogen plus sulfate.</s><s>Homoacetogenic growth occurs with ethanol and sometimes with methanol.</s><s>Contains a menaquinone with a side-chain having seven isoprene units (MK-7 type).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are even-numbered, saturated and unsaturated fatty acids, and minor amounts of branched chain and cyclopropane fatty acids may occur.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44.7-46.9 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetically, it is a member of the <i>Clostridium-Bacillus</i> subphylum of the Gram-positive bacteria.</s><s>The type species is <i>Desulfosporosinus orientis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>