<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3535_nm.5364" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5364" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5364" rank="species">Lactobacillus ferintoshensis</organism><reference id="rid.3535"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pettersson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of lactobacilli from Scotch malt whisky distilleries and description of Lactobacillus ferintoshensis sp. nov., a new species isolated from malt whisky fermentations.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>147</volume><fpage>1007</fpage><lpage>1016</lpage><source id="168">Microbiology (Reading, England)</source><abbrev>Microbiology</abbrev><issn>1350-0872</issn><essn>1465-2080</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11283296</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus ferintoshensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus ferintoshensis</i> (fe.rin.to.shen'sis. M.L. adj. <i>ferintoshensis</i> from Ferintosh, a Scottish estate famous for its whisky)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped and occur singly or in pairs or in short chains, 3-4 μm in length and about 1 μm wide.</s><s>After 48 h incubation on modified MRS agar (MRS agar supplemented with vitamins), colonies are 2-5 mm in diameter, circular, shiny and creamy white in colour.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-spore forming and non-motile.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows at 15 °C but not 45 °C.</s><s>Heterofermentative, producing DL-lactic acid from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabinose, galactose, glucose, fructose, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, D-xylose and in some cases from cellobiose, mannitol, mannose, α-methyl D-glucoside, α-methyl D-mannoside, raffinose, sorbitol, sorbose, tagatose and turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, D- and L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D- and L-fucose, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, gluconate, inositol, inulin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, lactose, rhamnose, L-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Aesculin but not starch is hydrolysed.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyse arbutin.</s><s>The type strain is positive for the variable reactions given above with the exception of acid from melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, tagatose and turanose for which it is negative.</s><s>Habitat: malt whisky fermentations.</s><s>The type strain is strain R7-84<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited with the Collection de L'Institut Pasteur as CIP 106749<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>