<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5539_nm.5190" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5190" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5190" rank="species">Planococcus antarcticus</organism><reference id="rid.5539"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vairamani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabhakar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planococcus antarcticus and Planococcus psychrophilus spp. nov. isolated from cyanobacterial mat samples collected from ponds in Antarctica.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>261</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00792-001-0250-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12072961</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planococcus antarcticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planococcus antarcticus</i> (<i>antarcticus</i>, N.L. pertaining to the Antarctic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid, and they occur singly, in pairs, in groups of three, or as tetrads and are motile.</s><s>They are Gram positive, aerobic, and lack endospores.</s><s>Colonies on peptone–yeast extract medium were orange, smooth, convex, circular, uniform-edged, and 1–2.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits a fine structure in its absorption spectrum with absorption maxima at 440, 465, and 487.5 nm.</s><s>Pigment production is not dependent on any specific growth conditions or on the composition of the medium.</s><s>It is psychrophilic and exhibits optimum growth at 20°C, but is able to grow between 2° and 30°C and pH 6 and 12, and it tolerates up to 12% NaCl.</s><s>It is catalase, lipase, gelatinase, β-galactosidase, and arginine dihydrolase positive, but negative with respect to oxidase, urease, and phosphatase, esculin hydrolysis, starch hydrolysis, nitrate to nitrite reduction, the indole, methyl red, and Voges-Proskauer tests, and levan formation.</s><s>It can utilize glucose, rhamnose, melibiose, lysine, fructose, xylose, glycerol, acetate, succinate, inositol, glutamic acid, and pyruvate, but it cannot utilize mannose, galactose, maltose, sorbose, glucosamine, glutamine, ribose, raffinose, trehalose, cellulose, dulcitol, cellobiose, sorbitol, mannitol, melezitol, adonitol, sucrose, lactose, lactic acid, inulin, β-hydroxybutyric acid, dextrin, glycine, alanine, polyethylene glycol, lysine, phenylalanine, serine, arginine, arabinose, cellulose, methionine, tyrosine, myristic acid, creatinine, potassium hydrogen phthalate, or glycogen, when these are provided as the only carbon source.</s><s>It produces acid from glucose and sucrose but not from lactose, cellobiose, sodium glutamate, or thioglycollate.</s><s>Gas is not produced from any of the above six carbon sources tested for acid production.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is L-lys-D-glu, and MK-7 and MK-8 are the major menaquinones.</s><s>Iso-C<sup>14:0</sup>, C<sup>14:1</sup>, iso-C<sup>15:0</sup>, anteiso-C<sup>15:0</sup>, C<sup>15:0</sup>, iso-C<sup>15:1</sup>, iso-C<sup>16:0</sup>, C<sup>16:1</sup>, iso-C<sup>16:1</sup>, iso-C<sup>17:1</sup>, C<sup>17:0</sup>, anteiso-C<sup>17:0</sup>, C<sup>17:0</sup>, iso-C<sup>17:1</sup>, C<sup>17:0</sup>, C<sup>18:0</sup>, and C<sup>18:1</sup> are the cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The mol% G+C content of the DNA is 41.5 mol%, and this species is phylogenetically related to <i>P. mcmeekinii</i> and <i>P. okeanokoites,</i> on the basis of 16S rDNA analysis.</s><s>It is resistant to carbenicillin, tobramycin, nitrofurazone, furazolidone, colistin, kanamycin, nystatin, ampicillin, and amoxicillin, but sensitive to chlortetracycline, polymyxin, oxytetracycline, nitrofurantoin, penicillin, bacitracin, gentamicin, lincomycin, rifampicin, cotrimoxazole, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, trimethoprim, nalidixic acid, neomycin, streptomycin, novobiocin, and erythromycin. <i>P. antarcticus</i> sp. nov. was isolated from a cyanobacterial mat sample from McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s><s>The type strain is CMS 26or<sup>T</sup> (MTCC 3854; DSM 14505).</s><s>The EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of CMS 26or<sup>T</sup> is AJ314745.</s></p></content></protolog>