<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7386_nm.6742" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6742" rank="genus">Prauserella</organism><reference id="rid.7386"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Amycolatopsis rugosa Lechevalier et al. 1986 as Prauserella rugosa gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>507</fpage><lpage>512</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-507</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319471</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prauserella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prauserella</i> (Prau.se.rel'la. M.L. dim. ending -<i>ella</i>; M. L. fem. n. <i>Prauserella</i> named after Helmut Prauser, a German microbiologist who made many contributions to actinomycete systematics)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and earlier studies (Di Marco &#x0026; Spalla, 1957; Lechevalier et al., 1986; Henssenet al., 1987).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-alcohol-fast, nonmotile actinomycetes that form an extensively branched substrate mycelium (0.6-0.8 μm in diameter) which fragments into irregular rods within 24-48 h on rich media.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are not formed.</s><s>Produce cream to yellowish, glistening colonies that may be wrinkled or folded.</s><s>Good growth occurs on asparagine, modified Bennett's, Czapek Dox-yeast extract, glycerine and nutrient agars.</s><s>Brownish, soluble pigments are formed on some media.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10-15°C with the optimum temperature of 34°C.</s><s>Grow optimally between pH 6-8 and 7.2.</s><s>Contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid, an acetylated peptidoglycan, major amounts of arabinose and galactose, di- and tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenologue and diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine as diagnostic polar lipids, have a fatty-acid profile rich in branched-chain and saturated components and lack mycolic acids.</s><s>The genus belongs to the family <i>Pseudonocardiaceae</i> Warwick et al. (1994).</s><s>The type and only species is <i>Prauserella rugosa</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>