<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10796_nm.17906" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17906" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17906" rank="species">Indibacter alkaliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.10796"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Madhu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manorama</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Indibacter alkaliphilus gen. nov., sp. nov., an alkaliphilic bacterium isolated from a haloalkaline lake</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>721</fpage><lpage>726</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014076</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20371870</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Indibacter alkaliphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Indibacter alkaliphilus</em> (al.ka.li′phi.lus. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. adj. <em>alkaliphilus</em> alkali-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile rods (0.5–0.7 μm in width and 2.0–3.0 μm in length) that occur singly and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Colonies on half-strength marine agar are circular, 2–3 mm in diameter, smooth, reddish-orange in colour, opaque, convex and entire.</s><s>Cells grow at 15–40 °C, with optimum growth at 30–37 °C, and tolerate up to 8.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7.5–12.0.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, ornithine decarboxylase and lysine decarboxylase are positive, but urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Starch and aesculin are hydrolysed, but Tween 60, Tween 85 and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and H<sub>2</sub>S gas is not produced.</s><s>Cells produce acid from xylose, melezitose, maltose, d-fructose, d-arabinose, melibiose, cellobiose, d-glucose, lactose and l-rhamnose, but not from inulin, aesculin, xylitol, salicin, erythritol, adonitol, dulcitol, d-galactose, inositol, mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose, d-sorbitol or trehalose, even after 1 week of incubation at optimum temperature and pH.</s><s>Assimilates lactose, xylose, maltose, fructose, glucose, galactose, raffinose, trehalose, melibiose, sucrose, l-arabinose, mannose, glucosamine, adonitol, rhamnose, aesculin and d-arabinose, but not inulin, sodium gluconate, glycerol, salicin, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, ribose, melezitose, xylitol, ONPG, citrate, malonate, sorbose or amygdalin.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc except where indicated): cefazolin (30), colistin (10), co-trimoxazole (25), lincomycin (2), nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (50 U), amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), bacitracin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), gentamicin G (30), kanamycin (30), lomefloxacin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), norfloxacin (10), novobiocin (30), oleandomycin (15), penicillin G (10), rifampicin (30), spectinomycin (100), tetracycline (30), doxycycline (10), cefuroxime (30), cefoperazone (75), roxithromycin (30), streptomycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Polar lipids comprise phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine and one unidentified lipid.</s><s>Isoprenoid quinones are MK-4 and MK-7.</s><s>Cellular fatty acid composition is given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LW1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22604<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 57479<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected at a depth of 3.5 m from Lonar Lake, Lonar, Buldhana district, Maharashtra, India.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.7±1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>