<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7650_nm.12189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4582" rank="species">Haloanaerobium salsugo</organism><reference id="rid.7650"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bhupathiraju</surname><given-names>V.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sharma</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McInerney</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloanaerobium salsugo sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, anaerobic bacterium from a subterranean brine.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>565</fpage><lpage>572</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-565</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520744</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloanaerobium salsugo</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloanaerobium salsugo</i> (sal.su'go. L. fem. n. <i>salsugo</i>, water impregnated with salt; brine, referring to isolation of this organism from oil field brine)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Haloanaerobium salsugo</i> has straight, rod-shaped cells that are 0.3 to 0.4 by 2.6 to 4 μm.</s><s>Cells characteristically appear singly, in pairs, or occasionally as long chains and are nonmotile.</s><s>The bacterium stains gram-negative and is non-spore forming.</s><s>Colonies on complex medium are circular, entire, opaque, white, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth in liquid medium is uniform, with pellicle formation after 72 h.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, tetracycline, and penicillin but not by cycloheximide or azide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacterium is obligately halophilic.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 9%; growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of between 6 and 24%.</s><s>NaCl is specifically required, with no growth observed at NaCl concentrations less than 6% or in medium with potassium, lithium, magnesium, or ammonium salts or sodium bromide, sodium nitrate, sodium sulfate, or sodium thiosulfate.</s><s>The temperature range is 22 to 51°C, with the fastest growth occurring at 40°C.</s><s>The pH range is 5.6 to 8.0, with the optimum for growth at pH 6.1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacterium is strictly anaerobic, is catalase and oxidase negative, and has a fermentative metabolism.</s><s>The end products of glucose fermentation are acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The molar growth yield was 24.5 ± 0.3 g (dry weight) of cells per mol of glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds supported growth in mineral salts medium: L-arabinose, N-acetylglucosamine, fructose, galactose, glucosamine, D-glucose, lactose, maltotriose, melizitose, D-mannose, maltose, melibiose, pyruvate, D-ribose, rhamnose, raffinose, sucrose, L-sorbose, trehalose, D-xylose, and yeast extract.</s><s>The following compounds did not support growth in mineral salts medium: L-alanine, L-ascorbate, adonitol, betaine, butyrate, chitin, crotonate, Casamino Acids, dextran, dextrin, dulcitol, ethylene glycol, formate, fucose, fumarate, glycerol, glutamate, glycine, glycogen, D-gluconate, inositol, inulin, L-lysine, lactate, malate, methanol, mannitol, methionine, pectin, proline, propionate, peptone, starch, succinate, sarcosine, sorbitol, salicin, trypticase, whey, and xylan.</s><s>Amino acid mixtures such as alanine-glycine, leucine-proline, isoleucine-tryptophan, valine-ornithine, phenylalanine-leucine, and histidine-sarcosine were not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major (&#x003E;7%) cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, and C<sub>17:0cyc</sub> acids.</s><s>The minor (0.5 to 7%) fatty acids are C<sub>10:0</sub>, C<sub>12:0</sub>, and C<sub>15:0</sub> acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 34 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat is hypersaline petroleum reservoir production fluid from Payne County, Okla.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VS-752, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 51327.</s></p></content></protolog>