<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5912_nm.10104" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10104" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10104" rank="species">Thalassomonas agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5912"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jean</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shieh</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassomonas agarivorans sp. nov., a marine agarolytic bacterium isolated from shallow coastal water of An-Ping Harbour, Taiwan, and emended description of the genus Thalassomonas</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1245</fpage><lpage>1250</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64130-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738099</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassomonas agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassomonas agarivorans</em> (a.ga.ri.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>agarum</em> agar; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, destroying; N.L. part. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics included in the emended description of the genus, the following characteristics are observed.</s><s>Cells during late exponential to early stationary phase of growth in broth cultures are non-motile, straight or curved rods that measure approximately 1.4–2.2 by 0.4–0.7 μm.</s><s>Colonies produced on agar plates are circular, off-white, opaque, non-luminescent and agarolytic; distinct depressions are formed by these colonies in a few days and much of the agar in the plate medium is liquefied after incubation for several weeks.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 37 °C with optimal growth at 25 °C; no growth at 4–13 or 40 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1–5 % NaCl with optimal growth at 3 %; no growth at 0 or 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Able to grow over a pH range of 7–9 but not at pH 6.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from thiosulphate.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Aesculin, alginate, casein, DNA, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed but lecithin, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, acid phosphatase and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Organic growth factors are probably required since growth does not occur on the following compounds as sole carbon sources: glucose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, glycerol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, acetate, citrate, fumarate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, malonate, tartrate, l-alanine, arginine, aspartate, gluconate, glutamine, glutamate, leucine, lysine, tryptophan and l-aconitate.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids present at levels greater than 5 % include C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>13 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), colistin (10 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (300 U) and tetracycline (30 μg); intermediate susceptibility to nalidixic acid (30 μg); resistant to carbenicillin (100 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), oxacillin (1 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TMA1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17492<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13379<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shallow seawater of An-Ping Harbour, Tainan, Taiwan.</s><s>It has a DNA G+C content of 41.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>