<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6101_nm.10246" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10246" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10246" rank="species">Acetobacter nitrogenifigens</organism><reference id="rid.6101"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dutta</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gachhui</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel nitrogen-fixing Acetobacter nitrogenifigens sp. nov., isolated from Kombucha tea.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1899</fpage><lpage>1903</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64101-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902028</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acetobacter nitrogenifigens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acetobacter nitrogenifigens</em> (ni.tro.gen.i′fi.gens. N.L. n. <em>nitrogenium</em> nitrogen; L. part. adj. <em>figens</em> fixing; N.L. part. adj. <em>nitrogenifigens</em> nitrogen-fixing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods with rounded ends, approximately 1.5–2.0 μm in length and 0.1–0.2 μm in width and occur singly or in chains.</s><s>These Gram-negative bacteria are motile with polar flagellation, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs on nitrogen-free LGI plates at 30 °C, but not at 37 °C and in LGI broth under microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days, colonies grown on LGI plates are smooth, round, glistening, transparent and 2–3 mm in diameter, while dark-yellow colonies are formed on LGI agar supplemented with 0.001 % bromothymol blue.</s><s>Colonies on potato agar are light brown after 5 days of incubation, but the intensity increases after 10 days.</s><s>Strains are aerobic and fix atmospheric nitrogen microaerobically.</s><s>Growth occurs well in the presence of ammonium, but nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>In absence of yeast extract, strains can utilize different carbon sources such as d-galactose, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-arabinose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, and grow on 30 % sucrose and 30 % glucose.</s><s>Dihydroxyacetone is produced from glycerol and <em>γ</em>-pyrone from d-glucose.</s><s>Ethanol is oxidized to acetic acid, and acetate and lactate over oxidize to CO<sub>2</sub> and water.</s><s>Methanol is not utilized.</s><s>Single amino acids like l-alanine, l-cysteine and l-phenylalanine can be used as a sole source of carbon and nitrogen.</s><s>l-Threonine is not utilized as the sole source of carbon and nitrogen.</s><s>The ubiquinone present is of the type Q-9 and DNA G+C content is 64.1 mol%.</s><s>Based on data from the MLEE assay along with DNA–DNA relatedness and <em>nifH</em> gene sequence, the type strain RG1<sup>T</sup> can be differentiated from other <em>Acetobacter</em> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain RG1<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 6912<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23498<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Kombucha tea.</s></p></content></protolog>