<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1390_nm.5979" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5979" rank="genus">Brachybacterium</organism><reference id="rid.1390"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium faecium gen. nov., sp. nov., a coryneform bacterium from poultry deep litter.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>48</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachybacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachybacterium</i> (Bra.chy.bac.te´ri.um. Gr. adj. <i>brachy</i> short; L. neut. dim. n. <i>bacterium</i> rod; M.L. neut. n. <i>Brachybacterium</i> a small rodlet)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells vary in shape and exhibit a rod-coccus growth cycle.</s><s>Stationary-phase cultures are composed entirely or largely of coccoid cells, which, after transfer to fresh medium, grow out to give the irregular slender rods (0.5 to 0.75 by 1.5 to 2.5 μm) characteristic of exponential-phase cultures.</s><s>Some cells are arranged at an angle to give V formations.</s><s>Both rods and coccoid cells are gram-positive, nonacid fast, and nonmotile; endospores are not formed.</s><s>Essentially aerobic but may show very weak growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Does not survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose and some other sugars.</s><s>Esculin and starch are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cellulose, chitin, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-DAP, alanine, and glutamic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are predominantly of the straight-chain saturated, iso- and anteisomethyl branched types.</s><s>The major polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, an unknown phospholipid, and several glycolipids.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 68 to 71.5 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Brachybacterium faecium</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>