<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7185_nm.5476" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5476" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5476" rank="species">Facklamia hominis</organism><reference id="rid.7185"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lemozy</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Åkervall</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and phylogenetic characterization of some Globicatella-like organisms from human sources: description of Facklamia hominis gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>880</fpage><lpage>882</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-880</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226922</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Facklamia hominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Facklamia hominis</i> (ho'mi.nis. L.gen.n. <i>hominis</i>, of human, from which the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and ovoid and occur in pairs or groups.</s><s>Cells are nonpigmented and nonmotile.</s><s>Spores are not produced.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and cat alase negative .</s><s>Growth occurs on 5% blood agar, producing a weakly alphα-hemolytic reaction.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 5% NaC1.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cellobiose, glucose, inulin, glycogen, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, mannitol, lactose, pullulan, D-raffinose, D-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, D-xylose, L-xylose, D-tagatose, or trehalose.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and leucine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, β-mannosidase, pyrazinamidase, phosphoamidase, valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, and trypsin are not produced.</s><s>Urease, alanylphenylalanylproline arylamidase, α-galactosidase, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, and pyroglutamine arylamidase may or may not be produced.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer and indole negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is L-Lys-D-Asp(type A4α).</s><s>The type strain of <i>F. hominis</i> is CCUG 36813.</s><s>Strain CCUG 36813<sup>T</sup> was isolated from an abscess on buttocks and has the characteristics of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces pyrrolidonyl arylamidase but not urease, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, or pyroglutamine arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nucleotide sequence accession number.</s><s>The 16s rRNA gene sequence of strain CCUG 36813<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the GenBank database under accession no. Y10772.</s></p></content></protolog>