<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2818_nm.3097" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3097" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3097" rank="species">Escherichia fergusonii</organism><reference id="rid.2818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riddle</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asbury</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lowery</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Escherichia fergusonii and Enterobacter taylorae, two new species of Enterobacteriaceae isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3968204</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> (<i>fergusonii</i>, (pronunciation [with a classical Latin pronunciation of the ending], fur guh sew' knee ee) is a neo (modern) Latin substantive (masculine) coined to honor the American microbiologist William H. Ferguson, who made many contributions to enteric bacteriology and was one of the first to show the role of certain strains of <i>E. coli</i> in infantile diarrhea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> have the following properties of other species in the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>: they are gram-negative rods, oxidase negative, catalase positive, and usually motile, reduce nitrate to nitrite, and ferment D-glucose.</s><s>Strains of <i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> have the following properties of the genus <i>Escherichia</i>: they are positive for indole production, methyl red, motility, and acetate utilization and negative for the Voges-Proskauer reaction, H<sub>2</sub>S production on triple sugar-iron agar, urea hydrolysis, phenylalanine  deaminase, and growth in the presence of KCN. <i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> ferments many of the sugars nad polyhydroxyl alcohols used in enteric bacteriology.</s><s>More details on these biochemical reactions that form the species description are given in Table 4.</s><s>All strains were susceptible to colistin, gentamicin, and chloramphenicol, but were resistant to penicillin.</s><s>Susceptibility was variable for nalidixic acid (77% susceptible), sulfadiazine (62% susceptible), streptomycin (46% susceptible), tetracycline (62% susceptible), ampicillin (77% susceptible), carbenicillin (77% susceptible), and cephalothin (31% susceptible).</s><s>A more complete description of <i>Escherichia fergusonii</i> based on 26 strains is given in Table 4.</s><s>The type strain (holotype) is designated as ATCC 35469, which has biochemical reactions typical of the species (Table 4).</s><s>Some comments that were sent with cultures include: "multiple abscesses following a gun shot to the abdomen"; "'from urinary tract infection in a woman"; "from the cloaca of a hawk"; "isolated from the infusion material of a 58-year-old male with ALS who had post infusion sepsis"; "diarrheal stool from a 66-year-old female with diabetes"; "large intestine of 'Sitatunga' from the National Animal Center, Ames, Iowa."</s></p></content></protolog>