<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1235_nm.5958" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5958" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5958" rank="species">Cellulomonas fermentans</organism><reference id="rid.1235"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bagnara</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toci</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gaudin</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Belaich</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a cellulolytic microorganism, Cellulomonas fermentans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>502</fpage><lpage>507</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellulomonas fermentans</i>, sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellulomonas fermentans</i> (Fer.men'tans. L.part.adj. <i>fermentans</i> fermenting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Coryneform rod exhibiting a polymorphism, 0.2 to 0.5 by 0.6 to 1.7 μm.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony characteristics.</s><s>White with an undulate margin, 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>A zone of cellulose digestion extending from the periphery of the colony is observed in cellulose agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Anaerobic, but with growth under aerobic conditions without any apparent benefit.</s><s>Growth on arabinose, cellulose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, raffinose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, and xylan but not on asparagine, arbutine, glycerol, inulin, melibiose, melezitose, pectin, rhamnose, ribose, pyruvate, salicin, sorbitol, and urea.</s><s>It does not grow under aerobic conditions on butanol, butyrate, citrate, ethanol, gluconate, lactate, propanol, propionate, or succinate but grows slowly on acetate.</s><s>Yeast extract (0.05%) and Casamino Acids (0.2%) support only slight growth.</s><s>Growth factors other than biotin and thiamine together are required and can be provided by 0.05% yeast extract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation products.</s><s>Fermentation products are acetic acid, formic acid, ethanol, occasionally L-(+)-lactic acid, and, in smaller amounts, carbon dioxide and succinic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions.</s><s>Gelatin liquefied, nitrate reduced, NH<sub>3</sub> produced from peptone.</s><s>Neither acetyl methyl carbinol nor indole is produced.</s><s>Catalase and urease negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature relationships.</s><s>Optimum temperature between 30 and 37°C.</s><s>No growth at 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH relationships.</s><s>Optimum pH around 7.4.</s><s>Growth rate decreases substantially under 7 and over 8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall structure.</s><s>Ornithine is the diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Cell wall sugars are glucose, rhamnose, and ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition. 75.8 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source.</s><s>Methanogenic enrichment culture from a municipal dumping ground was the source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain M<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen (DSM) under accession number 3133.</s></p></content></protolog>