<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11575_nm.18610" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18610" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18610" rank="species">Nonomuraea rosea</organism><reference id="rid.11575"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nimtz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grün-Wollny</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonomuraea rosea sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1118</fpage><lpage>1124</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014845-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666797</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nonomuraea rosea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nonomuraea rosea</em> (ro.se′a. L. fem. adj. <em>rosea</em> rose-coloured or rosy, referring to the pinkish colour of the colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms an extensive branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>A white aerial mycelium is visible on oatmeal agar.</s><s>Spore chains are spiral; sporangia are not detected.</s><s>Gram-stain-positive and oxidase-positive; shows an aerobic respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 3 days of incubation on oatmeal agar or nutrient agar (Oxoid) at 25–30 °C.</s><s>The polar lipids include the major compound diphosphatidylglycerol, moderate amounts of PME, PE, OH-PE, OH-PME and an unknown aminophosphoglycolipid.</s><s>Phosphatidylinositol-mannosides and phosphatidylinositol are present and small amounts of an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The fatty acids comprise mainly iso- and 10-heptadecanoic-branched fatty acids.</s><s>Smaller amounts of unsaturated fatty acids and hydroxylated fatty acids (15 : 0 2-OH, 16 : 0 2-OH) are also detected.</s><s>Results of carbon-source utilization and degradation tests (including differentiating characteristics) are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The type strain does not produce acids from the following carbon sources: glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose and arabitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (after 7 days of incubation): <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate (weak), dl-malate, l-aspartate (weak) and l-proline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-gluconate, melibiose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, maltitol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, azelate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, mesaconate, pyruvate, dl-lactate, suberate, 2-oxoglutarate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, dl-3-hydroxybenzoate, dl-4-hydroxybenzoate and l-phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GW 12687<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45177<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 56107<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample.</s></p></content></protolog>