<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4408_nm.488" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.488" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.488" rank="species">Thermosipho geolei</organism><reference id="rid.4408"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>L'Haridon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miroshnichenko</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonch-Osmolovskaya</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeanthon</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermosipho geolei sp. nov., a thermophilic bacterium isolated from a continental petroleum reservoir in Western Siberia.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1327</fpage><lpage>1334</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491329</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermosipho geolei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermosipho geolei</i> (ge.o'le.i. Gr. n. <i>ge</i> earth; L. gen. neut. n. <i>olei</i> of oil ; N.L. gen. neut. n. <i>geolei</i> from earth oil, referring to the site of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods with a length of about 2-3 μm and a width of about 0.4-0.6 μm.</s><s>No motility is observed under the microscope.</s><s>A polar flagellum is inserted on unsheathed cells in the very early exponential phase of growth.</s><s>A sheath-like structure is clearly visible after the mid-exponential phase of growth.</s><s>Cells form enlarged spherical bodies in stationary phase.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs or in chains of a maximum of six cells.</s><s>White colonies, about 1-2 mm in diameter, are formed on `Phytagel' plates.</s><s>Growth occurs between 45 and 75 °C (optimum growth at 70 °C; doubling time of 115 min), between pH 6.0 and 9.4 (optimum growth at approximately pH 7.5) and at NaCl concentrations between 0.5 and 7.0% (optimum growth between 2 and 3%).</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub> inhibits growth but inhibition is alleviated by addition of elemental sulfur; under these conditions, hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Neither thiosulfate nor sulfate can be used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Metabolism shifts to alanine production in the absence of elemental sulfur.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), vancomycin and rifampicin (both at a final concentrations of 100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) ; growth occurs in the presence of streptomycin (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>DNA G­C composition of the type strain is 30.0 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis based on the complete 16S rRNA sequence affiliates the strain conclusively with the `<i>Thermotogales</i>' and, more specifically, with the genus <i>Thermosipho</i>.</s><s>No significant bulk DNA similarity to <i>Thermosipho africanus</i> or <i>Thermosipho melanesiensis</i>.</s><s>The type strain is SL31<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13256<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10986<sup>T</sup>), obtained from an oil/water mixture collected from a deep continental oil reservoir in Western Siberia (Russia).</s></p></content></protolog>