<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4082_nm.3290" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3290" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3290" rank="species">Saccharobacter fermentatus</organism><reference id="rid.4082"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yaping</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiaoyang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiaqi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharobacter fermentatus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new ethanol-producing bacterium.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>412</fpage><lpage>414</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-412</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharobacter fermentatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharobacter fermentatus</i> (fer. men. ta' tus. M. L. adj. <i>fermentatus</i>, fermentative)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological characteristics are the same as those described above for the genus.</s><s>Colonies on glucose-yeast extract agar are nonpigmented, opaque, milky white, smooth, and low convex with entire margins.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 63.5 ± 0.2 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method) (6).</s><s>The following carbon sources are fermented after incubation at 30°C for 1 day: D-glucose, D-fructose, sucrose, maltose, D-xylose, L-sorbose, trehalose, L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-mannitol, esculin, L-rhamnose, melibiose, and starch.</s><s>Lactose is fermented after incubation for 9 days.</s><s>Dulcitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, raffinose, and gluconate are not fermented after incubation for 9 days.</s><s>Malonate is used as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, yeast extract, urea, phenylalanine, glutamine, and tryptone are used as sole nitrogen sources, but sodium glutamate is not.</s><s>The following enzyme activity tests are negative: hydrolysis of gelatin, H<sub>2</sub>S production on TSI medium, oxidase, urease, nitrate reduction, and Moeller tests for decarboxylase.</s><s>Catalase positive, β-galactosidase positive, and arginine dihydrolase positive (on day 4).</s><s>Positive for growth on 0.5% (wt/vol) KCN.</s><s>Tolerates 35% (wt/vol) glucose and 6% NaCl but not 40% (wt/vol) glucose or 8% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain WVB8512, which is kept at the Wuhan Institute of Virology, Academia Sinica, Wuhan, People's Republic of China.</s><s>This culture is grown on glucose-peptone-yeast extract agar and is stored in lyophilized ampoules.</s></p></content></protolog>