<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3576_nm.5147" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5147" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5147" rank="species">Paenibacillus naphthalenovorans</organism><reference id="rid.3576"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Daane</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harjono</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barns</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Launen</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palleron</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Häggblom</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>PAH-degradation by Paenibacillus spp. and description of Paenibacillus naphthalenovorans sp. nov., a naphthalene-degrading bacterium from the rhizosphere of salt marsh plants.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>131</fpage><lpage>139</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837295</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus naphthalenovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus naphthalenovorans</i> (naph.tha.le.no.vo'rans. L. neut. n. <i>naphthalene</i> from Persian <i>neft</i> naphtha; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <i>naphthalenovorans</i> naphthalene-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped and are 0.8 μm wide by 2.8-4.0 μm long, are motile by peritrichous flagella, and are Gram-positive.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in swelling sporangia.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs between 30 and 37 °C, but does not occur at either 10 or 55 °C.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 5%(w/v) NaCl, and growth with 3%(w/v) NaCl is variable.</s><s>Forms white, translucent, mucoid colonies when grown on solid media.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is negative; starch hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Gelatin and ONPG are not hydrolysed, and arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced.</s><s>Citrate utilization and nitrate reduction are variable.</s><s>Urease and acetoin are produced.</s><s>Acid, but no gas, is produced from galactose, D-glucose, maltose, mannitol, D-mannose, saccharose and trehalose.</s><s>Strain variation is observed for fermentation of D-fructose, melibose, methyl α-D-glucoside, L-sorbose, D-turanose and xylitol.</s><s>Neither acid nor gas is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, starch, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, melezitose, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl β-xyloside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, D-tagatose, D-xylose and L-xylose.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are 14:0 (2.9%), 15:0 iso (5.6%), 15:0 anteiso (50.5%), 16:0 iso (5.2%), 16:1<i>ω</i>11<i>c</i> (12.0%), 16:0 (11.2%), 17:0 iso (2.8%) and 17:0 anteiso (6.5%).</s><s>The mean G­+C content of the DNA is 49 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The habitats are estuarine sediments and salt marsh rhizospheres.</s><s>Isolate PR-N1<sup>T</sup> is the type strain (=ATCC BAA-206<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14203<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description of this strain is essentially identical to that of the species.</s><s>This strain does not grow in the presence of 3% NaCl, is negative for starch hydrolysis, and does not utilize citrate or reduce nitrate.</s><s>It produces acid, but not gas, from D-fructose, methyl α-D-glucoside, L-sorbose and dturanose.</s><s>No acid or gas is produced from melibose or xylitol.</s></p></content></protolog>