<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7505_nm.8369" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8369" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8369" rank="species">Fusobacterium sulci</organism><reference id="rid.7505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium alocis sp. nov. and Fusobacterium sulci sp. nov. from the human gingival sulcus.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>475</fpage><lpage>477</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium sulci</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium sulci</i> (sul'ki. L. gen. n. <i>sulci</i> of a furrow, referring to its habitat, the human gingival sulcus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, obligately anaerobic, straight rods, 0.4 to 0.7 by 1.0 to 7.0 μm, with rounded ends.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains, often with cells of different sizes in the same chain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on blood agar plates are pinpoint to 1.0 mm, circular, entire, flat to low convex, translucent, colorless, shiny, smooth, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>No internal colony structure is visible.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C, at which growth is only moderate at best.</s><s>No growth occur at 25 or 45°C.</s><s>Growth can be stimulated by the addition of rabbit serum (10 to 15% [vol/vol]) and cocarboxylase (5 μg/ml) and in an atmosphere of 10% CO<sub>2</sub>-90% N<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in PYG broth have a stringy or granular sediment and may be slightly turbid.</s><s>After 5 to 7 days of incubation under CO<sub>2</sub>-N<sub>2</sub>, the pH of PYG and basal medium broth cultures is 6.9 to 7.1; under 100% CO<sub>2</sub>, the pH of each is 6.0 to 6.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gas is not detected in PYG deep agar cultures; trace to moderate amounts of H<sub>2</sub> may be produced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not detected in sulfide-indole-motility medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, esculin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, Dmannose, melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, D-(-)ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, catalase, lecithinase, lipase, urease, oxidase, and deoxyribonuclease are not produced.</s><s>Esculin, starch, and hippurate were not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced; neither resazurin nor neutral red is reduced.</s><s>There is no reaction in milk and no digestion of gelatin or chopped meat.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products of fermentation in PYG broth are moderate to large amounts of butyrate and trace to small amounts of acetate; traces of succinate are occasionally detected.</s><s>Pyruvate, DL-lactate, D-gluconate, and L-threonine are utilized.</s><s>All 15 strains tested are susceptible to chloramphenicol(l2 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s><s>The principal habitat of F . sulci is the human gingival sulcus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. sulci</i> is VPI D45A-29A (=ATCC 35585).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of this strain is 39 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>