<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3595_nm.7709" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7709" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7709" rank="species">Bifidobacterium scardovii</organism><reference id="rid.3595"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inganäs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drancourt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McCartney</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium scardovii sp. nov., from human sources.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>995</fpage><lpage>999</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02065-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054269</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium scardovii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium scardovii</i> (scar.dov'i.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>scardovii</i> of Scardovi; named after Vittorio Scardovi, in recognition of his contribution to our knowledge of the bifidobacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-motile, asporogenous rod-shaped cells, some of which are curved.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Weak haemolysis is observed on Columbia blood agar.</s><s>Colonies are 2-3 mm in diameter, convex, shiny, with a dense white centre.</s><s>End products of glucose fermentation are acetic and L-lactic acid.</s><s>No gas production is observed.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from L-arabinose, lactose, mannose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, pullulan, glycogen, mannitol, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from melezitose.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Activity of alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, α-arabinosidase, α-fucosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenyl alanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase is observed.</s><s>No activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, proline arylamidase or leucyl glycine arylamidase.</s><s>Activity may or may not be observed for alanine arylamidase, bglucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-mannosidase and urease.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Indole-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Cell wall murein is of the A3α type, L-Lys-L-Ser-L-Ala<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical sources.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 13008<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13734<sup>T</sup>) and it was isolated from human blood.</s><s>G+­C content of the type strain is 60.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>