<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8292_nm.14145" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14145" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14145" rank="species">Rhodoplanes serenus</organism><reference id="rid.8292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Okamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanbe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoplanes serenus sp. nov., a purple non-sulfur bacterium isolated from pond water.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>531</fpage><lpage>535</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000174-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244435</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodoplanes serenus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodoplanes serenus</em> (se′re.nus. L. adj. <em>serenus</em> clear, bright, pertaining to the bright-pink culture).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, 0.8–1.0 μm wide and 2.0–3.0 μm long.</s><s>Multiplication is by budding and asymmetrical cell division during which a division tube occurs between the mother and daughter cells.</s><s>Motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Rosette-like clusters are formed in older cultures.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are of the lamellar type and are parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Phototrophic cultures are bright pink to red in colour, whereas aerobic cultures are pale pink.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cells at high light intensities have absorption maxima at 378, 482, 512, 550, 590, 800 and 850 nm.</s><s>Anaerobic photo-organotrophy is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Aerobic growth at full atmospheric oxygen tension is detected.</s><s>Anaerobic growth in darkness with nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor is also possible and denitrification is detected.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20–43 °C (optimum, 35 °C).</s><s>The pH range for phototrophic growth is 5.5–9.0 (optimum, pH 8.0).</s><s>Little or no growth occurs with ≥1 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth factors are required.</s><s>Photolithotrophic growth occurs with thiosulfate, but not with sulfide or H<sub>2</sub>, as the electron donor.</s><s>Photoassimilates the following organic substrates: acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, glycerol, ethanol, pyruvate, lactate, citrate, malate, malonate, fumarate, succinate, tartrate, asparagine, aspartate, glutamate, glutamine, yeast extract, peptone and Casamino acids.</s><s>The following are not utilized: formate, caprylate, pelargonate, palmitate, gluconate, benzoate, nicotinate, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, fructose, glucose, sucrose, mannose, galactose, trehalose, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, methanol, propanol, alanine, methionine and leucine.</s><s>Ammonium, nitrate, glutamate, glutamine, urea and molecular nitrogen are utilized as nitrogen sources, but nitrite is not.</s><s>Sulfate is assimilated as a sulfur source.</s><s>C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> is the major cellular fatty acid.</s><s>The major quinones are Q-10 and RQ-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.5 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TUT3530<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18633<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102049<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from pond water.</s></p></content></protolog>