<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4444_nm.3285" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3285" rank="genus">Raoultella</organism><reference id="rid.4444"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Drancourt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bollet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rousselier</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analyses of Klebsiella species delineate Klebsiella and Raoultella gen. nov., with description of Raoultella ornithinolytica comb. nov., Raoultella terrigena comb. nov. and Raoultella planticola comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>925</fpage><lpage>932</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411716</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Raoultella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Raoultella</i> (Ra.oul.tel'la. M.L. dim. suffix tella ; M.L. fem. n. <i>Raoultella</i> named after the French bacteriologist Didier Raoult, Université de la Me!diterranée, Marseille, France)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <i>Raoultella</i> is composed of Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, aerobic, non-motile, capsulated rods.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, having both a respiratory and a fermentative type of metabolism.</s><s>Cells grow on meat extract medium; growth at 10 °C is a hallmark of the genus.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Most strains can use citrate and glucose as sole carbon source.</s><s>Glucose is fermented with the production of acid and gas, and most strains produce 2,3-butanediol as a major end product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is always positive.</s><s>Recovered from water, soil, plants and occasionally mammal mucosae, including human specimens.</s><s>Type species is <i>Raoultella planticola</i> comb. nov. and the type strain is <i>Raoultella planticola</i> ATCC 33531<sup>T</sup> (CIP 100751<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>