<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.200_nm.3945" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3945" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3945" rank="species">Clostridium herbivorans</organism><reference id="rid.200"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Varel</surname><given-names>V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium herbivorans sp. nov., a cellulolytic anaerobe from the pig intestine.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>490</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-490</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590675</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium herbivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium herbivorans</i> (her.bi.vo'rans.L. fem. n. <i>herba</i>, a green plant; L. v. <i>voro</i>, to devour; M. L. part. adj. <i>herbivorans</i>, devouring plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive straight rods (0.7 to 0.9 by 3.5 to 4.0 μm) that occur in pairs or as single cells.</s><s>Cells are motile, and peritrichous with 15 to 20 flagella per cell.</s><s>Cells rarely sporulate; however, when spores are present, they are subterminal to terminal and 1 μm wide by 2 μm long and cause the sporangium to swell.</s><s>Cultures grown with insoluble substrates such as cellulose or plant cell walls more readily produce spores than do those grown with soluble substrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Growth requires a fermentable carbohydrate such as cellobiose, cellulose, maltose, starch, or glycogen.</s><s>The following compounds do not support growth: amygdalin, arabinose, Casamino Acids, erythritol, fructose, glucose, inositol, lactate, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose,  melibiose, pectin, pyruvate, raffinose, rhammose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, and xylan.</s><s>Nitrate and sulfate are not reduced.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, and urease negative.</s><s>Esculin, lecithin, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Meat is not digested.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 39 to 42°C, and the optimum pH for growth is 6.8 to 7.2.</s><s>Rapid lysis of cells occurs in broth media once the stationary growth phase is reached; this is slightly less true with agar media.</s><s>Ruminal fluid (15%, vol/vol) and yeast extract (1%, wt/vol) stimulate growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products of cellobiose fermentation are formate 0and butyrate; minor amounts of ethanol and hydrogen are also produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38 mol% (as determined by the buoyant density method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 54408, was isolated from intestinal contents of a pig and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49925.</s></p></content></protolog>