<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14705" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14705" rank="species">Planktoluna difficilis</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Planktoluna difficilis’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Planktoluna difficilis’ [Plank′to.lu′na. Gr. adj. <em>planktos</em> wandering, drifting; L. fem. n. <em>luna</em> the moon; N.L. fem. n. <em>Planktoluna</em> planktonic moon, referring to the planktonic lifestyle and the solenoid morphology of the first strain. dif.fi.ci′lis. L. fem. adj. <em>difficilis</em> difficult, referring to difficulties in cultivation of the first strain]. Represented by the aerobic, red-pigmented strain MWH-7Well8, which was isolated from Mailing Bay, Lake Taihu, China. The strain is cultured as a mixed culture containing a relatively large fraction of a spirochaete. Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-7Well8 (GenBank accession no. AM939566) and the presence of the specific oligonucleotide sequence 5′-CTTGGAGGCATCTCCAGG-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 183–193) within the 16S rRNA gene. This diagnostic oligonucleotide sequence is also present in five environmental sequences of uncultured actinobacteria (Supplementary Fig. S2) originating from four different European lakes (Warnecke <em>et al.</em>, 2004). The sequences of strain MWH-7Well8 and the five uncultured actinobacteria form a cluster characterized by sequence similarity values &#x003E;98.9 % (Supplementary Fig. S2). Furthermore, the diagnostic sequence is also present in three partial sequences (GenBank accession nos EF150062, EF150044 and AF141476) that show sequence similarities in the range 98.3–99.4 % with the sequence of strain MWH-7Well8. These sequences were retrieved from the Columbia River, USA, and from freshwater habitats in Kenya populated by <em>Anopheles</em> spp. larvae.</s></p></content></protolog>