<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1336_nm.4876" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4876" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4876" rank="species">Bacillus azotoformans</organism><reference id="rid.1336"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pichinoty</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Barjac</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asselineau</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Bacillus azotoformans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>660</fpage><lpage>662</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-660</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus azotoformans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus azotoformans</i> (a.zoto.for.mans. French n. <i>azote</i> nitrogen; L. part. adj. <i>formans</i> forming; <i>azotoformans</i> nitrogen forming)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Bacillus azotoformans</i> has (0.9 to 1 by 3 to 10 μm), have rounded ends, and are rapidly motile by means of numerous long peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Gram reaction negative.</s><s>Gram type positive.</s><s>The cells have thick walls, mesosomes, and persistent septa.</s><s>Aminopeptidase is absent.</s><s>The endospores of this organism are oval (1.4 by 2 to 2.5 μm) and make the sporangium bulge; the spores are located terminally or subterminally.</s><s>Exosporium lacking.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire margins, convex, and partially translucent, attaining a diameter of 5 mm on yeast extract-salts agar.</s><s>Growth is rapid and produces uniform and dense turbidity in yeast extract-salts liquid medium.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate</s></p><p class="description"><s>is produced when cells are grown in the presence of DL-3-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Growth factors are required.</s><s>Aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Glucose is neither fermented nor oxidized.</s><s>The following respiratory electron acceptors are utilized anaerobically; NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup>, N<sub>2</sub>O, S<sub>4</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup>, and fumarate.</s><s>S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup> is not utilized as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Considerable quantities of N<sub>2</sub> are produced in the course of reduction of NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup>, N<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>Oxidase reaction positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzymes and electron carriers are present: cytochromes <i>b</i> and <i>c</i> ; oxidase <i>a</i> + <i>a<sub>3</sub></i>; nitrate reductase A; nitrite (NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> → NO), nitric oxide (NO → N<sub>2</sub>O), nitrous oxide (N<sub>2</sub>O → N<sub>2</sub>O), tetrathionate (S<sub>4</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup> → S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup>), and fumarate reductases ; and L-glutamate dehydrogenase.</s><s>The following enzymes are not detected: catalase, thiosulfate reductase, arginine dihydrolase, L-phenylalanine deaminase, urease, and β-galactosidase .</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following tests are negative: hydrolysis of gelatin, starch, and Tween 80; growth at pH 5.6; growth in the presence of 5% NaCl, 8% KN03, 0.02% NaN<sub>3</sub>, and 0.001% lysozyme; Voges-Proskauer reaction; indole production; decomposition of tyrosine; production of brown pigment in tyrosine-containing media; decomposition of hippurate with production of benzoate; and conversion of glycerol to dihydroxyacetone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following organic acids are degraded: acetate, succinate, DL-lactate, pyruvate, L-malate, citrate, L-glutamate, and L-aspartate.</s><s>Propionate, glycolate, malonate, glutarate, tartrate, and glycine are not degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The maximum growth temperature is between 42 and 46°C; no growth occurs at 4°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipids comprise 5.7 to 7.4% of total cell dry weight.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine is the major phospholipid; cardiolipin and phosphatidylglycerol are also present.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is as follows: iso-C<sub>14</sub>, 15 to 30 mol%; n-C<sub>14</sub>, 2 to 5 mol%; iso-C<sub>15</sub>, 28 to 52 mol%; anteiso-C<sub>15</sub>, 16 to 20 mol%; n-C<sub>15</sub>, 0 to 1 mol% iso-C<sub>16</sub>, 5 to 8 mol%; n-C<sub>16</sub>, 2 to 6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of deoxyribonucleic acid: 39.8 ± 1.2 mol% (as determined by buoyant density in CsCl).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selective isolation can be performed by enrichment culture of pasteurized (10 min, 80°C) soil samples in media containing 1% Bacto-Peptone (Difco Laboratories, Detroit, Mich.) incubated at 32°C in an atmosphere of pure N<sub>2</sub>O.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain 1 (= ATCC 29788 = CCM 2849 = CIP R925).</s></p></content></protolog>