<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.80_nm.1554" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1554" rank="genus">Pedomicrobium</organism><reference id="rid.80"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gebers</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beese</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedomicrobium americanum sp. nov. and Pedomicrobium australicum sp. nov. from aquatic habitats, Pedomicrobium gen. emend., and Pedomicrobium ferrugineum sp. emend.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>303</fpage><lpage>315</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Pedomicrobium</i> Aristovskaya 1961 (Gebers 1981)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are spherical, oval, tetrahedral, or rod, pear, bean, or spindle shaped. Up to five or more prosthecae (i.e., cellular outgrowths [hyphae] of constant diameter) are formed per cell; these are 0.15 to 0.3 μm in diameter and vary in length with cultural conditions. At least one hypha originates laterally; other hyphae may appear polarly or subpolarly. True branching of the hyphae occurs. Multiplication is primarily by budding at the hyphal tips, where local swellings form young buds which elongate perpendicularly to the hyphal axis and enlarge up to the size of a mother cell. Hyphal insertion of the buds is lateral in all cases. Up to three buds per mother cell may occur at the same time. Mature buds either separate from the hyphae as uniflagellated swarmers or remain attached. Buds may arise in an intercalary fashion by localized hyphal swelling. Occasionally, direct budding of mother cells or division of single mother cells is observed (1,3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain gram negative, although older cells may stain gram variable.</s><s>Extracellular polymers stain with ruthenium red.</s><s>Oxidized iron compounds or manganese compounds or both are deposited primarily on mother cells and also on hyphae.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic membranes are observed in cells of manganese-depositing species.</s><s>Up to three granules of poly-β- hydroxybutyric acid are stored per cell.</s><s>Small, dense granules stainable with Loeffler methylene blue suggest the presence of polyphosphates.</s><s>Liquid cultures grown in the dark and in synthetic light may be yellowish white and reddish orange, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two colony types may develop on solid media.</s><s>Type 1 colonies are round and convex and have entire or rhizoid edges; they are yellowish red to dark brown, sometimes with concentric rings.</s><s>These colonies have a soft consistency.</s><s>Type 2 colonies are round and flat; they pit the agar so that their surfaces remain near the agar level.</s><s>Their edges are entire or rhizoid.</s><s>Type 2 colonies are yellowish red to dark brown, and the cells in the center of the colonies are often lysed, giving a granular appearance to the colonies.</s><s>These colonies have a cartilaginous consistency and may be removed from the agar intact.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After restreaking on solid media, type 1 or 2 colonies give rise to both types of colonies.</s><s>With periodic transfers to fresh medium type 1 colonies tend to predominate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are microaerophilic to aerobic and heterotrophic.</s><s>Slow, poor growth occurs on 0.1 to 1% fulvic acid iron sesquioxide complexes as sole carbon and nitrogen sources; good growth occurs with 10 mM acetate, 10 mM malate, 10 mM succinate, or 10 mM gluconate as the carbon source and a nitrogen source such as yeast extract, peptone, Casamino Acids (Difco), or Soytone (Difco) at a concentration of 0.05%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vitamin mixtures stimulate growth; lack of vitamins produces pleomorphic cells.</s><s>Good growth occurs in the presence of 0.1% NaCl; no growth, but survival, occurs in the presence of 1 or 2.5% NaCl; 5% NaCl is bactericidal for the species that have been described (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Neither acid nor gas is produced anaerobically from glucose.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed in stab cultures.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>On PSM agar supplemented with sheep blood (100 ml/liter), all strains grow well but are not hemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>These organisms are widely distributed in podzolic and other soils, freshwater habitats, iron springs, and seawater; they are probably ubiquitous.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition (four species, 11 strains) ranges from 63 to 66 mol% guanine plus cytosine (G+C) as determined by the thermal denaturation (T<sub>m</sub>) method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology of <i>P. ferrugineum</i> IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> to representative strains of other genera of hyphal, budding bacteria are less than 7% (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>P. ferrugineum</i> Aristovskaya 1961.</s></p></content></protolog>