<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2989_nm.6487" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6487" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6487" rank="species">Rhodococcus luteus</organism><reference id="rid.2989"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nesterenko</surname><given-names>O.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogina</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasumova</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kvasnikov</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Batrakov</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus luteus nom. nov. and Rhodococcus maris nom. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-1</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus luteus</i> nom. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Forty-nine of the isolates were placed in group I, and the following description is based on 32 of these strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology of group I bacteria.</s><s>Smears of cultures grown on GA and NA for 16 to 24 h showed straight or slightly curved rods (0.6 to 1.0 μm by 3.0 to 6.0 μm) arranged in an angular or parallel fashion.</s><s>Rods and branching filaments (15 to 16 μm) rarely occurred.</s><s>On WA, the 16- to 24-h-old cultures consisted, as a rule, of rods that were shorter than the cells grown on NA and GA (1.5 to 2.5 μm); many coccoid forms were also found.</s><s>The morphological transformation of cells during growth on agar slants depended on the composition of the medium.</s><s>Thus, the rod-shaped cells cultivated on WA generally transformed rapidly to the coccoid form.</s><s>However, on NA and GA the rods became shorter but ordinarily did not become coccoid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As shown by time-lapse microscopy, the rodshaped bacteria elongated and bent within 16 h of cultivation (Fig. 1); sometimes branches were formed.</s><s>During elongation, septa were formed, and 16 h later, filaments fragmented into rodshaped elements.</s><s>The latter then divided, as a rule, by snapping or bending and formed characteristic V forms.</s><s>In 48 h, the microcolony consisted of rods (2 to 4 μm in length) characteristically arranged in Vs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group I bacteria were gram-positive, were not (or rarely only partly) acid-fast, and were nonmotile; endospores were not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics of group I bacteria.</s><s>Growth on GA and WA slants was usually abundant, butyrous or mucoid, and intensely yellow; growth on NA slants was moderate or poor, butyrous, and deep yellow to pale orange; on Lowenstein-Jensen medium growth was abundant and yellow-orange.</s><s>Colonies on the surfaces of NA plates were flat, opaque, raised, glistening, and smooth; colonies that had raised centers and that were opaque and smooth or gently folded also occurred.</s><s>In nutrient broth, a membrane formed on the surface and the broth remained clear.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and chemotaxonomic characteristics of group I bacteria.</s><s>The results of the physiological tests are listed in Tables 3-5.</s><s>All of the strains actively oxidized glucose.</s><s>Catalase was produced.</s><s>Casein (91% of the strains were negative), cellulose, guanine, hypoxanthine (88%), starch, tyrosine, and xanthine were not attacked, but urea was.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40, 60, and 80 were hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, indole, phosphatase (94% of the strains were negative), and p-nitrophenoloxidase were not produced; NH<sub>3</sub> was produced from peptone.</s><s>No growth occurred with acetamide or benzamide as a sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>Benzoate, oxalate, and tartrate were not utilized.</s><s>Acetate, γ-aminobutyrate, butyrate (94% of the strains were positive), <i>cis</i>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, α-ketoglutarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, and succinate were utilized.</s><s>Acid was produced from arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, sucrose, and xylose (87% of the strains were positive).</s><s>No acid was produced from adonitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, inositol, lactose, maltose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose (97% of the strains were negative), rhamnose, or salicin.</s><s>Growth occurred in the presence of 5 and 7% NaCl and of C<sub>9</sub> to C<sub>17</sub>, C<sub>19</sub>, and C<sub>23</sub> n-alkanes.</s><s>No growth occurred with methane, ethane, or C<sub>8</sub> <i>n</i>-alkane.</s><s>No growth occurred at 45°C.</s><s>Nitrate was reduced to nitrite (85% of the strains were negative).</s><s>Litmus milk became alkaline (91% of the strains were positive).</s><s>Properties such as the liquefaction of gelatin, the production of H<sub>2</sub>S, and growth in the presence of C<sub>3</sub>, C<sub>6</sub>, and C<sub>7</sub> <i>n</i>-alkanes were quite variable within the group (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains contained <i>meso</i>-DAP, arabinose, and galactose in their cells as well as lipid LCNA that on plates with silica gel moved similarly to that from <i>Rhodococcus</i> sp. strain NCTC 576.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of strain 385 was 64.1 mol% by thermal denaturation.</s><s>Fatty acid analysis of stationary-phase cells of strain 385 revealed that the main acids were (percentage of total detected): C<sub>14:0</sub> (12%), C<sub>16:1</sub> (12%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (20%), C<sub>18:1</sub> (22%), and 10CH<sub>3</sub>C<sub>18</sub> (13%).</s><s>Strain 385 contained, as the major component, menaquinone having eight isoprene units with one hydrogenated double-bond, MK-8(H,); small amounts of MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and traces of MK-8 were detected as well.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of the following characteristics, we classify these organisms as members of the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i> in the family <i>Nocardiaceae</i> (9, 11, 28): gram-positive, nonmotile, do not form endospores, aerobic, form a primary mycelium that soon fragments into rod-shaped elements, produce soft colonies without aerial hyphae, have a cell wall of chemotype IV, have a lipid LCN-A of the <i>Rhodococcus</i> type, have a guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of 64.1 mol%, have fatty acids containing a high proportion of tuberculostearic acid (10CH<sub>3</sub>C<sub>18</sub>), straight-chain, and unsaturated acids, and have menaquinone MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) as the major isoprenolog.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We compared the properties of group I bacteria with those of eight type strains and two reference strains of 10 established <i>Rhodococcus</i> species (Table 6) and concluded that the members of group I should be classified as a distinct species of <i>Rhodococcus</i>.</s><s>As to selecting a name for these organisms, we should like to point out the following.</s><s>The characters of the bacteria of group I correspond to the description of "<i>M. luteum</i>" given by Söhngen (39) and later supplemented by Krasil'nikov (25).</s><s>In Söhngen’s report (39) we found nothing about the strains on which the author based his original description of "<i>M. luteum</i>," and a type or neotype strain of "<i>M. luteum</i>" has not been officially established (39, 40).</s><s>According to Gordon and Mihm (16) and Gordon (15), Söhngen's strain 587 of "<i>M. luteum</i>" from Kluyver agrees with the original description of "<i>M. luteum</i>" (39), and it is accepted by Gordon and Mihm as authentic for the species.</s><s>These authors (16) assigned this strain to "'<i>M.' rhodochrous</i>' ("<i>rhodochrous</i>" complex).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological, cultural, chemotaxonomic, and most of the physiological properties of group I bacteria are similar to those of the culture of "<i>M. luteum</i>" 587 studied in this work (Tables 3, 4, and 6).</s><s>However, in contrast to strain 587, our isolates did not utilize benzoate or oxalate but did utilize γ-aminobutyrate and did form acid from galactose and xylose (87% of the strains were positive) but did not form acid from maltose.</s><s>In contrast to the description of "<i>M. luteum</i>" by Krasil'nikov (25), group I bacteria did not peptonize milk.</s><s>Group I bacteria are also very closely related to "<i>M. luteum</i>" AUCNM B-868 (Tables 3-6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thus, "<i>M. luteum</i>" corresponding to the isolates of group I, must be considered as a species of <i>Rhodococcus</i> (16; our data).</s><s>However, "<i>M. luteum</i>" was not included on the Approved Lists (37), and hence it has no standing in nomenclature.</s><s>Furthermore, since we here regard "<i>M. luteum</i>" as a member of the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i>, it would serve no useful purpose to revive the name "<i>M. luteum</i>".</s><s>Consequently, we propose the name <i>Rhodococcus luteus</i> for the group I bacteria.</s><s>This name cannot be regarded as a new combination, and the organism cannot be regarded as a new species since it was already recognized as such by Söhngen in 1913.</s><s>We therefore regard <i>R. luteus</i> as a new name, realizing that this use of "nom. nov." will require an amendment of rule 34a of the Bacteriological Code to accommodate this and similar situations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain IMV 385 (= AUCNM A-594) is the type strain of <i>R. luteus</i>.</s><s>The characters of this strain are given in Table 6.</s><s>In general, the description of IMV 385 agrees with the original description of "<i>M. luteum</i>" (39).</s><s>However, in contrast to this description, but similar to strains AUCNM B-868 and 587 of "<i>M. luteum</i>", strain IMV 385 produces urease.</s><s>In contrast to "<i>M. luteum</i>" 587, strain IMV 385 decomposes hypoxanthine, does not reduce nitrate to nitrite, does not utilize benzoate or oxalate but utilizes γ-aminobutyrate, and produces acid from galactose and xylose but does not form acid from maltose.</s><s>The properties of strain IMV 385 are similar to those of <i>M. luteum</i> AUCNM B-868 except for its ability to decompose tyrosine (Table 6).</s></p></content></protolog>