<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3464_nm.3014" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3014" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3014" rank="species">Vibrio wodanis</organism><reference id="rid.3464"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lunder</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sørum</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holstad</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mowinckel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and genotypic characterization of Vibrio viscosus sp. nov. and Vibrio wodanis sp. nov. isolated from Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar) with 'winter ulcer'.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>427</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758846</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio wodanis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio wodanis</i> (wo.da'nis. M.L. gen. n. <i>wodanis</i> from Wodan, the Norse god of art, culture, war and the dead, because its closest relative, <i>Vibrio logei</i>, also a cold water vibrio, takes its name from another Norse God, Loge)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Conforms to the description of the family <i>Vibrionaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Vibrio</i> (Baumann &#x0026; Schubert, 1984).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short or elongated, nonspore-forming rods that are motile by means of multiple polar flagella when grown on solid or in liquid media.</s><s>Colonies on bovine blood agar containing 2% NaCl after 48 h incubation at 15 °Care round, opaque, yellow, non-swarming and non-luminescent.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Produce acid, but not gas from D-glucose aerobically and anaerobically.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4-25 °C, but not at 30 °C.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth, at 1-4%.</s><s>A majority of strains produce indole.</s><s>Positive methyl red reaction; negative Voges-Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Negative tests for lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase and ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>A majority of the strains hydrolyse DNA.</s><s>A minority of strains hydrolyse alginate, lecithin, urea and aesculin.</s><s>Casein is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from dextrin, D-mannose, D-galactose and trehalose, but not from L-arabinose, cellobiose, inositol, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin nor D-xylose.Amajority of strains produce acid from glycerol and sucrose, and a minority of strains produce acid from D-mannitol and D-sorbitol.</s><s>The enzymes alkaline phosphatase, caprylate esterase and leucine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Butyrate esterase,valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and acetyl β-glucosaminidase are produced by the majority of the strains.</s><s>Myristate lipase is produced by one of the strains only.</s><s>Chymotrypsinase, trypsinase, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucoronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase were not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (O/129 vibriostatic agent), ampicillin, sulphamethizol, oxytetracycline and oxolinic acid, and resistant to penicillin.</s><s>The majority of strains (94%) are haemolytic when grown on bovine blood agar containing 2% NaCl.</s><s>Isolated from the lesions of Atlantic salmon with the ulcerative skin disease called winter ulcer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain of <i>Vibrio wodanis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>V. wodanis</i> is NVI 88/441<sup>T</sup>, isolated in 1988 in Norway from an Atlantic salmon with winter ulcer.</s><s>It is housed in the bacterial culture collection of the National Veterinary Institute, Oslo, Norway.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain is as given for the species, except as follows.</s><s>Hydrolysis of DNA, but not alginate, lecithin, urea and aesculin, production of indole, oxidative production of acid from glycerol and sucrose, but not from D-mannitol and D-sorbitol.</s><s>The type strain produces valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and acetyl β-glucosaminidase, but not butyrate esterase or myristate lipase.</s><s>The type strain haemolyses bovine red blood cells.</s><s>The G+­C content is 40±0 mol%.</s><s>This strain has been deposited at the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria (Aberdeen, UK) as NCIMB 13582<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>