<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8728_nm.13490" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13490" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13490" rank="species">Nocardiopsis quinghaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.8728"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis quinghaiensis sp. nov., isolated from saline soil in China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>699</fpage><lpage>705</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65441-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319481</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardiopsis quinghaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardiopsis quinghaiensis</em> (quing.hai.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>quinghaiensis</em> pertaining to Qinghai, a province of China in which the sample was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, obligately aerobic, non-motile, catalase-positive nocardioform actinomycete that forms white aerial mycelium.</s><s>The colour of the substrate mycelium is white to pale yellow.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Substrate hyphae are well developed and fragment with age.</s><s>Long spore chains are borne on aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spores are rod-shaped, smooth and non-motile.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs on marine agar 2216 and Czapek agar with 3 % (w/v) NaCl at 28 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>The temperature, pH and NaCl concentration ranges for growth are 10–37 °C, pH 6.0–8.0 and 0–10 %.</s><s>Positive in tests for hydrolysis of casein, chitin, starch, Tween 20 and Tween 80, but negative for hydrolysis of cellulose and gelatin.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, melanin and urease are not produced.</s><s>l-Arabinose, cellobiose, citrate, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, starch and trehalose are used as sole carbon and energy sources, whereas acetate, adonitol, d-galactose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, d-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, d-xylitol and d-xylose cannot be used for growth.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-asparagine, l-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-methionine, l-proline, l-threonine and l-tyrosine can be utilized as sole nitrogen sources, whereas adenine, l-arginine, l-cystine, glutamic acid, l-lysine, phenylalanine, l-tryptophan and l-valine cannot.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and no diagnostic sugars.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10 (29.7 %), MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>) (23.3 %), MK-11(H<sub>2</sub>) (17.7 %), MK-11 (15.2 %) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) (5.2 %).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (30.0 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (14.6 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (10.0 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (5.9 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (4.6 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 28A4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44739<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 4.3494<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of saline soil collected from the Qaidam Basin, Qinghai Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>