<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9062_nm.14347" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14347" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14347" rank="species">Mycoplasma leachii</organism><reference id="rid.9062"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Manso-Silván</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vilei</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sachse</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Djordjevic</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thiaucourt</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma leachii sp. nov. as a new species designation for Mycoplasma sp. bovine group 7 of Leach, and reclassification of Mycoplasma mycoides subsp. mycoides LC as a serovar of Mycoplasma mycoides subsp. capri.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1353</fpage><lpage>1358</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005546-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycoplasma leachii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycoplasma leachii</em> (lea′chi.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>leachii</em> of Leach, named in honour of Dr R. H. Leach, who first characterized this taxon).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on data obtained from previous reports (Abu-Groun <em>et al.</em>, 1994; Cottew <em>et al.</em>, 1987; Leach, 1967).</s><s>Non-spiral, non-motile, pleomorphic cells that lack a cell wall, are bounded by a single plasma membrane and pass through 0.45 μm pore-size membranes.</s><s>As a facultative anaerobe, it grows rapidly, producing heavily turbid cultures and relatively large colonies with characteristic fried-egg morphology, which measure about 2 mm in diameter on suitable solid media such as Hayflick medium (Hayflick, 1965).</s><s>It does not produce films or spots, nor does it form filaments.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C; it may grow at 28 °C, but not at 22 °C.</s><s>Susceptible to digitonin, requires sterols for growth, digests casein, liquefies inspissated serum and produces haemolysis on horse blood agar.</s><s>Ferments glucose, but does not metabolize arginine or urea.</s><s>Can be distinguished from other members of the <em>M. mycoides</em> cluster by a high rate of trehalose metabolism, coupled to an inability to oxidize mannose and glucosamine at concentrations &#x003C;50 μM.</s><s>Members of this species produce strong serological cross-reactivity with <em>M. capricolum</em> subsp. <em>capripneumoniae</em> and limited reactivity with strains of <em>M. capricolum</em> subsp. <em>capricolum</em>, and share antigens with <em>M. mycoides</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content was estimated to be 25.4 mol% (Askaa <em>et al.</em>, 1978; Christiansen &#x0026; Erno, 1982).</s><s>Associated mainly with mastitis, polyarthritis and abortion in dairy cattle, although it may also be found in healthy cattle, as well as in small ruminant hosts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain PG50<sup>T</sup>, previously known as N29<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 10133<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21131<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in Australia in 1963 from an arthritic joint of a calf.</s></p></content></protolog>