<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12171_nm.20164" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20164" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20164" rank="species">Camelimonas lactis</organism><reference id="rid.12171"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scholz</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Langer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wernery</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wernery</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Camelimonas lactis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated
from the milk of camels</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2382</fpage><lpage>2386</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017806-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19933583</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Camelimonas lactis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Camelimonas</em> <em>lactis</em> (lac′tis. L. gen. n. <em>lactis</em> from milk, referring to milk as the isolation source of the first reported strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell and colony morphology and growth characteristics are as given in the genus description.</s><s>Growth is detected on TSA at 15–37 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed in TS broth at pH 5.5–10.5.</s><s>Positive for urease.</s><s>In addition to Q-10, minor amounts of Q-8 and Q-9 and traces of Q-11 are detected.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids listed in the genus description, minor amounts of three unidentified polar lipids and a third aminolipid are detectable.</s><s>Putrescine is detectable in minor to moderate amounts.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon sources: d-glucose, acetate, propionate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, l-alanine and l-aspartate.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-mannose, maltose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>cis</em>- or <em>trans</em>-aconitate, putrescine, <em>β</em>-alanine, d-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate or 4-hydroxybenzate.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) and does not hydrolyse <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate or l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pNA.</s><s>Further details of carbon source utilization and hydrolysis of chromogenic substrates (including differentiating characters from <em>Chelatococcus</em> species) are indicated in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M 2040<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 58638<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7696<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from milk of a camel.</s><s>Other strains of this species are M 1973 and M 1878-SK2.</s></p></content></protolog>