<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7442_nm.7790" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7790" rank="family">Waddliaceae</organism><reference id="rid.7442"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rurangirwa</surname><given-names>F.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dilbeck</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Crawford</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McGuire</surname><given-names>T.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McElwain</surname><given-names>T.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Analysis of the 16S rRNA gene of micro-organism WSU 86-1044 from an aborted bovine foetus reveals that it is a member of the order Chlamydiales: proposal of Waddliaceae fam. nov., Waddlia chondrophila gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>577</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-577</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319478</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Waddliaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Waddliaceae</i> (Wadd'li.a'ce.ae M . L. fem. n. <i>Waddlia</i> the type genus of the family; -<i>aceae</i> ending to denote a family; M.L. fem. pl. <i>Waddliaceae</i> the <i>Waddlia</i> family)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Waddliaceae</i> currently includes the type genus, <i>Waddlia</i>.</s><s>The description of this family is identical at present to that of 'micro-organism WSU 86-1044' (Dilbeck et al., 1990; Kocan et al., 1990) which are obligate intracellular organisms resistant to penicillin.</s><s>They grow well in BT producing multiple cytoplasmic vacuoles and Gram-negative, periodic acid-Schiff negative and non-acid-fast inclusions.</s><s>The inclusions contain coccoid organisms ranging from 0.2 to 0.5 μm in size.</s><s>The BT infectivity is abolished by tetracycline and/or chloroform treatment.</s><s>The organism multiplies by binary fission and has two developmental forms: the dense form which is infective, and the reticulated form, usually associated with mitochondria, which undergoes binary fission.</s><s>These organisms do not react with antisera used for typing chlamydiae or rickettsiae.</s><s>The 16s rDNA of the <i>Waddliaceae</i> strains are &#x003E;90% similar to ribosomal genes in WSU 86-1044<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The family <i>Waddliaceae</i> belongs to the order <i>Chlamydiales</i> and is a sister taxon of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> because the ribosomal genes are 80-90% similar to ribosomal genes in the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>.</s><s>Phylogenetic analyses of the <i>Waddliaceae</i> 16s rDNA sequence is presented here.</s><s>At present this family comprises a single genus, the type genus <i>Waddlia</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>