<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6439_nm.12084" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12084" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5795" rank="subspecies">Actinomyces neuii neuii</organism><reference id="rid.6439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stubbs</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>von Graevenitz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of human-derived CDC group 1 coryneform bacteria and CDC group 1-like coryneform bacteria to the genus Actinomyces as Actinomyces neuii subsp. neuii sp. nov., subsp. nov., and Actinomyces neuii subsp. anitratus subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>167</fpage><lpage>171</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-167</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123558</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces neuii</i> subsp. <i>neuii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces neuii</i> subsp. <i>neuii</i> (neu'.ii. N. L. gen. n. <i>neuii</i>, of Neu, named to honor Harold Neu, an authority in antimicrobial chemotherapy and infectious diseases)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description of morphological and physiological features is based on a study of 17 strains (references 7 and 12 and unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and predominantly diphtheroidal, but coccobacilli may occur; the rods are mainly arranged in clusters or V or Y forms.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile and non-spore forming.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex, opaque, more white than creamy in color, and with entire edges.</s><s>Colony sizes range from 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation in 5% CO<sub>2</sub> on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Alphα-hemolysis is observed for most strains on sheep blood agar and for all strains on human blood agar.</s><s>Cells are catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-arabitol, erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, 5-ketogluconate, D-glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, D-lyxose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from N-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, L-arabitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, D-fucose, L-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glycogen, inulin, α-methyl-D-mannoside, D-tagatose, and xylitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabinose, 2-ketogluconate, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-glucitol, L-sorbose, and L-xylose.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and pyrazinamidase are positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, β-glucuronidase, and β-glucosidase are negative.</s><s>Esculin, urea and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated fatty acids are mainly palmitic and stearic acids.</s><s>Oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>DNA base composition is 55 to 58 mol% G+C (midpoint temperature).</s><s>The strains are isolated mainly from abscesses in association with mixed anaerobic flora as well as from human blood cultures.</s><s>The type strain 97/90 has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung für Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, Germany, under no. DSM 8576.</s><s>Strain 97/90<sup>T</sup> has the characteristics described for the species, except that, in the variable carbohydrate fermentation tests, only gentiobiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, and xylitol are positive.</s><s>The G+C content of strain 97/9O<sup>T</sup>'s DNA is 55 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>