<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6703_nm.5875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5875" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5875" rank="species">Arthrobacter sulfonivorans</organism><reference id="rid.6703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Borodina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward-Rainey</surname><given-names>N.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enzymes of dimethylsulfone metabolism and the phylogenetic characterization of the facultative methylotrophs Arthrobacter sulfonivorans sp. nov., Arthrobacter methylotrophus sp. nov., and Hyphomicrobium sulfonivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>177</volume><fpage>173</fpage><lpage>183</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00203-001-0373-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11807567</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter sulfonivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter sulfonivorans</i> (sul.fo.ni.vo'rans. M.L. prefix <i>sulfoni</i> from the sulfone group, L. v. <i>vorare</i> devour, M.L. adj. <i>sulfonivorans</i> sulfone-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical, 0.7 μm in diameter.</s><s>Gram-positive, forming clumps and chains in liquid culture; motile; spores or capsules not seen; catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Grows heterotrophically and aerobically on glucose, fructose, sucrose, galactose, acetate, ethanol, pyruvate, malate, succinate, citrate, serine, alanine, taurine, diethylsulfone, and yeast extract.</s><s>Grows aerobically on methylated sulfur compounds (dimethylsulfone, dimethylsulfoxide, dimethylsulfide), methanol, methylamine and dimethylamine.</s><s>Methylotrophic growth with dimethylsulfone uses the ribulose monophosphate cycle for formaldehyde assimilation.</s><s>Does not grow with trimethylamine or alkanesulfonates (methane-, propane-, butane-, pentaneand hexane-sulfonate), or autotrophically on inorganic sulfur compounds.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Growth on dimethylsulfone occurs optimally at pH 7.3–7.4 and at 20–25°C.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–30°C with no growth at 37 or 44°C.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, nitrate and methylamine are used as nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1.5% or 2.5% (w/v) NaCl, but not with 5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>On dimethylsulfoneagar medium, produces creamy-yellow, circular-umbonate colonies, 0.5–0.7 mm in diameter.</s><s>The principal isoprenoid quinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>), with smaller amounts of MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-9, MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK11(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The principal cellular fatty acid is 13-methylpentadecanoic acid, with 14-methylpentadecanoic acid, 15-methylhexadecanoic acid and 15-methylheptadecanoic acid also present.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains lysine as the diagnostic diamino acid, as well as alanine, glutamic acid, threonine and serine; peptidoglycan type (L-Lys–L-Ser–L-Thr–L-Ala) is A11.23.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61 mol%.</s><s>As determined by 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis the organism is closely related to other members of the genus.</s><s>The type strain is strain ALL, which was isolated from soil from the root ball of <i>Allium aflatunense</i> and is deposited at the American Type Culture Collection under the accession number ATCC BAA-112, and at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as DSM 14002.</s><s>The GenBank accession number for its 16S rRNA gene sequence is AF235091.</s></p></content></protolog>