<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1242_nm.146" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.146" rank="genus">Methanococcus</organism><reference id="rid.1242"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuhn</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of the type species of the genus Methanococcus to the genus Methanosarcina naming it Methanosarcina mazei (Barker 1936) comb. nov. et emend. and conservation of the genus Methanococcus (Approved List 1980) with Methanococcus vannielii (Approved List 1980) as the type species: Request for an Opinion.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>263</fpage><lpage>265</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-263</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of genus <i>Methanococcus</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanococcus</i> (Me.tha.no.coc'cus. N.L. n. <i>methanum</i> methane; N.L. n. <i>coccus</i> spherical cell; N.L. masc. n. <i>Methanococcus</i> methane coccus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are fragile, regular to irregular cocci that are 0.5 to 5 μm in diameter and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cells are highly motile (flagella may be inserted in clusters) and gram negative.</s><s>There is a single layer of protein subunits external to the plasma membrane.</s><s>Muramic acid not detected.</s><s>Ether-linked polyisoprenoid (branched) chain lipids are the predominant lipid components.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Very strict anaerobes.</s><s>Energy for growth is obtained by oxidation of H<sub>2</sub> or formate with reduction of CO<sub>2</sub> to CH<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Cells contain coenzyme M and coenzyme F<sub>420</sub>, Carbohydrates, proteinaceous material, and organic compounds other than formate are not used as energy sources.</s><s>Yeast extract is stimulatory, and Se and W may be stimulatory for growth.</s><s>May require 1.2 to 4.8% NaCl.</s><s>May be osmotically fragile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal growth temperature is between 32 and 40°C; the optimal pH varies with species from pH 6.7 to 9.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid base composition is 31 mol% guanine plus cytosine (determined for <i>Methanococcus voltae</i> DSM 153<sup>T</sup> and <i>Methanococcus vannielii</i> DSM 1224<sup>T</sup>), as determined by the buoyant density method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Methanococcus vannielii</i> Stadtman and Barker 1951, 269 (Approved Lists 1980).</s></p></content></protolog>