<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6320_nm.11349" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11349" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11349" rank="species">Halotalea alkalilenta</organism><reference id="rid.6320"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ntougias</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zervakis</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fasseas</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halotalea alkalilenta gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel osmotolerant and alkalitolerant bacterium from alkaline olive mill wastes, and emended description of the family Halomonadaceae Franzmann et al. 1989, emend. Dobson and Franzmann 1996</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1975</fpage><lpage>1983</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65078-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766858</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halotalea alkalilenta</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halotalea alkalilenta</em> (al.ka.li.len.ta. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> from Arabic <em>al qaliy</em>, soda ash; L. adj. <em>lentus</em> -<em>a</em> slow; N.L. n. <em>alkalilenta</em> slow in alkaline conditions/alkalitolerant).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict aerobe that tolerates up to 15 % w/v NaCl, with an optimum salt concentration of 0–3 % w/v NaCl.</s><s>Tolerates up to 45 and 60 % w/v (+)-d-glucose and maltose, respectively.</s><s>Grows at pH 5 to 11, with optimum pH at 7.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5 to 45 °C, with an optimum temperature of 32–37 °C.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Preferentially utilizes l-glutamine and l-proline (OD<sub>600</sub> &#x003E; 0.35; growth measured at 32 °C and pH 7; OD<sub>600</sub> values cited correspond to measurements taken after 72 h), followed by (+)-d-galactose, (+)-d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, protocatechuate, l-serine, succinate, sucrose and (+)-d-xylose (respective OD<sub>600</sub> values in the range 0.13–0.35).</s><s>Weak growth on acetate, citrate, (−)-d-fructose, maltose and sorbitol (respective OD<sub>600</sub> values in the range 0.05–0.12).</s><s>Grows on gallate (10<sup>6</sup> cells ml<sup>−1</sup> in the defined medium).</s><s>(+)-d-Cellobiose, cinnamate, l-cysteine, ethanol, ferrulate, glycine, l-histidine, inositol, l-isoleucine, lactose, l-lysine, l-methionine, phenol, syringate, l-tryptophan, vanillate and <em>o</em>-vanillin are not utilized.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production from l-cysteine, indole production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer.</s><s>Acid is produced from (−)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, (+)-d-glucose, maltose, (+)-d-mannose and melibiose, but it is not produced from (+)-l-arabinose, (+)-d-cellobiose, inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, sorbitol, sucrose or (+)-d-xylose.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 20, but does not hydrolyse casein, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 or urea.</s><s>Susceptible to (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) kanamycin, polymixin B, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, penicillin and trimethoprim.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AW-7<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17697<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7134<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from olive mill waste (alkaline alpeorujo) obtained from the premises of the Toplou Monastery in the region of Sitia, Crete, Greece.</s></p></content></protolog>