<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6418_nm.529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.529" rank="species">Thermus silvanus</organism><reference id="rid.6418"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tenreiro</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermus silvanus sp. nov. and Thermus chliarophilus sp. nov., two new species related to thermus ruber but with lower growth temperatures.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>633</fpage><lpage>639</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-633</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547281</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermus silvanus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermus silvanus</i> (sil. va' nus. L. adj. <i>silvanus</i>, in honor of Manuel T. Silva, a Portuguese microbiologist and immunologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. silvanus</i> strains form rod-shaped cells; cell length is variable, and the cells are 0.5 to 0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Long filaments are also present.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile, and spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on <i>Thermus</i> medium are orange-red pigmented and 0.5 to 1.2 mm in diameter after 72 h of growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 40 and 65°C in <i>Thermus</i> medium; the optimum growth temperature for strain VI-R2<sup>T</sup> is about 55°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 8.0 and 8.5; growth does not occur at pH 5.0 or 10.0.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:0 iso and 15:0 anteiso; 17:0 iso and 17:0 anteiso are present at low levels.</s><s>All strains are oxidase positive and catalase negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>α-Galactosidase negative and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>Casein, elastin, gelatin, hide powder azure, and starch are degraded.</s><s>Hydrolysis of fibrin is weak or negative.</s><s>Strain VI-R2<sup>T</sup> utilizes D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, D-xylose, maltose, lactose, D-melibiose, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, ribitol, pyruvate, L-glutamate, L-asparagine, L-serine, L-glutamine, and L-proline.</s><s>Strain VI-R2<sup>T</sup> does not utilize L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, D-cellobiose, Dtrehalose, D-raffinose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, galactitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, acetate, succinate, citrate, salicin, or acetamide.</s><s>The DNA of strain VI-R2<sup>T</sup> has a G+C content of 63.6 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from the hot spring at Vizela in northern Portugal.</s><s>Strain VI-R2<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 9946<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>