<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6082_nm.10171" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10171" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10171" rank="species">Chryseobacterium wanjuense</organism><reference id="rid.6082"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium wanjuense sp. nov., isolated from greenhouse soil in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1501</fpage><lpage>1504</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64179-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825619</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium wanjuense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium wanjuense</em> (wan.ju.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>wanjuense</em> pertaining to Wanju, a province in Korea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods (0.7–0.8×2.0–3.5 μm).</s><s>Yellow colonies with entire edges are formed on R2A agar plates.</s><s>Grows at 5–37 °C (optimum 28 °C), with 0–2 % NaCl (optimum 0–1 % NaCl) and at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A, trypticase soy agar and nutrient agar (Difco), but weak growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Degrades casein, gelatin, starch and tyrosine, and weakly degrades DNA.</s><s>Urea, chitin and carboxymethylcellulose are not degraded.</s><s>Utilizes malonate.</s><s>The type strain shows positive reactions for aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis and for β-galactosidase activity, but shows negative reactions for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation and for arginine dihydrolase and urease activities (API 20NE).</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, sodium acetate, glycogen and l-proline (API 20NE and API ID 32 GN).</s><s>Does not assimilate l-arabinose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, d-sucrose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, d-melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid (API 20NE and API ID 32 GN).</s><s>Activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, weak activity is observed for esterase (C4), cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin and α-glucosidase and no activity is observed for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Acids are produced only from d-glucose, d-mannose, d-trehalose and gentiobiose (API 50 CH).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-15 : 0, iso-17 : 0 3-OH, iso-17 : 1ω9<em>c</em> and summed feature 4.</s><s>Menaquinone MK-6 is the sole respiratory quinone.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 37.8 mol%.</s><s>The closest phylogenetic relative is <em>C. daecheongense</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R2A10-2<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11468<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17724<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from greenhouse soil cultivated with lettuce (<em>L. sativa</em> L.), collected from Wanju Province, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>