<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3339_nm.3147" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3147" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3147" rank="species">Edwardsiella ictaluri</organism><reference id="rid.3339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hawke</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McWhorter</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Edwardsiella ictaluri sp. nov., the causative agent of enteric septicemia of catfish.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>396</fpage><lpage>400</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-396</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Edwardsiella ictaluri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Edwardsiella ictaluri</i> (ic ta lu'ri. M.L. masc.n. <i>Ictalurus</i> generic name of the host catfish; M.L. gen.n. <i>ictaluri</i> of <i>Ictalurus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ESC bacterium is a gram-negative rod-shaped organism which measures 1.75 by 5.0 μm after 6 h of culture on solid media and 0.5 by 1.25 μm after 18 to 48 h of culture (A.</s><s>Scott, personal communication).</s><s>This organism is peritrichous; all strains tested except strain MS 78-1 were motile at 25°C but not at 37°C; strain MS 78-1 was not motile at either temperature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The biochemical reactions of the 13 strains of the ESC bacterium tested were almost identical (Table 2).</s><s>The optimum growth temperature for the ESC bacterium was between 25 and 30°C.</s><s>Growth was slow on blood agar plates; at 30°C this organism took 48 h to form typical colonies 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>All strains produced gas from glucose at 25°C but not at 37°C, and all strains were negative for indole production and H<sub>2</sub>S production from triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Six of the strains were positive for ornithine decarboxylase after 24 h, four strains were positive after 3 days, and three strains were positive after 5 days of incubation at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The tests which differentiated the ESC bacterium from <i>E. tarda</i> were motility at 37°C, the indole test, the Jordan tartrate test, gas production from glucose at 37°C, and H<sub>2</sub>S production from triple sugar iron agar; the ESC strains were negative for all of these characters (4,7,13).</s><s>The ESC bacterium was differentiated from <i>Yersinia ruckeri</i> (another enteric fish pathogen) by the delayed motility of the ESC bacterium at 25°C, by gas production from glucose at 25°C, and by negative tests for citrate utilization (Simmons), trehalose utilization, gelatin liquefaction (22°C), and tartrate utilization (Jordan) (8, 12).</s><s>The tests which have diagnostic significance for the ESC bacterium are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We detected no cross-agglutination in experiments with <i>E. tarda</i> antiserum and ESC bacterium antigen or with <i>E. tarda</i> antigen and ESC bacterium antiserum.</s><s>A titer of 160 was obtained with <i>E. tarda</i> antigen and the homologous antiserum, and a titer of 320 was obtained with ESC bacterium antigen and the homologous antiserum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the ESC bacterium DNA was 53 mol%, as determined by buoyant density centrifugation (Lewis, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The antimicrobial agent susceptibility of the ESC bacterium has been reported previously (9); this bacterium is susceptible to oxytetracycline, chlortetracycline, kanamycin, neomycin, nitrofurazone, and dihydrostreptomycin and resistant to erythromycin and sulfamerizine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 4 shows the DNA relatedness among the ESC strains and between the ESC bacterium and other members of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>Five strains of the ESC bacterium were 80% or more related to strain 1976-78 (GA 77-52) in 60°C reactions.</s><s>There was no evidence of divergence within related sequences, as judged by the absence of decreased thermal stability within related DNA sequences.</s><s>The species level relatedness among the ESC strains was evident from the more than 80% relatedness observed in the 75°C reactions, in which only very closely related DNA sequences could form duplexes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The relatedness of the ESC bacterium to species of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> is shown in Table 4.</s><s>This bacterium is most closely related to <i>E. tarda</i> (56 to 62% in 60°C reactions).</s><s>In these react,ions the percent divergence was 12 to 14.5%, and relatedness fell to about 30% in 75°C reactions, leaving no doubt that the ESC bacterium and <i>E. tarda</i> are separate species.</s><s>The relatedness of the ESC bacterium to species of <i>Escherichia</i>, <i>Shigella</i>, <i>Salmonella</i>, <i>Klebsiella</i>, <i>Enterobacter</i>, <i>Erwinia</i>,<i> Serratia</i>, <i>Hafnia</i>, and <i>Morganella</i> (<i>Proteus morganii</i>) was generally between 25 and 3556, and its relatedness to <i>Proteus</i> and <i>Providencia</i> species was 6 to 11%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>These DNA relatedness data and the biochemical characteristics of the ESC bacterium are consistent with placing this organism in the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> as a new species.</s><s>The ESC bacterium is phenotypically and genetically most closely related to <i>E. tarda</i>.</s><s>Therefore, we propose the name <i>Edwardsiella ictaluri</i> sp. nov. (ic ta lu'ri.</s><s>M.L. masc.n. <i>Ictalurus</i> generic name of the host catfish; M.L. gen.n. <i>ictaluri</i> of <i>Ictalurus</i>) for the ESC bacterium.</s><s>The type strain of <i>E. ictaluri</i> is GA 77-52 (=CDC 1976-78 =ATCC 33202).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A comparison between <i>E. ictaluri</i> and “<i>Paracolo bactrum anguillimortiferum</i>” (not on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names [ 141) was not possible due to the lack of viable strains of the latter.</s><s>The data reported by Wakabayashi and Egusa (15) indicate that "<i>P. anguzllimortiferum</i>" may be more closely related to <i>E. tarda</i> than to <i>E. ictaluri</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>