<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11683_nm.19288" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19288" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19288" rank="species">Dactylosporangium darangshiense</organism><reference id="rid.11683"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dactylosporangium darangshiense sp. nov., isolated from rock soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1256</fpage><lpage>1260</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012856-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dactylosporangium darangshiense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dactylosporangium darangshiense</em> (da.rang.shi.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>darangshiense</em> pertaining to Darangshi, referring to Darangshi Oreum in Jeju, Republic of Korea, the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium is well-developed and orange–yellow in colour on ISP 2.</s><s>Globose bodies (1.0–1.1 μm in diameter) are formed directly from substrate mycelium.</s><s>Finger-shaped sporangia (0.6–0.9×1.7 μm) emerge directly from the vegetative mycelium and are arranged singly or in clusters.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not produced on any media tested.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30–37 °C (optimum 37 °C) and pH 6.1–8.1 (optimum pH 7.1).</s><s>Growth does not occur in the presence of 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but casein, DNA, CM-cellulose, gelatin, starch and urea are not.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and H<sub>2</sub>S production are not observed.</s><s>d-Arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextran, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, glycerol and d-mannitol are utilized as sole carbon sources, but d-galactose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-ribose, l-sorbose, adonitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, acetate, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, succinate and dl-tartrate are not.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DLS-44<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19560<sup>T</sup> =DSM 45260<sup>T</sup>), isolated from rock soil collected from the peak of Darangshi Oreum in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>