<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1233_nm.5251" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5251" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5251" rank="species">Staphylococcus gallinarum</organism><reference id="rid.1233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poutrel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus gallinarum and Staphylococcus caprae, two new species from animals.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>480</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus gallinarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus gallinarum</i> (gal. li. na' rum. L. fem. n. <i>gallina</i> hen; L. fem, gen. pl. n. <i>gallinarum of hens</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-positive cocci 0.5 to 1.8 μm in diameter (median, 1.1 μm) and occur singly, in pairs, or in small groups or chains composed of 3 to 10 cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Eleven strains produce remarkably large colonies with lobate or crenate edges.</s><s>Most well separated colonies are 10 to 15 mm in diameter on brain heart infusion agar (Oxoid) or 5 to 10 mm in diameter on tryptone soya agar (Oxoid) after 2 days of incubation.</s><s>However, growth is highly variable, with outgrowths measuring up to 40 mm at times.</s><s>Sometimes these lobed outgrowths differ in pigmentation from the parent colonies.</s><s>The colonies are opaque and flat and have dry surfaces.</s><s>Strain VIII<sub>53</sub> produces raised glistening colonies with flattened outgrowths.</s><s>The strains dissociate into a smaller colony type (colony diameter, 4 to 7 mm) after 2 days on brain heart infusion agar; these colonies have entire edges and smooth glistening surfaces.</s><s>This is most easily demonstrated with strains VIII<sub>1</sub> and P<sub>21</sub>.</s><s>Three strains (strain VIII<sub>38</sub>, VIII<sub>38</sub>, and P<sub>57</sub>) appeared on the primary isolation plates only as the smaller colony type, and they maintained this form during repeated subcultures.</s><s>Three strains (strains VIII<sub>41</sub>, VIII<sub>52</sub>, and P<sub>21</sub>) are not pigmented; the others are yellow or have a yellowish tint.</s><s>In nutrient broth uniform turbidity with small deposits is observed after overnight incubation.</s><s>The strains grow well at 25, 30, 37, and 42°C, but colonies are smaller after 24 or 48 h at 25°C than at 30, 37, or 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce class I fructose 1,6-diphosphate aldolases.</s><s>They are able to grow aerobically and anaerobically.</s><s>However, anaerobic colonies in semisolid thioglycolate medium are smaller than aerobic colonies.</s><s>The pH of a peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth is lowered from 6.8 to 4.6 to 5.1 after 2 days of anaerobic growth.</s><s>Predominantly L-lactic acid is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains contain peptidoglycan of type L-Lys-Gly<sub>4-5</sub>, L-Ser<sub>0.7-1.0</sub>.</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acids of the strains are composed of glycerol, glucose, and small amounts of N-acetylglucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are resistant to novobiocin (MIC, 4 to 32 μg/ml) and lysozyme (MIC, &#x003E;800 μg/ml).</s><s>The lysostaphin MICs are 34 to 64 μg/ml.</s><s>The levels of susceptibility to the following antibiotics are higher than the levels normally found for <i>S . aureus</i>: penicillin G (MIC, 0.1 to 0.5 μg/ml), cloxacillin (MIC, 1 to 2 μg/ml), erythromycin (MIC for most strains, 0.5 to 1 μg/ml; the exceptions are strains VIII<sub>1</sub>, VIII<sub>43</sub>, VIII<sub>49</sub>, and P<sub>53</sub>, which have MICs of &#x003E;128 μg/ml), and lincomycin (MIC for all strains except one, 2 to 8 μg/ml; strain VIII<sub>1</sub> has a lincomycin MIC of &#x003E;128 μg/ml).</s><s>All strains are susceptible to neomycin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.25 μg/ml), sulfonamides (sodium sulfamethoxazole MIC, 4 to 32 μg/ml), and chloramphenicol (MIC, 4 to 16 μg/ml).</s><s>Most strains show acquired resistance to tetracyclines (tetracycline hydrocholoride MIC, 32 to 128 μg/ml).</s><s>Only strains P<sub>9</sub> and P P<sub>21</sub> are susceptible to tetracycline (MIC, 0.5 μg/ml).</s><s>Strains VIII<sub>1</sub> and VIII<sub>49</sub> are resistant to streptomycin (MIC, &#x003E;128 μg/ml); the other strains are inhibited at streptomycin concentrations of 2 to 4 μg/ml.</s><s>The levels of susceptibility to nitrofurazolidone are bimodally distributed; the furazolidone MICs for the more susceptible strains are 1 to 2 μg/ml, whereas strains VIII<sub>1</sub>, VIII<sub>32</sub>, VIII<sub>41</sub>, VIII<sub>43</sub>, VIII<sub>45</sub>, VIII<sub>49</sub>, and P<sub>21</sub> are only inhibited at a concentration of 8 μg/ml.</s><s>This low level of resistance to nitrofurans has not been reported previously in <i>Staphylococcus</i> strains.</s><s>This resistance level is lower than that for <i>Micrococcus</i> strains, and thus nitrofuran susceptibility still can be used to distinguish these strains from <i>Micrococcus</i> species, as has been proposed by Curry and Borovian and von Rheinbaben and Hadlok.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization studies indicated that the strains of <i>S . gallinarum</i> are closely related, whereas the levels of DNA homology with other staphylococci are rather low (10 to 25%); nevertheless, these levels are significantly higher than the levels obtained when staphylococci and <i>Streptococcus faecalis</i> are compared.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. gallinarum</i> is easily differentiated from the novobiocin-resistant organisms <i>Staphylococcus saprophyticus</i>, <i>Staphylococcus cohnii</i>, and <i>Staphylococcus xylosus</i> by its wide range of positive carbohydrate reactions.</s><s>None of these other species produces acid from fucose, cellobiose, melezitose, and raffinose, but <i>S. gallinarum</i> does.</s><s>Also, the very irregular colony morphology with strongly crenate edges is a useful diagnostic trait; this characteristic is found only in <i>S . gallinarum</i> and certain <i>S. xylosus</i> strains.</s><s>In particular, strains which produce only colonies with entire edges can be confused with <i>Staphylococcus sciuri</i> subsp. <i>lentus</i>.</s><s>The ability of these organisms to grow anaerobically in thioglycolate shake cultures, their positive urease reactions, and their negative oxidase reactions are useful distinguishing characteristics.</s><s>However, it is important to use the highly sensitive oxidase test described by Faller and Schleifer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain VIII<sub>1</sub> (= CCM 3572) is the type strain of <i>S . gallinarum</i>.</s><s>This strain was isolated from the nares of a chicken and a description of it is given below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain VIII<sub>1</sub>, cells are gram-positive cocci and are usually about 1 μm in diameter.</s><s>In broth these cells occur singly, in pairs, or in small groups or chains; the cells are nonmotile and nonsporeforming.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two colony forms occur; most colonies have dry surfaces and very pronounced crenate edges.</s><s>Well-separated colonies are 5 to 15 mm in diameter after 2 days, but larger outgrowths may occur.</s><s>Other colonies are smaller and have glistening surfaces and entire edges.</s><s>A yellowish or creamy pigment is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth cultures are uniformly turbid, with a small deposit.</s><s>Growth at 25°C is slower than growth at 30, 37, and 42°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>In addition to the negative and positive biochemical characteristics listed in Table 1, the following reactions occur: weakly hemolytic in sheep blood agar after 2 days of incubation; proteolytic on casein; urease positive; and acid produced from amygdalin, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, salicin, and glucitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from xylitol and rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The antibiotic susceptibilities of strain VIII<sup>T</sup> are as follows: resistant to novobiocin, tetracycline hydrochloride, streptomycin, erythromycin, and lincomycin; low-level resistance to penicillin G, cloxacillin, and furazolidone; and susceptible to neomycin, sulfamethoxazole , and chloramphenicol.</s><s>Erythromycin resistance, lincomycin resistance, tetracycline resistance, streptomycin resistance, and furazolidone resistance are probably due to acquired resistance determinants and are not representative for</s></p><p class="description"><s>the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lysostaphin MIC: 64 μg/ml.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Class I fructose 1,6-diphosphate aldolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type: L-Lys-Gly<sub>4-5</sub>, L-Ser<sub>0.8</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Composition of cell wall teichoic acid: glycerol, glucose, and small amounts of N-acetylglucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of DNA: 34.5 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>