<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.797" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.797" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.797" rank="species">Chlorobaculum thiosulfatiphilum</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chlorobaculum thiosulfatiphilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chlorobaculum thiosulfatiphilum</em> (thi.o.sul.fa.ti′phi.lum. N.L. n. <em>thiosulfas, -atis</em> thiosulfate; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. n. <em>thiosulfatiphilum</em> thiosulfate-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·7–1·1 μm wide, non-motile and occur as single cells.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is green, and photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>c</em> with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide, sulfur and thiosulfate as photosynthetic electron donors; molecular hydrogen also may be used.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria without a requirement for sodium chloride.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> may be required for growth.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 249<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is Y08102.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two strains known as <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> subsp. <em>thiosulfatophilum</em>, DSM 249 and strain 1430, belong to group 4 of the green sulfur bacteria according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>They have a significantly higher DNA G+C content (58·1 mol%) than <em>Chlorobium limicola</em>, and cannot be considered to be subspecies of this species.</s><s>They are considered to be strains of <em>Chlorobaculum thiosulfatiphilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>