<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7497_nm.7461" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7461" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7461" rank="species">Microbispora corallina</organism><reference id="rid.7497"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kitpreechavanich</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbispora corallina sp. nov., a new species of the genus Microbispora isolated from Thai soil</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1761</fpage><lpage>1767</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1761</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbispora corallina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbispora corallina</i> (co.ral'li.na. L. fem. adj. <i>corallina</i> coral-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelia are coral pink to reddish brown and aerial mycelia are pink on most agar media.</s><s>Either no pigments or faint, yellow, soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Spores arranged in longitudinal pairs are formed on short sporophores alternately branched from aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spores are oval and have smooth surfaces.</s><s>Decomposes casein and aesculin, but not adenine, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, keratin, testosterone, L-tyrosine, xanthine, xylan or DNA.</s><s>Utilizes amygdalin, L-arabinose, arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, methyl α-D-glucoside, D-ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, D-trehalose and D-xylose as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, D-arabitol, dulcitol, iso-erythritol, inulin, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose or xylitol.</s><s>Utilizes fumaric acid and succinic acid, but not benzoic acid, citric acid, mucic acid, oxalic acid or L-tartaric acid.</s><s>Negative for iodinin production.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl.</s><s>Requires thiamine for growth.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 71 to 72 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain DF-32<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10267<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>