<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.466_nm.8087" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8087" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8087" rank="species">Flavobacterium gelidilacus</organism><reference id="rid.466"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium gelidilacus sp. nov., isolated from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1241</fpage><lpage>1245</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02583-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130001</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium gelidilacus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium gelidilacus</em> (ge.li.di.la′cus. L. adj. <em>gelidus</em> ice-cold; L. n. <em>lacus</em> lake; N.L. gen. n. <em>gelidilacus</em> of the ice-cold lake, referring to the isolation source, microbial mats in Antarctic lakes).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, &#x003C;1×2–4 μm, that exhibit gliding motility on nutrient-poor medium (R2A), except for strains LMG 21477<sup>T</sup> and LMG 21619, for which no gliding motility is detected.</s><s>Strains grow at 5–25 °C, with optimal growth at 20 °C; no growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Yellow to orange, convex, translucent colonies, 1–4 mm in diameter and with entire margins, are formed on R2A plates after 6 days at 20 °C.</s><s>Colonies on Anacker &#x0026; Ordal's agar are flat, round with entire margins and 0·5–1 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on TSA, nutrient agar and marine agar, and colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Degrades casein and starch.</s><s>Gelatinase activity is observed, except in the case of strain LMG 21619.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>No growth is observed on glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin or arabinose.</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, aesculin, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, tyrosine and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed and no flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>There is no production of a brown diffusible pigment on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer reaction and tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains shows activity for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for cystine arylamidase, medium activity is found for acid phosphatase, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase and strong activity is found for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>No <em>β</em>-glucosidase or <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activity is detected, except for strain LMG 21621.</s><s>Different reactions are obtained for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>) and trypsin.</s><s>The cells contain the fatty acids 15 : 0 iso, 16 : 0 iso 3-OH, 15 : 1 iso, 15 : 0, 15 : 0 anteiso and 16 : 0 iso as the main constituents.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 1–5 % NaCl, but not 10 % NaCl, indicating that the strains are not halophilic but merely halotolerant.</s><s>The G+C content is 30·0–30·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21477<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15343<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Twenty-two strains were isolated from microbial mats from freshwater and saline lakes in eastern Antarctica (Table 1).</s></p></content></protolog>