<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8606_nm.13719" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13719" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13719" rank="species">Fulvibacter tottoriensis</organism><reference id="rid.8606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fulvibacter tottoriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from marine sediment.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1670</fpage><lpage>1674</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65554-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fulvibacter tottoriensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fulvibacter tottoriensis</em> (tot.to.ri.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>tottoriensis</em> pertaining to Tottori, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.7 μm wide and 5–14 μm long.</s><s>Three-day-old colonies on HSMA are yellowish brown in colour, circular with entire edges and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimally at 25–30 °C) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimally at pH 7.0–9.0).</s><s>Growth is not observed at 4, 40, 42 or 45 °C or at pH 5.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1–5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl, or with more than 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are degraded.</s><s>Agar, DNA, carrageenan, carboxymethylcellulose, cellulose (filter paper) and chitin are not degraded.</s><s>Weakly positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate and nitrite, production of indole from tryptophan, acidification of glucose and for arginine dihydrolase and urease activities.</s><s>Peptone, Casamino acids and glutamate are utilized as nitrogen sources but ammonium sulphate and sodium nitrate are not utilized.</s><s>No utilization or oxidation of carbon sources occurs in GN2 MicroPlates or API 50 CH strips, but l-glutamic acid, pyruvic acid, peptone and yeast extract are utilized with a conventional method.</s><s>Adonitol, d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, glycerol, l-aspartic acid, l-rhamnose, maltose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, raffinose and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid content is given in Table 2.</s><s>The G+C content of the chromosomal DNA is 35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MTT-39<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 102624<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22214<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.7058<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment from Tottori on the coast of the Sea of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>