<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.65_nm.10961" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10961" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.651" rank="species">Prochlorococcus marinus</organism><reference id="rid.65"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chisholm</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frankel</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goericke</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olson</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palenik</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Waterbury</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Westjohnsrud</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zettler</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prochlorococcus marinus nov. gen. nov. sp.: an oxyphototrophic marine prokaryote containing divinyl chlorophyll a and b.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>157</volume><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00245165</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prochlorococcus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prochlorococcus</i> (Pro.chloro.coc.cus. Gr. pref. <i>pro</i>, before (primitive); Gr. adj <i>chloros</i>, green; M.L. masc n. <i>coccus</i>, berry. Primitive green sphere.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The prokaryotic cells are spherical to rod shaped just prior to division, occur singly or in pairs and divide by transverse binary fission.</s><s>They possess a gram-negative cell wall and have peripheral photosynthetic thylakoids that are closely appressed to one another.</s><s>Phycobilisomes are absent.</s><s>They are oxygenic photoautotrophs that possess divinyl chlorophylls a and b as their principal photosynthetic pigments, and lack phycobiliproteins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of <i>Prochlorococcus marinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Prochlorococcus marinus</i> (ma.ri.nus. <i>marinus</i> L. adj., marine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.6 to 0.8 μm in diameter and 1.2 to 1.6 μm in length just prior to division.</s><s>In addition to divinyl chlorophylls a and b, <i>P. marinus</i> contains zeaxanthin, α-carotene, an unidentified carotenoid, and a chlorophyll c-like pigment possibly Mg 3,8-divinylpheoporphyrin a<sub>5</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. marinus</i> occurs at high cell concentrations in the euphoric zone of the open oceans.</s><s>In the temperate oceans its distribution and abundance follow seasonal patterns.</s><s>Two strains of <i>P. marinus</i> are in culture; both strains are clonal (derived from a single cell through serial dilution) but neither is bacteria-free.</s><s>The strains were isolated from the Sargasso Sea in May 1988 (28° 58.9' N, 64° 21.5' W, by B.</s><s>Palenik) and the Mediterranean Sea in Jan. 1989 (43° 12.15' N, 6° 52' E, by D.</s><s>Vaulot and F.</s><s>Partensky).</s><s>Both are grown in minimal media with a seawater base at light intensities of 60 μE m<sup>-2</sup> s<sup>-1</sup>, which is saturating for growth.</s><s>The strain from the Sargasso Sea grows optimally at 25 °C and fails to grow above 29 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Sargasso Sea strain (CCMP-1375) of <i>P. marinus</i> has been designated the type strain.</s><s>It, along with the Mediterranean strain (CCMP-1378), is deposited at the Center for the Culture of Marine Phytoplankton, Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences, West Boothbay Harbor, ME 04575, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>