<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.607_nm.8495" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8495" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8495" rank="species">Bacillus fordii</organism><reference id="rid.607"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pil</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herman</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus farraginis sp. nov., Bacillus fortis sp. nov. and Bacillus fordii sp. nov., isolated at dairy farms</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1355</fpage><lpage>1364</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63095-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280314</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus fordii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus fordii</em> (for′di.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>fordii</em> named after W. W. Ford, an American microbiologist working on aerobic spore-forming bacteria at the beginning of the twentieth century).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are long, straight, round-ended, motile, strictly aerobic, Gram-negative rods, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·6–0·8 μm and length 1·6–3·5 μm.</s><s>Spores are ellipsoidal and occur paracentrally or subterminally in, occasionally, slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies grown on nutrient agar at 30 °C for 3 days are cream coloured, raised, with entire margins and smooth glossy surfaces.</s><s>Their maximum diameter is 2 mm.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 and 45 °C and weak growth occurs at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 9 and some strains grow at pH 5.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and casein is not observed within 7 days of incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth on casein agar is coloured faint pink.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>All strains are unreactive in the API 20E and API 50CHB test kits.</s><s>In the Biotype100 kit using the Biotype 2 medium, all strains show very good production of biomass using malonate and l-tyrosine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Variable results with good production of biomass are obtained for l-histidine, 2-oxoglutarate, glutarate, dl-lactate, 5-aminovalerate and l-tryptophan.</s><s>All or most strains are capable of weak growth from the following carbon sources: aesculin, gentisate, protocatechuate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, d-glucosamine, dl-glycerate, quinate, ethanolamine, d-glucuronate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, hydroxyquinoline <em>β</em>-glucuronide and 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate.</s><s>Growth occurs seldom and weakly from the following substrates: adonitol, l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, benzoate, fumarate, d-galacturonate, d-gluconate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, histamine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, d-lyxose, d-malate, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, phenylacetate, propionate, putrescine, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-saccharate, l-sorbose, succinate, d-tagatose, l-tartrate, tricarballylate, trigonelline and d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are not used as sole carbon source: <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, d-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, d-arabitol, l-aspartate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, d-cellobiose, citrate, <em>m</em>-coumarate, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, l-glutamate, glycerol, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconate, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, l-malate, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 3-methyl d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, mucate, palatinose, 3-phenylpropionate, l-proline, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, sucrose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, d-tartrate, d-trehalose, tryptamine, d-turanose and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R-7190<sup>T</sup> (=MB 1878<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22080<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16014<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Where results are variable, the type strain uses the following substrates: aesculin, 5-aminovalerate, l-arabinose, benzoate, ethanolamine, d-galacturonate, gentisate, d-glucuronate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, histamine, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, 2-oxoglutarate, dl-lactate, d-lyxose, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, d-raffinose, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, tricarballylate, l-tryptophan and d-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 % of total cellular fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41·9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>