<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8409_nm.13261" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13261" rank="species">Caloramator australicus</organism><reference id="rid.8409"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ogg</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caloramator australicus sp. nov., a thermophilic, anaerobic bacterium from the Great Artesian Basin of Australia</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>95</fpage><lpage>101</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000802-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126731</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Caloramator australicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Caloramator australicus</em> (aus.tra′li.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>australicus</em> pertaining to Australia, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, slightly curved rods, 2.5–4.2×0.8–1.0 μm.</s><s>Gram reaction is positive.</s><s>Cells possess peritrichous flagella and exhibit roll and tumble motility.</s><s>No spores are observed.</s><s>Cells are heat resistant (95 °C for 30 min).</s><s>Growth occurs between 45 and 70 °C (optimum temperature 60 °C) and at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Grows on yeast extract but not tryptone as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Yeast extract but not tryptone is required for growth.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, fructose, galactose, xylose, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, mannose, cellobiose, cellulose, starch, amylopectin, xylan, peptone, tryptone, amyl media, threonine and pyruvate but not arabinose, ribose, lactose, CM-cellulose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, chitin, casein, Casamino acids, arginine, alanine, serine, glycine, glutamine, leucine, isoleucine, methionine, aspartate, formate, acetate, succinate, propionate, lactate, benzoate, glycerol, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub> or CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Fe(III), Mn(IV) and elemental sulfur serve as electron acceptors but not sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, nitrate or nitrite.</s><s>Fe(III) is reduced in the presence of yeast extract, tryptone, peptone, amyl media, threonine and glycerol but not rhamnose, chitin, xylan, pectin, starch, pyruvate, acetate, benzoate, lactate, propionate, succinate, inositol, ethanol, mannitol, arginine, glutamine, serine or H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Sensitive to chloramphenicol, streptomycin, tetracycline, penicillin and ampicillin.</s><s>Reduced growth in the presence of sodium azide.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 34±1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RC3<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 5601<sup>T</sup> =JCM 1508<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a microbial mat sample from the outflow of a Great Artesian Basin bore (the New Lorne bore) in Queensland, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>