<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10105_nm.15062" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15062" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15062" rank="species">Aliivibrio finisterrensis</organism><reference id="rid.10105"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beaz-Hidalgo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doce</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balboa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barja</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romalde</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aliivibrio finisterrensis sp. nov., isolated from Manila clam, Ruditapes philippinarum and emended description of the genus Aliivibrio</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>223</fpage><lpage>228</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010710-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648323</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aliivibrio finisterrensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aliivibrio finisterrensis</em> [fi.nis.ter.ren′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>finisterrensis</em> pertaining to Finisterra, literally the end of the world (at least for the Romans who named this place). Galicia was the western end of the ancient Roman world].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, motile and facultative anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies are round with smooth margins, translucent and non-swarming on MA plates.</s><s>Strains grow on TCBS agar producing colonies of size 1.0–1.5 mm after 24 h of incubation.</s><s>One strain (C 17.13) produces cream colonies on MA and yellow colonies on TCBS, the other strains produce green colonies.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative without gas production.</s><s>Strains reduce nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and ONPG tests are positive.</s><s>Sensitive to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 μg per disc) and resistant to ampicillin (10 μg per disc), and are able to grow at 4 °C but not at 35 °C nor at 0.5 or 8 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 1–3 % (w/v).</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>All strains are positive for arginine and lysine decarboxylase, urea and methyl red tests.</s><s>Tests for ornithine decarboxylase, indole, Voges–Proskauer and use of citrate are negative.</s><s>Strains do not hydrolyse starch, gelatin or alginate.</s><s>All strains are positive for DNase, Tween 80 and aesculin activities.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following compounds: glycerol, d-glucose, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin), gentiobiose and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Half of the strains produce acid from arbutin and melibiose.</s><s>Strain CMJ 11.1<sup>T</sup> and C 13.19 are positive for the production of acid from arbutin, type strain only also for melibiose, and strain C 17.13 for d-mannitol and sucrose.</s><s>None of the strains produce acid from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, starch, glycogen, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>API ZYM reaction tests were positive in all strains for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Strain C 17.13 also showed positive results for esterase (C4) and valine arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CMJ 11.1<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7228<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23869<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from clam <em>Ruditapes philippinarum</em> in the north-western coast of Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>