<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7030_nm.1478" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1478" rank="genus">Bosea</organism><reference id="rid.7030"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>La Scola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bosea eneae sp. nov., Bosea massiliensis sp. nov. and Bosea vestrisii sp. nov., isolated from hospital water supplies, and emendation of the genus Bosea (Das et al. 1996).</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02127-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656146</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Bosea</em> (Das <em>et al.</em> 1996)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bosea</em> (Bos′e.a. N.L. gen. n. <em>Bosea</em> of J. C. Bose, the founder of the Bose Institute, where the type species <em>Bosea thiooxidans</em> was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus are Gram-negative, but stain well with Gimenez stain, oxidase-positive, catalase-positive rods in the <em>α</em>-2 subgroup of the <em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Grow on BCYE agar, in NB and weakly on Columbia agar with 5 % sheep blood, but not in NB containing 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, mucoid, round and cream coloured.</s><s>Grow well at 25 and 37 °C.</s><s>Urease-positive and α-haemolytic on Columbia agar containing 5 % sheep blood and 0·2 % yeast extract.</s><s>Negative in assays for arginine dihydrolase activity, aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis, β-galactosidase activity and maltose assimilation, and in assays for acid production by fermentation or oxidation of substrates tested in the API 50CH system, especially d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose and sucrose.</s><s>Have high MIC values for penicillin and amoxicillin and low MIC values for doxycycline.</s><s>The most abundant fatty acid is <em>cis</em>-octadec-9-anoic acid (C<sub>18 : 1ω7<em>c</em></sub>).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 64·2–65 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Bosea thiooxidans.</em></s></p></content></protolog>