<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4257_nm.2795" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2795" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2795" rank="species">Psychrobacter pacificensis</organism><reference id="rid.4257"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Honda</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kitamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higashihara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of psychrophilic bacteria isolated from the Japan Trench, including a description of the deep-sea species Psychrobacter pacificensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>835</fpage><lpage>846</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758895</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Psychrobacter pacificensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Psychrobacter pacificensis</i> (pa.ci.fi.cen'sis. M.L. adj. <i>pacificensis</i> pertaining to the Pacific Ocean)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, nonpigmented, non-sporulating, oxidase-positive, catalase-positive coccobacilli 1.0-1.5 μm long and about 1 μm wide.</s><s>Strains produce many fimbriae as appendages, but no flagella.</s><s>Circular, convex, off-white colonies with a complete edge occur on agar plates containing polypeptone and yeast extract.</s><s>No fluorescent pigments form.</s><s>Seawater or NaCl at about 3% is required for optimal growth, with most strains not growing at 0 or 8% NaCl.</s><s>It takes 1-2 weeks to reach the stationary phase at 4 °C, but isolates give growth yields at 4 °C comparable to those at 20 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at about 25 °C, with the maximum growth temperature being 38 °C.</s><s>Acid is formed aerobically from glucose, xylose and arabinose.</s><s>Urease is positive, but phenylalanine deaminase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>The species is negative for the following biochemical tests : glucose fermentation, indole production, aesculin hydrolysis and gelatin and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Strains use L-histidine and DL-malate as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Some strains use acetate, L-alanine, 3- hydroxybutyrate, lactate, malonate and suberate, but none use <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, L-serine or <i>n</i>-valerate.</s><s>The major fatty acid is 18:1<i>ω</i>9<i>c</i> and Q8 is the major quinone.</s><s>DNA G­C content is 43±44 mol% as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The type strain is NIBH P2K6<sup>T</sup> (=IFO 16270<sup>T</sup>), isolated at 4 °C from 6000 m deep seawater in the Japan Trench off Hachijo Island, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>