<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5666_nm.9907" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9907" rank="genus">Krokinobacter</organism><reference id="rid.5666"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Krokinobacter gen. nov., with three novel species, in the family Flavobacteriaceae</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>323</fpage><lpage>328</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63841-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449433</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Krokinobacter</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Krokinobacter</em> (Kro.ki′no.bac.ter. Gr. adj. <em>krokinos</em> yellow; N.L. masc. n. <em>bacter</em> from Gr. n. <em>bakterion</em> rod; N.L. masc. n. <em>Krokinobacter</em> a yellow, rod-like bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic and flexirubin-negative rods 0·5–0·7 μm by 2·5–4·0 μm.</s><s>Carotenoid-type pigments present.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase and for degradation of gelatin, casein and DNA.</s><s>Negative for the following: degradation of agar, carrageenan, cellulose, chitin and starch, acid production from glucose, urease activity and nitrate reduction and denitrification.</s><s>Utilizes dextrin, cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, trehalose, sucrose, turanose, glycine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, proline, threonine, uridine and ornithine.</s><s>Cannot utilize adonitol, arabitol, erythritol, fucose, galactose, inositol, mannose, melibiose, psicose, rhamnose, sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvate, succinate, aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, galactonic acid lactone, galacturonic acid, gluconic acid, glucosaminic acid, glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, alanine, asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, histidine, leucine, phenylalanine, pyroglutamic acid, serine, carnitine, aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, aminoethanol, butanediol, glycerol, glycerol phosphate or glucose phosphate.</s><s>No growth occurs at 10 or 0 % NaCl.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, i-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 12-OH (summed feature A: fatty acids that could not be separated by GC).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is in the range 33–39 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Krokinobacter genikus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>