<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1425_nm.3980" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3980" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3980" rank="species">Clostridium orbiscindens</organism><reference id="rid.1425"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Popoff</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bokkenheuser</surname><given-names>V.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium orbiscindens sp. nov., a human intestinal bacterium capable of cleaving the flavonoid C-ring.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>357</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-355</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1883711</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium orbiscindens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium orbiscindens</i> (or. bi. scin' dens. N. L. adj. <i>orbiscindens</i>, ring cutting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in broth cultures are gram-variable, motile, peritrichous, sporeforming, straight rods that are 0.9 to 1.0 by 2 to 7 μm and occur singly or in pairs (Fig. 2).</s><s>Spores are round to oval, subterminal, 0.7 by 0.5 μm, and thermoresistant (80°C for 10 min).</s><s>Capsules are absent.</s><s>The organisms are strictly anaerobic but survive exposure to atmospheric air on sheep blood agar plates at 20°C for at least 24 h.</s><s>Good growth of all four strains occurs when they are incubated in brain heart infusion broth under anaerobic conditions (5% CO<sub>2</sub>, 95% N<sub>2</sub>) at 37°C for 2 days.</s><s>One of the four strains grows on bile agar.</s><s>Colonies on rabbit blood agar incubated anaerobically are 1 mm in diameter, circular, convex, slightly irregular, gray or white, shiny, smooth, and betahemolytic.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are slightly larger and are not hemolytic.</s><s>In brain heart infusion broth cultures produce distinct turbidity and sediment.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>The main specific enzymatic activity is C-ring cleavage of flavonoid molecules.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, glucose, glycogen, gum arabic, inositol, lactose, larch arabinogalactan, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, xylan, and xylose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of indole (one of four strains) and H<sub>2</sub>S (three of four strains) is variable.</s><s>Utilization of fumarate (two of four strains) and pyruvate (three of four strains) is variable.</s><s>Gelatin, meat, and casein are not digested.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase, and urease are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to cephalothin (30 U), kanamycin (1,000 U), and metronidazole (80 U); they are resistant to nalidixic acid (30 U), rifampin (15 U), and vancomycin (5 U).</s><s>Susceptibility to penicillin is variable (two of four strains are susceptible).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products of metabolism from peptone-yeast-glucose broth include large amounts of acetic acid and butyric acid and a small amount of propionic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 56 to 57 mol% (as determined by the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>All four strains administered intramuscularly to mice are apathogenic.</s><s>The outstanding characteristics of this species are the high G+C content, the lack of glycolytic activity, and the synthesis of a C-ring cleaving enzyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Type strain 265 (= ATCC 49531) has all of the characteristics described above for the species except that pyruvate (but not fumarate) is utilized, indole is not produced, no growth occurs on bile agar, and it is not susceptible to penicillin and kanamycin.</s></p></content></protolog>