<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1476_nm.8942" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8942" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8942" rank="species">Pseudonocardia benzenivorans</organism><reference id="rid.1476"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia benzenivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>749</fpage><lpage>751</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02825-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143019</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia benzenivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia benzenivorans</em> (ben.ze.ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>benzenum</em> benzene; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, digesting; N.L. part. adj. <em>benzenivorans</em> digesting benzene).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms a pale vegetative mycelium that fragments very easily into rod-shaped and coccoid elements.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white.</s><s>Gram-positive and oxidase-positive; shows an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 3 days incubation on R2A agar and nutrient agar at 25–30 °C; no growth is observed at 4, 10, 15, 20, 40, 45 or 55 °C.</s><s>Main menaquinone of the type strain is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol; phosphatidylcholine is missing.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-branched hexadecanoate and hexadecanoate.</s><s>Small amounts of methyl-branched fatty acids (C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 10-methyl and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 10-methyl) are detected.</s><s>Carbon source utilization and hydrolysis of chromogenic substrates (including differentiating characters) are indicated in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics of the type strains of <em>Pseudonocardia</em> species</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxa: 1, B5<sup>T</sup>; 2, <em>P. sulfidoxydans</em> DSM 44248<sup>T</sup>; 3, <em>P. hydrocarbonoxydans</em> DSM 43281<sup>T</sup>. +, Positive; −, negative; (+) weakly positive.</s><s>All strains were positive for hydrolysis of <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide.</s><s>All strains were negative for hydrolysis of aesculin, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate and l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide.</s><s>All strains were also positive for assimilation of d-fructose*, d-galactose*, d-glucose*, d-maltose, acetate, propionate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, l-aspartate, l-leucine and phenylacetate.</s><s>All strains were negative for assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose*, l-rhamnose*, adonitol, d-sorbitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, mesaconate, salicin, putrescine, l-histidine, ornithine, adipate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose and l-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44703<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107928<sup>T</sup>), which originated from a soil sample from Bitterfeld, Germany, and was isolated from an enrichment culture that contained 1,2,3,5-tetrachlorobenzene as the sole source of carbon.</s></p></content></protolog>