<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8624_nm.13262" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13262" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13262" rank="species">Capnocytophaga leadbetteri</organism><reference id="rid.8624"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Frandsen</surname><given-names>E.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poulsen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Könönen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Diversity of Capnocytophaga species in children and description of Capnocytophaga leadbetteri sp. nov. and Capnocytophaga genospecies AHN8471.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>324</fpage><lpage>336</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65373-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218926</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Capnocytophaga leadbetteri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Capnocytophaga leadbetteri</em> [lead.bet′te.ri. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>leadbetteri</em> of Leadbetter, in honour of E. R. Leadbetter, the American microbiologist who (as first author) described and proposed the genus <em>Capnocytophaga</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slender (0.35–0.45×3–5 μm), Gram-negative rods motile by gliding.</s><s>Colonies 1–2 mm in diameter and ranging from beige to yellow–orange or pink appear 2–3 days after anaerobic incubation on plaque agar.</s><s>On Columbia blood agar, the colonial appearance varies from beige to yellow–orange, green or pink.</s><s>Pellets of cells grown anaerobically in liquid culture are beige.</s><s>Grows in air enriched with 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>, but not in air alone.</s><s>Tests for catalase, indole, oxidase, <em>β</em>-haemolysis on blood agar, hydrolysis of gelatin and urea and fermentation of melibiose, glycogen, starch and inulin are negative, except for AHN8730, which ferments starch and inulin.</s><s>All strains reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics, including the specific reactions of the type strain, are presented in Table 3.</s><s>The species consists of strains with weak saccharolytic activity.</s><s>Lack of fermentation of sucrose has the highest discriminatory power from other species.</s><s>MLEE and partial 16S rRNA gene sequencing are also useful for species differentiation.</s><s>All strains cleave human IgA1 in the hinge region.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AHN8855<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 51857<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13375<sup>T</sup>) and has a DNA G+C content of 41.3 mol%.</s><s>Other strains belonging to the species are AHN8708, AHN8725, AHN8730 and AHN8996.</s><s>All strains have been isolated from the oral cavity of children.</s></p></content></protolog>