<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12564_nm.21809" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21809" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21809" rank="species">Agromyces soli</organism><reference id="rid.12564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>S.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces soli sp. nov., isolated from farm soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1286</fpage><lpage>1292</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021568-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20639226</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic to microaerophilic, straight or curved rods (0.3–0.4 µm wide and 0.8–1.2 µm long).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–30 °C and at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, but not casein, HE-cellulose, chitin, starch or xylan.</s><s>In API ID 32 GN and API 20NE tests, utilizes acetate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, l-histidine, lactate, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, propionate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin and sucrose for growth, but not adipate, l-alanine, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, malonate, phenylacetate, l-proline, l-serine, d-sorbitol, suberate or valerate.</s><s>In API ZYM and API 20NE tests, positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), β<em>-</em>galactosidase, β<em>-</em>glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, α-chymotrypsin, α<em>-</em>fucosidase, α<em>-</em>galactosidase, α<em>-</em>glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase and urease.</s><s>In API 50 CHB tests, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, β-gentiobiose, d-glucose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl α<em>-</em>d-mannopyranoside, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose, but not from adonitol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, melibiose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, raffinose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>MK-12 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Cell-wall sugars are rhamnose, galactose and xylose.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, two unknown glycolipids and one unidentified phospholipid.</s><s>Cell-wall amino acids are 2,4-diaminobutyric acid, glutamic acid, glycine and alanine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MJ21<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 19549<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16247<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a farm soil near Daejeon, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>