<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12694_nm.22434" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22434" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22434" rank="species">Reichenbachiella faecimaris</organism><reference id="rid.12694"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cha</surname><given-names>I.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>B.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>A.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhee</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>D.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reichenbachiella faecimaris sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat, and emended descriptions of the genus Reichenbachiella and Reichenbachiella agariperforans</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1994</fpage><lpage>1999</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026849-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851915</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Reichenbachiella faecimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Reichenbachiella faecimaris</em> (fae′ci.ma′ris. L. n. <em>faex</em>, <em>faecis</em> sediment; L. n. <em>mare</em>, <em>-is</em> the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>faecimaris</em> of the sediment of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, strictly aerobic, oxidase- and catalase-positive, straight rods, approx. 0.3–0.5 µm in diameter and 3.0–5.0 µm long, motile by gliding.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are beige and circular with regular edges, approx. 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation at 28 °C on MA.</s><s>Colonies are not sunken into the agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–35 °C (optimum, 28–30 °C) and at pH 5.5–8.5 (optimum, pH 7.0–7.5).</s><s>Requires sodium ions for growth; grows in the presence of 1–5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 3 %).</s><s>Carotenoid and flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Casein, starch (soluble) and aesculin are hydrolysed, but gelatin, urea, alginate, DNA, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, CM-cellulose, filter paper, starch (from rice), chitin and agar are not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced and d-glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, sucrose, maltose, sodium acetate, l-alanine, glycogen, l-serine, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate and l-proline; does not utilize potassium gluconate, caprate, l-arabinose, d-mannose, citrate, l-rhamnose, inositol, itaconate, suberate, malonate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionate, valerate, 3-hydroxybutyrate or 4-hydroxybenzonate (API 32GN and API 20NE galleries).</s><s>Malate, d-ribose, lactate and 3-hydroxybenzoate are weakly utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin ferric citrate, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, glycogen, gentiobiose and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Production of acid from sucrose and inulin is strain-dependent.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the other substrates in the API 50 CH gallery.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, β-galactosidase (4-nitrophenyl β-d-galactopyranoside), esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase (weak) and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present; arginine dihydrolase, urease, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase (2-naphthyl β-d-galactopyranoside), β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase (6-bromo-2-naphthyl β-d-glucopyranoside), α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent (API 20NE and API ZYM galleries).</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disc) ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (25), erythromycin (15), mitomycin C (50), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30), but resistant to gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30) and penicillin G (10).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 39.6–41.9 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PCP11<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14523<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16588<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a tidal flat of the Yellow Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>