<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1775_nm.7875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7875" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7875" rank="subspecies">Treponema socranskii buccale</organism><reference id="rid.1775"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Smibert</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ranney</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema socranskii sp. nov., Treponema socranskii subsp. socranskii subsp. nov. Treponema socranskii subsp. buccale subsp. nov., and Treponema socranskii subsp. paredis subsp. nov. isolated from human periodontia</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>457</fpage><lpage>462</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Treponema socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> (buc.ca'le. L. N. <i>bucca</i> cheek: N.L. neu. adj. <i>buccale</i> pertaining to a cheek)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Treponemes in homology group A2 are designated <i>Treponema socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics of this subspecies are shown in Table 3.</s><s>Other characteristics of the subspecies are the same as those of the species.</s><s>The type strain of <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> is strain ATCC 35534 (= VPI D2B8), which was isolated from a subgingival sample from a patient with moderate periodontal disease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The patterns of phenotypic reactions in Table 3 show that <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> (homology group Al) cannot be readily differentiated from <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> (homology group A2).</s><s>However, when we used a slide agglutination test with washed cells as the antigen, 11 of 12 <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> strains agglutinated antisera against the type strain (strain ATCC 35536) and strain VPI D43BR1.</s><s>These antisera did not agglutinate any strain of either <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> or <i>T . socranskii</i> subsp. <i>paredis</i>.</s><s>Of 10 <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> strains, 7 agglutinated antisera against the type strain (strain ATCC 35534) and strains VPI D11A1 and VPI D40DPE1 of <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i>.</s><s>These antisera did not agglutinate any strain of either <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> or <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i>.</s><s>Antiserum against the type strain of <i>T . socranskii</i> subsp. <i>paredis</i> (strain ATCC 35535) was agglutinated by seven of nine <i>T . socranskii</i> subsp. <i>paredis</i> strains but not by any strain of either <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> or <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>