<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1388_nm.5792" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5792" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5792" rank="species">Actinomyces meyeri</organism><reference id="rid.1388"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nygaard</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces meyeri sp. nov., specific epithet rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>487</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> (mey´er.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>meyeri</i> named for K. F. Meyer, German bacteriologist who first isolated the species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Basionym, “Actinobacterium meyeri” A.-R.</s><s>Prdvot 1938,303</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in peptone-yeast extractglucose broth cultures supplemented with vitamin K<sub>1</sub>, hemin, and Tween 80 (4) are short, gram-positive, nonsporeforming, nonmotile rods 0.5 to 0.9 by 0.9 to 3.0 μm and occur in pairs, short chains, or clumps.</s><s>Terminal swellings are present occasionally.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on supplemented brain heart infusion blood agar plates are pinpoint to 1 mm in diameter, circular, flat to convex, translucent to opaque, and white, with shiny, smooth surfaces and entire margins.</s><s>They may be alpha- or nonhemolytic.</s><s>Growth is abundant on plates incubated anaerobically; very slight growth may occur on plates incubated in air enriched with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>; there is no growth on plates incubated aerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth are only slightly turbid with a smooth or stringy sediment and have a pH of 4.6 to 5.0 after incubation for 5 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains grow equally well at 30 or 37°C; they grow nearly as well at 25°C but not at all at 45°C.</s><s>They have an absolute requirement for vitamin K<sub>1</sub>,an d growth is greatly stimulated by 0.02% Tween 80 and by fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>There is no growth in 20% bile or 6.5% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No gas is formed in peptone-yeast extract-glucose agar deep cultures; neither hydrogen nor H<sub>2</sub>S is produced; ammonia may be produced in chopped meat cultures.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, maltose, starch, sucrose, ribose, and xylose ; fermentation of amygdalin, arabinose, galactose, glycogen, glycerol, and lactose is variable (Table 2); neither adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, cellobiose, esculin, inulin, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbose, nor trehalose is fermented.</s><s>Neither indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, catalase, lecithinase, nor lipase is produced.</s><s>Production of urease is variable when organisms are tested in paptone-yeast extract-urea broth (4).</s><s>Proline deaminase and α-glucosidase are produced when organisms are tested by the APIZYM system (Analytab Products, Plainview, N.Y.).</s><s>Milk is curdled by those strains that ferment lactose.</s><s>Esculin, starch, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced; neutral red is reduced, but the reduction of resazurin is variable.</s><s>There is no digestion of gelatin or chopped meat.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products of fermentation in peptone-yeast extract glucose broth are formic, acetic, and succinic acids, with small amounts of lactic or pyruvic acid occasionally detected.</s><s>Neither lactate, threonine, nor gluconate is utilized; pyruvate is converted to formate and acetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The patterns of soluble cellular proteins as determined by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (7) illustrate the homogeneity of the strains examined (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In a numerical taxonomic study, Holmberg and Nord ( 5 ) reported that four of these strains form a cluster related to but distinct from other species in the genus <i>Actinomyces</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains listed in Table 1 give a positive fluorescent antibody reaction with a monovalent conjugate prepared against strain ATCC 33972.</s><s>No cross-reactions have been found with conjugates to other species of oral isolates, including two serotypes of <i>Actinomyces israelii</i>, two serotypes of <i>Actinomyces odontolyticus</i>, three serotypes of <i>Actinomyces naesfundii</i>, <i>Actinomyces viscosus</i>, and a common but unnamed oral isolate, <i>Actinomyces</i> sp. strain WVU 963.</s><s>Several strains that are otherwise phenotypically identical to <i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> do not react with this conjugate although their protein patterns are similar, which indicates that there are other serotypes of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains tested are susceptible to achievable blood levels of chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin G, and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> can be distinguished from <i>Actinomyces israelii</i> and <i>Actinomyces naeslundii</i> by not fermenting raffinose, from <i>Actinomyces viscosus</i> by not producing catalase, from <i>Actinomyces odontolyticus</i> by not producing pink colonies on blood agar and by not reducing nitrate, from <i>Actinomyces bovis</i> by fermenting ribose and xylose, and from <i>Actinomyces</i> sp. strain WVU 963 by not hydrolyzing esculin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The principal habitat of <i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> is human periodontal sulci.</s><s>It has been isolated frequently from brain abscesses and pleural fluid and less often from abscesses of hips, hands, feet, and spleens and from bite wounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Actinomyces meyeri</i> is strain ATCC 35568 (= Prévot 2477B = VPI 8617).</s><s>The guanine-pluscytosine content of this strain, as determined by chromatographic analysis, is 67 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>