<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5343_nm.5623" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5623" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5623" rank="species">Streptococcus defectivus</organism><reference id="rid.5343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus defectivus sp. nov and Streptococcus adjacens sp. nov., nutritionally variant streptococci from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>294</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus defectivus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus defectivus</i> (de. fec' ti. vus. L. adj. <i>defectivus</i>, deficient)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on five clinical isolates (3-5).</s><s>Gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Nonmotile, nonsporulating, catalase negative, and oxidase negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic with complex growth requirements.</s><s>Grows as satellite colonies adjacent to Staphylococcus epidermidis on horse blood- Trypticase-soy agar and on stored sheep blood agar.</s><s>α-Hemolytic on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Tiny colonies up to 0.2 mm in diameter are formed on fresh sheep blood agar or on blood agar supplemented with 10 mg of p yridoxal hydrochloride per liter or 100 mg of L-cysteine per liter.</s><s>Grows in Todd- Hewitt broth enriched with 10 mg of pyridoxal per liter or 100 mg of cysteine per liter.</s><s>Grows in CDMT semisynthetic medium (4) and produces a red chromophore visualized by boiling the bacteria at pH 2 for 5 min.</s><s>The morphology depends upon the conditions of growth; the organism is pleomorphic with chains including cocci, coccobacilli, and rod-shaped cells when it is grown in eysteine- or pyridoxalsupplemented broth.</s><s>Small ovoid cocci (diameter, 0.40 to 0.55 μm) occur singly, in pairs, or in chains of variable length in CDMT semisynthetic medium.</s><s>Some tendency toward rod formation is observed in the stationary phase of growth.</s><s>Lactic acid is the predominant acid produced from glucose fermentation.</s><s>Resistant to optochin and susceptible to vancomycin.</s><s>No production of extracellular polysaccharide from sucrose.</s><s>Ungroupable in the Lancefield system, although some strains give a weak reaction with anti-H serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces pyrrolidonyl-arylamidase and does not produce alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Produces α- and β-galactosidases.</s><s>β-Glucuronidase is not produced.</s><s>Trehalose is fermented, and inulin is not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces leucine aminopeptidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from starch.</s><s>β-Glucosidase is not produced.</s><s>Hippurate and arginine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>D-Ribose, L-arabinose, D-mannitol, sorbitol, and glycogen are not fermented.</s><s>Lactose and D-raffinose are fermented by some strains.</s><s>The PBP pattern includes five major bands, at 188, 96. 88, 77, and 62 kilodaltons.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Streptococcus defectivus</i> has been isolated mostly from The G+C content of the DNA is 46.0 to 46.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain SC10 (= ATCC 49176 = CIP 103242).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain SC10<sup>T</sup> was isolated from the blood of a patient with bacterial endocarditis.</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics of the species and ferments lactose and raffinose. the blood of patients with endocarditis or bacteremia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 46.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>