<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4525_nm.6157" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6157" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6157" rank="species">Rhodoglobus vestalii</organism><reference id="rid.4525"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheridan</surname><given-names>P.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Loveland-Curtze</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miteva</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenchley</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoglobus vestalii gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel psychrophilic organism isolated from an Antarctic Dry Valley lake</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>985</fpage><lpage>994</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02415-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892115</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodoglobus vestalii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodoglobus vestalii</em> [ves.ta′li.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>vestalii</em> in honour of the late J. Robie Vestal, who studied Antarctic micro-organisms and was a mentor to one of the authors (P. P. S.)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following characteristics are shown in addition to those that define the genus.</s><s>Cells do not exhibit a marked rod–coccus cycle and grow optimally at 18 °C.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is approximately 62 mol%.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso- and iso-branched fatty acids.</s><s>When cells are grown at −2 °C, the amount of the unsaturated fatty acid anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> increases substantially and the amount of anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> decreases.</s><s>Cells show positive enzymic activities for pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase (weak), <em>β</em>-galactosidase (weak), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and catalase, but are negative for nitrate reductase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosidase and urease.</s><s>Cells do not hydrolyse gelatin and do not form acid from glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose or glycogen.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence contains an insertion of 13 nucleotides that is shared with some of its most closely related neighbours.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LV3<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-534<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107482<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an Antarctic Dry Valley lake.</s></p></content></protolog>