<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2703_nm.7588" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7588" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7588" rank="species">Actinomadura fibrosa</organism><reference id="rid.2703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura fibrosa sp. nov. isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>28</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-28</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223595</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomadura fibrosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomadura fibrosa</i> (fi.bro'sa. L. adj. <i>fibrosa</i>, fibrous, referring to the fibrous appearance of the aerial hyphae)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, gram positive, nonmotile, and filamentous, occasionally producing aerial hyphae.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> grows well on both complex and defined media.</s><s>However, aerial mycelia are rarely produced except on ISP medium 2, Bennett agar, and tomato paste oatmeal agar.</s><s>When aerial hyphae are produced, they are pink to white.</s><s>The reverse sides are reddish brown to a distinctive reddish orange.</s><s>No soluble pigments are observed.</s><s>These cultural characteristics are shown in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological characteristics.</s><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> produces an extensive substrate mycelium.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are unusual.</s><s>When they are observed by using light microscopy and scanning electron microscopy, no segmentation into spores is observed.</s><s>The hyphae appear to be mainly asporogenous.</s><s>Numerous bundles of hyphae forming thick fibers are readily apparent.</s><s>Figure 4 is a scanning electron micrograph that shows the lack of segmentation into spores and the formation of bundles of fibers.</s><s>Occasionally other fibrous structures are observed.</s><s>These structures, in addition to the fibrous appearance of the aerial hyphae in general, are the basis for the species name.</s><s>No typical morphology nor spore characteristics can be reported.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics.</s><s>A82810.1<sup>T</sup> produces acid from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabinose, cellulose, dextrin, dulcitol, ethanol, erithritol, inositol, inulin, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, and xylitol.</s><s>The following organic acids are utilized as sodium salts: acetate, butyrate, propionate, and pyruvate.</s><s>Benzoate, citrate, formate, lactate, malate, mucate, oxalate, succinate, and tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> decomposes casein, elastin, esculin, hypoxanthine, starch, testosterone, tyrosine, and urea, but not adenine, allantoin, calcium malate, guanine, hippurate, and xanthine.</s><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> produces catalase, phosphatase, and urease, liquefies gelatin, hydrolyzes skim milk, and is able to survive a temperature of 50°C for 8 h.</s><s>It does not produce melanoid pigments or H<sub>2</sub>S, reduce nitrates, or peptonize skim milk.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> is resistant to cephalothin (30 μm), lincomycin (2 μm), penicillin G (10 U), rifampin (5 μm), and lysozyme (50 μm/ml).</s><s>It is susceptible to bacitracin (10 U), gentamicin (10 μm), neomycin (30 μm), oleandomycin (15 μm), streptomycin (10 μm), tetracycline (30 μm), tobramycin (10 μm), and vancomycin (30 μm).</s><s>Strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> grows in a temperature range of 20 to 45°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature appears to be 37°C.</s><s>The organism tolerates NaCl at levels up to and including 5%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemotaxonomy.</s><s>Hydrolyzed whole cells contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The following sugars are detected in whole-cell extracts: galactose, glucose, mannose, madurose, and ribose.</s><s>Thus, strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> has a type III cell wall and a type B sugar pattern (15).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>Phospholipid determinations on whole cells indicate the presence of phosphatidylinositol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>No phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, or phosphatidylcholine is detected.</s><s>Therefore, strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> has a type PI phospholipid pattern (17).</s><s>The menaquinones detected in strain A82810.1<sup>T</sup> are hexahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units [MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>)].</s><s>A minor amount of octahydrogenated menaquinones [MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>)] are also detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain A82810.1 (= NRRL 18348).</s><s>This organism was isolated from soil collected in Togo, West Africa.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and thus serves as the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>