<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6833_nm.9858" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9858" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9858" rank="species">Epilithonimonas tenax</organism><reference id="rid.6833"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>O'Sullivan</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rinna</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Humphreys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weightman</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fry</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Culturable phylogenetic diversity of the phylum 'Bacteroidetes' from river epilithon and coastal water and description of novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae: Epilithonimonas tenax gen. nov., sp. nov. and Persicivirga xylanidelens gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>169</fpage><lpage>180</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63941-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Epilithonimonas tenax</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Epilithonimonas tenax</em> (ten′ax. L. fem. adj. <em>tenax</em> sticky, holding firm, referring to the organism's viscous colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following characteristics in addition to those properties described for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are 3–6 mm in diameter, bright orange, opaque, smooth, with an entire edge and a viscous consistency (PCA after 1 week at 20 °C).</s><s>Cells are short, rounded rods which do not form chains or filaments and are 1–2·5 μm long and 0·6–0·7 μm wide.</s><s>Cells do not exhibit gliding motility.</s><s>Cell mass is pigmented orange and flexirubin pigments are synthesized.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 30 °C, but not in the presence of NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, NA, MacConkey agar and DNase agar, but not on MA2216 or cetrimide agar.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Agar, arginine, DNA, Tween 80 and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>No <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease or xylanase activities.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Resistant to chloramphenicol, streptomycin, kanamycin and tetracycline, but susceptible to penicillin G, ampicillin and rifampicin.</s><s>Growth occurs on glucose, mannose, maltose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, sucrose, d-trehalose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-alanyl-glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine and thymidine.</s><s>Growth does not occur on arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, d,l-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EP105<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14026<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16811<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from epilithon-covered stones from the River Taff in Cardiff, UK.</s></p></content></protolog>