<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.807" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.789" rank="species">Prosthecochloris vibrioformis</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prosthecochloris vibrioformis</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> Pelsh 1936.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species description is as given by Pfennig &#x0026; Overmann (2001a) for <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em>, with the following modifications.</s><s>Cells are curved rods or vibrioid, 0·5–0·7 μm wide, non-motile and occur as single cells.</s><s>Gas vesicles may be formed.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is green or brown, and photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>d</em> (occasionally also BChl <em>c</em>) with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid in green strains, and BChl <em>e</em> with isorenieratene as the major carotenoid in brown strains.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and sulfur as photosynthetic electron donors; molecular hydrogen may be used by some strains.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required for growth by most strains.</s><s>Brackish water and marine bacteria that require at least 1 % NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 53·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 260<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is M62791.</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>The type strain of <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em>, DSM 260<sup>T</sup>, does not belong to the genus <em>Chlorobium</em>, but is genetically closely related to <em>Prosthecochloris aestuarii</em>.</s><s>The degree of relatedness justifies its recognition as a species of the genus <em>Prosthecochloris</em>.</s><s>It is therefore proposed that strain DSM 260<sup>T</sup> is recognized as the type strain of <em>Prosthecochloris vibrioformis</em> comb. nov.</s><s>With this transfer, <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> becomes a synonym of <em>Prosthecochloris vibrioformis</em>, and other strains assigned to this species, including subspecies, must be assigned to different species (see Table 1).</s><s>Sequence similarities of more than 99 % for both the 16S rRNA and the <em>fmo</em> genes support the recognition of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em> DSM 1678 and <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> CHP 3402 as additional strains of <em>Prosthecochloris vibrioformis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>