<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.544_nm.4397" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4397" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4397" rank="species">Dialister invisus</organism><reference id="rid.544"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Munson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dialister invisus sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1937</fpage><lpage>1940</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02640-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657126</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dialister invisus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dialister invisus</em> (in.vis′us. L. masc. adj. <em>invisus</em> unseen, referring to the lack of turbidity of broth cultures of this organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The etymology, and therefore the gender, of the genus name is unknown.</s><s>We therefore propose that the gender of the genus name be assigned as male, as allowed under Rule 65(3) of the <em>Bacteriological Code</em>, and hence the male form of the adjective selected as the specific epithet is given.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on six strains isolated from the human oral cavity.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, Gram-negative, small cocci or ovoid cocci (0·3–0·4×0·3–0·6 μm) that occur singly, in pairs, in short chains and in small clumps.</s><s>After 7 days incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 0·5–0·7 mm in diameter, circular, entire and either translucent and umbonate or transparent and low-convex with a narrow marginal, translucent fringe.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces only a slight turbidity and is not visibly stimulated by the addition of 1 % carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are asaccharolytic and only trace amounts of acetate and propionate are detected as end products of metabolism in peptone/yeast extract/glucose medium.</s><s>Aesculin, arginine and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced.</s><s>No growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is E7.25<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 47026<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15470<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the human oral cavity in patients with endodontic and periodontal infections.</s></p></content></protolog>