<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1037_nm.7955" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7955" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7955" rank="species">Bacteroides helcogenes</organism><reference id="rid.1037"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides pyogenes sp. nov., Bacteroides suis sp. nov., and Bacteroides helcogenes sp. nov., new species from absesses and feces of pigs</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>396</fpage><lpage>407</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides helcogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides helcogenes</i> (<i>hel.co.ge'nes</i>. Gr. n. <i>helkos</i> abscess; Gr. v. <i>gennaio</i> produce; M.L. <i>adj. helcogenes</i> abscess-producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmenting, non-spore rods.</s><s>Gram stains of single colonies from agar plates show predominantly short, Gram-negative rods, single or in pairs (0.5-0.6 μm by0.8-4.0 μm).</s><s>After 2 days incubation, surface colonies are 1.0-2.0 mm in diameter, circular with an entire edge, convex, translucent to opaque grey to grey-white, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>No growth on blood agar plates incubated in a candle-extinction jar or in an aerobic atmosphere.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 1 day incubation, the pH in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate decreases to about 5.0.</s><s>Most strains do not grow in PYFG broth containing 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Xylose, glucose, mannose, fructose, galactose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, cellubiose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, salicin, amygdalin and xylan are fermented.</s><s>Esculin and starch are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Arabinose, treahlose melezitose, glycerol, inulin, mannitol, sorbitol, inositol, adonitol, erythritol ad gum arabic are not fermented.</s><s>Indole is not produced; nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetic and succinct acids and very small amounts of isobutyric and propionic acids are produced in PYFG broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin (10 μg/ml) and cepharothin (10 μm/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: swine abscess and feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 20613 (= P 36-108) isolated from abscess in pig.</s></p></content></protolog>