<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12348_nm.20381" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20381" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20381" rank="species">Fibrella aestuarina</organism><reference id="rid.12348"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Filippini</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svercel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laczko</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaech</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ziegler</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bagheri</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fibrella aestuarina gen. nov., sp. nov., a filamentous bacterium of the family Cytophagaceae isolated from a tidal flat, and emended description of the genus Rudanella Weon et al. 2008</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>184</fpage><lpage>189</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020503-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20190021</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fibrella aestuarina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fibrella aestuarina</em> (aes.tu.a.ri′na. L. n. <em>aestuarium</em> a tidal marsh; N.L. fem. adj. <em>aestuarina</em> belonging to a marsh, referring to the location where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following properties are in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>After 1 day of incubation in SM broth, cells are usually 0.8 μm wide and 1.1–6.9 μm long, but multicellular filaments up to 245 μm long also occur (Fig. 2).</s><s>During the transient growth phase in liquid culture, multicellular filaments up to 400 μm long may be formed.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are pink, convex and circular with regular edges.</s><s>Flagellar and gliding motility are absent.</s><s>Growth occurs in R2A, SM, NB and 0.5 % yeast water and on YT agar and TSA but not on blood agar or MacConkey agar, or in peptone water.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–8.0, with an optimum at pH 7.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–40 °C, with an optimum at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth but can tolerate 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Agar, agarose, amylopectin, casein, CM-cellulose, starch and xylan are hydrolysed (showing clear haloes around the colonies).</s><s>Pectin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, negative results are observed for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease activities, citrate utilization and H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production.</s><s>In the API ZYM strip, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are present; lipase (C14) and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the API 20NE strip, positive reactions are observed for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity, aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of arabinose, glucose, maltose, mannose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine; potassium gluconate is weakly assimilated and negative reactions are observed for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities and assimilation of d-mannitol, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API 50CH strip after 7 days of incubation, the following substrates are assimilated: l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin), melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose and potassium 2-ketogluconate; potassium gluconate is weakly assimilated and the following substrates are not assimilated: glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Resistant to amikacin (30 μg), colistin (30 U), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 U) and vancomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Sensitive to amoxicillin (10 μg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (20/10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (30 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron micrographs of strain BUZ 2<sup>T</sup>. (a) Scanning electron micrograph showing filamentous cells. (b) Transmission electron micrograph of a longitudinal section and cross-sections of bacterial cells.</s><s>Bars, 1 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BUZ 2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 58136<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22563<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mud from a tidal flat on the North Sea coast of Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>