<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7473_nm.965" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.965" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.965" rank="species">Rickettsia massiliae</organism><reference id="rid.7473"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beati</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia massiliae sp. nov., a new spotted fever group Rickettsia.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>839</fpage><lpage>840</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-839</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240964</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia massiliae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia massiliae</i> (mas.si'li.ae. L. gen. n. <i>massiliae</i>, from Massilia, the Latin name of Marseille, France, where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Rickettsia massiliae</i> is an obligately gram-negative intracellular organism.</s><s>It grows in tissue cultures of L929, Vero, or human embryonic lung fibroblast cells.</s><s>Gimenez-stained infected cells contain small, intracellular, rod-shaped or diplobacillary bacteria that are slightly shorter (0.3 to 0.4 by 0.6 to 1 μm) than the other SFG rickettsiae (3).</s><s>This organism can also be detected in infected cells by indirect immunofluorescence by using human immune sera reactive with the lipopolysaccharide of Rickettsia cunurii, a cross-reaction which has previously been demonstrated by a Western blot (immunoblot) analysis (3, 6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This rickettsia possesses an outer slime layer and a trilaminar cell wall, as determined by electron microscopy.</s><s>It grows free in the cytoplasm of the cells without membrane enclosure and is not present in nuclei (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity for humans or animals has not been demonstrated.</s><s>Male Hartley’s guinea pigs show no symptoms after inoculation of 10<sup>5</sup> organisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results of microimmunofluorescence serotyping and SDS-PAGE protein analysis of purified organisms, as well as polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism and pulsed-field electrophoresis genetic analyses strain Mtu1<sup>T</sup>, show that this rickettsia is different from all previously described SFG rickettsiae.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Type strain Mtu1 has been deposited in the Collection of the World Health Organization Collaborative Center for Rickettsial Reference, Marseille, France.</s></p></content></protolog>