<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14700" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14700" rank="species">Aquiluna rubra</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Aquiluna rubra’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Aquiluna rubra’ [A′qui.lu′na. L. fem. n. <em>aqua</em> water; L. fem. n. <em>luna</em> the moon; N.L. fem. n. <em>Aquiluna</em> water moon, referring to the aquatic habitat of the first strain and its selenoid morphology. rub′ra. L. fem. adj. <em>rubra</em> red]. Represented by the aerobic, red-pigmented strain MWH-Dar4, which was isolated from a eutrophic pond in Tanzania. The strain is contained in a mixed culture with a variable fraction of a non-actinobacterial strain. Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-Dar4 (GenBank accession no. AJ565416). This strain and closely related strains (Supplementary Fig. S2) can be distinguished from other bacteria by the combined presence of the two specific sequences 5′-AAACTGTAGCTAATACCGGATACTTTCC-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 160–183) and 5′-AATATTGCACAATGGGCGCAAGCCT-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 363–387) within the 16S rRNA gene. These two oligonucleotide sequences are also present in almost full-length 16S rRNA sequences of three cultivated, red-pigmented strains and one uncultured bacterium, which all share sequence similarities &#x003E;98.6 % with strain MWH-Dar4 (Supplementary Fig. S2). Furthermore, a blast search revealed many short sequences of 300–500 nt that also contain these two oligonucleotide sequences. Preliminary phylogenetic analyses indicated a close relationship between these short sequences and the above-mentioned almost full-length sequences (data not shown). The three cultivated strains were isolated from freshwater habitats in Tanzania, France and China, while the sequence of the uncultured bacterium PH-F7 was retrieved from a seawater sample taken in Poole Harbour, UK.</s></p></content></protolog>