<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3767_nm.10656" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10656" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10656" rank="species">Chimaereicella boritolerans</organism><reference id="rid.3767"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ahmed</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujiwara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chimaereicella boritolerans sp. nov., a boron-tolerant and alkaliphilic bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from soil</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>986</fpage><lpage>992</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64728-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chimaereicella boritolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chimaereicella boritolerans</em> (bo′ri.to′le.rans. N.L. n. <em>borum</em> boron; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>boritolerans</em> boron-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile and rod-shaped, 1.2–3.4 μm long and 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter, occurring singly and occasionally in pairs.</s><s>Gram staining is negative.</s><s>Colonies are red-pigmented, circular with entire margins, convex, butyrous in texture and small in diameter after several days of growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The red pigment loses its intensity at pH 10.0 on agar medium and is diffusible in liquid medium.</s><s>Grows optimally at 28–30 °C; very slight growth at 37 and 16 °C after several days.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 8.0–9.0, with a range of pH 6.5–10.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 300 mM boron, but grows optimally without boron supply.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated up to 3 % (w/v).</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, hydrolysis of aesculin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase tests are positive, whereas tests for production of indole, nitrate reduction and hydrolysis of gelatin and urea are negative.</s><s>Produces acid from the following substrates: d-galactose, d-glucose, aesculin, inulin, d-raffinose, starch, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, potassium 5-ketogluconate, gentiobiose and d-turanose.</s><s>Can use the following substrates as carbon sources: d-mannitol, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, inulin and d-melezitose.</s><s>Additional physiological characteristics are provided in Table 1.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; traces of some other fatty acids are apparent.</s><s>The respiratory lipoquinone system is MK-7.</s><s>Strong enzyme activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and valine arylamidase, whereas weak activity is observed for leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, esterase (C8), esterase lipase (C8), trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM strip).</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin, oxacillin, sulfamethizol and metronidazol and weakly sensitive to penicillin, gentamicin, rifampicin and cefoperazon (ATB-VET strip).</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 42.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain T-22<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17298<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 101277<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1189<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil that naturally contains boron (Hisarcik, Kutahya, Turkey).</s></p></content></protolog>