<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2704_nm.8330" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8330" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8330" rank="species">Thermonema rossianum</organism><reference id="rid.2704"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tenreiro</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miguel</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermonema rossianum sp. nov., a new thermophilic and slightly halophilic species from saline hot springs in Naples, Italy.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>126</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-122</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995813</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermonema rossianum</i> sp. nov. Nobre, Rainey, and da Costa.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermonema rossianum</i> (ros. si. á num. M. L. adj. <i>rossianum</i>, pertaining to Rossi, in honor of Mosé Rossi, noted Neapolitan biochemist)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Thermonema rossianum</i> strains form long filaments of variable length, which are about 0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Gram stain negative.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile, and spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on medium 162 are yellow pigmented and 2 mm in diameter after 48 h of growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature for strain NR-27<sup>T</sup> is about 60°C; growth does not occur at 30 and 70°C in medium 162.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 7.0 and 7.5; growth does not occur at pH 5.0 or 10.0.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is between 1.0 and 3.0%; growth does not occur in medium 162 without added NaCl or in medium containing an NaCl concentration greater than 6.0%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:O iso and 17:O iso 3-OH.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is menaquinone 7; sphingolipids are present.</s><s>All strains are oxidase positive and catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Casein, elastin, and gelatin are degraded; starch, xylan, and cellulose are not degraded.</s><s>The strains utilize Casamino Acids and complex amino acid mixtures for growth.</s><s>The strains of this species do not grow on single amino acids, sugars, organic acids, and polyols.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA of strain NR-27<sup>T</sup> has a G+C content of 50.9 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from a saline hot spring close to the Bay of Naples.</s><s>Strain NR-27<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10300<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Strains SC-1 (= DSM 10298) and AG3-1 (= DSM 10299) are reference strains of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>