<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3150_nm.3607" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3607" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3607" rank="species">Desulforhopalus singaporensis</organism><reference id="rid.3150"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lie</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clawson</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Godchaux</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leadbetter</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sulfidogenesis from 2-aminoethanesulfonate (taurine) fermentation by a morphologically unusual sulfate-reducing bacterium, Desulforhopalus singaporensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>65</volume><fpage>3328</fpage><lpage>3334</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10427015</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulforhopalus singaporensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulforhopalus singaporensis</i> (sin.ga.po'rensis. M.L. n. <i>Singapore</i>, Republic of Singapore; L. suff. -<i>ensis</i>, native of; M.L. adj. <i>Singaporensis</i>, native of Singapore, referring to the place of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative cells that are 1.7 to 2.3 μm long and 0.9 to 1.2 μm wide.</s><s>Endospores not detected.</s><s>Cells may grow as chains containing two to six cells.</s><s>No flagella.</s><s>Cells able to produce the nonprosthecate structures called spinae.</s><s>Strict anaerobe.</s><s>Grows with 2-aminoethanesulfonate (taurine) as a sole carbon, energy, and nitrogen source without an additional TEA.</s><s>Grows with sulfite as the sole source of energy with acetate as the source of assimilatory carbon.</s><s>Grows chemotrophically with oxidation of formate, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, succinate, butyrate, ethanol, butanol, or Casamino Acids coupled to reduction of sulfate; slow growth occurs with propionate, isobutyrate, and caproate.</s><s>Acetate accumulates from lactate oxidation but not from fumarate oxidation.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub> and acetate are not utilized.</s><s>Pyruvate is fermented.</s><s>Sulfite, thiosulfate, and nitrate serve as alternate TEA for growth; 0.5 mM sulfide inhibits growth on nitrate.</s><s>Desulfoviridin not detected.</s><s>Cells contain menaquinone 5(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0 to 8.2, and the optimum pH is 7.4.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 35°C, and the optimum temperature is 31°C.</s><s>Isolated from marine sulfidogenic mud from a saltwater marsh in the Republic of Singapore.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 50.6 ± 0.2 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is S'pore T1, which has been deposited in the DSMZ as strain DSM 12130.</s></p></content></protolog>