<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4421_nm.1201" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1201" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1201" rank="species">Sphingomonas wittichii</organism><reference id="rid.4421"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Terakubo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okamura</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujiwara</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kosako</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Sphingomonas wittichii sp. nov. for strain RW1T, known as a dibenzo-p-dioxin metabolizer.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>281</fpage><lpage>292</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321072</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas wittichi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingomonas wittichi</i> (wi.tti.chi.i. L. gen. n. <i>wittichii</i> of Wittich, referring to Rolf-Michael Wittich, the German bacteriologist who first isolated this potent metabolizer of dibenzo-<i>p</i>-dioxin from the water of the River Elbe and described the metabolism of dibenzo-pdioxin by this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are pin-point after 2 d incubation and, after a further 2-3 d are 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>They are smooth, shiny, convex, semi-translucent and initially greyish-white, becoming faintly yellow after 3 d incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Gram-negative rods with rounded ends.</s><s>Soma size is 0.4-0.6x0.9-1.5 μm.</s><s>Actively motile with single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Flagellar wave morphology is regular (Fig. 2a, b) or with only one long curve (Fig. 2c).</s><s>Able to grow at 30 °C.</s><s>Oxidaseand catalase-positive.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, never fermentative or photosynthetic.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, liquefies gelatin and alkalinizes malonate broth, but does not alkalinize Simmons' citrate medium and does not hydrolyse starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Failed to grow on MacConkey agar medium.</s><s>The following tests are negative: deoxyribonuclease, nitrate reduction to nitrite, acylamidase, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>In OF medium, oxidative acidity observed from D-arabinose, D-ribose, fructose, galactose, glucose, maltose, glycerol, sorbitol, mannitol, rhamnose, salicin and inulin within 3 d.</s><s>Among the 99 substrates of Biotype 100 (bioMérieux), only two carbohydrates, α-L(-)fucose and D-glucuronate are assimilated; the amino acids phenylalanine, L-glutamate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-aspartate and L-tyrosine and the organic acids gentisate, DL-lactate, succinate, fumarate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate and malonate are assimilated.</s><s>Resistant to macrolide and new quinolone antibiotics.</s><s>Major fatty acid of cellular lipid is 18:1; the only hydroxy acid is 2-OH 14:0.</s><s>Alkali-stable cellular lipids contain both SGL-1 and SGL-1'.</s><s>DNA G+­C content is 67 mol% (Wittich et al., 1992).</s><s>Type strain is DSM 6014<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10273<sup>T</sup>=EY 4224<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>