<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3882_nm.9596" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9596" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9596" rank="species">Clostridium carboxidivorans</organism><reference id="rid.3882"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liou</surname><given-names>J.S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balkwill</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drake</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium carboxidivorans sp. nov., a solvent-producing clostridium isolated from an agricultural settling lagoon, and reclassification of the acetogen Clostridium scatologenes strain SL1 as Clostridium drakei sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2085</fpage><lpage>2091</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63482-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium carboxidivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium carboxidivorans</em> (car.bo.xi.di.vo′rans. N.L. neut. n. <em>carboxidum</em> carbon monoxide; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>carboxidivorans</em> carbon monoxide-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, motile rods (0·5×3 μm) occurring singly and in pairs.</s><s>Cells rarely sporulate, but spores are subterminal to terminal with slight cell swelling.</s><s>Obligate anaerobe with an optimum growth temperature of 38 °C and an optimum pH of 6·2.</s><s>Grows autotrophically with H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> or CO and chemoorganotrophically with ribose, xylose, fructose, glucose, galactose, l-arabinose, mannose, rhamnose, sucrose, cellobiose, trehalose, melezitose, pectin, starch, cellulose, inositol, mannitol, glycerol, ethanol, propanol, 2-propanol, butanol, citrate, serine, alanine, histidine, glutamate, aspartate, asparagine, Casamino acids, betaine, choline and syringate.</s><s>Methanol, d-arabinose, fucose, maltose, lactose, raffinose, melibiose, amygdalin, sorbitol, gluconate, lactate, malate, succinate and arginine do not support growth.</s><s>Acetic acid, ethanol, butyrate and butanol are the end-products of metabolism.</s><s>Cultures are methyl red-positive, but negative for the Voges–Proskauer reaction, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, indole production, catalase, oxidase and urease.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 31–32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain P7<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-624<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15243<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an agricultural settling lagoon in Oklahoma, USA.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence analysis showed that <em>C. carboxidivorans</em> is very closely related to <em>C. scatologenes</em> ATCC 25775<sup>T</sup> and <em>C. drakei</em>, but DNA reassociation analysis showed that <em>C. carboxidivorans</em> is a distinct species, with a reassociation value of 50 % with respect to <em>C. scatologenes</em> ATCC 25775<sup>T</sup> and a reassociation value of 32 % with respect to <em>C. drakei</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>