<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5776_nm.11721" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11721" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7140" rank="species">Kitasatosporia mediocidica</organism><reference id="rid.5776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kitasatosporia mediocidica sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>290</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-287</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kitasatosporia mediocidica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kitasatosporia mediocidica</i> (med'i.o.cid.i.ca. L. n. <i>mediocidin</i>, antibiotic produced by the type strain of this species; L. adj. suff. -<i>icus</i>, possessing a character of; <i>mediocidica</i>, possessing mediocidin)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Kitasatosporia mediocidica</i> substrate mycelium ranges from moderate yellow to shades of light brown, depending upon the growth medium; very sparse white to gray aerial hyphae bearing smooth-surfaced spores in short open coils (<i>Retinaculum-Apertum</i>) are produced on several media (e.g., inorganic salts-starch agar, glycerol-asparagine agar, or yeast extract-malt extract agar).</s><s>Yellow to brown soluble pigments are produced on many growth media.</s><s>Adenine, hippurate, hypoxanthine, starch, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed; allantoin, casein, cellulose, esculin, gelatin, guanine, tyrosine, urea, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase but not nitrate reductase activity produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1.5% NaCl but not in the presence of 3.0% NaCl.</s><s>Assimilation of DL-malate but not acetate, benzoate, citrate, lactate, mucate, oxalate, propionate, succinate, or L-tartrate.</s><s>Acid produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, sucrose, and D-xylose; variable production of acid from D-mannitol and trehalose ; no acid produced from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-xyloside, D-raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, or sorbitol.</s><s>Temperature range for growth, 15 to 30°C.</s><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of DNA, 74 mol% (thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>Produces the antibiotic mediocidin.</s><s>The type strain of <i>K. mediocidica</i> is strain NRRL B-16109.</s></p></content></protolog>