<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7780" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7780" rank="family">Parachlamydiaceae</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> (Par.a.chla.my.di.a'ce.ae. M . L. fem. n. <i>Parachlamydia</i> type genus of the family; -<i>aceae</i> ending to denote a family; M.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> the Parachlamydia family)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> naturally infect amoebae and can be grown in cultured Vero cells.</s><s>The <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> are not recognized by monoclonal antibodies specific for the antigenic LPS trisaccharide αKdo-(2→8)-αKdo-(2→4)-αKdo of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>.</s><s>The description of this family derives from the description of '<i>Candidatus</i> Parachlamydia acanthamoebae' strain Bn<sub>9</sub><sup>T</sup>, strain Berg<sub>17</sub>, and several unnamed isolates (Amann et al., 1997; Birtles et al., 1997; Michel et al., 1994).</s><s>The <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> comprise strains with rRNAs that are 80-90% identical to the ribosomal genes of strain Bn<sub>9</sub><sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> belong to the order <i>Chlamydiales</i> and form a sister taxon to the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> because they have a chlamydia-like cycle of replication and their ribosomal genes are 80-90% identical to ribosomal genes in the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis of a 16s rRNA from the <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i> gene has been published previously (Amann et al., 1997; Pettersson et al., 1997).</s><s>At present, this family comprises but a single genus, the type genus <i>Parachlamydia</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>