<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4220_nm.1658" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1658" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1658" rank="species">Lautropia mirabilis</organism><reference id="rid.4220"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gerner-Smidt</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Keiser-Nielsen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ursing</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blom</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frederiksen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoffmann</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lautropia mirabilis gen. nov., sp. nov., a gram-negative motile coccus with unusual morphology isolated from the human mouth.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>140</volume><fpage>1787</fpage><lpage>1797</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8075812</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lautropia mirabilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lautropia mirabilis</i> (mi.ra'bi.lis. The specific epithet was kept from Brskov's original description (1930))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative cocci occurring in at least three forms: (1) encapsulated cocci, 1-2 μm in diameter, often occurring in clusters of 10-&#x003E; 100 cells; (2) unencapsulated cocci, 1-2 μm in diameter, motile by the action of a tuft of three to nine flagella; and (3) large, &#x003E; 5 μm in diameter, sphaeroblast-like cells.</s><s>Facultative, but grows best under aerobic conditions with no requirement for CO<sup>2</sup>.</s><s>Mesophilic, growing at temperatures between 30°C and 44°C.</s><s>Non-pigmented, grows on most enriched media, especially on chocolate, Levinthal, TGY and Tween 80 agar; grows slower with no haemolysis on horse-blood agar.</s><s>At least three colony morphologies are seen: (1) flat, dry, circular colonies predominating in young cultures, becoming (2) larger, wrinkled, crisp and crateriform on prolonged incubation, and (3) smooth, glistering, raised, round, mucoid colonies.</s><s>The colony diameter varies between pinpoint size and more than 5 mm; all colony types may occur in all sizes, largest in older cultures; colonies are usually adherent to the substrate.</s><s>Growth in broth is granular with a coarse sediment and granules adherent to the side of the tube.</s><s>Biochemically, strains are oxidase, catalase and urease positive, reduce nitrate and nitrites, produce polysaccharide on sucrose agar, ferment glucose, fructose, maltose, sucrose and mannitol and do not ferment lactose, trehalose, raffinose, inulin, salicin, adonitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, inositol, xylose, rhamnose or arabinose or hydrolyse starch.</s><s>Most strains hydrolyse esculin.</s><s>They may produce β-xylosidase, but not β- galactosidase or β-glucuronidase.</s><s>Do not decarboxylate lysine or ornithine and do not produce arginine decarboxylase/dihydrolase or phenylalanine deaminase.</s><s>VP, gelatinase, H<sub>2</sub>S negative; do not hydrolyse hippurate or Tween 80.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin G, ampicillin, piperacillin, cefuroxime, gentamicin and erythromycin.</s><s>Mean mol% (G+C) is 65 (range 64.6-65.4).</s><s>The habitat is the human oral cavity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AB2188 (= NCTC 12852).</s></p></content></protolog>