<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4334_nm.2126" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2126" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2126" rank="species">Thiocapsa litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.4334"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Puchkova</surname><given-names>N.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiocapsa litoralis sp. nov., a new purple sulfur bacterium from microbial mats from the White Sea.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1441</fpage><lpage>1447</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939648</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiocapsa litoralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiocapsa litoralis</i> (li.to.ra'lis. L. adj. <i>litoralis</i> from the shore)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical and non-motile, 1.5-2.5 μm in diameter and organized in regular platelets of 4, 8 and 16 or even more cells.</s><s>Photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of cell suspensions is pink to rose-red.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and most probably members of the spirilloxanthin series are present as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Phototrophic growth occurs under anoxic conditions in the light and chemoautotrophic growth is possible under microoxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Electron donors used for photoautotrophic growth are hydrogen sulfide, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate and sulfite.</s><s>Globules of elemental sulfur are stored inside the cells as an intermediary product.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, pyruvate, lactate, malate, succinate, fumarate, fructose, glucose, Casamino acids and yeast extract are photoassimilated.</s><s>Caprylate, tartrate, formate, ascorbate, asparaginate, benzoate, malonate, citrate, maltose, galactose, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, methanol and ethanol are not utilized.</s><s>Assimilatory sulfate reduction occurs.</s><s>Chemolithoautotrophic growth occurs with hydrogen sulfide and thiosulfate as electron donors.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required as growth factor.</s><s>Storage materials are poly β-hydroxybutyrate and polyphosphates.</s><s>The species is mesophilic, with optimum growth at 30 °C, at pH 6.5 and in 1% NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G­+C content is 64±0 mol% (by thermal denaturation).</s><s>Isolated from microbial mat communities from the White Sea littoral shore.</s><s>The type strain is BM5<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700894).</s><s>The EMBL accession number of the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is AJ24772.</s></p></content></protolog>