<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.482_nm.6671" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6671" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6671" rank="species">Propionicimonas paludicola</organism><reference id="rid.482"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akasaka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamagata</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionicimonas paludicola gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel facultatively anaerobic, Gram-positive, propionate-producing bacterium isolated from plant residue in irrigated rice-field soil</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1991</fpage><lpage>1998</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02764-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657135</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Propionicimonas paludicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Propionicimonas paludicola</em> (pa.lu.di′co.la. L. n. <em>palus</em>, -<em>udis</em> swamp, marsh; L. suff. <em>-cola</em> derived from <em>incola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. masc. n. <em>paludicola</em> an inhabitant of swamps).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, irregular, often slightly curved rods, 0·4–0·5 μm in diameter and 1·8–2·0 μm in length and frequently arranged in irregular V- or crescent-shapes.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 35 °C and pH 6·5.</s><s>Grows in the presence of up to 2·0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cells produce acetate, propionate, lactate, succinate and CO<sub>2</sub> anaerobically from glucose.</s><s>Growth and production of propionate are both stimulated by addition of cyanocobalamin to the medium.</s><s>Cells grow on arabinose, xylose, fructose, galactose, glucose, mannose, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, glycerol, mannitol, pyruvate and lactate, but growth is scarce on ribose, lactose, malate, fumarate and succinate.</s><s>Fucose, rhamnose, sorbose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, cellulose, glycogen, soluble starch, xylan, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, sorbitol, ethanol, methanol and propanol are not utilized.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics of the species are the same as those described for the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Wd<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 11933<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15597<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from rice-plant residue ploughed into the soil of a Japanese rice field.</s></p></content></protolog>