<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7637_nm.14058" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14058" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14058" rank="species">Sneathiella glossodoripedis</organism><reference id="rid.7637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kurahashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fukunaga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sneathiella glossodoripedis sp. nov., a marine alphaproteobacterium isolated from the nudibranch Glossodoris cincta, and proposal of Sneathiellales ord. nov. and Sneathiellaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>548</fpage><lpage>552</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65328-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sneathiella glossodoripedis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sneathiella glossodoripedis</em> [glos.so.do.ri.pe′dis. N.L. n. <em>Glossodoris</em> name of a zoological genus; L. gen. n. <em>pedis</em> of the foot; N.L. gen. n. <em>Glossodoripedis</em> of the foot of <em>Glossodoris</em> (<em>G. cincta</em>), the source of isolation of the type strain].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are slightly curved rods, 0.2–0.3×0.7–1.0 μm, motile by one polar flagellum, non-spore-forming and have poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate inclusions.</s><s>Colonies on MA are colourless, circular, convex, smooth and less than 1.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 1 week at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 40 °C, while no growth occurs at 10 or 50 °C.</s><s>Cultures grow aerobically, but not anaerobically.</s><s>The ubiquinone system is Q-10 and the major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>No growth occurs without NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 56.9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is positive for catalase, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, production of acetoin, utilization of citrate and reduction of nitrate to nitrite, but negative for urease, gelatinase, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole, reduction of nitrite to N<sub>2</sub> and assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) (weak), esterase lipase (C8) (weak), leucine arylamidase, trypsin (weak), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase (weak) and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are detected, but lipase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MKT133<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15419<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 12842<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the nudibranch <em>Glossodoris cincta</em> off Aka island, Okinawa, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>