<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.995_nm.7719" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7719" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7719" rank="species">Falcivibrio vaginalis</organism><reference id="rid.995"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hammann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kronibus</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Viebahn</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandis</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Falcivibrio grandis gen. nov. sp. nov., and Falcivibrio vaginalis gen. nov. sp. nov., new genus and species to accomodate anaerobic motile curved rods formerly described as Vibrio mulieris, Prevot 1940 Breed et al. 1948.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>96</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Falcivibrio vaginalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Falcivibrio vaginalis</i> sp. nov. (va.gi.na'lis L. adj. <i>vaginalis</i> from the vagina)</s></p><p class="description"><s>More or less crescent, also almost straight or coryneform rods occurring singly or in pairs, 2-3 μm in length and 0.4-0.6 μm in width.</s><s>Motile by means of one to four, seldom more laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Cell ends slight rounded, often pointed.</s><s>Endospores not formed.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract-glucose-sheep blood agar or Columbia agar with human blood after 3 days of anaerobic incubation are gray or white, pin-point to 1 mm in diameter and non-hemolytic.</s><s>Strict anaerobes, but some strains able to grow in a partially reduced atmosphere with 5% O<sub>2</sub> after several transfers.</s><s>Carbohydrates usually not fermented, esculin never hydrolyzed, indole not formed.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites by most of the strains.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase never produced.</s><s>Growth stimulated by fumarate which is reduced to succinate.</s><s>Traces of malate formed from fumarate, too.</s><s>Products in PYG broth are acetic, lactic, and succinic acids; same products in PY broth but smaller amounts.</s><s>Minor amounts of gas formed under a paraffin wax seal over a broth culture.</s><s>Gram stain shows predominantly Gram-positive cells in young cultures, and increasingly Gram-negative cells in older ones.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 53-54 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from vaginal or cervical specimens of women with vaginitis, but role in pathogenicity not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: V 125 = DSM 2711 deposited in : Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>