<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2436_nm.11313" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11313" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11313" rank="species">Flavisolibacter ginsengiterrae</organism><reference id="rid.2436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavisolibacter ginsengiterrae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Flavisolibacter ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from ginseng cultivating soil.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1834</fpage><lpage>1839</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65011-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684267</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavisolibacter ginsengiterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavisolibacter ginsengiterrae</em> (gin.sen.gi.te.r′rae. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengiterrae</em> of soil from a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.3–0.7×0.6–1.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar plates are smooth, circular, convex, opaque and yellow in colour within 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature and pH are 30 °C and pH 7.0. <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, l-fucose, glycogen, glucose, histidine, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-proline, rhamnose, salicin and d-sucrose are assimilated.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin and for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for hydrolysis of urea, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, H<sub>2</sub>S production and assimilation of acetate, adipate, l-alanine, n-caprate, citrate, gluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactate, dl-malic acid, malonate, mannitol, phenylacetate, propionate, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, suberate and valerate.</s><s>With the API ZYM gallery, positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase, and weakly positive for <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Negative for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 492<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12656<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18136<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>