<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12213_nm.20208" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20208" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20208" rank="species">Actinomadura scrupuli</organism><reference id="rid.12213"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura scrupuli sp. nov., isolated from rock</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2647</fpage><lpage>2651</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017608-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20042751</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomadura scrupuli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomadura scrupuli</em> (scru′pu.li. L. gen. n. <em>scrupuli</em> of a small stone, referring to the isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive.</s><s>Cells grow well on ISP media 2, 3, 4, 5 and 7, NA, oatmeal-nitrate agar, HV agar and water agar plates and show poor growth on ISP medium 6 and TSA.</s><s>The organism forms abundant vegetative mycelium that is branched and twisted.</s><s>The reverse colour of the colonies is brownish-yellow.</s><s>Aerial mycelium and soluble pigments are not produced on any of the tested media.</s><s>Wrinkled arthrospores (0.9–1.1 μm in diameter) are produced directly from the substrate mycelium on water agar.</s><s>Sporangia are not observed.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.1–8.1.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20–30 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are degraded but not casein, cellulose, chitin, DNA, elastin, hypoxanthine, starch, l-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Acetate, adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextran, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, lactose, dl-malate, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose can be utilized as carbon sources, but d-arabinose, benzoate, citrate, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, formate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, d-mannose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-mannitol, raffinose, l-ribose, salicin, l-tartrate and d-xylitol are not utilized.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid and rhamnose, glucose, ribose, xylose and arabinose are the diagnostic diamino acid and whole-cell sugars, respectively.</s><s>The polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R-Ac121<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19488<sup>T</sup> =DSM 45225<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a small stone in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>