<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5700_nm.6553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6553" rank="species">Actinoplanes durhamensis</organism><reference id="rid.5700"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical and chemical classification of Actinoplanes and some related actinomycetes</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinoplanes durhamensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinoplanes durhamensis</i> (dur. ham.en'sis. ML adj. <i>durhamensis</i>, belonging to Durham, a city in the North-East of England)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Light to dark orange substrate mycelium formed on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Sporangia globose, spores motile and arranged irregularly within sporangia.</s><s>Melanin produced on ISP7 medium.</s><s>Degrades arbutin, casein, lecithin and starch; utilizes L-arabinose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, methyl β-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, D-xylose and p-hydroxybenzoic acid as sole carbon sources but not D-cellobiose, erythritol, catechol, coumarin, o-hydroxybenzoic acid, sodium fumarate, sodium succinate, syringaldehyde, syringic acid or vanillin.</s><s>Neither hydrogen sulphide nor urease is formed.</s><s>The organism is sensitive to a number of antibiotics and chemical inhibitors (Table 6) and shows activity against Staphylococcus aureus.</s><s>It grows at 4 and 30 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>- and hydroxydiaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The principal wall sugars are arabinose, galactose, glucose, mannose and xylose.</s><s>The organism also contains complex mixtures of straight- and branched-chain fatty acids, with octadecanoic, 14- methylpentadecanoic and 14-methylhexadecanoic acids predominating, tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenologue, and major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from river sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Actinoplanes durhamensis</i> LA 139 (IFO 14914, NCIB 20041).</s></p></content></protolog>