<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9268_nm.14548" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14548" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14548" rank="species">Virgibacillus sediminis</organism><reference id="rid.9268"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus sediminis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake in China</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2058</fpage><lpage>2063</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003624-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus sediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus sediminis</em> (se.di′min.is. L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of sediment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase- and oxidase-positive, strictly aerobic rods, approximately 0.4–0.7 μm wide and 2.5–4.0 μm long, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in subterminally swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 3 days on MA supplemented with 5 % (w/v) NaCl at 37 °C, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular to slightly irregular, raised, translucent and creamy white to pale yellow.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–20 % (w/v) total salts (optimum, 5–10 %) and at 10–55 °C (optimum, 35–40 °C) and pH 6.0–10.5 (optimum, pH 7.5–8.0).</s><s>Unable to grow with NaCl as sole salt.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, but casein, starch, Tweens (20, 40, 60 and 80) and urea are not.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and oxidation of glucose, but negative for fermentation of glucose, nitrite reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production, and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Respiration on nitrate, nitrite and fumarate under anaerobic conditions is not observed.</s><s>Acids are produced from cellobiose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose and turanose (API 50CH); other organic substrates included in the API 50CH panels are not metabolized.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole source of carbon and energy or sole source of carbon, nitrogen and energy: cellobiose, dextrin, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, trehalose, acetate, gluconate and l-alanine.</s><s>The following substances are not utilized: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, sucrose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, butyrate, citrate, fumarate, propionate, succinate, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, d-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), gelatinase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but alkaline phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14), lysine decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not produced (API 20E and ZYM).</s><s>Cells are resistant to ampicillin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg) and nalidixic acid (20 μg), but susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), licomycin (2 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and galactose, glucose and ribose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids of the type strain (comprising 86.2 % of the total) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM kkny3<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 207023<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19797<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 13193<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline sediment sample collected from the Keke salt lake in the Qaidam Basin in Qinghai Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>