<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8397_nm.13778" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13778" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13778" rank="species">Singularimonas variicoloris</organism><reference id="rid.8397"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Friedrich</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alkanibacter difficilis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Singularimonas variicoloris gen. nov., sp. nov., hexane-degrading bacteria isolated from a hexane-treated biofilter.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2324</fpage><lpage>2329</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65517-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842850</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Singularimonas variicoloris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Singularimonas variicoloris</em> (va.ri.i.co.lo′ris. L. adj. <em>varius</em> varying; L. gen. n. <em>coloris</em> of colour; N.L. gen n. <em>variicoloris</em> of varying colour).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following characteristics in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Catalase-positive (weak reaction).</s><s>Colonies vary in colour between yellow, orange and brown.</s><s>Colonies on trypticase soy agar are 1–3 mm in diameter, umbonate and are each surrounded by a flat, pale white rim.</s><s>The colour is more intense in the centre of the colony.</s><s>Gram-staining is negative and the KOH and aminopeptidase tests give positive results.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.9 mol% (sd, 0.07).</s><s>Growth is positive with hexane on minimal medium agar but is negative in liquid medium.</s><s>Positive for growth on the following: Tween 40, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, l-alanylglycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-threonine and urocanic acid.</s><s>The gelatinase reaction is positive.</s><s>No growth occurs on the following: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, caprate, adipate, malate, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 14 : 0 3-OH, 16 : 0 and 18 : 1<em>cis</em>11; iso-branched fatty acids are present.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.9 mol% (sd, 0.07).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MN28<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15731<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22844<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an industrial biofilter.</s></p></content></protolog>