<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6332_nm.5303" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5303" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5303" rank="species">Salinicoccus alkaliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.6332"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus alkaliphilus sp. nov., a novel alkaliphile and moderate halophile from Baer Soda Lake in Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>789</fpage><lpage>793</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01912-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054239</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Salinicoccus alkaliphilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Salinicoccus alkaliphilus</i> (N.L. fem. n. <i>alkali</i> alkali; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <i>alkaliphilus</i> liking alkaline media)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci, 0.5-0.8 μm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, tetrads or clumps.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Gram-positive and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are round, smooth and slightly convex with pinkish colour and no diffusible pigment.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.5-11.5 (optimum at 9.5), at temperatures of 10.0-49.0 °C (optimum at 32 °C) and in media with 0-25.0% (w/v) NaCl [optimum at 10% (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Catalase, oxidase and urease are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole, methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, whereas casein, starch, gelatin and Tweens 80, 60 and 20 are not.</s><s>Utilizes D-arabinose, D(­+)-melibiose, creatinine, aesculin, lactose, D-xylose, D-fructose, amylose, sorbose, D(+­)-α-melezitose, erythritol, inulin, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, trehalose, D-mannose, D-sorbitol, stachyose, ribose, mannitol, D-galactose, adonitol, D-cellobiose, glycogen, dulcitol and α-L-rhamnose as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, but not from maltose, galactose, fructose, sucrose, D-arabinose, glycerol or D-xylose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole nitrogen sources: polypeptone, yeast extract, DL-tryptophan, bacto-peptone, casitone, urea, L-proline, L-methionine, L-serine, L-arginine, L-alanine, L-threonine, L-histidine, sodium L-glutamate, L-ornithine, L-leucine, L-glycine, L-glutamic acid and DL-lysine.</s><s>Amino acids that are not utilized as sole nitrogen sources are L-asparagine, L-tyrosine, L-isoleucine and L-cysteine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 49.6 mol% (determined by thermal denaturation).</s><s>The predominant lipoquinone is MK-6; no other quinones are detected.</s><s>The assumed cell wall murein type is L- Lys-Gly<sub>5</sub>.</s><s>Isolated from Baer Soda Lake, China.</s><s>The type strain is strain T8<sup>T</sup> (=AS 1.2691<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11311<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>