<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.125_nm.1563" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1563" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1563" rank="species">Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</organism><reference id="rid.125"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bauld</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bigford</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum, a new species from marine habitats.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>613</fpage><lpage>617</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</i> (li.to.ra'lum. L. adj. <i>litoralis</i> of the seashore)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short to long rods (diameter, ca. 1.0 μm) with numerous tapering prosthecae.</s><s>Most prosthecae are short (i.e., less than 0.5 μm long), although occasional prosthecae are longer.</s><s>Gas vacuoles are not produced.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies are white and raised initially, becoming cream colored and umbonate after prolonged incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sodium ions are required for growth.</s><s>The minimum salinity for growth is 5‰,; the optimum salinity 25‰.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 27 to 34°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 66 to 67 mol%, as determined by buoyant density (two strains tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the species is strain 524-16.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 35022 and has all of the properties described above for the species.</s><s>Additional properties are given in Tables 1 and 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The observation that all of the strains of <i>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</i> which we studied utilize agar may be of ecological significance.</s><s>It suggests that these marine strains may degrade algal polysaccharide materials in littoral regions.</s><s>In addition, <i>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</i> can utilize numerous sugars and some sugar alcohols, which comprise the degradation products of polysaccharides.</s><s>These nutritional features may explain why enrichment with <i>Ulva</i> fronds was so successful. <i>Prosthecomicrobium litoralum</i> may also use dissolved organic carbon excreted by marine phytoplankton.</s></p></content></protolog>