<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2809_nm.9166" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9166" rank="genus">Serpula</organism><reference id="rid.2809"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casey</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tordoff</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Treponema hyodysenteriae and Treponema innocens in a new genus, Serpula gen. nov., as Serpula hyodysenteriae comb. nov. and Serpula innocens comb. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>50</fpage><lpage>58</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-50</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1704792</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serpula</i> Stanton, Jensen, Casey, Tordoff, Dewhirst, and Paster gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Serpula (Ser'pu.la. L. fem. n. <i>Serpula</i>, a little serpent [53])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Unless otherwise indicated, the information below was taken from previous descriptions of <i>T. hyodysenteriae</i> and <i>T. innocens</i> (11, 23, 42).</s><s>Helical cells with loose, regular coils, 7 to 9 μm by 0.3 to 0.4 μm.</s><s>Gram reaction negative.</s><s>Typical spirochete ultrastructure consisting of outer sheath, protoplasmic cylinder bounded by a cytoplasmic membrane, and endoflagella inserted at each end of a protoplasmic cylinder and lying between the outer sheath and the protoplasmic cylinder.</s><s>Eight or nine flagella are inserted at each end of a cell.</s><s>Motile; flexing and creeping at 22°C; translational movement at 37 to 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Host associated.</s><s>Isolated from intestinal contents and feces of swine and other mammals.</s><s>One species, <i>Serpula hyodysenteriae</i>, is enteropathogenic for swine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Uses soluble sugars for growth.</s><s>Weakly fermentative.</s><s>Produces acetate, butyrate, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub> from glucose.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>Negative for lipase and lecithinase.</s><s>Does not grow in media containing 1% glycine.</s><s>Grows anaerobically in Trypticase soy or brain heart infusion broth containing 10% fetal calf, calf, or rabbit serum.</s><s>Growth occurs at 36 to 42°C.</s><s>Does not grow at 25 and 30°C.</s><s>Surface colonies on Trypticase soy blood agar plates are visible after 48 to 96 h of incubation at 38°C.</s><s>Colonies are 0.5 to 3 mm in diameter, flat, translucent, and, depending on the species, weakly or strongly beta-hemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selective culture media for isolating <i>Serpula hyodysenteriae</i> and <i>Serpula innocens</i> from intestinal contents contain spectinomycin (43) or a combination of spectinomycin, colistin, vancomycin, rifampin, and spiramycin (26).</s></p><p class="description"><s>At specific base locations in the 16s rRNA, <i>Serpula</i> species contain spirochete signature nucleotides (38, 52; this study).</s><s>The genus <i>Serpula</i> is differentiated from other spirochete genera on the basis of DNA homology or 16s rRNA sequence similarity data.</s><s>A 16s rRNA signature region for three strains of <i>Serpula hyodysenteriae</i> and two strains of <i>Serpula innocens</i> has the following sequence: 5’-CGGRAACGCCUCGGAUACUGURAGUC-3’, where R is A or G (this study).</s><s>This sequence corresponds to <i>E. coli</i> 16s rRNA base positions 625 to 650 (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the strains tested are 25 to 26 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Serpula hyodysenteriae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>