<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2787_nm.2585" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2585" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2585" rank="species">Pseudomonas chloritidismutans</organism><reference id="rid.2787"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wolterink</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jonker</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kengen</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stams</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas chloritidismutans sp. nov., a non-denitrifying, chlorate-reducing bacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2183</fpage><lpage>2190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02102-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508887</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas chloritidismutans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas chloritidismutans</i> (chlo.ri.ti.dis.mu'tans. N.L. n. <i>chloris</i> chlorite ; L. part. pres. <i>dismutans</i> splitting ; N.L. part. pres. <i>chloritidismutans</i> chlorite-splitting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, motile rods.</s><s>Cells are 0.5-2 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies growing in anaerobic agar are circular and pale orange.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient broth plates are wrinkled, coherent and have a pale brown or sometimes reddish brown colour.</s><s>In strictly anaerobic medium prereduced with sulfide, the growth characteristics as follows: growth range, 10-37 °C, optimum 30 °C; pH range for growth, pH 8.0-9.0, optimum pH 8.5.</s><s>In nutrient broth medium, growth is in the pH range 7.0-9.0, with an optimum at pH 7.5.</s><s>Doubling times are respectively 1.5 and 1.2 h for chlorate and oxygen.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing up to 40 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>At high NaCl concentrations, cells in stationary phase may lyse.</s><s>Growth occurs on the following: acetate, propionate, glucose, maltose, gluconate, mannitol, ethanol, starch, glycerol and citrate.</s><s>There is no growth on malate, succinate, lactate, glycine, arabinose or H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Glucose and maltose are not fermented.</s><s>Chlorate and oxygen are used as electron acceptors.</s><s>No growth with perchlorate, chlorite, nitrate, nitrite, bromate, sulfate or selenate.</s><s>Cell extracts contain chlorate reductase and bromate reductase activities.</s><s>Chlorite is converted to chloride and oxygen by a chlorite dismutase.</s><s>The type strain belongs to the <i>γ</i>-<i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The 16S rDNA sequence is 98.6% similar to that of <i>P. stutzeri</i> DSM 5190<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>DNA-DNA hybridization between strain AW-1<sup>T</sup> and <i>P. stutzeri</i> DSM 5190<sup>T</sup> showed 56±5% similarity.</s><s>The G­+C content is 63.9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, strain AW-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13592<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-443<sup>T</sup>), was obtained from biomass of an anaerobic bioreactor treating chlorate- and bromate-polluted wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>