<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12859_nm.22666" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22666" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22666" rank="species">Ochrobactrum daejeonense</organism><reference id="rid.12859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>S.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum daejeonense sp. nov., a nitrate-reducing bacterium isolated from sludge of a leachate treatment plant</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2690</fpage><lpage>2696</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025510-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21169456</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ochrobactrum daejeonense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ochrobactrum daejeonense</em> (dae.jeon.en′se. N.L. fem. adj. <em>daejeonense</em> pertaining to Daejeon, a city in South Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 6.0–8.0, with an optimum of pH 7.0.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, chitin, DNA, HE-cellulose, gelatin, starch and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The results of tests for carbon source utilization (API ID 32 GN and API 20 NE), enzyme activities (API ZYM and API 20 E) and acid production (API 50 CHB) are reported in Table 1.</s><s><em>N</em>-Acetylglucosamine, l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, l-histidine, 2-ketogluconate, lactate, malate, maltose, d-mannose, l-proline, l-serine and sucrose are utilized for growth but adipate, glycogen, 5-ketogluconate, malonate and melibiose are not utilized.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase and trypsin activities but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-chymotrypsin, α<em>-</em>fucosidase, α<em>-</em>galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), lysine decarboxylase, α-mannosidase and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Acid is produced without gas from d-arabinose, erythritol, d-fructose, d- and l-fucose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, turanose and l-xylose but not from amygdalin, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate, melezitose or l-sorbose.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the predominant respiratory lipoquinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are PG, PE, PC, PME, DPG and two unknown AL.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone Q-10 with a trace amount of Q-9.</s><s>The major polyamines are putrescine and spermidine and the minor polyamine is <em>sym</em>-homospermidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MJ11<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22458<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16234<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge of the aerobic treatment tanks of a municipal leachate treatment plant located in Daejeon, South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>