<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12418_nm.21248" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21248" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21248" rank="species">Erwinia piriflorinigrans</organism><reference id="rid.12418"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>López</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roselló</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llop</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferrer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia piriflorinigrans sp. nov., a novel pathogen that causes necrosis of pear blossoms</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>561</fpage><lpage>567</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020479-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Erwinia piriflorinigrans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Erwinia piriflorinigrans</em> (pi.ri.flo.ri.ni′grans. L. n. <em>pirus</em> pear tree; L. n. <em>flos</em> -<em>floris</em> flower; L. part. adj. <em>nigrans</em> blackened, darkened; N.L. part. adj. <em>piriflorinigrans</em> blackened pear blossom, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, facultatively anaerobic, non-spore-forming, motile, straight rods.</s><s>Glucose is oxidized and fermented without producing gas in Hugh–Leifson's medium (Hugh &#x0026; Leifson, 1953).</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Grows on King's medium B (King <em>et al.</em>, 1954) producing non-fluorescent, circular, white, slightly convex, mucoid colonies, 2–3 mm in diameter with regular margins after 48 h at 25 °C.</s><s>Produces convex colonies on Sucrose Nutrient agar and CCT media (Ishimaru &#x0026; Klos, 1984) and produces levan.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse arginine in anaerobiosis.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Does not use calcium galacturonate in Sutton's medium (Sutton, 1957), or show ice nucleation activity.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 20 but not Tween 80 or gelatin.</s><s>Reduces sugars from sucrose and produces acetoin.</s><s>Grows in nutrient broth at 25 and 30 °C but not at 37 °C or higher.</s><s>In the API 20E (bioMérieux) system, tests are positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity, citrate and acetoin production and acidification of glucose, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sucrose, melibiose and arabinose but negative for arginine dihydrolase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase activities, acid production from sodium thiosulfate, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole, gelatin and acidification of sorbitol, rhamnose and amygdalin.</s><s>In the API 50 CH (bioMérieux) (Roselló <em>et al.</em>, 2006) and Biotype 100 systems (bioMérieux) (this study), glycerol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, adonitol, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose methyl-<em>α</em>-glucoside, d-fucose, d- and l-alanine, l-serine, l-proline, fumarate, d-gluconate, l-glutamate, l-malate and succinate are utilized.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are (in decreasing order): C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, unknown fatty acids of equivalent chain-lengths (ECL) 14 502 and 13 597, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, and, as a minor component, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (Roselló <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s><s>Does not react with a mixture of commercially available mAbs (IVIA 3B+IVIA 5H; PlantPrint Diagnostics) designed for the detection of <em>E. amylovora</em> in a DASI-ELISA protocol (Roselló <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CFBP 5888<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7348<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from, and causes necrosis of, pear blossoms of Ercolini (Coscia) and Tendral pear trees and elicits a hypersensitive reaction when inoculated in tobacco and tomato leaves.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains show identical rep-PCR profiles, which are different from the profiles obtained with <em>E. amylovora</em> or <em>E. pyrifoliae</em>.</s><s>Amplification is observed when using the primers EaF-EaR (Maes <em>et al.</em>, 1996), whose targets are 23S rRNA gene sequences, and primers from other chromosomal sequences such as <em>ams</em>BL-<em>ams</em>BR (Bereswill <em>et al.</em>, 1995).</s><s>PCR analyses give negative results using the <em>E. amylovora</em> pEA29 primers (Bereswill <em>et al.</em>, 1992; Llop <em>et al.</em>, 2000; McManus &#x0026; Jones, 1995) and using other primers based on <em>E. amylovora</em> chromosomal sequences, such as the Ea71 primers (Guilford <em>et al.</em>, 1996).</s><s>The isolates contain a plasmid of similar size to the pEA29 of <em>E. amylovora</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50–51 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>