<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.251_nm.1496" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1496" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1496" rank="species">Rhodopseudomonas adriatica</organism><reference id="rid.251"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Neutzling</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Truper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodopseudomonas adriatica spec. nov., a new species of the Rhodospirillaceae dependent on reduced sulfur compounds.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>137</volume><fpage>256</fpage><lpage>261</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodopseudomonas adriatica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodopseudomonas adriatica</i> (a. dri. a'ti. ca. M. L. fem. adj. pertaining to Adria, the Adriatic Sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, 0.5-0.8 μm wide, 1.3 - 1.8 μm long, non-motile.</s><s>They multiply by binary fission and have the tendency to form chains of cells.</s><s>Photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth under anaerobic conditions in the light with organic carbon compounds or reduced sulfur compounds as electron donors.</s><s>Addition of Na-ascorbate stimulates growth.</s><s>Slow growth at low oxygen tension.</s><s>Sulfide and thiosulfate can be used as electron donors with CO<sub>2</sub> as sole carbon source.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is formed during photolithotrophie growth on sulfide, and during photoheterotrophic growth with higher concentrations of sulfide or cysteine.</s><s>Growth is not possible with sulfate as sole sulfur source, or molecular hydrogen as electron</s></p><p class="description"><s>donor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth is at 25-30°C pH 6.5-7.0, 2.5-7.5% NaCl, and light intensities of 1000-2000 lux.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most intermediates of the tricarboxylic acid cycle, some sugars and fatty acids, amino acids, lactate and ethanol are photoassimilated.</s><s>Not used are citrate, tartrate, benzoate, mannitol, fructose, methanol, and 2-propanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen sources are ammonium salts, some amino acids, urea, and N<sub>2</sub>; not utilized are nitrate, thymine and</s></p><p class="description"><s>adenine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biotin and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition of the type strain is 66.7 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: mud and water of the marine lake Malo Jezero (Island of Mljet), Yugoslavia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: BN 721 (6 II), deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen in Göttingen, number DSM 2781.</s></p></content></protolog>