<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10753_nm.17846" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17846" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7077" rank="species">Streptomyces decoyicus</organism><reference id="rid.10753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Streptomyces hygroscopicus strains as Streptomyces aldersoniae sp. nov., Streptomyces angustmyceticus sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces ascomycinicus sp. nov., Streptomyces decoyicus sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces milbemycinicus sp. nov. and Streptomyces wellingtoniae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>769</fpage><lpage>775</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012161-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656929</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces decoyicus</em> (Vavra <em>et al.</em> 1959) sp. nov., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces decoyicus</em> [de.co′yi.cus. N.L. n. <em>decoyininum</em> decoyinine, an antibiotic; L. masc. suff. -<em>icus</em> adjectival suffix used with various meanings; N.L. masc. adj. <em>decoyicus</em> (sic) related to decoyinine, referring to the ability of the organism to produce decoyinine].</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Streptomyces hygroscopicus</em> subsp. <em>decoyicus</em> Vavra <em>et al.</em> 1959.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from this and from previous studies (Vavra <em>et al.</em>, 1959; Dietz &#x0026; Mathews, 1969).</s><s>Spores (0.5–0.7×0.5–1.2 μm) are borne in spiral chains with two to three turns.</s><s>Spore surface smooth.</s><s>Grows well on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 60 are degraded.</s><s>Does not use methanol or propanol as a sole carbon source (at 1 %, v/v).</s><s><em>α</em>-Alanine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, dl-methionine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine and l-valine are used as sole nitrogen sources (at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Sensitive to doxycycline hydrochloride, erythromycin, gentamicin sulphate, kanamycin sulphate, neomycin sulphate, oleandomycin phosphate, rifampicin, streptomycin sulphate, tetracycline hydrochloride and tobramycin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), cephaloridine hydrochloride (32 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chlortetracycline hydrochloride (64 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), fusidic acid (16 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), lincomycin hydrochloride and novobiocin (4 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), and penicillin G (20 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are mentioned in the text or in Table 1.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71.2 mol%.</s><s>Produces decoyinin and psicofuranine; the latter shows antitumour activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSM 41427<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL 2666<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from garden soil.</s></p></content></protolog>