<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8343_nm.1280" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1280" rank="species">Rhizobium leguminosarum</organism><reference id="rid.8343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ramírez-Bahena</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García-Fraile</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peix</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valverde</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Igual</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revision of the taxonomic status of the species Rhizobium leguminosarum (Frank 1879) Frank 1889AL, Rhizobium phaseoli Dangeard 1926AL and Rhizobium trifolii Dangeard 1926AL. R. trifolii is a later synonym of R. leguminosarum. Reclassification of the strain R. leguminosarum DSM 30132 (=NCIMB 11478) as Rhizobium pisi sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2484</fpage><lpage>2490</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65621-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984681</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Rhizobium leguminosarum</em> (Frank 1879) Frank 1889</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium leguminosarum</em> [le.gu.mi.no.sa′rum. N.L. gen. pl. fem. n. <em>leguminosarum</em> of Leguminosae (the former systematic family name of the legumes)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods as characteristic for the other species of the genus.</s><s>Colonies are small, pearl white coloured in YMA at 28 °C, the optimal growth temperature.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7–7.5.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 to 35 °C and from pH 6 to 8.</s><s>No growth is observed at 37 °C, at pH 5 or in the presence of 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Positive for the production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease; aesculin hydrolysis is variable in the API 20NE system.</s><s>Positive for the production of <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-arabinosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-and <em>β</em>-fucosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-mannosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-xylosidases, <em>α</em>-rhamnosidase and acid and alkaline phosphatases using chromogenic paranitrophenyl substrates.</s><s>The production of <em>β</em>-galactosaminidase and <em>β</em>-cellobiase was variable.</s><s>The production of lactosidase and <em>α</em>-and <em>β</em>-maltosidases is negative for most strains.</s><s>The production of indole, arginine dehydrolase and gelatinase is negative in API 20NE tests.</s><s>Glucose, l-arabinose, fructose, galactose, l-rhamnose, xylose, melibiose, cellobiose, mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, inositol, xylitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, salicin, l-alanine, l-histidine, aspartate, glutamate, betaine and sarcosine are used as the sole carbon source, whereas l-sorbose, melezitose, caproate, adipate, citrate, pyruvate, propionate, phenylacetate, l-serine, l-lysine and l-valine are not utilized as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Erythritol is used as a carbon source by most strains.</s><s>l-Arginine is weakly utilized by some strains as a carbon source.</s><s>Assimilation of l-malate and gluconate is variable.</s><s>Sensitive to ciprofloxacin, polymyxin B, oxytetracycline, cefuroxime and gentamicin.</s><s>Weakly sensitive to neomycin and erythromycin.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin and cloxacillin.</s><s>Resistance to ampicillin is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, USDA 2370<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 10004<sup>T</sup>=LMG 14904<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from effective nodules of <em>Pisum sativum</em> and is also known to nodulate <em>Trifolium repens</em> and <em>Phaseolus vulgaris</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>