<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6328_nm.9995" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9995" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9995" rank="species">Pelagibaca bermudensis</organism><reference id="rid.6328"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pelagibaca bermudensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium within the Roseobacter clade in the order Rhodobacterales</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>855</fpage><lpage>859</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64063-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585706</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pelagibaca bermudensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pelagibaca bermudensis</em> (ber.mu.den′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bermudensis</em> from Bermuda).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to having the traits reported for the genus, colonies on MA are circular, convex, cream-coloured, butyrous and 1·2–2·5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 10–40 °C, optimally at 30–33 °C, but not at 4 or 44 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5·0–10·5 and 0·25–15 % NaCl, optimally at pH 8·5 and 3·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-negative.</s><s>Urea, aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s><em>β</em>-Glucosidase activity is present.</s><s>Utilizes dl-glyceraldehyde, d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methanol, glycerol, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, itaconic acid, citric acid, gluconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-lysine, l-alanine, l-serine, l-leucine and l-arginine.</s><s>d-Melezitose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-glutamic acid, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, <em>β</em>-lactose, d-raffinose, adonitol, ethanol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-malic acid, formic acid, d-glucosamine, l-isoleucine and glycine are not utilized as sole carbon sources (tested using custom-made, 48-well plate).</s><s>In tests with Biolog SF-N2 microplates, the following substrates are utilized oxidatively: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, and <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (25 μg), nalidixic acid (25 μg), carbenicillin (25 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), puromycin (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), rifampicin (50 μg), benzylpenicillin (100 U) and gentamicin (10 μg), but resistant to kanamycin (30 μg), vancomycin (30 μg) and cycloheximide (50 μg).</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (79·7 %), 11-methyl 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (7·5 %), 16 : 0 (4·9 %), 12 : 0 3-OH (3·4 %), 18 : 0 (0·8 %), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (0·6 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (0·6 %), 10 : 0 3-OH (0·4 %), 12 : 1 3-OH (0·2 %) and 17 : 0 (0·2 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HTCC2601<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12554<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13377<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the Bermuda Atlantic Time Series Station in the western Sargasso Sea, Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>