<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3846_nm.3998" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3998" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3998" rank="species">Clostridium proteoclasticum</organism><reference id="rid.3846"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Attwood</surname><given-names>G.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reilly</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium proteoclasticum sp. nov., a novel proteolytic bacterium from the bovine rumen.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>753</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-753</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782685</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium proteoclasticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium proteoclasticum</i> (pro.te.o.clas'ti.cum. M. L. neut. n. <i>proteinum</i>, protein, from G. v.<i>proteueiun</i>, to be first; M. L. adj. <i>clasticus</i>, breaking, from G. part. perf. <i>klastos</i>, broken; <i>proteoclasticum</i> M. L. adj. protein breaking)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, straight to slightly curved rods that are 0.4 to 0.6 μm wide and 1.3 to 3.0 μm long and do not form endospores.</s><s>Cells occur in short chains and have tapered ends, and each cell possesses a single, subterminal flagellum, although cells are not motile in liquid culture.</s><s>After overnight incubation, cells form a ropy sediment, which is easily dispersed with shaking.</s><s>Colonies grown overnight on CC-glucose medium are 0.5 mm in diameter, tan, irregular, convex with undulate margins, and transparent with smooth surfaces and a viscous texture.</s><s>Older colonies (2 to 3 days) are 1 mm in diameter and become granular.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Growth is supported by amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, inulin, lactose, maltose, melibiose, rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose, xylan, and xylose, while glycogen and mannose support weak growth.</s><s>The substrates adonitol, cellulose, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, galacturonic acid, glycerol, inositol, lactate, mannitol, melizitose, sorbitol, sorbose, and trehalose do not support growth.</s><s>The fermentation products from growth on CC medium include formate, butyrate, acetate, propionate, and a trace of succinate.</s><s>Hydrogen is produced from growth on CC-glucose medium.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by the presence of 20% rumen fluid, is inhibited by bile, and is not affected by Tween 80 or hemin.</s><s>There is no growth aerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characterization tests and G+C content. <i>C. proteoclasticum</i> hydrolyzes gelatin and casein, and proteolytic activity against casein is almost totally inhibited by phenylmethylsulfonyl fluoride and is inhibited to lesser degrees by merthiolate, N-tosyl-1-lysine chloromethyl ketone, <i>p</i>-chloromercuribenzote, EDTA, and <i>o</i>-phenanthroline.</s><s>This organism also exhibits a curd reaction with milk and hydrolyzes esculin. <i>C. proteoclasticum</i> does not produce indole or ammonia, does not exhibit catalase, lipase, or lecithinase activity, and does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>The heat test data, spore strain results, and growth on sporulation medium all indicate that no endospores are formed, while colonies on blood agar are nonhemolytic.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 28 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. proteoclasticum</i> strain B316 is the type strain and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51982.</s></p></content></protolog>