<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6596_nm.4483" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4483" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4483" rank="species">Caldicellulosiruptor owensensis</organism><reference id="rid.6596"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baresi</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caldicellulosiruptor owensensis sp. nov., an anaerobic, extremely thermophilic, xylanolytic bacterium.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>97</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-91</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542080</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Caldicellulosiruptor owensensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Caldicellulosiruptor owensensis</i> (O.wen.sen'sis. N. L. adj. <i>owensensis</i> from Owens Lake, CA, USA)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile straight rods that are 2-5 μm by 0.5-0-8 μm, and occur singly, in pairs, or in chains.</s><s>Lophotrichous flagella.</s><s>Gram staining reaction was negative.</s><s>Endospores were not found in any tested conditions.</s><s>Colonies (diameter, ≤ 2 mm) are circular with smooth edges, convex, opaque and yellowish.</s><s>Growth occurred over the temperature range 50-80°C with an optimum of 75°C.</s><s>No growth was detected at and below 45°C or above 80°C.</s><s>Alkalitolerant.</s><s>pH range, 5.5-9-0 with an optimum at about pH 7.5.</s><s>Growth factors found in either yeast extract or vitamin solutions were not required for growth.</s><s>Growth was inhibited by penicillin G, streptomycin, chloramphenicol and ampicillin at 100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Cells are resistant to D-cycloserine (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), erythromycin (200 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and tetracycline (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Growth strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Growth with arabinose, cellobiose, cellulose, dextrin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, mannitol, mannose, maltose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, starch, sucrose, tagatose, xylan, xylose and yeast extract.</s><s>Does not grow on acetate, amygdalin, arbutin, erythritol, glycerol, lactate, melezitose, melibiose, methanol, pyruvate, sorbitol, trehalose, trypticase peptone or H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The fermentation products from glucose are acetate, lactate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The bacterium does not reduce nitrate, sulfate, sulfite and thiosulfate.</s><s>The G+C content is 36.6 mol% (as determined by buoyant density of purified DNA by CsCl gradient centrifugation).</s><s>Type strain OL<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700167) was isolated from the Owens Lake in California, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>