<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6288_nm.9967" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9967" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9967" rank="species">Sporacetigenium mesophilum</organism><reference id="rid.6288"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sporacetigenium mesophilum gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from an anaerobic digester treating municipal solid waste and sewage</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>721</fpage><lpage>725</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63686-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585683</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sporacetigenium mesophilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sporacetigenium mesophilum</em> (Gr. neut. n. <em>meson</em> the middle; N.L. adj. <em>philus</em> from Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>mesophilum</em> friendly to the middle, mesophilic, referring to its preference for moderate temperatures).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and general characters are as described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0·9–1·0×3·6–7·3 μm in size.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5·0–9·5 with an optimum at pH 6·5–7·0.</s><s>Acid is produced from a few mono- and disaccharides such as d-glucose, d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-xylose and d-maltose.</s><s>d-Galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, sucrose, rhamnose, trehalose, melibiose, melezitose and raffinose are fermented weakly.</s><s>Acid is not produced from sorbose, starch, inulin, glycogen, salicin, amygdalin, glycerol, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol or sorbitol.</s><s>Fermentation of d-lactose and ribose is variable.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, citrate, fumarate, malate, succinate, malonic acid, hippurate, sodium gluconate, butanedioic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid, cellulose and xylan.</s><s>Milk is not curdled.</s><s>Urease, lecithinase and lipase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive while Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and NH<sub>3</sub> are produced from PYG.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (7·1–16·5 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (9·4–14·1 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14·0–17·0 %), together with 3-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (13·6 %) and C<sub>17 : 1</sub> iso I (8·4 %) detected in the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ZLJ115<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16796<sup>T</sup>=AS 1.5019<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sludge of an anaerobic digester treating municipal solid waste and sewage.</s></p></content></protolog>