<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1349_nm.3923" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3923" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3923" rank="species">Clostridium cylindrosporum</organism><reference id="rid.1349"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Andreesen</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zindel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dürre</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium cylindrosporum, ex Barker and Beck 1972 nom. rev.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>206</fpage><lpage>208</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-2-206</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium cylindrosporum</i> (ex Barker and Beck 1942) sp. nov.,  nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium cylindrosporum</i> (cy.lin.dro.spo'rum. Gr.n. <i>kylindros</i> a cylinder; Gr.n. <i>sporos</i> a seed; N.L. adj. <i>cylindrosporum</i> cylinder spored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods with an average length of 3.3 μm and an average diameter of 0.8 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on solid medium unpigmented, flat, circular, and up to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Spore form cylindrical to oval, with a terminal to subterminal location.</s><s>Only actively growing cultures stain gram positive.</s><s>The pH optimum changes slightly with different substrates and ranges between pH 6.7 and 8.5.</s><s>Highest growth rates are observed at temperatures of 40 to 45°C; some growth occurs at 19°C.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>No growth occurs with a variety of carbohydrates, amino acids, aromatic compounds, organic acids (for a list see references 8 and 10), Milk medium, or chopped meat medium.</s><s>Only uric acid, xanthine, guanine, 6,8-dihydroxypurine, and hypoxanthine are used as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>A suitable medium has been described by Diirre et al. (8).</s><s>Glycine is fermented in combination with small amounts of uric acid or some other purines, whereas no degradation by growing cells occurs without the addition of a purine.</s><s>Marginal growth is observed with 4-aminoimidazole-5-carboxamide.</s><s>Some strains require thiamine and biotin for growth.</s><s>Selenite is an essential microdutrient.</s><s>Fermentation products from purines are acetate, formate, carbon dioxide, and ammonia; glycine is sometimes detectable in trace amounts (depending on the medium).</s><s>Acetoin, butanediol, butyrate, caproate, diacetyl, gas, indole, and sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Esculin, gelatin, and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Catalase, lecithinase, and urease activities are not detected.</s><s>Lipase is formed by a few strains.</s><s>No hemolysis of bovine erythrocytes occurs.</s><s>Growth occurs but is inhibited by the presence of 2% bile extract.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 27.2 to 30.4 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: various strains have been isolated from different soils and from chicken intestines.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the type strain is identical to that of the species; only thiamine and biotin are required vitamins.</s><s>Growth is optimal at pH 7.5 to 8.0.</s><s>Strain HC-1 of Barker and Beck (3) is the type strain and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen as strain DSM 605 (= ATCC 7905) (guanine-plus-cytosine content, 27.9 mol%) .</s></p></content></protolog>