<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3452_nm.1356" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1356" rank="family">Bartonellaceae</organism><reference id="rid.3452"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Connor</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winkler</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposals to unify the genera Bartonella and Rochalimaea, with descriptions of Bartonella quintana comb. nov., Bartonella vinsonii comb. nov., Bartonella henselae comb. nov., and Bartonella elizabethae comb. nov., and to remove the family Bartonellaceae from the order Rickettsiales.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>777</fpage><lpage>786</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-777</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the family <i>Bartonelleae</i> (Gieszczykiewicz 1939) Ristic and Krier 1984.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>It is proposed that the genus <i>Rochalimaea</i> should be transferred to the family <i>Bartonellaceae</i>. This requires emending the description of the <i>Bartonellaceae</i> (36) by integrating portions of the description of the genus <i>Rochalimaea</i> (56) and data for <i>Rochalimaea henselae</i> and <i>Rochalimaea elizabethae</i>, as follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Parasites of erythrocytes of humans and other vertebrates and of human cutaneous and osseous tissue.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped, cocci, or ring or disk shaped, often beaded or filamentous.</s><s>Greatest cell diameter is less than 3 μm.</s><s>Gram negative; aerobic; not acid fast.</s><s>Strains do not utilize carbohydrates.</s><s>One species has unipolar flagella.</s><s>Cultivable on bacteriologic media.</s><s>Arthropod transmission has been established for many species.</s><s>Human pathogens include etiologic agents of trench fever, bartonellosis, bacillary angiomatosis (10, 39, 40), peliosis hepatis, septicemia, and possibly cat scratch disease (32).</s><s>Animal species, which have been found in erythrocytes of rodents and other vertebrates, are nonpathogenic (48).</s><s>The type genus is <i>Bartonella</i> Strong, Tyzzer, and Sellards 1915</s></p></content></protolog>