<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7374_nm.1140" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1140" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1140" rank="species">Roseovarius tolerans</organism><reference id="rid.7374"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labrenz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseovarius tolerans gen. nov., sp. nov., a budding bacterium with variable bacteriochlorophyll a production from hypersaline Ekho Lake.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>137</fpage><lpage>147</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-137</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028255</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Roseovarius tolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Roseovarius tolerans</i> (tol'e.rans. L. part. adj. <i>tolerans</i> bearing/tolerating, as the bacterium endures stress conditions)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell sizes vary (0.7-1.0 x 1.1-2.2 μm), with a mean size of 0.74-0.83 x 1.34-1.94 μm.</s><s>On PYGV+ASW or R2A+ASW media, colonies of individual strains are smooth and convex and red, pinkish, beige to red, beige or whitish-beige.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 8-33.5°C with salt concentrations of 1.0-8.0 % NaCl or 10-13‰, ASW.</s><s>The optimum pH is 5.9-&#x003E;9.0.</s><s>Bchl <i>a</i> may be produced with a large in vivo absorption band at 877-879 nm and smaller ones at 589-591 and 799-802 nm.</s><s>The production of bchl <i>a</i> is repressed by constant dim light.</s><s>The isolates have a weak requirement for thiamin and nicotinic acid.</s><s>The requirement for vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is variable, and cells are stimulated by biotin but do not need pantothenate.</s><s>Alginate, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed, Tween 80 and DNA are only hydrolysed by some strains.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetate, pyruvate, malate, succinate, butyrate or glutamate, but not on citrate, methanesulfonic acid, methanol or α-D-glucose.</s><s>In the absence of any added nitrogen compounds, the cells grow slightly on acetate, pyruvate, succinate, malate and butyrate.</s><s>Glutamate is used with and without an additional source of combined nitrogen.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to chloramphenicol, streptomycin, penicillin G and tetracycline, but not to polymyxin B.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>The G+C content is 62.2-63.8 mol%.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic properties and other characteristics are as for the genus.</s><s>The type strain, <i>Roseovarius tolerans</i> EL- 172<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen under accession number DSM 11457<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Additional isolates of <i>Roseovarius tolerans</i> are EL-222 (=DSM 11463), EL-52, EL-78, EL-83, EL-90, EL-164 and EL-171.</s></p></content></protolog>