<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10552_nm.17791" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17791" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17791" rank="species">Halopiger aswanensis</organism><reference id="rid.10552"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hezayen</surname><given-names>F.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutiérrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steinbüchel</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rehm</surname><given-names>B.H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halopiger aswanensis sp. nov., a polymer-producing and extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from hypersaline soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>633</fpage><lpage>637</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013078-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654343</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halopiger aswanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halopiger aswanensis</em> (as.wan.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>aswanensis</em> isolated from a hypersaline soil in Aswan, Egypt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-negative, pleomorphic rods (short and long) measuring 1.25–6.50×0.6–0.9 μm and 0.9–3.75×0.6–0.9 μm from liquid and solid cultivation media under optimum conditions, respectively.</s><s>Colonies may be pink-pigmented and small.</s><s>Cells require at least 1.7 M (10 % w/v) NaCl for growth.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 3.8–4.3 M (22.5–25 %) NaCl with an optimum pH of 7.5 and an optimum temperature of 40 °C.</s><s>Cells are able to grow over a pH range of 6–9.2.</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 55 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells lyse in distilled water.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur even in the presence of KNO<sub>3</sub> or arginine.</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> is not required for growth.</s><s>Indole was produced from tryptone, sulfide was produced from cysteine, and starch, Tween 20, Tween 40 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, gelatin or lipids from egg yolk are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose and starch, but not from lactose.</s><s>Susceptible to fusidic acid, bacitracin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, anisomycin, trimethoprim and rifampicin.</s><s>Resistant to nystatin, tetracycline, nalidixic acid, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin and penicillin.</s><s>Organic nitrogenous compounds, e.g. proteose peptone, tryptone, Casamino acids and non-nitrogenous compounds such as some carbohydrates and acetate, gluconate and pyruvate can be used as the carbon and energy source.</s><s>Menaquinones are the only respiratory lipoquinones present and comprise MK-8 (67.5 %) and MK-8(VIII-H<sub>2</sub>) (32.5 %).</s><s>Polar lipid analysis shows the presence of the bis-sulfated glycolipid S<sub>2</sub>-DGD-1 as the sole glycolipid and the glycerol diether analogue of phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.</s><s>Growth occurs with starch or other compounds as the sole carbon and energy source in the presence of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl as the sole nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 56<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13151<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11628<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface of hypersaline salt soils close to Aswan, Egypt.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of type strain is 67.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>