<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6692_nm.10773" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10773" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10773" rank="species">Halomonas salaria</organism><reference id="rid.6692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas gomseomensis sp. nov., Halomonas janggokensis sp. nov., Halomonas salaria sp. nov. and Halomonas denitrificans sp. nov., moderately halophilic bacteria isolated from saline water.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>675</fpage><lpage>681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64767-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392185</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas salaria</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas salaria</em> (sa.la′ri.a. L. fem. adj. <em>salaria</em> of or belonging to salt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods (0.8–0.9×1.3–1.7 μm).</s><s>Colonies are yellow, smooth, translucent and circular with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are motile with lateral/polar flagella.</s><s>Oxidase-positive and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH 5–10 (optimum pH 7–8).</s><s>Growth occurs at salinities of 0–25 % NaCl (optimum 10–20 % NaCl).</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Casein and DNA are hydrolysed, but aesculin, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, mannitol, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, d-lyxose, d-fucose and d-arabitol, but not from d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: mannitol, d-glucose, d-ribose, l-fucose, maltose, mannose, l-arabinose, itaconate, gluconate, propionate, malate, valerate, acetate, adipate, citrate, dl-lactate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, d-melibiose, inositol, sucrose, d-sorbitol, suberate, caprate, malonate, phenylacetate, histidine, l-alanine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, glycogen, 4-hydroxybenzoate and 3-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are available as Supplementary Table S2.</s><s>The predominant quinone is ubiquinone Q-9; a small amount of Q-8 is also present.</s><s>The fatty acids C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> are predominant.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 58.8–60.1 mol% (58.8 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M27<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12664<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18044<sup>T</sup>), isolated from seawater in Anmyeondo, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>