<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7083_nm.5519" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5519" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5519" rank="species">Marinilactibacillus psychrotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.7083"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yanagi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinilactibacillus psychrotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic and alkaliphilic marine lactic acid bacterium isolated from marine organisms in temperate and subtropical areas of Japan.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>711</fpage><lpage>720</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02446-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807191</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinilactibacillus psychrotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinilactibacillus psychrotolerans</em> (psy.chro.to′le.rans. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. adj. <em>psychrotolerans</em> tolerating cold temperature).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species has all of the characteristics that define the genus.</s><s>In addition, it has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Deep colonies in agar medium are pale yellow, opaque and lenticular with diameters of 2–4 mm.</s><s>Cells are 0·4–0·5×2·3–4·5 μm and elongated in older cultures.</s><s>Grows evenly throughout a column of semi-solid agar medium.</s><s>Acid is produced from a fairly wide range of carbohydrates, sugar alcohols and related carbon compounds (Table 1).</s><s>Sodium gluconate is fermented without gas production.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain M13-2<sup>T</sup> is 36·2 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a living sponge, raw Japanese ivory shell and decomposing alga.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited at the IAM Culture Collection, the Institute of Molecular and Cellular Biosciences, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan, the NITE Biological Resource Center (NBRC), National Institute of Technology and Evaluation, Kisarazu, Japan, the National Collections of Industrial, Food and Marine Bacteria (NCIMB), Aberdeen, UK and the Nodai Culture Collection Center (NRIC), Tokyo University of Agriculture, Tokyo, Japan, under the accession numbers IAM 14980<sup>T</sup>, NBRC 100002<sup>T</sup>, NCIMB 13873<sup>T</sup> and NRIC 0510<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>