<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12634_nm.22172" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22172" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22172" rank="species">Thiocystis chemoclinalis</organism><reference id="rid.12634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peduzzi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Welsh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Demarta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Decristophoris</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peduzzi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tonolla</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiocystis chemoclinalis sp. nov. and Thiocystis cadagnonensis sp. nov., motile purple sulfur bacteria isolated from the chemocline of a meromictic lake</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1682</fpage><lpage>1687</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010397-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20729307</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thiocystis chemoclinalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thiocystis chemoclinalis</em> (che.mo.cli.na′lis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>chemoclinalis</em> pertaining to chemocline, found to inhabit environments with steep physico-chemical gradients, isolated from the chemocline of a meromictic freshwater lake).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical to ovoid (~2.3–3.6 µm in diameter) and occur as singularly but can form small aggregates of up to 5–10 cells.</s><s>Rod-shaped cells may be observed at the end of the stationary phase.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile by means of flagella and divide by binary fission.</s><s>The colour of cell suspensions is purple–red.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments, including bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids of the okenone group, are present.</s><s>Phototrophic growth occurs under anoxic conditions.</s><s>In the presence of reduced sulfur compounds (sulfide, thiosulfate), globules of elemental sulfur are formed and appear to be randomly distributed within the cells.</s><s>Growth also occurs on elemental sulfur as sole electron source.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, glucose, fructose and ethanol are photo-assimilated in the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate.</s><s>Chemolithotrophic growth is observed in the presence of oxygen in the dark with sulfide and thiosulfate.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–25 °C (optimum 20 °C) and pH 6.6–7.5 (optimum pH 7.2).</s><s>Salt is not required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CadH11<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 15112<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 5954<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the boundary layer (chemocline) between the oxic upper layer and the anoxic sulfidic layer along steep physico-chemical gradients of Lake Cadagno, a meromictic alpine lake in the southern Swiss Alps at 1923 m above sea level (46° 33′ N 8° 43′ E).</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>