<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8507_nm.13288" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13288" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13288" rank="species">Corynebacterium ulceribovis</organism><reference id="rid.8507"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium ulceribovis sp. nov., isolated from the skin of the udder of a cow with a profound ulceration</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>34</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65832-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium ulceribovis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium ulceribovis</em> (ul.ce.ri.bo′vis. L. n. <em>ulcus</em> -<em>eris</em> ulcer; L. n. <em>bos</em> <em>bovis</em> a cow, a bull; N.L. gen. n. <em>ulceribovis</em> of an ulcer of a cow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods.</s><s>Colonies are creamy, circular, smooth, entire and 2–4 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation at 37 °C on Columbia agar supplemented with 5 % sheep blood.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are non-haemolytic.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, but not from l-arabinose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Hippurate and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but aesculin, gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>Activity is detected for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, pyrazinamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>No activity is detected for arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cysteine arylamidase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin production is positive.</s><s>Corynemycolic acids are present.</s><s>Long-chain cellular acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types, with C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> predominating; tuberculostearic acid is not present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB L-1395<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45146<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55727<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the skin of the udder of a cow with a profound ulceration, in Schleswig Holstein, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>