<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6504_nm.10252" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10252" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10252" rank="species">Thiorhodococcus mannitoliphagus</organism><reference id="rid.6504"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rabold</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiorhodococcus mannitoliphagus sp. nov., a purple sulfur bacterium from the White Sea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1945</fpage><lpage>1951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63981-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thiorhodococcus mannitoliphagus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thiorhodococcus mannitoliphagus</em> (mann.i.to′li.pha′gus. N.L. n. <em>mannitolum</em> mannitol; Gr. v. <em>phagein</em> to eat; N.L. masc. adj. <em>mannitoliphagus</em> consuming mannitol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid with mean cell diameter of 1.85 μm.</s><s>During binary fission, diplococci are formed.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile by flagella and do not contain gas vesicles.</s><s>In the stationary growth phase, cells form irregular microcolonies.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is purple–violet.</s><s>Photosynthetic membrane system is of the vesicular type.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids of the rhodopinal series.</s><s>Phototrophic growth occurs under anoxic conditions in the light.</s><s>No growth occurs under microaerobic conditions in the light or under chemotrophic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required as a growth factor.</s><s>Electron donors used for photolithoautotrophic growth are sulfide, thiosulfate, sulfite and elemental sulfur.</s><s>Globules of elemental sulfur, which are formed during photolithoautotrophic growth with sulfide and thiosulfate, are stored transiently inside the cells and are oxidized further to sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of carbonate and a reduced sulfur source (sulfide and/or thiosulfate), oxoglutarate, fructose, acetate, lactate, pyruvate, malate, peptone, Casamino acids, yeast extract, propionate, succinate, fumarate, glucose and mannitol are photoassimilated.</s><s>The utilization of mannitol results in an outstanding increase in growth.</s><s>Conditions for optimal growth are 25–30 °C, 2000 lx (42 μmol m<sup>−2</sup> s<sup>−1</sup>), pH 7.0–7.5 and concentrations of 0.5–2 % NaCl.</s><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 61.8 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WS<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1228<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2393<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from microbial mat communities of an estuary of the White Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>