<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3705_nm.9343" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9343" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9343" rank="species">Bradyrhizobium canariense</organism><reference id="rid.3705"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vinuesa</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>León-Barrios</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Silva</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jarabo-Lorenzo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pérez-Galdona</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Werner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bradyrhizobium canariense sp. nov., an acid-tolerant endosymbiont that nodulates endemic genistoid legumes (Papilionoideae: Genisteae) from the Canary Islands, along with Bradyrhizobium japonicum bv. genistearum, Bradyrhizobium genospecies alpha and Bradyrhizobium genospecies beta</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>569</fpage><lpage>575</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63292-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774626</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bradyrhizobium canariense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bradyrhizobium canariense</em> [ca.na.ri.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>canariense</em> pertaining to the Canary Islands (Islas Canarias), where it is the dominant species nodulating endemic shrub legumes Papilionoideae: Genisteae].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, slow-growing, non-spore-forming rods, as for other species of the genus, motile by a single subpolar flagellum (León-Barrios <em>et al.</em>, 1991).</s><s>Phenotypically, <em>B. canariense</em> strains are highly diverse.</s><s>Colonies on YMA (pH 6·8) are white or creamy, 1–1·5 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation at 28 °C, producing an acid reaction and variable amounts of exopolysaccharides, as reflected by the diverse textures, consistencies and growth patterns they exhibit on solid media.</s><s>Their lipopolysaccharide (LPS) O-antigens are also highly diverse as determined by DOC-PAGE analysis of purified LPSs and immunological cross-reactions (León-Barrios <em>et al.</em>, 1991; Santamaría <em>et al.</em>, 1997).</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 28–30 °C, but inhibited at 37 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at pH 9, or in the presence of 1 % NaCl on YMA.</s><s>They use (+)-d-glucose, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-d-galactose, (−)-d-fructose, (−)-l-rhamnose, (+)-d-xylose, (−)-d-ribose, (−)-d-arabinose, glycerol, mannitol, sorbitol, citrate, fumarate and succinate, but not (−)-l-sorbose, melibiose, lactose, sucrose, (+)-d-trehalose, inulin, starch or catechol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Use l-glutamine but not l-glycine as sole N source.</s><s>They are highly acid-tolerant, forming colonies of 1 mm in diameter after 6 to 7 days incubation at 30 °C on acidified 20E plates at pH 4·2 solidified with GelRite (Roth, Germany) and buffered with 25 mM Homopipes (Vinuesa <em>et al.</em>, 2003).</s><s>The symbiotic genes map to the chromosome, lacking plasmids as revealed by Eckhardt gel-electrophoresis (Eckhardt, 1978).</s><s>Its known geographical distribution includes Spain, Morocco, the Canary Islands and the Americas.</s><s>A single biovariety (bv. <em>genistearum</em>) is presently known, which nodulates different genera and species in the legume tribe Genisteae (e.g. <em>Lupinus</em> spp., <em>Adenocarpus</em> spp., <em>Chamaecytisus proliferus</em>, <em>Spartocytisus supranubius</em> and <em>Teline</em> spp.), as well as <em>Ornithopus</em> spp. (Papilionoideae: Loteae), but does not nodulate soybeans (<em>Glycine max</em> or <em>Glycine soja</em>, Papilionoideae: Phaseoleae).</s><s>At the molecular level this species can be easily distinguished from strains of its sister species <em>B. japonicum</em> and all other described <em>Bradyrhizobium</em> species by the unique 16S rRNA PCR-RFLP genotype obtained with the endonucleases <em>Hha</em>I, <em>Dde</em>I and <em>Hin</em>fI (Jarabo-Lorenzo <em>et al.</em>, 2000, 2003; Vinuesa <em>et al.</em>, 1998, 1999, 2005). <em>B. canariense</em> strains also display a distinct fingerprint of stable low-molecular-weight RNAs (Jarabo-Lorenzo <em>et al.</em>, 2000).</s><s>It forms statistically highly supported ITS, <em>atpD</em>, <em>glnII</em> and <em>recA</em> sequence clades under the maximum-likelihood optimality criterion using best-fit models of nucleotide substitution (with bootstrap support &#x003E;90 % in all cases). <em>B. canariense</em> strains are only weakly clonal, with significant recombination taking place within populations.</s><s>DNA homology is greater than 69 % between <em>B. canariense</em> strains, and lower than 50 % with <em>B. japonicum</em> or <em>B. liaoningense</em> strains, its closest phylogenetic relatives.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BTA-1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1002<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22265<sup>T</sup>=CFNE 1008<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the root nodules of <em>Chamaecytisus proliferus</em> subsp. <em>proliferus</em> var. palmensis (Papilionoideae: Genisteae) in La Laguna, Tenerife, Canary Islands, Spain, and has a G+C content of 63·8 mol%.</s><s>This and other <em>B. canariense</em> strains have been deposited at the strain collections of the CIFN-UNAM and the Departments of Microbiology at the Universities of La Laguna and Gent, from where they are freely available.</s></p></content></protolog>