<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9958_nm.14942" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14942" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14942" rank="species">Kosmotoga olearia</organism><reference id="rid.9958"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>DiPippo</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nesbø</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dahle</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doolittle</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birkland</surname><given-names>N.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Noll</surname><given-names>K.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kosmotoga olearia gen. nov., sp. nov., a thermophilic, anaerobic heterotroph isolated from an oil production fluid</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2991</fpage><lpage>3000</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008045-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643902</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kosmotoga olearia</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kosmotoga olearia</em> (o.le.a′ri.a. L. fem. adj. <em>olearia</em> of or belonging to oil, describing the environment from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.4–0.7 μm wide and 0.8–1.2 μm long, with one to three cells per sheath (toga).</s><s>Rarely found in chains or aggregations of up to 50 cells.</s><s>Spherical forms appear in stationary phase.</s><s>Motile forms and flagella are not observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on TBFXP 1 % (w/v) Gelrite bottle plates with maltose at 65 °C are 0.5–2.5 mm in diameter, circular with entire margins, convex, mucoid and opaque, grey with a slight yellow hue.</s><s>Colonies grown on TBFXP 1 % (w/v) Gelrite Petri dishes with maltose at 37 °C are similar in form but larger (up to 5 mm in diameter).</s><s>Grows at 20–80 °C.</s><s>Heat-resistant forms (but not spores) are detected up to 90 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.0 and 10–60 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>The doubling time under optimal growth conditions (65 °C) is 103 min.</s><s>At 37 °C, the optimal doubling time is 175 min.</s><s>Anaerobic heterotroph; requires a reduced growth medium, but relatively tolerant of oxygen.</s><s>Maltose, ribose, sucrose, starch, Casamino acids, tryptone and pyruvate can serve as growth substrates.</s><s>Fructose, galactose, mannose, raffinose, xylan, casein and peptone allow relatively weaker growth.</s><s>Requires yeast extract for growth.</s><s>Acetate, lactate and propionate inhibit growth slightly, while malate and butanol prevent growth.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, maltose is fermented primarily into hydrogen, carbon dioxide and acetic acid.</s><s>Traces of ethanol and propionic acid are detected, but not butyric acid or alanine.</s><s>Arabinose, CM-cellulose, cellobiose, glucose, lactose, xylose, methanol, propanol, chitin, <em>myo</em>-inositol, putrescine and glycerol do not serve as carbon sources.</s><s>Thiosulfate enhances growth, while elemental sulfur, nitrate and cystine do not.</s><s>Sulfate also enhances growth, but sulfide is not produced.</s><s>Sulfite inhibits growth slightly and nitrite prevents growth.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by vancomycin and chloramphenicol (each at 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and 50 μg rifampicin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of ampicillin, carbenicillin, kanamycin and streptomycin (each at 100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 42.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TBF 19.5.1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21960<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1733<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from oil production fluid from the Troll B platform in the North Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>