<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7628_nm.14052" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14052" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14052" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter kameinonensis</organism><reference id="rid.7628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aizawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sunairi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter kameinonensis sp., nov., isolated from garden soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2046</fpage><lpage>2050</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65777-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768602</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter kameinonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter kameinonensis</em> (ka.me.i.no.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kameinonensis</em> pertaining to Kameino, the location from which the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-endospore-forming, non-motile, aerobic, irregular rods, 0.3–0.7 μm wide and 0.8–3.5 μm long.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA and IB agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are pale pink, mucoid, convex and round with entire margins on TSA and IB agar.</s><s>Growth occurs between 5 and 30 °C with an optimum at 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 4–9, with optimum growth at pH 5–8.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of 1 % (w/v) NaCl or higher.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and Tweens 20 and 60, but negative for casein and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>Positive for activities of <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, catalase, cystine arylamidase, DNase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase, but negative for activities of arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, heparinase, lipase (C14), lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, oxidase, tryptophan deaminase and urease, as determined with the API ZYM system.</s><s>Positive for the Voges–Proskauer test, but negative for hydrogen sulphide and indole production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Positive for acid production from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, potassium 5-ketogluconate, raffinose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose, but negative for acid production from d-adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, glycerol, inositol, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, xylitol and l-xylose, as determined with the API 50CH system.</s><s>Positive for Biolog GN2 MicroPlate substrates cellobiose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, l-proline, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose, but negative for acetic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, adonitol, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, 2,3-butanediol, d- and l-carnitine, citrate, i-erythritol, formic acid, l-fucose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, d-glucuronic acid, l-glutamic acid, d- and l-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d- and l-lactic acid, l-leucine, malate, d-mannitol, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, phenylethylamine, propionic acid, d-psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, d- and l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, l-threonine, thymidine, Tweens 40 and 80, uridine, urocanic acid and xylitol.</s><s>Resistant to apramycin, cefoperazone, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, colistin, enrofloxacin, erythromycin, flumequine, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, metronidazole, nitrofurantoin, oxacillin, oxolinic acid, penicillin, rifampicin and streptomycin, but sensitive to amoxicillin, augmentin, cotrimoxazole, doxycycline, fusidic acid, pristinamycin, spectinomycin, sulphamethizole, tetracycline and tylosin (API VET system).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7 and the major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (25.9 %) and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) (49.2 %).</s><s>Sphingolipids are present, with d-17 : 0 as the main dihydrosphingosine.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 43.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SCK<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 102645<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22227<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from the campus of the College of Bioresource Sciences, Nihon University, at Kameino, Fujisawa, Kanagawa, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>