<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4547_nm.5975" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5975" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5975" rank="species">Tropheryma whipplei</organism><reference id="rid.4547"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>La Scola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fenollar</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fournier</surname><given-names>P.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altwegg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Tropheryma whipplei gen. nov., sp. nov., the Whipple's disease bacillus.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1479</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491348</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tropheryma whipplei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tropheryma whipplei</i> (whipp'le.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>whipplei</i> of Whipple, after George Whipple, who described the first patient with the clinical syndrome that is today known as Whipple's disease)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formerly named `<i>Tropheryma whippelii</i> '.</s><s>Short rods, 0.25-0.3 μm in diameter and 0.8-1.7 μm long, sometimes longer when cell division is impaired.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Flagella do not occur.</s><s>The plasma-membrane is surrounded by a thin homogeneous wall and by a plasma membrane-like structure, resulting in a trilamellar appearance of the cell wall under electron microscopy.</s><s>Appear Gram-negative.</s><s>Ziehl-negative.</s><s>Retain basic fuchsin when stained by the method of Gimenez when intracellular.</s><s>Well stained by PAS staining.</s><s>Although we have shown that the bacterium can be observed extracellularly, it has not been cultivated in the absence of host cells.</s><s>Grows well in or associated with HEL and MRC-5 cells in minimal essential medium with 10% foetal calf serum and 2 mM l-glutamine when incubated at 37 °C in a 5% CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere.</s><s>May be observed in an intracellular or extracellular location.</s><s>When extracellular, has a tendency to aggregate in masses of bacteria embedded in an extracellular matrix, with the appearance of long, rope-like structures.</s><s>Doubling time has been estimated to be 18 d.</s><s>Well preserved by rapid freezing and storage at -80 °C.</s><s>On SDS-PAGE, proteins of 213 to 10 kDa are detected, with major bands of 213 and 85 kDa.</s><s>Sequence of the 16S rDNA gene places it in the class <i>Actinomycetes</i> and sequences of the 16S-23S rDNA ITS and domain III of the 23S rDNA identify the strain as genotype 2A.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content of strain Twist-MarseilleT is 59.4 mol%.</s><s>Opportunistic pathogen for humans.</s><s>Responsible for Whipple's disease, a systemic infection with symptoms of fever, weight loss, diarrhoea, polyadenopathy and polyarthritis.</s><s>Occasionally responsible for cardiac manifestations such as myocarditis, pericarditis and endocarditis or central nervous system involvement that may include dementia, lethargy and neurological deficits or ocular diseases such as uveitis.</s><s>The type strain is Twist-Marseille<sup>T</sup> (=CNCM I-2202<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the aortic valve of a patient with endocarditis.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the Collection Nationale de Cultures de Micro-organismes (CNCM, Institut Pasteur, Paris, France) and the Collection de l'Unité des Rickettsies (WHO Collaborative Center for Rickettsial Reference and Research, Marseilles, France), and is available upon request from the authors or from the Institut National de la Propriété Industrielle (Paris, France).</s></p></content></protolog>