<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1070_nm.3189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3189" rank="species">Erwinia psidii</organism><reference id="rid.1070"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Neto</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robbs</surname><given-names>C.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamashiro</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A bacterial disease of guava, Psidium guajava caused by Erwinia psidii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>345</fpage><lpage>350</lpage><source id="332">Fitopatologia Brasileira</source><abbrev>Fitopatol Bras</abbrev><issn>0100-4158</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia psidii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia psidii</i> sp.nov. (<i>psi. di. i.</i> L. n. <i>Psidium</i> generic name).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods. measuring 1.0-2.7x0.5-0.8 micrometers non spore forming, occurina singly, in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Gram negative and motile by pentrichous flagella.</s><s>Slow growth on GYCA and glucose nutrient agar media.</s><s>Colonies on KB medium are circular, smooth or wrinkled, glistening, white, without production of diffusible pigments on KB or on GYCA media.</s><s>Facultative anaerobe fermentative metabolism of glucose.</s><s>No growth factors are required and there is no visible development at 36°C after 7 days.</s><s>Acid  ut no gas produced from the following carbohydrates; inositol, L-arabinose,  orbitol, rhamnose, salicin dulcitol, mannose, sucrose, fructose, galactose and mannitol.</s><s>No acid produced from: rafffinose, cellobiose. lactose, xylose, trehalose, and α-methyl-glucoside.</s><s>Succinate is utilized, but not acetate, benzoate, malonate, oxalate and tartrate.</s><s>Positive in catalase, hydrogen sulphide, leaven, and reducing substances from sucrose.</s><s>Negative in oxidase, urease, acetoin, indol, nitrate reduction, casein and starch hydrolyses, pectate degradation and gelatin liquefaction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenic to guava (<i>Psidium guajara</i> L.) causing a die-back of twigs and branches, characterized by a collapse of the vascular tissue.</s><s>In artificial inoculations, the bacterium was also pathogenic to strawberry guava (<i>Psidium cattleianum</i> Lam.), jambolana (<i>Eugenia jambolana</i> Lam.) and "melaleuca" (<i>Melaleuca viridiflora</i> Brogn. &#x0026; Gris.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G+C of the DNA is 51.7- 52.2 (Tm).</s><s>No hypmensitive reaction was observed on infiltrated tobacco leaves.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolates of <i>Erwinia psidii</i> sp. nov. have been deposited at the PDDCC, Aukland, New Zealand.</s><s>The isolate IBSBF 435 (=PDDCC 8426) is designated as the type culture of the bacterium.</s></p></content></protolog>