<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12306_nm.20322" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20322" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20322" rank="species">Chryseobacterium hagamense</organism><reference id="rid.12306"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>D.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Four new species of Chryseobacterium from the rhizosphere of coastal sand dune plants, Chryseobacterium elymi sp. nov., Chryseobacterium hagamense sp. nov., Chryseobacterium lathyri sp. nov. and Chryseobacterium rhizosphaerae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2009.12.004</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium hagamense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(ha.ga.men'se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>hagamense</em> of Hagam, geographic location where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth is observed on TSA, nutrient agar and R2A agar, but there is no growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, circular and shiny.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 30–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, but not at 5 °C or 42 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5–10, and that for optimal growth is pH 7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2% (<em>w</em>/<em>v</em>) NaCl within 14 days.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is given in <a href="#tbl2">Table 2</a>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 36.9 mol%.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose (weakly), glycerol, maltose, D-mannitol and trehalose, but not from L-arabinose, lactose and D-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>i</em>-erythritol, D-fructose, L-fucose (weakly), D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, D-melibiose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-psicose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid (weakly), citric acid, formic acid, D-galacturonic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid (weakly), succinic acid, L-alaninamide, L-alanine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-D-galactosamine (weakly), L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol (weakly), α-D-lactose, lactulose (weakly), maltose, D-mannose, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid (weakly), D-glucuronic acid (weakly), hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid (weakly), γ-hydroxybutyric acid (weakly), malonic acid (weakly), propionic acid, quinic acid (weakly), D-saccharic acid (weakly), sebacic acid (weakly), succinamic acid, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-aspartic acid, glycyl L-glutamic acid, L-serine, L-threonine, 2,3-butanediol (weakly), α-glucose-1-phosphate and D-glucose-6-phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: D-galactonic acid lactone, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, D-alanine, L-histidine, L-ornithine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-D-glucosamine, adonitol, D-arabitol, mannitol, L-pyroglutamic acid, D-serine, DL-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol and DL-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Other properties are given in <a href="#tbl1">Table 1</a>.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are given in <a href="#sec7">Supplementary Table S1</a>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is RHA2-9<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22545<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 105253<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the rhizosphere of wild pea (<em>Lathyrus japonica</em>) growing in a coastal sand dune area.</s></p></content></protolog>