<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5606_nm.9872" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9872" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9872" rank="species">Patulibacter minatonensis</organism><reference id="rid.5606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morisaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ōmura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Patulibacter minatonensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated using an agar medium supplemented with superoxide dismutase, and proposal of Patulibacteraceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>401</fpage><lpage>406</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63796-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449447</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Patulibacter minatonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Patulibacter minatonensis</em> (mi.na.to.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>minatonensis</em> pertaining to Minato-ku, the ward of Tokyo, Japan, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Forms flat and nearly transparent colonies with a whitish or pale yellow colour.</s><s>Cells are 1·2–1·5×0·6–0·7 μm in size, motile by long flagella, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates: dextrin, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, turanose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-serine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, inosine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, d-ribose, d-tagatose, d-xylose, acetic acid, propionic acid, d-alanine, putrescine, maltose, potassium gluconate, adipic acid and l-malic acid.</s><s>Shows the following enzyme activities: alkaline phosphatase, elastase (C4), elastase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative result in Biolog substrate panels, API ZYM enzyme assay and API NE gallery tests for: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, amygdalin, arbutin, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, palatinose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylitol, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-malic acid, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl l-glutamic acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycerol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, thymidine, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, n-decanoic acid, citric acid, phenylacetate, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, tryptophan degradation, glucose fermentation, gelatin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Does not grow on media containing 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–8.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 16–28 °C.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to tetracycline (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), amikacin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), tobramycin (10 μg), vancomycin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), ampicillin (10 μg) and imipenem (10 μg).</s><s>Cells are resistant to aztreonam (30 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), nalidixic acid (1 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg) and oxacillin (1 μg).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KV-614<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-24346<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12834<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100761<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>