<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5064_nm.6817" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6817" rank="genus">Streptomyces</organism><reference id="rid.5064"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Witt</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Unification of the genera Streptoverticillium and Streptomyces, and amendation of Streptomyces Waksman and Henrici 1943, 339 AL.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>361</fpage><lpage>371</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> Waksman and Henrici 1943, 339AL.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> (18) together with emendation, including <i>Streptoverticillium</i> (22) and adding to the description to include <i>Kitasatosporia</i> (10), forms the basis for this emendation. Vegetative hyphae (0.5 to 0.2 μm in diameter) produce a well-developed branched mycelium that rarely fragments. Reproduction by germination of the aerial, nonmotile spores. In most species, the aerial mycelium forms chains of spores, the surfaces of which are smooth, hairy, spiny, or warty. In other species, the aerial mycelium consists of long straight filaments bearing branches (3 to 6) at regular intervals which are arranged in whorls (verticils). The appearance at ca. 100 magnification is of barbed wire, Each branch of the verticil produces at its apex an umbel of two or more spore chains, with spores lacking ornaments. A few species produce spores on the substrate mycelium or in liquid culture. Sclerotia, pycnidia, sporangiumlike bodies, and synnemalike structures may be formed. Form discrete and lichenoid, leathery or butyrous colonies. Initially, colonies are smooth surfaced but later develop a weft of aerial mycelium that may appear floccose, cottony, granular, powdery, or velvety.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produce a wide variety of pigments responsible for the color of the vegetative and aerial mycelia.</s><s>Colored diffusible pigments may also be formed.</s><s>Many strains produce one or more antibiotics.</s><s>Gram positive but not acid fast.</s><s>Aerobes.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, having an oxidative type of metabolism.</s><s>Most strains use a wide range of organic compounds as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth, but some can utilize only a limited number of carbon sources.</s><s>Substrate growth may develop under reduced oxygen tensions or increased carbon dioxide concentrations.</s><s>Temperature optimum, 25 to 35°C at pH 5.5 to 9.0; some species grow at temperatures within the psychrophilic and thermophilic ranges.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains major amounts of LL-DAP in spores and hyphae; major amounts of <i>meso</i>-DAP may be detected in the vegetative hyphae.</s><s>Galactose may be present in the whole-cell hydrolysate.</s><s>They lack mycolic acids, contain major amounts of saturated, iso-, and anteisofatty acids, possess either hexa- or octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenolog, and have complex polar lipid patterns that typically contain diphosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyldiglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylmannosides.</s><s>They are widely distributed in soil, including compost.</s><s>A few species are pathogenic for animals and humans; others are phytopathogens.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66 to 78 mol% (at melting temperature).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: <i>S. albus</i> (Rossi-Doria) Waksman and Henrici 1943, 339.</s></p></content></protolog>