<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6103_nm.10248" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10248" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10248" rank="species">Shewanella loihica</organism><reference id="rid.6103"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Obraztova</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stewart</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Popa</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fredrickson</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nealson</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella loihica sp. nov., isolated from iron-rich microbial mats in the Pacific Ocean.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1911</fpage><lpage>1916</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64354-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella loihica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella loihica</em> (lo.i.hi′ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>loihica</em> of Loihi Seamount, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, straight rod with a mean length of 1.8 μm and a mean width of 0.7 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Facultative psychrotolerant anaerobe.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, glistening, circular, flat to slightly raised, orange in colour and 2.0–4.0 mm in diameter after 2 days incubation in air at room temperature on Luria–Bertani agar plates.</s><s>Grows at temperatures ranging from 0 to 42 °C, with 18 °C as the optimum.</s><s>Does not grow at temperatures above 43 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 4.5–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–8.0).</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> is required for growth.</s><s>Grows at 0.5–5 % NaCl, with an optimum at 2 % NaCl; does not grow in the presence of more than 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>With lactate as the substrate, fumarate, MnO<sub>2</sub>, ferric citrate, akaganeite, cobalt [Co(III)] EDTA, potassium chromate, uranyl carbonate, hydrous ferric oxides and trimethylamine <em>N</em>-oxide are reduced, but ferric EDTA, nitrate, nitrite, thiosulfate, sulfur, sulfate, sulfite and DMSO are not.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, rifampicin and tetracycline.</s><s>Slightly susceptible to spectinomycin and streptomycin.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, Tween 20 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, citrate utilization, <em>p</em>-phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and malonate utilization.</s><s>Negative for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-phospho-6-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamate arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamate arylamidase, serine arylamidase, lysine decarboxylase, mannose fermentation, raffinose fermentation, indole formation and acetoin production.</s><s>Positive for utilization of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, succinate, dl-malate, l-malate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, alanine, threonine, isoleucine, leucine, glycyl aspartate, glycyl glutamate, glycyl proline, alanyl glycine, gelatin, <em>α</em>-ketobutyrate, monomethyl succinate, pyruvate, butyrate, caproate, <em>β</em>-hydroxypyruvate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, dextrin, d-galactose, maltose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>γ</em>-cyclodextrin, maltotriose, adenosine, inosine, Tween 20, Tween 80, chondroitin sulfate, acetamide, putrescine and 2,3-butanediol; negative for utilization of acetate, propionate and Tween 40.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, l-rhamnose, d-cellobiose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose or d-glucose.</s><s>Fatty acids C<sub>i13 : 0</sub> (10 %), iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (36 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (5 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (3 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8 (13 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 (3 %) are present.</s><s>Quinone composition is Q-7 (53 %), Q-8 (28 %) and MK-7 (74 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 53.8 mol% (http://www.jgi.doe.gov) and the genome size is about 4.5 Mbp.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PV-4<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1088<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17748<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from iron-rich microbial mats at the active, deep-sea, hydrothermal Naha Vent located on the South Rift of Loihi Seamount, Hawaii, in the Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>