<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1609_nm.8368" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8368" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8368" rank="species">Fusobacterium simiae</organism><reference id="rid.1609"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slots</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potts</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium simiae, a new species from monkey dental plaque.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>191</fpage><lpage>194</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusabacterium simiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusabacterium simiae</i> sp. nov. (sim'i.ae.L. fem. noun <i>simia</i> monkey; L. gen. noun <i>simiae</i> of the monkey)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains which we isolated were gram-negative, nonmotile, anaerobic organisms.</s><s>The cells were 0.7 to 1.0 by 5.0 to 8.0 μm and were cigar shaped with pointed ends, a morphology typical of fusobacteria (Fig. 1).</s><s>After anaerobic incubation for 5 days on brain heart infusion blood agar plates, the colonies were 1.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, circular, convex, entire, grayish, translucent, and slightly glistening.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA study revealed that the three monkey strains examined contained 27 to 28.5 mol% guanine plus cytosine (Table 1).</s><s>In addition, the hybridization data obtained with a 3H-labeled strain 7511 R2-13 DNA probe showed that these three strains were genetically similar (Table 1).</s><s>Also, the DNA-DNA homologies with type strains of other <i>Fusobacterium</i> species were less than 50% (Table l), indicating that the monkey strains possessed a unique DNA composition.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 2 shows the biochemical test results for the 10 isolates.</s><s>There was a close overall similarity among the strains studied.</s><s>These strains fermented glucose and fructose but not the 27 other carbohydrates studied.</s><s>They were indole positive, produced hydrogen sulfide (as determined by lead acetate test paper), reduced litmus milk, hydrolyzed hippurate, and decarboxylated glutamic acid.</s><s>Otherwise, the organisms were basically inert in commonly used biochemical tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The acid end products formed in glucose broth cultures included large amounts of butyric acid and smaller quantities of acetic and propionic acids (Table 3).</s><s>An analysis of the metabolic products also showed that pyruvate was utilized and propionate was produced from threonine.</s><s>Lactate was not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 4 shows the results of susceptibility tests.</s><s>The strains were resistant to most dyes.</s><s>They were also resistant to erythromycin but susceptible to chloramphenicol, clindamycin, metronidazole, penicillin, and tetracycline.</s><s>In addition, the organisms grew in the presence of 2% oxgall but did not grow on MacConkey agar, Simmons citrate agar, or Levine eosin methylene blue agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species is strain 7511 R2-13 (= ATCC 33568).</s></p></content></protolog>