<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.486_nm.14946" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14946" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5978" rank="species">Dermabacter hominus</organism><reference id="rid.486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on some human cutaneous coryneform bacteria: description of Dermabacter hominis gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.1988.tb02967.x</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dermabacter hominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dermabacter hominis</i> (ho'mi.nis. L.n. <i>homo</i> man; L.gen.n. <i>hominis</i> of man; named for the host on whose skin the species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies are small, cream, white, low convex.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-acid fast, non-motile, short rods.</s><s>Grows at 37 °C but not at 10°C; some strains grow at 45°C.</s><s>Grows in 5% NaCl.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from Nacetylglucosamine, amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, metibiose, D-raffinose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycerol, glycogen, 2-ceto-gluconate, 5-ceto-gluconate, gluconate, inositol, inulin, mannitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, rhanmose, sorbitol, D-tagatose, L-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from arbutin, D-lyxose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, saticin, and o-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyse Tween 80 weakly (4-7 days).</s><s>Arginine, cellulose, hippurate, tyrosine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, lecithinase, α-glucosidase and α-mannosidase positive, α- Galactosidase, B-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, ornithine decarboxylase, sulphatase, urease and valine arylamidase negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced by some strains.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, alanine and glutamic acid.</s><s>Mycotic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-9 with MK-8 and MK-7 also present in substantial amounts.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are predominantly of the <i>iso</i>- and <i>anteiso</i>-methyl branched types.</s><s>The major polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, some phospholipids and a diglycosyldiacylglycerol.</s><s>The mol% G + C content of DNA is 62 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCFB 2769 (=S69).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from arbutin but not from α-methyl-D-glucoside, D-lyxose, salicin and D-xylose.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed after 4-7 days.</s></p></content></protolog>