<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1570_nm.2924" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2924" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2924" rank="species">Shewanella gaetbuli</organism><reference id="rid.1570"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella gaetbuli sp. nov., a slight halophile isolated from a tidal flat in Korea.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>487</fpage><lpage>491</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02731-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023965</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella gaetbuli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella gaetbuli</em> (gaet.bu′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>gaetbuli</em> of gaetbul, the Korean name for a tidal flat).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0·5–0·7×1·5–3·0 μm on MA.</s><s>Gram-stain reaction is negative.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, glistening, circular to slightly irregular, flat to raised, light brown in colour and 2·0–4·0 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 30 °C on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 39 °C, but not above 40 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 5·0, but not at pH 4·5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % NaCl; no growth occurs in the presence of &#x003E;8 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine and xylan (birch wood) are not hydrolysed.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are present and leucine arylamidase is weakly present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-ribose and d-trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, stachyose, sucrose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-mannitol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Both menaquinones and ubiquinones are present; predominant menaquinone is MK-7 and predominant ubiquinones are Q-7 and Q-8.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 42 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Other characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TF-27<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 41648<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11814<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from a tidal flat near Mokpo, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>