<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7389_nm.6017" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6017" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6017" rank="species">Ornithinicoccus hortensis</organism><reference id="rid.7389"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kramer</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ornithinicoccus hortensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a soil actinomycete which contains L-ornithine.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1717</fpage><lpage>1724</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1717</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555353</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ornithinicoccus hortensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ornithinicoccus hortensis</i> (hor.ten'sis. L. masc. n. <i>hortus</i> garden; M.L. adj. <i>hortensis</i> referring to the place where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregularly spherical occurring singly, in pairs, short chains and clusters.</s><s>Cell diameters vary from 0.8 to 1.3 μm.</s><s>Gram-positive, not acid-fast, non-motile, no formation of spores.</s><s>Aerobic to microaerophilic.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies are 0.6-4.3 mm in diameter, cream coloured, circular, convex with an entire or structured surface and marginal zone.</s><s>Acids produced in a low amount from D-glucose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-glucitol, trehalose, starch, dextrin, sucrose.</s><s>No acid production from L-arabinose, lactose, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, inulin, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid production is variable from D-fructose, glycerol and D-mannose.</s><s>Aconitate, formate, malate and succinate are used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilization of acetate and citrate is variable.</s><s>Benzoate and DL-tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, H<sub>2</sub>S and catalase are produced, indole and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, xanthin and Tween 80 are decomposed; aesculin and tyrosin are not decomposed.</s><s>Urease activity is variable.</s><s>NaCl in combination with R medium is well tolerated up to a concentration of 4%.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 28 and 37°C; no growth at 42°C.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), nitrofuran (300 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), penicillin G (2 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampin (2 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Susceptibility to oxacillin (5 μg) is unclear, no susceptibility to sulfonamide.</s><s>Tested by the API ZYM enzyme assay HKI 0125<sup>T</sup> and HKI 0131 are positive for phosphatase alkaline, esterase (C 4), esterase lipase (C 8), lipase (C 14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, phosphatase acid, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and negative for trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the A4β-type with an L-Orn←Gly<sub>(1,2)</sub>←D-Glu as interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The acyl type is acetyl.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is of the iso and anteiso branched type.</s><s>The major menaquinone MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylserine and two unknown phospholipids.</s><s>Glucose is the only whole-cell sugar.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 72 mol YOM. ycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0125<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 12335<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>