<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9081_nm.14261" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14261" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora rosea</organism><reference id="rid.9081"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora rosea sp. nov., isolated from a patient with bronchial carcinoma.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1148</fpage><lpage>1152</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005249-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406809</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharopolyspora rosea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharopolyspora rosea</em> (ro.se′a. L. fem. adj. <em>rosea</em> rose-coloured, pink, referring to the colour of the diffusible pigment produced by the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative and thermotolerant, growing at 22–42 °C and pH 6.0–8.0.</s><s>Gram-positive and non-acid–alcohol fast.</s><s>Forms yellowish to brownish yellow, extensively branched substrate mycelia (0.4–0.5 μm in diameter) that fragment into rod-shaped elements and carry yellowish to white aerial hyphae (0.5–0.7 μm) that differentiate into long chains of smooth-surfaced spores.</s><s>Pink-coloured diffusible pigment is produced on ISP2, ISP3 and ISP4 media.</s><s>Melanin pigment is not formed in ISP6 or ISP7 media.</s><s>Adenine, aesculin, casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and urea are hydrolysed; elastin, guanine, keratin, testosterone and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, adipate, adonitol, iso-amyl alcohol, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, citrate, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-galactose, d-gluconate, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-lactate, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, d-sorbitol, trehalose and d-xylose as carbon sources, but not cellobiose, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, d-lactose, melezitose, 1,2-propanediol, raffinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Acetamide, l-alanine, arginine, gelatin, ornithine, l-proline and l-serine are utilized as simultaneous sources of carbon and nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB L-1070<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45226<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 56401<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from bronchial lavage from a 45-year-old patient with bronchial carcinoma.</s></p></content></protolog>