<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2042_nm.11212" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11212" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11212" rank="species">Georgenia ruanii</organism><reference id="rid.2042"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Georgenia ruanii sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from forest soil in Yunnan (China), and emended description of the genus Georgenia</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1424</fpage><lpage>1428</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64749-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625169</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Georgenia ruanii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Georgenia ruanii</em> [ru.a′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>ruanii</em> of Ruan, named in honour of Ji-Sheng Ruan (born in 1926), a Chinese microbiologist who devotes himself to the study of actinomycete taxonomy].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described above for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are 1.1–1.2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, slightly convex, opaque and pale white–yellow to straw-coloured on ISP 2 agar.</s><s>Cells are short-rod-shaped, 0.5–0.8×1.4–2.0 μm in size, and motile (by means of a single flagellum at each end of the cell).</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, with respiratory-type metabolism.</s><s>Endospores and poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate are not formed.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of sodium chloride at concentrations above 5 %.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, with optimum growth at 28–30 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.5–10.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Tests for the hydrolysis of gelatin, for melanin production, H<sub>2</sub>S production and indole production, for resistance to KCN, for milk coagulation and for peptonization are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Dextrin, rhamnose, fructose, glucose, arabinose, sorbose, lactose, galactose, sucrose, dulcitol, inositol, maltose, mannose, cellobiose, turanose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, xylitol, adonitol, arabitol, galacturonate and sorbitol are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, and acid is produced from fructose, galactose, mannose, mannitol, xylose, ribose, lactose, glucose and sucrose.</s><s>Starch and aesculin are hydrolysed and acetamide, xanthine, hypoxanthine and Tweens 20 and 80 are degraded weakly; urea is not degraded.</s><s>Lipase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-maltosidase and l-aspartic arylamidase tests are positive, while arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase tests are negative.</s><s>Resistant to oleandomycin and nalidixic acid but sensitive to penicillin G, vancomycin, polymyxin B, erythromycin, terramycin, aureomycin, tetracycline, streptomycin sulfate, novobiocin, gentamicin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A4<em>α</em> (l-lys–l-ala–l-Glu).</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose and rhamnose.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The menaquinones are MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-7(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) (90 : 2 : 1).</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile consists mainly of ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (78.3 %) and i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (14.9 %), with other minor components, including ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.6 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.0 %), ai-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (1.0 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.0 %), ai-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0.7 %), i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (0.6 %), i-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (0.5 %), i-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.5 %) and i-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0.1 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 004<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 204065<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17458<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19029<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in Lijiang, Yunnan Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>