<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2569_nm.10562" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10562" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10562" rank="species">Aerococcus suis</organism><reference id="rid.2569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Latre</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casamayor</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Briones</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aerococcus suis sp. nov., isolated from clinical specimens from swine.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1291</fpage><lpage>1294</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64537-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551045</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aerococcus suis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aerococcus suis</em> (su′is. L. fem. n. <em>sus</em>, <em>suis</em> pig, hog; L. gen. n. <em>suis</em> of the hog).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive cocci, arranged as single cells, in pairs, in tetrads or in small groups.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and oxidase-negative.</s><s>A positive catalase reaction is clearly evident when cells are cultivated on blood agar, but cells grown on blood-free medium are catalase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, circular and &#x003C;1 mm in diameter after 24 h on blood agar, and produce an <em>α</em>-haemolytic reaction.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37 °C, at pH 9.6 and in broth containing 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of urea is variable.</s><s>Acid is produced from 5-ketogluconate after 48 h and from ribose and d-tagatose after 7 days.</s><s>Acid is not produced from mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, trehalose, glucose, fructose, mannose, maltose, sorbose, galactose, rhamnose, raffinose, sucrose, cellobiose, gentiobiose, inulin, arabinose, xylose, turanose, lyxose, fucose, arabitol, adonitol, xylitol, dulcitol, inositol, aesculin, salicin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cyclodextrin, glycogen, pullulan, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, glycerol, erythritol or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Activities for arginine dihydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (<em>β</em>-GAL test), esterase C4, ester lipase C8, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (weak reaction) and alkaline phosphatase (weak reaction) are detected.</s><s><em>β</em>-Glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (<em>β</em>-GAR test), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, lipase C14, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and glycyl tryptophan arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1821/02<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7139<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52530<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the brain of a pig with meningitis.</s></p></content></protolog>