<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1045_nm.6054" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6054" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6054" rank="species">Microbacterium laevaniformans</organism><reference id="rid.1045"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Brevibacterium imperiale (Steinhaus) and Corynebacterium laevaniformans (Dias and Bhat) in a redefined genus Microbacterium (Orla-Jensen) as Microbacterium imperiale comb. nov. and Microbacterium laevaniformans nom. rev.; comb. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>65</fpage><lpage>78</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium laevaniformans</i> nom. rev.; comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>This description is based on the literature description of "<i>Corynebacterium laevaniformans</i>" (<i>Dias</i> and <i>Bhat</i>); <i>Dias</i> and <i>Bhat</i>, 1962, 1964; <i>Bousfield</i>, 1972; <i>Schleifer</i> and <i>Kandler</i>, 1972; <i>Keddie</i> and <i>Cure</i>, 1978; <i>Collins</i> and <i>Jones</i>, 1981; <i>Döpfer</i> et al., 1982; the present work.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth on solid media in air; colonies are 1 to 3 mm diam., circular, low convex, entire margin, opaque and moist.</s><s>Yellow pigment produced.</s><s>In young cultures, small, slender rods formed.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at an angle to give V-formations; primary branching uncommon.</s><s>In older cultures rods become shorter.</s><s>Rods are Gram-positive, non-acid fast, non-motile; endospores are not formed.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature <i>ca.</i> 30°C.</s><s>Good aerobic growth; weak anaerobic growth.</s><s>Acid (but no gas) produced from glucose, fructose, galactose, sucrose, mannose, trehalose, raffinose, lactose, maltose, cellobiose, dextrin, sorbitol, mannitol, glycerol and glycogen.</s><s>No acid produced from N-acctylglucosamine, xylose, arabinose, inulin, inositol, salicin, arbutin, sorbose, dulcitol, ribose, melibiose and rhamnose. β-galactosidase negative.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Cellulose and hippurate not hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch and gelatin hydrolysed.</s><s>Arginine utilized.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S produced.</s><s>Nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Nutritionally exacting: biotin, thiamine and pantothenic acid required for growth (<i>Dias</i> and <i>Bhat</i>, 1964).</s><s>Survive heating at 60°C for</s></p><p class="description"><s>30 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan type B1α: (<i>Schleifer</i> and <i>Kandler</i>, 1972).</s><s>Galactose is the main cell wall sugar (<i>Keddie</i> and <i>Cure</i>, 1978).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>Non-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids consist of predominantly <i>anteiso</i>- and <i>iso</i>- methyl branched chain acids; straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated acids present in only small amounts.</s><s>Major fatty acids are <i>anteiso</i>-C<sub>15</sub> and <i>anteiso</i>-C<sub>17</sub>;.</s><s>Major menaquinones consist of unsaturated MK-11 and MK-12.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and dimannosyldiacylglycerol; unknown monoglycosyldiacylglycerol sometimes present.</s><s>DNA base composition is 70 to 73.7 mol % G + C.</s><s>Habitat: activated sludge.</s><s>The type strain is NCIB 9659.</s></p></content></protolog>