<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6067_nm.1717" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1717" rank="genus">Telluria</organism><reference id="rid.6067"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spiegel</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Telluria mixta (Pseudomonas mixta Bowman, Sly, and Hayward 1988) gen. nov., comb. nov., and Telluria chitinolytica sp. nov., soil-dwelling organisms which actively degrade polysaccharides.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>120</fpage><lpage>124</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-120</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8427803</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Telluria</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Telluria</i> (Tel.lu'.ri.a. L. fem. n. <i>Tellus</i>, a Roman goddess of the earth, also the ground or earth; M. L. fem. n. <i>Telluria</i>, from the earth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Cells are straight rods that are 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide and 2.0 to 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Occasionally filamentous cells up to 30 μm long are formed, a tendency which increases in older cultures.</s><s>The cells occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>When cultures are grown in liquid media, a single polar flagellum is formed on each cell, while on solid media additional lateral flagella occur.</s><s>Strongly accumulates polyp- hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Strictly aerobic, growing only as a surface pellicle in static liquid cultures.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Incapable of gaining energy chemolithotrophically from hydrogen.</s><s>Denitrification does not occur.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is absent.</s><s>Good growth occurs on media containing carbohydrates and an inorganic or organic combined nitrogen source.</s><s>Much poorer growth occurs on media lacking carbohydrates.</s><s>NaCl sensitive; completely inhibited by NaCl concentrations greater than 1.5%, and only poor growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of 0.5%.</s><s>Actively utilizes complex polysaccharides, including starch and xylan, as well as other polysaccharides which vary among the species.</s><s>Cellulose is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrolyzes gelatin, casein, DNA, esculin, and Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80.</s><s>Produces phosphatase and arylsulfatase.</s><s>Grows well at temperatures between 20 and 45°C and optimally at 30 to 35°C; optimal growth occurs at pH 7.0.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone 8.</s><s>The DNA base composition varies between 67 and 72 mol% G+C (as determined by the <i>T<sub>i</sub></i> method).</s><s>The only known habitat is soil, particularly the rhizosphere.</s><s>The type species is <i>Telluria mixta</i> (formerly <i>Pseudomonas mixta</i>).</s><s>The genus <i>Telluria</i> is a member of the β subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is not closely related phylogenetically to other taxa.</s></p></content></protolog>