<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1500_nm.6390" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6390" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6390" rank="species">Mycobacterium peregrinum</organism><reference id="rid.1500"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kusunoki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Mycobacterium peregrinum sp. nov., nom. rev., and elevation of Mycobacterium chelonae subsp. abscessus (Kubica et al.) to species status: Mycobacterium abscessus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>240</fpage><lpage>245</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-2-240</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1581184</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the type strain of <i>Mycobacterium peregrinum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium peregrinum</i> (L. adj. <i>peregrinus</i>, strange, foreign)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the type strain are as follows: acid-fast rods (1.5 to 4 μm long by 0.5 μm wide); colonies on egg medium are intermediate between smooth and rough and white to slightly yellowish but nonphotochromogenic.</s><s>Growth occurs after 7 days on egg medium at 28 and 37°C but not at 43°C.</s><s>On MacConkey agar, growth occurs at 28°C but not at 37°C.</s><s>This organism tolerates 5% NaCl and 500 μg of hydroxylamine per ml in Ogawa egg medium and 0.2% picrate in Sauton agar medium.</s><s>Tests for iron uptake and degradation of <i>p</i>-aminosalicylate are positive.</s><s>This bacterium produces arylsulfatase (3 days), nitrate reductase, and Tween 80 hydrolase.</s><s>Urease, pyrazinamidase, alantoinase, and acetamidase are present, while benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, nicotinamidase, and succinamidase are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannitol, xylose, mannose, trehalose, and dextrose, but not from inositol, dulcitol, arabinose, galactose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and saccharose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. peregrinum</i> utilizes fructose and glucose as sole carbon sources but does not utilize oxalate or citrate.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 14467.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differential characterestics of <i>M. peregrinum</i>.</s><s>Characteristics that differentiate <i>M. peregrinum</i> from <i>M. fortuitum</i> are shown in Table 4. <i>M. peregrinum</i> is a rapid grower, growing to naked eye visibility on egg medium within 7 days at 37°C.</s><s>It produces arylsulfatase (3 days) and degrades <i>p</i>-aminosalicyclic acid.</s><s>These characteristics differentiate this species from nonpathogenic rapid growers.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite is the characteristic that differentiates it from <i>M. chelonae</i> and <i>Mycobacteriurn abscessus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. peregrinum</i> can be distinguished from <i>M. fortuitum</i> by its failure to grow at 43°C on egg medium and at 37°C on MacConkey agar and by acid production from mannitol and trehalose.</s><s>Its relatively low tolerance to cefmetazol and cefoxitin is helpful for differentiation (Fig. 1).</s></p></content></protolog>