<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4256_nm.2034" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2034" rank="genus">Azovibrio</organism><reference id="rid.4256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold-Hurek</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the taxonomic structure of the diazotrophic genus Azoarcus sensu lato and description of three new genera and new species, Azovibrio restrictus gen. nov., sp. nov., Azospira oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Azonexus fungiphilus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>659</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azovibrio</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azovibrio</i> (A.zo'vi.bri.o. Fr. n. <i>azote</i> nitrogen; L. v. <i>vibrare</i> move rapidly to and fro, vibrate; M.L. masc. n. <i>Azovibrio</i> nitrogen-fixing organism which vibrates; combination of French/Latin by analogy with <i>Azospirillum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formerly <i>Azoarcus</i> sp. group C.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonspore-forming, slightly curved rods; cells range from 0.6 to 0.8 μmin width and from 1.5 to 3.6 μmin length; elongated cells occur very rarely in stationary, alkalinized cultures.</s><s>Highly motile with a corkscrew-like motion by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Microaerophilic growth as veil-like pellicles which move up to the surface in semi-solid N-free media.</s><s>Strictly respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen or nitrate as terminal electron acceptor; however, strictly microaerobic growth may occur.</s><s>Chemorganoheterotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Catalase-weak.</s><s>No dissimilatory nitrate reductase.</s><s>Growth factor requirement varies.</s><s>Capable of growth in atmospheric nitrogen (N<sub>2</sub>) and reduction of acetylene to ethylene.</s><s>Growth is restricted to a few carbon sources, like salts of organic acids such as l-malate, dl-lactate, succinate, fumarate, acetate, propionate and ethanol, and amino acids such as L-glutamate.</s><s>No growth occurs on most other organic acids and amino acids, nor on any mono-or disaccharides (Table 2).</s><s>Grow well at 37 °C.</s><s>Not halophilic or NaCl-dependent.</s><s>Neutral pH optimal for growth.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are cis-9 16:1, 16: 0, 18:1, 14:0 and 3-OH-10:1.</s><s>G­+C content of DNA is 64±65 mol%.</s><s>Member of the β-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Characteristics differentiating them from other diazotrophs given in Table 2 and 3.</s><s>Type species is <i>Azovibrio restrictus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>