<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7364_nm.5890" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5890" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5890" rank="species">Kocuria palustris</organism><reference id="rid.7364"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kovács</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pradella</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Màrialigeti</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kocuria palustris sp. nov. and Kocuria rhizophila sp. nov., isolated from the rhizoplane of the narrow-leaved cattail (Typha angustifolia).</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>167</fpage><lpage>173</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028258</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kocuria palustris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kocuria palustris</i> (pa.lus'tris. L.fem. adj. <i>palustris</i> marshy, swampy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are spherical, occurring in pairs, tetrads and packets, 1.0-1.5 μm in diameter, Gram-positive and non-motile.</s><s>Endospores not produced.</s><s>Not acid-fast.</s><s>The colonies are pale-yellow, 20-3.0 mm in diameter, opaque, smooth with irregular edges with pale-yellow pigmentation.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>No growth above 30°C.</s><s>Good growth at pH 5.7-7.7.</s><s>Catalase, urease benzidine and growth on inorganic nitrogen are positive.</s><s>Phosphatase, Tween 80 hydrolysis and aesculin hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Oxidase, gelatinase, starch hydrolysis, growth on Simmons' citrate, indole, aesculin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase and phenylalanine deaminase reaction are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S reaction weak.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid production from D-glucose, D-fructose, galactose, lactose and saccharose.</s><s>No acid production from glycerol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribose, D-xylose, Larabinose, D-mannose, maltose, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, arbutine, salicine, trehalose, melezitose or amidon.</s><s>Utilization of adonitol, glucuronamide, inosine, Tween 40 or Tween 80.</s><s>No utilization of cello biose, turanose, xylitol, methyl-pyruvate, dextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-trehalose, L-arabinose, D-fructose, L-fucose, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, <i>meso</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, sorbitol, glycerol, L-glutamic acid or L-alanine.</s><s>Growth at 7% NaCl, but no growth at 10% NaCl.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains L-lysine as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge consists of three alanine residues (variation A3α).</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acid is ai-C15:0.</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 69.6 mol% G + C.</s><s>Isolated from the rhizosphere of <i>Typha angustifolia</i> from a floating mat in the Soroksar tributary of the river Danube, Hungary.</s><s>The type strain is strain TAGA27<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>It has been deposited at the DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures as strain DSM 11925<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>