<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2421_nm.11296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11296" rank="species">Lentzea kentuckyensis</organism><reference id="rid.2421"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Donahue</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sells</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lentzea kentuckyensis sp. nov., of equine origin</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1780</fpage><lpage>1783</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64245-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684256</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lentzea kentuckyensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lentzea kentuckyensis</em> (ken.tuc.ky.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>kentuckyensis</em> from Kentucky, named after the place of origin of the type strain, the state of Kentucky, USA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yellow to strong-yellow substrate mycelium is produced on most media.</s><s>Aerial mycelium ranging in colour from white to yellowish white is produced on most media.</s><s>A faint-brown, soluble pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>Micromorphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are typical for the genus <em>Lentzea</em>.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Adenine and allantoin are not hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Phosphatase is not produced.</s><s>Malate, oxalate, and succinate are assimilated; citrate and lactate are assimilated weakly.</s><s>Acetate, benzoate, mucate, propionate and dl-tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, melezitose or methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of NaCl concentrations up to 7 % (w/v).</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LDDC 2876-05<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-24416<sup>T</sup> =DSM 44909<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an equine placenta in Lexington, KY, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>