<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9536_nm.14691" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14691" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14691" rank="species">Midichloria mitochondrii</organism><reference id="rid.9536"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sassera</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beninati</surname><given-names>T .</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bandi</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouman</surname><given-names>E.A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sacchi</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fabbi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lo</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>‘Candidatus Midichloria mitochondrii’, an endosymbiont of the tick Ixodes ricinus with a unique intramitochondrial lifestyle</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2535</fpage><lpage>2540</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64386-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082386</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Midichloria mitochondrii’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Midichloria</em> (mi.di.chlo′ria. N.L. fem. n.) is derived from the midichlorians, organisms within the fictional Star Wars universe. Midichlorians are microscopic symbionts that reside within the cells of living things and “communicate with the Force”. Star Wars creator George Lucas stated that the idea of the midichlorians is based on endosymbiotic theory. The word ‘midichlorian’ appears to be a blend of the words mitochondrion and chloroplast. The specific epithet, mitochondrii (mi.to′chon.drii. N.L. n. <em>mitochondrium</em> -<em>i</em> a mitochondrion; N.L. gen. n. <em>mitochondrii</em> of a mitochondrion), refers to the unique intramitochondrial lifestyle of this bacterium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ appears in EM observations (Lewis, 1979; Zhu <em>et al.</em>, 1992; Sacchi <em>et al.</em>, 2004) as a Gram-negative bacterium with a bacillus shape of ≈ 0.45 μm in diameter and ≈1.2 μm in length.</s><s>This bacterium is observed within various cell types (lumenal cells, funicular cells and oocytes) of the ovary of the hard tick <em>I. ricinus</em> (Ixodidae).</s><s>In all of the above cell types, the bacteria are observed free in the cytoplasm or included in a host-derived membrane.</s><s>In addition, in luminal cells and oocytes, the bacterium is also observed within the mitochondria, in the periplasmic space between the two membranes of these organelles.</s><s>As the development of the oocyte proceeds, the bacteria appear to consume the inner part of the mitochondria and multiply therein.</s><s>The mitochondrial matrix is reduced as a result and some mitochondria appear as sacs full of bacteria (Sacchi <em>et al.</em>, 2004).</s><s>Different numbers of bacteria have been observed within the mitochondria, from a single bacterium to over 20.</s><s>Despite the high number of mitochondria consumed by the bacterium, the eggs of the tick develop normally. <em>In situ</em> hybridization with probes designed to target specific 16S rRNA gene regions resulted in the staining of only ovarian cells in female ticks (Beninati <em>et al.</em>, 2004).</s><s>In male ticks, there is only PCR evidence for the presence of the bacterium (Lo <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s><s>The symbiont appears to be ubiquitous in the females of <em>I. ricinus</em> across its distribution (prevalence, 100 %), while a significantly lower prevalence is observed in males (44 %).</s><s>In males that test positive by PCR, the bacterial load also appears lower compared with females (Lo <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s><s>Evidence for efficient vertical transmission of the bacterium has been reported based on PCR screening of eggs.</s><s>Sequencing of the 16S rRNA and <em>gyrB</em> genes from ticks from 11 different countries from across the distribution of <em>I. ricinus</em> showed a low level of variability in both genes.</s><s>One substitution in 380 bases was found in the 16S rRNA gene sequence and two substitutions in 519 bases were found in the <em>gyrB</em> gene sequence (Lo <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In accordance with the guidelines of the International Committee of Systematic Bacteriology, unculturable bacteria should be classified as <em>Candidatus</em> (Murray &#x0026; Stackebrandt, 1995).</s><s>Thus we propose the name ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Midichloria mitochondrii’ for the novel bacterium. ‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ belongs to the phylum <em>Proteobacteria</em>, to the class <em>Alphaproteobacteria</em> and to the order <em>Rickettsiales</em>. ‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ is assigned on the basis of the 16S rRNA (AJ566640) and <em>gyrB</em> gene sequences (AM159536).</s></p><p class="description"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ has so far only been observed within the ovary of <em>I. ricinus</em> with 100 % prevalence in female ticks. <em>I. ricinus</em> is the main vector of various important human and animal pathogens.</s><s>This ubiquitous presence suggests that the symbiont plays a role in the biology of female ticks.</s><s>In addition, ‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ is certainly an important component of the tick microbial community, possibly interacting with the pathogens transmitted by this arthropod.</s><s>The most striking feature, however, is its unique intramitochondrial localization which could make this symbiont an important model for various studies on the biology of this organelle.</s><s>The presence of various unclassified 16S rRNA gene sequences with high similarity to that of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> M. mitochondrii’ suggests the existence of a family of related bacteria which has yet to be explored.</s></p></content></protolog>