<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8298_nm.13648" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13648" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13648" rank="species">Streptomyces specialis</organism><reference id="rid.8298"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buczolits</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thummes</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grün-Wollny</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces specialis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2602</fpage><lpage>2606</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001008-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984700</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces specialis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces specialis</em> (spe.ci.a′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>specialis</em> particular, special, because of the unusual quinone type and the separate phylogenetic position).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive actinomycete that forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium and aerial hyphae that differentiate into spiral chains of spores.</s><s>Spore chains consist of up to 15 spores.</s><s>Spores are elliptical or short rods (Fig. 1).</s><s>Grows well on all tested ISP media (ISP1–5; Shirling &#x0026; Gottlieb, 1966) after 2 weeks incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>On all media, a pinkish white aerial mycelium and a pale yellow substrate mycelium are produced.</s><s>Produces a black pigment on all tested ISP media.</s><s>Good growth occurs on nutrient agar and DSMZ medium 65 at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0,</sub> C<sub>16 : 0,</sub> anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H.</s><s>The quinone system is composed of the major compound MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) and moderate to minor amounts of MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>In the polar lipid profile, diphosphatidylglycerol is predominant.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol are present in moderate amounts and phosphatidylinositol mannosides, an unknown aminolipid, an unknown phospholipid and three unknown polar lipids are present in minor to trace amounts.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucose, d-gluconate, d-ribose, sucrose, adonitol, d-arabitol, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, propionate, glutarate, butyrate, isobutyrate, isovaleric acid, l-arginine and l-asparagine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, salicin and d-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GW41-1564<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41924<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7499<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>