<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7385_nm.5469" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5469" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5469" rank="species">Abiotrophia balaenopterae</organism><reference id="rid.7385"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Abiotrophia balaenopterae sp. nov., isolated from the minke whale (Balaenoptera acutorostrata).</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>503</fpage><lpage>506</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-503</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319470</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Abiotrophia balaenopterae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Abiotrophia halaenopterae</i> (bal.aen.op'ter.ae. M. L. fem. n. <i>balaenopterae</i> pertaining to minke whale, <i>Balaenoptera acutorostrata</i>, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci occurring as single cells, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Tiny colonies up to 0.2 mm in diameter are formed on Columbia agar supplemented with 5% horse blood at 37°C.</s><s>Neither pyridoxal hydrochloride nor satellitism is required to support growth.</s><s>Haemolysis is not observed.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, pullulan and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, D-raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose, sorbitol, tagatose or D-xylose.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (weak reaction), N-acetylglucosaminidase, ester lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase and urease (weak reaction) activity is detected.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, alanyl-phenylalanineproline arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galac turonidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophanarylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, α-fucosidase and pyrazinamidase activity is not detected.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Hippurate and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The cell wall contains an L-Orn-D-Aspbased, directly cross-linked murein (type A4β).</s><s>The G + C content of DNA of the type strain is 37 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>As determined by 16s rRNA gene sequence analysis, the new species belongs to the lactic acid group of bacteria with low DNA G + C contents, and is phylogenetically closely related to <i>A. adiacens</i> and <i>A. elegans</i>, but may be distinguished from the latter two species using traits shown in Table 1.</s><s>Isolated from minke whale.</s><s>Habitat not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 37380<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>