<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5711_nm.3989" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3989" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3989" rank="species">Clostridium peptidivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5711"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mechichi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhé</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium peptidivorans sp. nov., a peptide-fermenting bacterium from an olive mill wastewater treatment digester.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1259</fpage><lpage>1264</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843071</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium peptidivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium peptidivorans</i> (pep.ti.di.vo'rans. N.L. n. <i>peptidum</i> peptide; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <i>peptidivorans</i> peptide consuming)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, stain Gram-positive, are rod-shaped (0.6-1.2x5-10 μm) and form spores.</s><s>Spores are terminal to subterminal and oval and distend the cell.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic and grows optimally at 37 °C over a temperature range of 20-42 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at or below 15 °C or above 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is between 6 and 9 with an optimum at 7.0.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl concentrations less than 4%.</s><s>Grows on Biotrypcase, yeast extract, Casamino acids, gelatin, peptone, arginine, lysine, cysteine, methionine, histidine, serine, isoleucine and crotonate but not on carbohydrates (glucose, fructose, xylose, sorbose, sorbitol, sucrose, melibiose, raffinose, galactose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, sucrose, lactose, cellobiose, mannitol, mannose, arabinose, arabitol, raffinose, cellulose or xylan ribose), organic acids (formate, acetate, propionate, <i>n</i>-butyrate, valerate, fumarate, malonate, malate, lactate, citrate or succinate) or other amino acids (alanine, proline, aspartate, glycine, threonine, glutamate, glutamine, leucine, aspartate, asparagine, valine, tyrosine, phenylalanine or tryptophan).</s><s>Thiosulfate is reduced but not sulfate, elemental sulfur, nitrate or fumarate.</s><s>The fermentation endproducts are: acetate and butyrate from lysine and crotonate; acetate, butyrate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from Biotrypcase, gelatin and peptone; acetate, alanine, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from cysteine ; acetate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from serine, cysteine and yeast extract; acetate and formate from histidine ; propionate from methionine; methyl 2- butyrate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from isoleucine; acetate and ethanol from arginine; and acetate, propionate, butyrate, methyl 2-butyrate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from Casamino acids.</s><s>The G+­C content of DNA is 31 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The type strain is TMC4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12505<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from an olive mill wastewater treatment digester.</s></p></content></protolog>