<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5420_nm.8854" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8854" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8854" rank="species">Spirochaeta bajacaliforniensis</organism><reference id="rid.5420"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fracek</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stolz</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta bajacaliforniensis sp. n. from a microbial mat community at Laguna Figueroa, Baja California Norte, Mexico</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>142</volume><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>325</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542001</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirochaeta bajacaliforniensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirochaeta bajacaliforniensis</i> (ba.ja.ca.li.for.ni.en'sis. L. adj. <i>bajacaliforniensis</i> from Baja California; named for the geographical location from where it was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Single, helical cells, 0.2-0.3 μm by 15-45 gin.</s><s>Shorter (10 jam) and longer (up to 300 μm) cells may occur.</s><s>Highly motile.</s><s>The amplitute is 0.5 μm and the wavelength is 1.0-1.5 μm.</s><s>Two subterminally inserted periplasmic flagella are present in a 1-2-1 arrangement.</s><s>The ratio of protoplasmic cylinder diameter to the cell diameter is 2: 3.</s><s>The surface of the protoplasmic cylinder has a characteristic polygonal pattern.</s><s>Subsurface colonies are fluffy, white and spherical.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophs: strictly fermentative metabolism, carbohydrates are the fermentable substrates.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, galactitol, fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, inulin, lactose, malate, maltose, mannitol, pyruvate, rhamnose, sorbose and trehalose are fermented.</s><s>Ethanol, alpha-keto glutaric acid, glycerol, lactate, mannose, methanol, raffinose, soluble starch, glucitol, sucrose and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Products of glucose fermentation are acetate, ethanol, carbon dioxide and hydrogen.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grow in media containing at least 20% seawater and 0.12 M NaCl.</s><s>Reducing agent needed in liquid medium.</s><s>An 80% N<sub>2</sub>, 17% CO<sub>2</sub> and 3% H<sub>2</sub> atmosphere needed for solid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature optimum: 36 °C.</s><s>Do not grow below 25 °C or above 44 °C.</s><s>Survive frozen in 1:1 medium/glycerol at -70°C.</s><s>Optimum growth at pH 7.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The GC content of the DNA is 50.1% (buoyant density).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from anaerobic sulfide-rich mud underlying the laminated sediment of the microbial mats at North Pond, Laguna Figueroa, Baja California Norte, Mexico.</s></p></content></protolog>