<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2752_nm.10300" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10300" rank="genus">Aggregatibacter</organism><reference id="rid.2752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nørskov-Lauritsen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans, Haemophilus aphrophilus, Haemophilus paraphrophilus and Haemophilus segnis as Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans gen. nov., comb. nov., Aggregatibacter aphrophilus comb. nov. and Aggregatibacter segnis comb. nov., and emended description of Aggregatibacter aphrophilus to include V factor-dependent and V factor-independent isolates.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64207-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aggregatibacter</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aggregatibacter</em> (Ag.gre.ga.ti.bac′ter. L. v. <em>aggregare</em> to come together, aggregate, N.L. masc. n. <em>bacter</em> bacterial rod, N.L. masc. n. <em>Aggregatibacter</em> rod-shaped bacterium that aggregates with others).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A member of the family <em>Pasteurellaceae</em>.</s><s>Gram-negative, non-motile, facultatively anaerobic rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Growth is mesophilic.</s><s>Several species of the genus are capnophilic and primary isolation may require the presence of 5–10 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>There is no dependence on X factor and the requirement for V factor is variable.</s><s>Granular growth in broth is common.</s><s>Colonies on sheep- and horse-blood agar are greyish white and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose and maltose, whereas arabinose, cellobiose, melibiose, melezitose, salicin and sorbitol are not attacked.</s><s>The fermentation of galactose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose and xylose is variable and may aid in identification to the species level.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase is produced, but strains are negative in tests for indole, urease, ornithine and lysine decarboxylases and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Oxidase reaction is negative or weak; catalase is variably present.</s><s>IgA1 protease is not expressed.</s><s>The species of the genus are intimately associated with man; they are part of the human oral flora and are occasionally recovered from other body sites, including blood and brain, as causes of endocarditis and abscesses.</s><s>The type species is <em>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</em>, originally described as ‘<em>Bacterium actinomycetem comitans</em>’ by Klinger (1912).</s></p></content></protolog>