<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1360_nm.1727" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1727" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1727" rank="species">Alcaligenes denitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.1360"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rüger</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Separation of Alcaligenes denitrificans sp. nov. nom. rev. from Alcaligenes faecalis on the basis of DNA base composition, DNA homology and nitrate reduction.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>85</fpage><lpage>89</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-85</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alcaligenes denitrificans</i> sp. nov. nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The cells are gram-negative, short rods with rounded ends and occur singly, in pairs, or short chains. The average size is 0.7 to 1.0 μm by 1.2 to 3.0 μm as measured by phase-contrast microscopy. The cells are motile and peritrichous.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological characteristics: colonies on agar are circular with an entire margin, flat, smooth, nonpigmented, translucent, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Good growth occurs in nutrient broth with uniform turbidity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological growth characteristics: aerobic, but capable of anaerobic respiration in the presence of nitrate or nitrite.</s><s>The cells are mesophilic; growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 37°C, and the optimal growth temperature is 24°C.</s><s>The highest concentrations of NaCl permitting growth are 3.5 to 4.5%.</s><s>Prototrophic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite and gas.</s><s>Gas produced from nitrite.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite, as sole sources of nitrogen, support growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oxidase and catalase are produced.</s><s>Indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, hydrogen sulfide, and fluorescent pigment in King medium B are not produced.</s><s>Traces of ammonia are generated from peptone.</s><s>Methyl red test is negative.</s><s>No change in litmus milk.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin and casein are not digested.</s><s>Urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, and extracellular DNase are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acid from arabinose, fructose, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, sucrose, or xylose within 42 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipid, chitin, starch, and alginate are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D-Glucose, D-galactose, D-fructose, and D-mannose are not utilized as sole sources of carbon, but growth occurs with sodium acetate, sodium succinate, sodium glutamate, and citrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition: 69.1 ± 0.3 mol% G+C (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> estimation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pichinoty et al. (17) reported the following nutritional tests as positive for "<i>A . denitrificans</i>": utilization of D-saccharate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, β-hydroxy-β-methyl-glutarate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, azelate, and itaconate.</s></p></content></protolog>