<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1652_nm.11157" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11157" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11157" rank="species">Zhouia amylolytica</organism><reference id="rid.1652"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zhouia amylolytica gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from sediment of the South China Sea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2825</fpage><lpage>2829</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64587-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17158983</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Zhouia amylolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Zhouia amylolytica</em> (a.my.lo.ly′ti.ca. Gr. n. <em>amylos</em> starch; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus</em> from Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>amylolytica</em> dissolving starch, pertaining to the ability of the bacterium to hydrolyse starch).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description and in Table 1.</s><s>Cells are 0.25–0.3×1.3–3.0 μm in size; devoid of flagellar and gliding motility.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, slightly raised, smooth, yellow to pale-yellow in colour and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 7–42 °C, with an optimum at 30 °C; growth does not occur at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 6.0–8.0, with an optimum at pH 7.2–7.4; growth does not occur at pH 5.8 or 8.2.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 4.5–5 % (w/v) NaCl; growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of &#x003E;9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed, but agar, casein and Tweens are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, L-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-galactonolactone, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are utilized.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate are not utilized.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G (24.2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (14.9 %), summed feature 4 (10.7 %) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (9.4 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HN-171<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6114<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14016<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sediment sample from the South China Sea, China.</s></p></content></protolog>