<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5720_nm.12185" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12185" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4577" rank="species">Haloanaerobium fermentans</organism><reference id="rid.5720"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kimura</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloanaerobium fermentans sp. nov., a strictly anaerobic, fermentative halophile isolated from fermented puffer fish ovaries.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1621</fpage><lpage>1627</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloanaerobium fermentans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloanaerobium fermentans</i> (fer.men'tans. L. part. adj. <i>fermentans</i> fermenting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods (1.0-1.2 μm wide by 2.7-3.3 μm long).</s><s>The bacterium is motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Spores are not observed.</s><s>Cells grow only anaerobically on solid medium.</s><s>Colonies on ABCM plate medium supplemented with 10% (w/v) NaCl are smooth, convex, opaque and yellowish.</s><s>It is a moderately halophilic bacterium that grows in the presence of 7-25% (w/v) NaCl, with an optimal NaCl concentration of 10% (w/v).</s><s>It grows well at 15 and 45 °C but not at 10 or 50 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 35 °C.</s><s>It grows well in the pH range of 6.0 to 9.0 with the optimum pH for growth being 7.5.</s><s>It ferments D-glucose to hydrogen, carbon dioxide, ethanol and other acidic end-products such as acetate, formate and lactate.</s><s>Butyrate and propionate are not produced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>The fermentative substrates include N-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose and D-xylose.</s><s>L-Arabinose, glycerol, pyruvate, rhamnose and starch are not fermented.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 33.3 mol%G­C (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from salted ovaries in the manufacturing process of a Japanese traditional food product, fermented puffer fish ovaries or <i>fugunoko nukaduke</i>.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the new isolate R-9<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the DDBJ database under accession no. AB023308.</s><s>The type strain is R-9<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited with the Japan Collection of Microorganisms under accession number JCM 10494<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>