<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5604_nm.9868" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9868" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9868" rank="species">Janibacter anophelis</organism><reference id="rid.5604"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Terenius</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lindh</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faye</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Janibacter anophelis sp. nov., isolated from the midgut of Anopheles arabiensis</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>389</fpage><lpage>392</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63905-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449445</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Janibacter anophelis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Janibacter anophelis</em> (a.no′phe.lis. N.L. gen. n. <em>anophelis</em> from a mosquito of the genus <em>Anopheles</em>, as the type strain was isolated from the midgut of <em>Anopheles arabiensis</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive and oxidase-positive; shows oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Non-motile, non-endospore-forming cocci of 1·0–1·5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Very young cultures show rod-like cells.</s><s>Good growth (visible colonies with a diameter &#x003E;1 mm) occurs after 3 days incubation on nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Grows in Luria–Bertani broth at 20–40 °C, with an optimum at 35 °C.</s><s>Generation time at 35 °C is 44 min.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The fatty acid content is mainly iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Different 10-methyl acids are present.</s><s>Results of carbon source utilization tests (including differentiating characteristics) are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The type strain does not produce acids from the following sugars: glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose or arabitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized as a sole source of carbon (after 48 h incubation): d-gluconate, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, i-inositol, acetate, propionate, 4-aminobutyrate, fumarate, glutarate, 3-hyroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-xylose, adonitol, maltitol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, l-azelate, citrate, itaconate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, l-suberate, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, dl-3-hydroxybenzoate, dl-4-hydroxybenzoate or l-phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, H2.16B<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 49715<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108728<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the midgut of <em>Anopheles arabiensis</em> from Kenya.</s></p></content></protolog>