<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11600_nm.18637" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18637" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18637" rank="species">Burkholderia heleia</organism><reference id="rid.11600"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aizawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ve</surname><given-names>N.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sunairi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia heleia sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium isolated from an aquatic plant, Eleocharis dulcis, that grows in highly acidic swamps in actual acid sulfate soil areas of Vietnam</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1152</fpage><lpage>1157</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015198-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666801</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia heleia</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia heleia</em> (he.le′ia. Gr. n. <em>heleios</em> a marsh, low ground, meadow; N.L. fem. adj. <em>heleia</em> of the marsh, referring to the isolation of this species from a plant growing in a marsh).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods (0.6–0.7 μm×1.5–1.7 μm).</s><s>Colonies are smooth, round, convex and pale yellow with entire margins after cultivation for 3 days at 32 °C on 1/10 tryptic soy agar plates (pH 4.0).</s><s>Growth occurs between 17 and 42 °C with an optimum at 32 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 3.5–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 5.0.</s><s>The bacteria grow on MacConkey agar at 29 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth and acetylene reduction to ethylene occur on N<sub>2</sub>-free soft gel medium.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but Tween 80 is not.</s><s>Positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>β</em>-glucosidase and urease activities, but negative for valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and arginine dihydrolase activities (API ZYM, API 20E and API 20NE systems).</s><s>Positive for acid production from erythritol, d-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, aesculin, salicin, d-lactose, trehalose, xylitol and gentiobiose, but negative for acid production from d-mannose, l-rhamnose, arbutin, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50CH system).</s><s>Can utilize adonitol, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, l-rhamnose, trehalose, quinic acid, l-ornithine, 2-aminoethanol and d-glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon source, but not <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, dl-carnitine, inosine, phenylethylamine, 2,3-butanediol or <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate (Biolog GN2 Microplate system).</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin (8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chloramphenicol (8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin (1 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), tylosin (2 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), colistin (4 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), flumequin (4 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and rifampicin (4 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but sensitive to kanamycin (8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), apramycin (16 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and cotrimoxazole (2 μg trimethoprim ml<sup>−1</sup> plus 38 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> sulfamethoxazole) (API VET system).</s><s>Additional physiological characteristics are summarized in Table 1.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8, as described for the genus.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of these strains is 64 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SA41<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 101817<sup>T</sup>=VTCC-D6-7<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an aquatic plant, <em>Eleocharis dulcis</em>, that grows luxuriantly in a highly acidic swamp (pH 3) in an AASS area in Vietnam.</s></p></content></protolog>