<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.516_nm.3007" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3007" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3007" rank="species">Vibrio superstes</organism><reference id="rid.516"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hayashi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moriwaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gudkovs</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio superstes sp. nov., isolated from the gut of Australian abalones Haliotis laevigata and Haliotis rubra.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1813</fpage><lpage>1817</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02625-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657109</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio superstes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio superstes</em> (su.per′stes. L. masc. adj. <em>superstes</em> remaining alive after another's death, outliving, surviving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile and non-flagellated.</s><s>Cells in ZoBell 2216E broth are rod-shaped with rounded ends (0·6–0·8×1·2–1·3 μm).</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solid and/or in liquid media.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are beige, circular, smooth and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph: grows between 15 and 30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 40 °C.</s><s>Positive for acid production from glucose, nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of alginate, oxidase and catalase and assimilation of d-mannose, sucrose, d-gluconate, d-galactose, cellobiose, melibiose, lactose, d-glucuronate, trehalose, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyrate, acetate, propionate, l-glutamate, d-xylose, d-fructose, maltose, d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-mannitol, fumarate, succinate, d-glucose and alginate.</s><s>The following tests are negative: gas production from glucose, acetoin production, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dehydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, indole production, <em>β</em>-galactosidase test, luminescence, pigmentation, requirement for organic growth factors, hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, chitin, Tween 80 and agar, accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, assimilation of d-sorbitol, glycerol, citrate, meso-erythritol, dl-malate, 2-oxoglutarate, putrescine, <em>δ</em>-aminovalerate, pyruvate, l-tyrosine, aconitate and l-arabinose.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 48·0–48·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21323<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15009<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The bacterium was isolated from the gut of the Australian abalones <em>Haliotis rubra</em> and <em>H. laevigata</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>