<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6589_nm.3974" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3974" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3974" rank="species">Clostridium methoxybenzovorans</organism><reference id="rid.6589"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mechichi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>T.H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium methoxybenzovorans sp. nov., a new aromatic o-demethylating homoacetogen from an olive mill wastewater treatment digester.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1201</fpage><lpage>1209</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1201</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425780</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium methoxybenzovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium methoxybenzovorans</i> (me.tho.xy.ben.zo'vo.rans. Fr. <i>méthyl</i> the methyl radical; Gr. n. <i>oxys</i> acid; Fr. n. <i>benzoin</i> frankincense of Java; Ger. n. <i>benzoesäure</i> resin obtained from the tree <i>Styrax</i> benzoin; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; M.L. neut. adj. <i>methoxybenzovorans</i> pertaining to the use of the organic acid methoxybenzoic acid as carbon and energy source, which is characteristic of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, 3.0-5.0 x 0.4-0.8 μm in size, occurring singly or in pairs, Gram-positive, non-motile.</s><s>Formation of spherical, terminal endospores swelling the vegetative cell.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemo-organoheterotroph.</s><s>Growth on a number of carbohydrates (glucose, fructose, sorbose, galactose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, sucrose, lactose, cellobiose), organic compounds (lactate, betaine, sarcosine, dimethylglycine, methanethiol, dimethylsulfide), alcohol (methanol) and all methoxylated aromatic compounds as sole source of carbon and energy.</s><s>Carbohydrates are fermented to formate, acetate and ethanol, lactate is fermented to methanol, methoxylated aromatics are fermented to acetate and butyrate, and betaine, sarcosine, dimethylglycine, methanethiol and dimethylsulfide are fermented to acetate.</s><s>Strain SR3<sup>T</sup> has a G+ C content of 44 mol% and grows optimally at 37°C and pH 7.4 on a glucose-containing medium.</s><s>Isolated from an anaerobic methanogenic pilot-scale digester fed with olive mill wastewater.</s><s>The type strain is SR3<sup>T</sup> deposited in DSMZ (= DSM 12182<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>