<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10582_nm.17833" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17833" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17833" rank="species">Salinisphaera dokdonensis</organism><reference id="rid.10582"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinisphaera dokdonensis sp. nov., isolated from surface seawater</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>680</fpage><lpage>685</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010058-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656943</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinisphaera dokdonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinisphaera dokdonensis</em> (dok.do.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>dokdonensis</em> of Dokdo, a Korean island, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic and motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Non-spore-forming and short-rod-shaped cells, approximately 0.3–0.6 μm wide and 0.5–0.9 μm long.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells contain PHB granules.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex and creamy and about 1 mm in diameter after incubation on MA supplemented with 7.5 % (w/v) NaCl at 25 °C for 6 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–40 °C (optimum 25 °C), at pH 5.2–8.8 (optimum pH 6.3–7.2) and with 4–21 % NaCl (optimum 10 % NaCl).</s><s>Tween 80 and starch are hydrolysed, but gelatin, aesculin, casein, DNA and Tween 40 are not.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, weakly positive for acid phosphatase, lipase (C14) and valine arylamidase and negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α-</em> and <em>β-</em>galactosidases, <em>α-</em> and <em>β-</em>glucosidases, <em>β-</em>glucuronidase, <em>α-</em>mannosidase and trypsin.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, negative for aesculin hydrolysis, glucose fermentation, nitrate reduction, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase and urease.</s><s>d-Glucose and glycerol (weak growth) are utilized as sole carbon sources, but acetate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, betaine, citrate, ethanol, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, raffinose, succinate, trehalose, urea and xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, starch, amygdalin, arbutin, d- and l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, d-fructose, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose (bovine origin), d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol and d- and l-xylose.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc) ampicillin (6), cephalexin (20), chloramphenicol (20), erythromycin (10), nalidixic acid (20), penicillin G (6), polymyxin B (25) and tetracycline (20), but resistant to gentamicin (6), kanamycin (20) and streptomycin (6).</s><s>The isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CL-ES53<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 90064<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19549<sup>T</sup>), isolated from surface seawater in the vicinity of Dokdo, an island in the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>