<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5802_nm.2758" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2758" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2758" rank="species">Moraxella lincolnii</organism><reference id="rid.5802"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moraxella lincolnii sp. nov., isolated from the human respiratory tract, and reevaluation of the taxonomic position of Moraxella osloensis.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>474</fpage><lpage>481</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-474</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347507</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moraxella lincolnii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moraxella lincolnii</i> (lin'col.ni.i. N. L. gen. n. <i>lincolnii</i>, of Lincoln, in honor of K. Lincoln, a Swedish microbiologist, in recognition of his many contributions in the field of urinary tract infections)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonmotile, coccus-like to plump rods 1 to 1.5 μm wide and 1.5 to 2.5 μm long.</s><s>The cells often occur in pairs and may form short chains.</s><s>After 2 days of incubation, colonies are whitish, smooth, convex, and circular and have a diameter of 1 to 3 mm.</s><s>The colonies of some strains may have a flattened edge.</s><s>No hemolysis and no production of pigment or odor.</s><s>Grows under aerobic, capnophilic, or microaerobic conditions but not anaerobically.</s><s>Grows on blood agar or nutrient agar, but not on Drigalski agar.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 28 to 33°C.</s><s>Growth also occurs at 36 to 37°C, but not at 42°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl; no growth occurs in the presence of 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin (10-μg discs).</s><s>Most strains reduce nitrites (seven of nine strains tested).</s><s>No fermentation or oxidation of D-glucose.</s><s>No acid production from D-glucose, maltose, D-fructose, or sucrose.</s><s>Lactate cannot be used as a carbon source.</s><s>No denitrification, liquefaction of gelatin, proteolysis on Löffler slants, hydrolysis of Tween 80, or indole production.</s><s>No urease, DNase, or β-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ester lipase C<sub>8</sub>, esterase, leucine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, lysine arylamidase, and seryl-methionine arylamidase activities are present; alkaline and acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, lipase (C<sub>14</sub>) valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, γ-glutamyl arylamidase, proline arylamidase, and alanyl-phenylalanyl-prolyl-alanine arylamidase activities are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition of <i>M. lincolnii</i> is 44 mol% G+C.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 10:0, 12:0 3OH, 16:1 cis-9, 16:0, 18:1 cis-9, and 18:0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>So far, <i>M. lincolnii</i> has been isolated mainly from the respiratory tract of humans.</s><s>Its clinical significance is unknown.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 9405 (= LMG 5127), which was isolated in 1980 in Göteborg, Sweden, from the nasopharynx of a 5-year-old girl with a fever.</s><s>All <i>M. lincolnii</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Goteborg and the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Ghent.</s></p></content></protolog>