<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8604_nm.13272" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13272" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13272" rank="species">Chryseobacterium arothri</organism><reference id="rid.8604"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium arothri sp. nov., isolated from the kidneys of a pufferfish.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>293</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65276-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175724</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium arothri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium arothri</em> (a.ro′thri. N. L. n. <em>Arothron</em> scientific genus name of a genus of fish; N. L. gen. n. <em>arothri</em> of <em>Arothron</em>, isolated from the pufferfish <em>Arothron</em> <em>hispidus</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, Gram-negative rods (1×0.5 μm in size).</s><s>Circular, yellowish colonies are formed on TSA at 30 °C after 1 day.</s><s>Optimum temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth, in the range 0.5–3.0 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 2.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Utilizes <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-psicose, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucoronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, and d-glucose 6-phosphate as carbon source in Biolog GN2 tests.</s><s>Produces H<sub>2</sub>S on triple-sugar iron+2 % NaCl agar.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (35.3 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (14.9 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P2K6<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109575<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19326<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the kidneys of a pufferfish <em>Arothron hispidus</em> caught off the coast of the windward side of the island of O‘ahu, Hawai‘i.</s></p></content></protolog>