<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7184_nm.2647" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2647" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2647" rank="species">Pseudomonas monteilii</organism><reference id="rid.7184"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Elomari</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coroler</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhille</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas monteilii sp. nov., isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>846</fpage><lpage>852</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-846</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226917</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas monteilii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas monteilii</i> (mon.tei'1i.i M. L. masc. gen. n. <i>monteilii</i>, of Monteil, in honor of Henri Monteil, a French microbiologist, for his contribution to medical microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and physiological characteristics.</s><s>The 10 <i>P. monteilii</i> strains are gram negative, motile, asporogenous, and rod shaped.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular and nonpigmented.</s><s>They are nonhemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>The cells are lipase, elastase, lecithinase, and tetrathionate reductase negative.</s><s>Arginine dihyrolase, catalase, and cytochrome oxidase are produced.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 36°C, and optimal growth occurs at 30°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl but not in the presence of 5 or 7% NaCl.</s><s>No strain reduces nitrate to nitrite or to gas; the strains are not able to form levan from sucrose but they are able to use citrate and arginine.</s><s>Tributyrin and fibrinolysis tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated as a carbon reserve material.</s><s>Phenazine pigments are not produced on King A medium (25).</s><s>Strains are unable to grow at 41°C.</s><s>Indole, coagulase, and β-xylosidase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Esculin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phenylalanine is not deaminated, and lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction and the o-nitrophenyl-β-galactopyranoside test are negative.</s><s>There is no action against DNA or RNA.</s><s>The strains are chondroitin negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Assimilation of carbon compounds.</s><s>All strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: glycerol, D-ribose, inositol, D-glucose, D-fructose, L-glutamate, L-arabinose, 2-ket ogluconate, DL-glycerate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, gluconate, isobutyrate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-norleucine, L-valine, L-aspartate, L-ornithine, L-lysine, L-arginine, betaine, p-alanine, sarcosine, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, butylamine, amylamine, ethanolamine, benzylamine, diaminobutane, spermine, aconitate, phenylacetate, succinate, fumarate, L-malate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, n-valerate, isovalerate, n-caproate, heptanoate, caprylate, caprate, glutarate, DL-lactate, puryvate, citrate, benzoate, and p-hydroxybenzoate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No strain uses the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: L-xylose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, salicin, lactose, D-melibiose, inulin, D-tagatose, D-fucose, erythritol, D-arabinose, D-xylose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, D-galactose, D-mannose, L-sorbose, L-rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, esculin, D-cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, D-melezitose, D-raffinose, starch, glucogen, xylitol, β-gentobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, 5-ketogluconate,  L-cysteine, D-tryptophan, DL-aminobutyrate, L-methionine, L-tryptophan, DL-kynurenine, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-2-aminobenzoate, DL-3-aminobenzoate, DL-4-aminobenzoate, ethylamine, acetamide, tryptamine, glucosamine, levulinate, iso-phthalate, oxalate, maleate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, citrate, mesaconate, o-hydroxybenzoate, m-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalate, terephthalate, glycerate, oxalate, L-arabitol, mannitol, glycolate, citraconate, itaconate, and mucate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enzymatic tests.</s><s>All strains possess the following enzyme activities: L-phenylalanine arylamidase, L-lysine arylamidase, L-alanine arylamidase, γ-glutamyl-transferase, glycyl-phenylalanine arylamidase, L-tryptophan arylamidase, glycyl-L-alanine arylamidase, esterase C<sub>4</sub>, esterase C<sub>6</sub>, esterase C<sub>8</sub>, esterase C<sub>9</sub>, esterase C<sub>10</sub>, and esterase C<sub>18</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No strains possess the following enzyme activities: L-histidyl-L-phenylalanine arylamidase, glycyl-glycine arylamidase, L-hydroxyproline arylamidase, L-histidine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, L-aspartate arylamidase, glycyl-proline arylamidase, leucyl-glycine arylamidase, L-glutamine arylamidase, α-L-glutamate arylamidase, L-isoleucine arylamidase, L-ornithine arylamidase, L-serine arylamidase, L-threonine arylamidase, Ncarboxybenzoyl-glycyl-glycyl-argininaer ylamidase, p-alanine arylamidase, L-alanyl-L-arginine arylamidase, L-alanyl-L-phenylalanyl-L-proline arylamidase, L-alanyl-L-phenylalanyl-L-prolyl-L-alanine arylamidase, L-arginyl-L-arginine arylamidase, α-L-aspartyl-L-alanine arylamidase, α-L-aspartyl-L-arginine arylamidase, α-L-glutamyl-L-histidine arylamidase, glycyl-L-arginine arylamidase, L-histidyl-L-leucyl-L-histidine arylamidase, L-histidyl-L-serine arylamidase, L-lysyl-L-lysine arylamidase, L-phenylalanyl-L-arginine arylamidase, L-phenylalanyl-L-proline arylamidase, L-phenylalanyl-L-prolyl-L-alanine arylamidase, L-seryl-L-methionine arylamidase, L-valyl-L-tyrosyl-L-serine arylamidase, L-lysyl-L-serine-4-methoxyarylamidase, α-D-glucosidase, β-D-glucosidase, α-maltosidase, N-carboxybenzoyl-arginine-4-methoxya rylamidase, N-benzoylleucine arylamidase, 5-benzoyl-cysteine arylamidase, α-L-glutamyl-α-L-glutamic arylamidase, L-leucyl-L-leucyl-L-valyl-L-tyrosyl-L-serine arylamidase, N-benzoyl-L-alanine-4-methoxy arylamidase, N-acetyl-glycyl-L-lysine arylamidase, α-D-galactosidase, β-D-galactosidase, phospho-β-D-galactosidase, α-L-arabinosidase, β-D-galacturonohydrolase, β-D-glucuronidase, β-maltosidase, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminidase, β-D-fucosidase, β-L-fucosidase, β-D-lactosidase, α-D-mannosidase, p-D-mannosidase, α-D-xylosidase, β-D-xylosidase, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminidase, β-L-fucosidase, and esterase C<sub>16</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Variable characteristics of 10 <i>P. monteilii</i> strains are shown in Table 3.</s><s>All of the reactions of the type strain are the same as the reactions of the majority of the strains of <i>P. monteilii</i> except the reactions in the following three tests: assimilation of trigonelline and malonate and presence of L-pyrrolidone arylamidase.</s><s>The <i>P. monteilii</i> strains are phenotypically and genotypically homogeneous and can be differentiated from related nonphytopathogenic fluorescent members of section I of the genus <i>Pseudomonas</i> (32) by several phenotypic features (Table 4).</s><s>Differentiation of <i>P. monteilii</i> and P. aeruginosa is based on pyocyanin production, lipase activity, denitrification, growth at 41"C, and assimilation of L-arabinose, mannitol, adipate, sebecate, azelate, inositol, L-mandelate, phenylacetate, α-aminobutyrate, L-kynurenine, benzylamine, butylamine, amylamine, and acetamide. <i>P. monteilii</i> and <i>P. fluorescens</i> clearly differ phenotypically since all strains of <i>P. fluorescens</i> liquefy gelatin and are able to grow at PC, whereas strains of <i>P. monteilii</i> are unable to grow at this temperature and are unable to liquefy gelatin.</s><s>Moreover, most strains of P. fluurescens utilize D-mannose, mannitol, D-galactose, and mucate, whereas all strains of <i>P. monteilii</i> are unable to utilize these compounds.</s><s>Conversely, all strains of <i>P. monteilii</i> are able to grow on α-aminobutyrate, creatine (except one strain), and butylamine, whereas most strains of <i>P. fluorescens</i> fail to do so.</s><s>Phenotypically, <i>P. monteilii</i> is most similar to <i>P. putida</i>, but these two species can be differentiated by assimilation of inositol, L-tartrate, D-tartrate, o-hydroxybenzoate, m-hydroxybenzoate, tryptamine, D-mandelate, acetamide, D-xylose, mannitol, and mucate and by the presence of glycyl-glycine arylamidase, L-glutamine arylamidase, and L-arginine arylamidase (Table 4) (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>P. monteilii</i> were isolated from clinical specimens (Table 2).</s><s>Type strain CFML 90-60 has been deposited in the Collection Institut Pasteur) as CIP 104883; it was isolated in Lyon, France, from a bronchial aspirate, and its G+C content is 60 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Clinical significance.</s><s>The clinical significance of <i>P. monteilii</i> is not known.</s><s>Future isolates of this new organism should be investigated to determine their role in nosocomial infections.</s><s>At present, our hypothesis is that <i>P. monteilii</i> is a rare opportunistic pathogen or colonizer.</s></p></content></protolog>