<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1506_nm.12221" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12221" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2963" rank="species">Photobacterium damsela</organism><reference id="rid.1506"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutton</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuerst</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reichelt</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Evaluation of the genus Listonella and reassignment of Listonella damsela (Love et al.) MacDonell and Colwell to the genus Photobacterium as Photobacterium damsela comb. nov. with an emended description.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>534</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-4-529</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1742198</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Photobacterium damsela</i> (Love et al. 1981) Smith, Sutton, Fuerst, and Reichelt comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Photobacterium damsela</i> (dam.se'la. M.L. n. <i>damsela</i>, pertaining to damselfish)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, straight rods that are motile by means of one or more unsheathed polar flagella.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, often with weak gas production.</s><s>Able to accumulate the storage product PHB when grown on medium containing glucose, but unable to utilize the exogenous monomer DL-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and urease tests are strongly positive.</s><s>Oxidase, Voges-Proskauer, and extracellular lipase tests are weakly positive.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of sodium ions.</s><s>Not bioluminescent.</s><s>Negative for the production of the extracellular enzymes amylase, alginase, and gelatinase.</s><s>The following carbon compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources in the presence of 0.05% yeast extract; pyruvate, lactate, glutamate, mannose, galactose, cellobiose, and glycerate.</s><s>Utilization of serine and utilization of α-ketoglutarate in the presence of 0.05% yeast extract are variable.</s><s>In the absence of 0.05% yeast extract, growth on all of the compounds listed above is variable or negative.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources in the presence or absence of 0.05% yeast extract: L-arabinose, D-gluconate, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-xylose, caprate, caproate, butyrate, caprylate, heptanoate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, pelargonate, propionate, valerate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, aconitate, citrate, betaine, hippurate, sarcosine, glutarate, malonate, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, benzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, tyrosine, D-α-alanine, β-alanine, γ-aminobutyrate, β-aminovalerate, arginine, citrulline, glycine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, putrescine, and spermine.</s><s>Isolated from healthy and diseased marine animals, human wounds, and seawater.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 33539.</s><s>The description of this strain is the same as that given for the species except that this isolate utilizes α-ketoglutarate and serine in the presence of 0.05% yeast extract.</s></p></content></protolog>