<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5831_nm.5775" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5775" rank="species">Actinomyces canis</organism><reference id="rid.5831"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greko</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces canis sp. nov., isolated from dogs</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1547</fpage><lpage>1551</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939662</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces canis</i> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces canis</i> (can.is. L. gen. n. <i>canis</i> of the dog)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, some of which exhibit branching.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive, are non-aciD-fast and are non-motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>With API systems, acid is produced from fglucose, L-arabinose, glycogen, maltose, lactose, pullulan, D-ribose and dxylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D- glucopyranoside, sorbitol, tagatose or trehalose.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from sucrose and raffinose.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, aglucosidase, α-fucosidase, ester lipase C-8 (weak), cystine arylamidase (weak), leucine arylamidase, NacetyL- β-glucosaminidase and pyrazinamidase (weak reaction) are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C-14, phosphoamidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase, pyrrolydonyl arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Glycyl tryptophan arylamidase may or may not be produced.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 41706<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106351<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from clinical specimens from dogs.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s><s>The type strain shows the characteristics of the species and produces acid from sucrose and raffinose.</s></p></content></protolog>