<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1725_nm.8796" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8796" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8796" rank="species">Pseudomonas proteolytica</organism><reference id="rid.1725"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrophilic pseudomonads from Antarctica: Pseudomonas antarctica sp. nov., Pseudomonas meridiana sp. nov. and Pseudomonas proteolytica sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>713</fpage><lpage>719</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02827-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143013</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas proteolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas proteolytica</em> (pro.te.o.ly′ti.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>proteolytica</em> proteolytic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms circular, convex, smooth and translucent colonies with a diameter of 1–2 mm.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile with a polar flagellum, rod-shaped and psychrophilic (grow at 4–30 °C), can tolerate 3 % NaCl (w/v) and grow at an optimum pH of 7.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, lipase and gelatinase; reduces nitrate to nitrite; negative for phosphatase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, indole production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin, starch or cellulose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose and d-mannitol, but not from l-arabinose, lactose, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, adonitol, citrate, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lactic acid, d-mannose, d-mannitol, pyruvate, d-ribose, sorbitol, trehalose, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-lysine, l-serine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine and l-tryptophan as sole carbon sources, but not d-cellobiose, cellulose, dextran, dulcitol, fumaric acid, inulin, lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, melezitose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbose, sucrose, succinic acid, thioglycollate, d-xylose, l-aspartic acid, l-aspargine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-proline, l-threonine or l-valine.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, amoxycillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, furazolidone, furoxone, lincomycin, nitrofurazone, nitrofurantoin, nystatin, penicillin and trimethoprim, but sensitive to chlortetracycline, colistin, gentamicin, kanamycin, oxytetracycline, polymyxin B, rifampicin, tetracycline and tobramycin.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 58·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CMS 64<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4994<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15321<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>