<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9292_nm.14583" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14583" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14583" rank="species">Lutaonella thermophila</organism><reference id="rid.9292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.-A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lutaonella thermophila gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately thermophilic member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from a coastal hot spring</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2069</fpage><lpage>2073</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005256-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605713</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lutaonella thermophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lutaonella thermophila</em> (ther.mo′phi.la. Gr. adj. <em>thermos</em> hot; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>thermophila</em> heat-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics reported for the genus, cells are rods, 0.4–0.5 μm in width and 1.0–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Growth is visible after 24 h incubation on MA at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies on MA are shiny, transparent, yellow and circular with regular edges.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–55 °C (optimum 40–45 °C), but not at 20 or 60 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 8) and in the presence of 2–6 % NaCl (optimum 3–5 %) in MB.</s><s>Growth does not occur on tryptic soy broth or on R2A agar without supplementation with sea salts or seawater.</s><s>Growth does not occur on R2A and tryptic soy agars supplemented with NaCl only.</s><s>Obligate requirement for natural seawater or artificial sea salts (1–3 %).</s><s>No anaerobic growth occurs on MB and MA supplemented with potassium nitrate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and gelatin are hydrolysed, but agar, starch and Tween 40 are not.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in the Biolog GN2 system: glycogen, cellobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine and l-proline.</s><s>All of the other carbon sources in the GN2 system are not utilized.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16</sub><sub> : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Additional physiological features are given in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-MHSW-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22538<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15069<sup>T</sup>), isolated from water of a coastal hot spring, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>