<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2264_nm.2540" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2540" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2540" rank="species">Deleya salina</organism><reference id="rid.2264"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Valderrama</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bejar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutierrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruiz-Berraquero</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deleya salina, sp. nov., a moderately halophilic Gram-negative bacterium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>377</fpage><lpage>384</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-377</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Deleya salina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Deleya salina</i> (sa.li'na. L. adj. <i>salina</i>, salted, saline)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short rods that are 0.7 to 0.8 μm in diameter and 2.0 to 2.5 μm long when the organism is grown in presence of 7.5% (wt/vol) salts; they commonly occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>At higher salt concentrations, the cells are elongated filaments (15 to 18 μm or more long), and only coccoid cells occur at low salt concentrations.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Endospores or sheaths are not formed.</s><s>Encapsulated.</s><s>The cells accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on MH medium containing 7.5% (wt/vol) salts are circular with entire margins, convex, smooth, glossy translucent, and slightly yellow or cream.</s><s>They are 1 to 2 mm in diamenter after 24 h and are more mucoid after 48 to 72 h.</s><s>Growth in liquid cultures is uniform.</s><s>Aerobic with a respiratory type of metabolism.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophs.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Moderate halophiles that are capable of growth at salt concentrations between 2.5 and 20% (wt/vol).</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salts.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in media supplemented with salt at a</s></p><p class="description"><s>concentration of 5% (wt/vol) at 32°C and pH 7.2.</s><s>These organisms show a specific requirement for Na<sup>+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup> cations supplied as Cl<sup>-</sup> or SO<sup>2-</sup> salts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Some strains are capable of respiration on nitrate or nitrite but not on fumarate.</s><s>They reduce nitrate to nitrite; nitrite is also reduced by some strains.</s><s>Acids are generally not produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>No strain produces pyocyanine or fluorescein.</s><s>Selenite is reduced, and urea, Tween 20, and tyrosine are hydrolyzed.</s><s>No hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, lecithovitellin, starch, or Tween 80.</s><s>No oxidation of gluconate.</s><s>No production of phosphatase.</s><s>Negative for arginine, lysine, and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>No growth on cetrimide agar.</s><s>No hemolysis of blood agar supplemented with 7.5% (wt/vol) salts occurs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D-Fructose, acetate, citrate, fumarate, D-gluconate, DL-malate, pyruvate, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, L-leucine, and L-serine are used by 80% or more of the strains as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized by at least 80% of the strains: esculin, D-salicin, benzoate, caprylate, oxalate, L-histidine, and L-tryptophan,</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to ampicillin (100 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), colistin (50 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), penicillin G (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampin (5 μg), and sulfonamide (200 μg)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 60.7 to 64.2 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from hypersaline habitats, such as soils, salt ponds, and salt lakes, and from the sea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain F8-11 (= ATCC 49509), which was isolated from a hypersaline soil near the Mediterranean Sea coast near Alicante, Spain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species; it has all of the characteristics described above except the following: nitrite reduction to gas, respiration on nitrate or nitrite, and utilization of salicin and serine as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.2 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>