<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.23_nm.3410" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3410" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3410" rank="species">Actinobacillus rossii</organism><reference id="rid.23"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stevens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus rossii sp. nov., Actinobacillus seminis sp. nov., nom. rev., Pasteurella bettii sp. nov., Pasteurella lymphangitidis sp. nov., Pasteurella mairi sp. nov., and Pasteurella trehalosi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinobacillus rossii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinobacillus rossii</i> (ross. i'i. M.L. gen. n. <i>rossii</i>, of Ross named after R. F. Ross, who with his colleagues isolated the organism [37])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenon 17 of Sneath and Stevens (46); group “Ross” of Kilian and Frederiksen (21).</s><s>Cells are small nonmotile bacilli, seldom coccobacilli, that are often &#x003E;2 μm long.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic and facultatively anaerobic; mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on sheep blood agar are round, greyish, semitransparent, and about 2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C, sometimes showing weak hemolysis without marked greening of the erythrocytes.</s><s>Notable for producing acid from <i>m</i>-inositol and sorbitol, but not from sucrose, and for reducing Janus green (46).</s><s>Other properties are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the vaginas of postparturient sows and aborted piglets (37, 46).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological cross-reactions have been reported with <i>Actinobacillus suis</i>, <i>A. lignieresii</i>, Actinobacillus equuli, and <i>A. seminis</i>, and <i>P. haemolytica</i> (37).</s><s>DNA-DNA pairing values of about 50% or less to <i>A. lignieresii</i>, <i>A. suis</i>, <i>A. equuli</i>, <i>P. haemolytica</i> sensu stricto, and <i>P. ureae</i> have been reported (13, 35).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 41.9 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) method (25, 34).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 27072 (= NCTC 10801 = Ross 192 = P624 = A55 and A68) (46).</s><s>In our hands this strain was positive for the tests marked d in Table 1, except for gas production from glucose and acid production from lactose.</s></p></content></protolog>