<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3239_nm.3593" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3593" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3593" rank="species">Desulfotignum phosphitoxidans</organism><reference id="rid.3239"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thiemann</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laue</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Friedrich</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfotignum phosphitoxidans sp. nov., a new marine sulfate reducer that oxidizes phosphite to phosphate.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>177</volume><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>391</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00203-002-0402-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11976747</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfotignum phosphitoxidans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfotignum phosphitoxidans</i> (phos.phit.o'xi.dans. M.L. adj. <i>phosphitoxidans</i> oxidizing phosphite, referring to its utilization of this unusual electron source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, 0.6–0.8 μm wide and 2–4 μm long, with pointed ends, gram-negative, non-sporing, non-motile.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemotroph, reducing sulfate, thiosulfate or sulfite, and oxidizing a broad variety of substrates, including phosphite, hydrogen, formate, fumarate, malate, pyruvate, glucose, arabinose, xylose, glycine, betaine, proline, glutamate, yeast extract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lithoautotrophic growth with phosphite, hydrogen, or formate; acetate not required for growth.</s><s>Acetate is co-oxidized in the presence of hydrogen, but does not support growth on its own.</s><s>In the absence of sulfate, phosphite is fermented to phosphate with acetate as reduced product.</s><s>Carbon monoxide dehydrogenase present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thiophosphate, ethanol, propanol, lactate, propionate, butyrate, crotonate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, 2-oxoglutarate, 3-oxoglutarate, choline, alanine, fructose, and ribose not used.</s><s>Thiosulfate not dismutated.</s><s>Growth requires mineral media with sulfide as reductant.</s><s>Growth is optimal in brackish water or saltwater medium, with at least 10 g NaCl and 1.5 g MgCl<sub>2</sub> per l.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range 5.0–8.0, optimum at pH 6.9–7.2.</s><s>Temperature range 15–30°C, optimum at 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain cytochromes <i>b</i> and <i>c</i> and desulforubidin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 53.9 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: anoxic marine and brackish sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: FiPS-3, deposited as DSM 13687 with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, and as OCM 818 with the Oregon Collection of Methanogens, Portland, OR, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>