<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.13285_nm.1266" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1266" rank="genus">Brevundimonas</organism><reference id="rid.13285"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Scottaa</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bennasara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moorec</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lalucata</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomilaf</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic characterisation of ceftazidime-resistant Brevundimonas isolates and description of Brevundimonas faecalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>34</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>408</fpage><lpage>413</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2011.06.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21782367</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevundimonas faecalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0090"&#x003E;<em>Brevundimonas faecalis</em> (fa.e.ca’lis. L.n. <em>faex</em> faecis, dregs, faeces; L. fem. suff. -alis, suffix denoting pertaining to; N.L. fem. adj. faecalis, pertaining to faeces).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0095"&#x003E;Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic rods (1.2–1.5 μm long, 0.5 μm wide), motile by means of a short-wavelength single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on LB agar medium are circular with a smooth border, slightly convex, creamy yellow in colour and 1.0 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>The strain does not grow at 4 °C or at 42 °C, and the optimal growth temperature oscillates between 30 and 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–1.5% but not 3% NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not utilized as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Oxidase activity is positive but catalase is negative.</s><s>Indole formation, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, β-glucosidase, gelatinase and PNPG tests are negative.</s><s>In the API ZYM assay, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase activities were detected, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities were absent.</s><s>It grows with N-acetyl-glucosamine and capric acid but not with glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, maltose, gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid, citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>It is able to assimilate l-histidine, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-leucine, l-alaninamide, Tween 40 and 80, l-rhamnose, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-proline, l-alanylglycine, propionic acid, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-serine, l-glutamic acid, l-threonine, pyruvic acid methyl ester, β-hydroxybutyric acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, and glycyl-l-glutamic acid as carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0100"&#x003E;The main cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18:1</sub>ω7c and C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>The G + C mol % of the DNA is 65.14.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0105"&#x003E;Strain CS20.3<sup>T</sup> (CCUG 58127<sup>T</sup> = CECT 7729<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain, isolated from sewage water from a hospital in Palma de Mallorca (Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>