<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8733_nm.13646" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13646" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13646" rank="species">Streptomyces rapamycinicus</organism><reference id="rid.8733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Five new members of the Streptomyces violaceusniger 16S rRNA gene clade: Streptomyces castelarensis sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces himastatinicus sp. nov., Streptomyces mordarskii sp. nov., Streptomyces rapamycinicus sp. nov. and Streptomyces ruanii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1369</fpage><lpage>1378</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65408-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523180</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces rapamycinicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces rapamycinicus</em> (ra.pa.my.ci′ni.cus. N.L. neut. n. <em>rapamycinum</em> rapamycin; L. suffix -<em>icus</em>-<em>a</em>-<em>um</em> related to; N.L. masc. adj. <em>rapamycinicus</em> related to rapamycin, referring to the ability to produce rapamycin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and a previous study (Vezina <em>et al.</em>, 1975).</s><s>Oval, rugose ornamented spores (0.8×1.6 μm) are borne in spirals of three or more turns; ten or more spores per spiral.</s><s>Grows well on modified Bennett's, glucose-asparagine, oatmeal, sabouraud-glucose, sabouraud-maltose, tomato paste, oatmeal, tryptone-yeast extract and yeast extract-malt extract agars.</s><s>On oatmeal agar the aerial spore mass colour is grey, becoming black and moist when mature, the substrate mycelium is greyish-yellow and a light-yellow diffusible pigment is formed.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on either peptone-yeast extract-iron or tyrosine agars.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C, but not at 4 or 40 °C, and from pH 6.0 to 10.0, but not at pH 5.0 or 11.0.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>Degrades adenine, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 and tyrosine, but not cellulose, chitin, DNA, keratin, pectin, RNA, tributyrin, xanthine or xylan.</s><s>d-Fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but not d-aesculin, amygdalin, arabinose, l-arabitol, dulcitol, glucosamine, inulin, pectin, d-sorbitol or l-sorbose (all at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Butan-1,4-diol is used as a sole carbon source, but not methanol or propanol (all at 1 %, v/v).</s><s>l-Arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-ornithine, l-proline and l-threonine are used as sole nitrogen sources for energy and growth, but not l-aminobutyric acid, dl-aspartic acid, l-leucine, dl-norleucine or l-norvaline (all at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 13 % (w/v) NaCl or 0.1 % (v/v) phenol.</s><s>Sensitive to gentamicin sulphate, kanamycin sulphate, neomycin sulphate, streptomycin sulphate and tobramycin sulphate (each at 8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Antimicrobial activity is shown against <em>Candida albicans</em>, <em>Enterobacter aerogenes</em>, <em>Escherichia coli</em>, <em>Microsporum gypseum</em>, <em>Proteus mirabilis</em>, <em>Staphylococcus aureus</em> and <em>Trichophyton granulosum</em>.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Produces the antibiotic rapamycin.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRRL 5491<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 29253<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from Easter Island.</s></p></content></protolog>