<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8197_nm.13358" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13358" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13358" rank="species">Halomonas salifodinae</organism><reference id="rid.8197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>X.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas salifodinae sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt mine in China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2855</fpage><lpage>2858</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000729-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060071</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas salifodinae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas salifodinae</em> (sa.li.fo.di′nae. L. n. <em>sal</em>, <em>salis</em> salt; L. n. <em>fodina</em> mine; N.L. gen. n. <em>salifodinae</em> of a salt mine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, long rods, 0.8–1.2×4.0–6.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on complex agar medium are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, elevated and brown–yellow after 2 days growth.</s><s>No growth in the absence of salt.</s><s>Grows in the presence of total salt concentrations of 0.5–20 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 3 % (w/v).</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.0 and 4–48 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0 and 30 °C).</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate, nitrite or fumarate.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar but not on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Does not produce exopolysaccharide or poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate.</s><s>Starch and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin and Tweens 20 and 80 are not.</s><s>Positive for methyl red test, oxidation of gluconate, reduction of selenite and urease.</s><s>Negative for indole production, lecithinase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>ο</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase and Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is formed from l-cysteine.</s><s>No nitrate or nitrite reduction.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: acetate, adonitol, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartate, citrate, d-fructose, fumarate, gluconate, glucose, l-glutamate, glycerol, glycine, l-histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, isoleucine, lactate, malate, maltose, mannitol, l-ornithine, propionate, pyruvate, ribose, l-serine, sorbitol, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and l-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, cellobiose, ethanol, formate, d-galactose, lactose, malonate, d-mannose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, d-fructose, glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, mannitol, sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose, but not from l-arabinose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, rhamnose or sorbose.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, neomycin, nitrofurantoin, penicillin, polymyxin B, rifampicin and streptomycin, but not to bacitracin, erythromycin, kanamycin, novobiocin, nystatin or tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is ubiquinone-9.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.5±0.2 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BC7<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6774<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14803<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt mine at Baicheng in Xinjiang Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>