<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7149_nm.6656" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6656" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6656" rank="species">Friedmanniella antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.7149"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prauser</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Friedmanniella antarctica gen. nov., sp. nov., an LL-diaminopimelic acid-containing actinomycete from Antarctic sandstone.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>278</fpage><lpage>283</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-278</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103610</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i><i>Friedmanniella antarctica</i></i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Friedmanniella antarctica</i> (ant'arc.ti.ca. M. L. fem. adj. <i>antarctica</i>, isolated from Antarctica)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The spherical cells are 0.5 to 2.2 μm in diameter.</s><s>The cells are arranged in more or less regular packets, which adhere to one another to form clusters.</s><s>Growth in submerged standing and shaking cultures is slow and poor.</s><s>Colonies on R agar are up to 2 mm in diameter and raised and have irregular edges and shapes.</s><s>The colony surface is crumbly and dull to smooth and shiny depending on the growth medium.</s><s>The orange color of colonies may become more intense when the organism is cultured in diffuse daylight.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 22°C.</s><s>The temperature range is approximately 9 to 25°C; no growth occurs at 6 and 28°C.</s><s>The optimal pH range for growth is 6.0 to 7.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Urease positive.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-ribose, is produced weakly from L-arabinose, and is produced very weakly from D-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-rhamnose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, D-cellobiose, trehalose, D-raffinose, glycerol, D-mannitol, and <i>myo</i>-inositol.</s><s>Starch and esculin are hydrolyzed, and Tween 80 and DNA are only weakly hydrolyzed.</s><s>Casein and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Sodium formate is utilized as a carbon source.</s><s>Sodium acetate, sodium aconitate, sodium benzoate, sodium citrate, disodium succinate, and potassium hydrogentartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, xanthine, adenine, DL-tyrosine, and sodium hippurate are not decomposed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 73 mol% G + C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism was isolated from a cryptoendolithic microbial community in sandstone on Linnaeus Terrace, McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain AA-1042.</s><s>It has been deposited in the DSMZ-Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH as strain DSM 11053<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>