<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6717_nm.4515" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4515" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4515" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacterium saccharolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.6717"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lowe</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zeikus</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic distinction of saccharolytic thermophilic anaerobes: description of Thermoanaerobacterium xylanolyticum gen. nov., sp. nov., and Thermoanaerobacterium saccharolyticum gen. nov., sp. nov.; reclassification of Thermoanaerobium brockii, Clostridium thermosulfurogenes, and Clostridium thermohydrosulfuricum E100-69 as Thermoanaerobacter brockii comb. nov., Thermoanaerobacterium thermosulfurigenes comb. nov., and Thermoanaerobacter thermohydrosulfuricus comb. nov., respectively; and transfer of Clostridium thermohydrosulfuricum 39E to Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>41</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-41</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium saccharolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacterium saccharolyticum</i> (sac.cha.ro. ly'ti-cum. Gr. n. <i>sacchar</i>, sugar; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; N.L. neut. adj. <i>saccharolyticum</i>, sugar dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular characteristics.</s><s>Rods (approximately 0.8 to 1.0 by 3.0 to 15 μm; some cells are occasionally as long as 30 μm).</s><s>Elongated cell morphology occurs during nutrient limitation or stationary phase.</s><s>The cell walls contain three electron-dense layers that are 5 nm thick and alternate with electron-light layers of similar thickness.</s><s>Gram-negative, but the distinct outer membrane characteristic of many gram-negative bacteria is not observed.</s><s>Cell division proceeds by formation of well-defined division septa, often producing daughter cells of unequal lengths.</s><s>Cells are motile and peritrichous.</s><s>Cells survive heating at 85°C for 15 min but not heating at 90°C for 5 min.</s><s>Cells contain a 1.5-MDa plasmid.</s><s>Surface colonies on agar plates are soft, tan, circular, and convex with hollow centers ("donut" shape).</s><s>Colony diameters range from 0.5 to 4.0 mm after 4 days of growth at 55°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Catalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs in an N<sub>2</sub>-gassed medium lacking chemical reducing agents.</s><s>Addition of reducing agents (cysteine or Na<sub>2</sub>S) does not stimulate growth.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 6.0, and the minimum and maximum pH values for growth initiation are 5.0 and less than 7.5, respectively.</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 68 to 70°C; the optimum temperature is 60°C; and the minimum temperature is 45°C.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by penicillin G (200 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (100 μg/ml), neomycin (100 μg/ml), or O<sub>2</sub> (0.2 atm [ca. 20.26 kPa]).</s><s>Resistant to 2% NaCl.</s><s>Yeast extract stimulates growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolic characteristics.</s><s>Ferments a wide variety of carbohydrates, including glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, xylose, starch, rhamnose, raffinose, and xylan.</s><s>Cellulose, ribose, melibiose, melezitose, xylitol, and sorbitol are not fermented.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The fermentation products from either glucose or xylan include ethanol, acetic acid, lactic acid, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>L-Rhamnose is fermented to equimolar amounts of 1,2-propandiol and a mixture of ethanol, acetic acid, lactic acid, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>The habitat is geothermal sites in Wyoming (Yellowstone National Park and Thermopolis areas) and Nevada (Steamboat area).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium saccharolyticum</i> is strain B6A-RI (= ATCC 49915 = DSM 7060).</s></p></content></protolog>