<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4601_nm.2950" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2950" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2950" rank="species">Vibrio agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.4601"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio agarivorans sp. nov., a novel agarolytic marine bacterium.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2031</fpage><lpage>2036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760944</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio agarivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio agarivorans</i> (a.ga.ri.vo'rans. Malayan n. <i>agar</i> agar; N.L. n. <i>agarum</i>, <i>-i</i> agar; M.L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <i>agarivorans</i> agar-eating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, approximately 2-4 μm long¬0.4-0.6 μm wide, facultatively anaerobic, motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are regular in shape and unpigmented.</s><s>On TCBS agar, they grow as green colonies.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative without gas production.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase and nitrate reduction to nitrite are positive.</s><s>No growth occurs without the addition of NaCl to the culture medium.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 37 °C.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulphate, Mùller's and Thornley's arginine dihydrolase, and ornithine and lysine decarboxylase test results are negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses agar.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-melibiose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, 1-O-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl α-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, mucate, L-malate, 2-keto-dgluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, caprate, succinate, fumarate, DL-glycerate, D-glucosamine, L-glutamate, L-serine and L-aspartate.</s><s>None of the strains utilizes the following substrates: D-trehalose, D-mannose, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-raffinose, lactulose, β-gentibiose, 1-O-methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, D-ribose, L-arabinose, palatinose, L-rhamnose, L-fucose, D-melezitose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, D-tagatose, glycerol, myo-inositol, maltitol, D-turanose, D-sorbitol, adonitol, hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide, D-lyxose, i-erythritol, 1-O-methyl α-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl D-glucopyranose, D-saccharate, L-tartrate, D-tartrate, <i>m</i>-tartrate, D-malate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, transaconitate, tricarballylate, citrate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, L-tryptophan, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, gentisate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, betain, putrescine, DL-α-aminobutyrate, histamine, DL-lactate, caprylate, L-histidine, glutarate, DL-aaminovalerate, ethanolamine, tryptamine, itaconate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, D-alanine, malonate, 2-oxoglutarate, L-arginine and salicin.</s><s>Isolated from sea water at the Mediterranean coast of Valencia (Spain).</s><s>Type strain 289<sup>T</sup> has been deposited at the Colección Española de Cultivos Tipo (Valencia, Spain) as strain CECT 5085<sup>T</sup>, and at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as DSM 13756<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The G+­C content of DNA of the type strain is 44.8 mol%.</s><s>Strain 351 has been also deposited at both collections as CECT 5084 and DSM 13755, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics of the type strain of <i>Vibrio agarivorans</i> sp. nov.</s><s>The type strain of <i>V. agarivorans</i> is 289<sup>T</sup>, isolated in Spain from Mediterranean sea water.</s><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the species, it has the following features: it utilizes aesculin and L-proline as sole carbon and energy sources, but not D-gluconate, L-alanine, L-tyrosine or pyruvate.</s></p></content></protolog>