<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7382_nm.3335" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3335" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3335" rank="species">Sodalis glossinidius</organism><reference id="rid.7382"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dale</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maudlin</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sodalis gen. nov. and Sodalis glossinidius sp. nov., a microaerophilic secondary endosymbiont of the tsetse fly Glossina morsitans morsitans.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>267</fpage><lpage>275</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-267</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028272</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sodalis glossinidius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sodalis glossinidius</i> (glos.sin.i'dus. M. L. <i>glossinidius</i> of the genus <i>Glossina</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are non motile, non spore-forming, filamentous, Gram-negative rods (2-12 μm in length, 1-1.5 μm in diameter), dividing by septation.</s><s>The bacteria grow intracellularly in <i>Aedes albopictus</i> cell culture and can grow axenically in media containing enzymically digested proteins as nitrogen sources.</s><s>They are microaerophilic and can only be cultivated on solid media with aerotolerance-enhancing supplements or under a reduced-oxygen atmosphere.</s><s>Optimum atmospheric conditions for solid-phase culture are 5 % oxygen, balanced with carbon dioxide.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 25°C with little or no growth at temperatures exceeding 30°C.</s><s>Negative for catalase, oxidase, DNase, gelatinase, urease, nitrate reductase, indole production, hippurate hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine decarboxylase and starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Produces α-galactosidase and β-N-acetylglucosaminidase.</s><s>Do not produce α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase and β-xylosidase.</s><s>Utilizes N-acetyl-D-glucosamine and raffinose accompanied by a high level of acid production.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, glycol chitosan, mannitol and sorbitol with accompanying weak acid production.</s><s>No increase in growth is detected when any of the following carbon sources are incorporated in media: acetic acid, adonitol, δ-amino valeric acid, L-arabinose, n-butanol, citric acid, dulcitol, ethanol, fructose, fumaric acid, galactose, glycerol, glycolic acid, histamine, β-hydroxybenzoic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, lactose, D,L-malic acid, maltose, mannose, melibiose, methyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, <i>myo</i>-inositol, n-propanol, pyruvic acid, quinic acid, rhamnose, ribose, saccharic acid, salicin, sarcosine, sorbose, succinic acid, sucrose, starch, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>The type strain is M1<sup>T</sup>, isolated from a laboratory colony of Glossinia morsitans morsitans.</s><s>The bacterium is found in the midgut, fat body and haemolymph of <i>G. m. morsitans</i>.</s><s>Strain M1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited at the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria (Aberdeen, UK) under deposition NCIMB 13495.</s></p></content></protolog>