<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1569_nm.3070" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3070" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3070" rank="species">Aeromonas simiae</organism><reference id="rid.1569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harf-Monteil</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flèche</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bermond</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas simiae sp. nov., isolated from monkey faeces.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>481</fpage><lpage>485</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02786-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023964</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromonas simiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aeromonas simiae</em> (si′mi.ae. Gr. n. <em>simia</em> monkey; N.L. adj. <em>simiae</em> from monkeys).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains display the following characteristics that are typical of the genus <em>Aeromonas</em>: Gram-negative, straight, motile rods with a polar flagellum, cytochrome oxidase-positive, chemoorganotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolisms, catalase-positive, reduce nitrate to nitrite without production of gas and resistant to vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 μg).</s><s>Unable to grow in nutrient broth with 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C after 24 h on trypticase soy agar or sheep-blood agar, but strains also grow at 42 °C after 24 h.</s><s>Unable to produce indole, gas from glucose or <em>β</em>-haemolysis on sheep-blood agar.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer- and ornithine decarboxylase-negative; lysine decarboxylase-, arginine dihydrolase- and pyrazinamidase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and acid production from arbutin are variable.</s><s>By fermentation, acid is produced from glycerol, ribose, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-sucrose, d-maltose, d-trehalose, starch, glycogen and gluconate, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, salicin or lactose.</s><s>Major characteristics that differentiate the species from other <em>Aeromonas</em> species are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Susceptible to cephalothin, but resistant to ampicillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IBS S6874<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107798<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 47378<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the faeces of a monkey (<em>Macaca fasciculari</em>s) that was kept in the Centre for Primatology, Louis Pasteur University, Strasbourg, France.</s><s>This strain has all of the above-described properties for the species; in addition, aesculin is not hydrolysed after 48 h incubation and acid is produced from arbutin.</s></p></content></protolog>