<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12682_nm.22421" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22421" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22421" rank="species">Bacillus thermolactis</organism><reference id="rid.12682"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coorevits</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dinsdale</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halket</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Landschoot</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus thermolactis sp. nov., isolated from dairy farms, and emended description of Bacillus thermoamylovorans</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1954</fpage><lpage>1961</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024240-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833876</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus thermolactis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus thermolactis</em> (ther.mo.lac′tis. Gr. adj. <em>thermos</em> hot; L. gen. n. <em>lactis</em> from milk; N.L. gen. n. <em>thermolactis</em> a thermotolerant bacterium isolated from milk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-stain-positive, rod-shaped cells (0.7–0.9×4–10 µm) that occur either singly or in short chains of two to four cells, and in filaments.</s><s>Mainly non-motile but some strains are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>After 24 h of incubation at 50 °C on TSA, colonies are circular and cream-coloured with irregular edges, slightly rough and matt surfaces and glossy centres, and have diameters of approximately 1–4 mm.</s><s>Endospores are formed within 24 h of incubation at 50 °C on TSA containing 5 mg MnSO<sub>4</sub> l<sup>−1</sup>; they are ellipsoidal, lie subterminally and do not swell the cells.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7 but not at pH 6 or 8.</s><s>Growth occurs between 40 and 60 °C, optimally at 50 °C, but does not occur at 30 or 70 °C.</s><s>Does not tolerate 1 % NaCl (w/v) for growth.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed, starch is hydrolysed weakly, and aesculin hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase production are positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, reactions for gelatin hydrolysis and nitrate reduction are positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide, indole, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>ortho</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactopyranosidase (ONPG), tryptophan deaminase, urease and the Voges–Proskauer (acetoin production) reactions are negative.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CHB gallery: trehalose (weak), d-fructose, d-glucose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, mannitol (weak), ribose, starch (weak) and sucrose (weak).</s><s>Acid production is variable between strains for maltose.</s><s>No acid is produced from: 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, adonitol, amygdalin, arbutin, raffinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fucose, melezitose, melibiose, turanose, d-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-mannose, d-tagatose, dulcitol, erythritol, galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, l-arabitol, l-fucose, lactose, l-sorbose, l-xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl d-glucoside, methyl d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol or xylitol.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone and the peptidoglycan type is A1γ.</s><s>The mol% G+C of the DNA of the type strain is 35.0±0.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R-6488<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25569<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23332<sup>T</sup>), isolated from milk and dairy farm environments.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain is very weakly positive for acid production from maltose, and negative for aesculin hydrolysis.</s></p></content></protolog>