<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7480_nm.5474" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5474" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5474" rank="species">Eremococcus coleocola</organism><reference id="rid.7480"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez Jovita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of a novel gram-positive, catalase-negative coccus from horses: description of Eremococcus coleocola gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1381</fpage><lpage>1385</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555316</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eremococcus coleocola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eremococcus coleocola</i> (co'le.o.co.la. Gr. n. <i>colea</i> vagina; L. masc. suffix -<i>cola</i> inhabitant; M.L. <i>coleocola</i> inhabitant of the vagina, referring to the isolation of the type strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of Gram-positive cocci, some of which may be elongated, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies are pin-point, shiny, entire, circular, convex and non-corroding on blood agar after 24 h.</s><s>α-Haemolytic on horse- and sheep-blood agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows at 42°C but not at 10°C.</s><s>Grows weakly in 6.5% NaCl but not in 10% NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow on Difco Bacto aesculin agar.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, maltose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, melibiose, melezitose, pullulan, D-raffinose, D-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Weak acid production from N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, esterase C-4 (weak reaction) and ester lipase C-8 (weak reaction) activities are detected.</s><s>Urease activity is variable.</s><s>Alanine-phenylalanine- proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, Pgalacturonidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycine-tryptophan arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C14, chymotrypsin, trypsin and pyrazinamidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The G + C content of DNA of the type strain is 40 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is L-lysine-direct (A1α).</s><s>Isolated from horse vaginal and clitoral fossa swabs.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Eremococcus coleocola</i> is CCUG 38207<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>