<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4611_nm.10603" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10603" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10603" rank="species">Arenimonas donghaensis</organism><reference id="rid.4611"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>Y.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenimonas donghaensis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from seashore sand</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>954</fpage><lpage>958</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64457-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473240</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenimonas donghaensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenimonas donghaensis</em> (dong.ha.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>donghaensis</em> pertaining to Donghae, the Korean name of the East Sea of Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved rods that are 0.4–0.6 μm wide and 1.3–3.0 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish white, translucent and convex on R2A agar after 3 days cultivation.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 7.0–9.0, with an optimum at pH 8.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C, with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0–3 % (w/v) (optimum of 1–2 %).</s><s>Does not grow under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein, tyrosine, DNA and gelatin.</s><s>Negative for indole production, Voges–Proskauer test, phenylalanine deamination and hydrolysis of starch, urea and cellulose.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, cells are positive only for hydrolysis of gelatin, and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, cells are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, a small amount of an unknown phospholipid and two unknown aminophospholipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> when grown on R2A for 3 days.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 65.0 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HO3-R19<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11381<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18148<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seashore sand in Pohang, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>