<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7607_nm.14037" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14037" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14037" rank="species">Castellaniella caeni</organism><reference id="rid.7607"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Castellaniella caeni sp. nov., a denitrifying bacterium isolated from sludge of a leachate treatment plant.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2141</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65314-0</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Castellaniella caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Castellaniella caeni</em> (ca.e′ni. L. gen. neut. n. <em>caeni</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in width and 1.2–2.0 μm in legnth.</s><s>After 2 days on R2A, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, transparent, circular, convex and brownish.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, but negative for catalase and lipase.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C; optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>The pH growth range is 5.0–8.5, with an optimum between pH 6.5 and 7.0.</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth and can tolerate 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobically reduces nitrate to nitrite and nitrite to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar, TSA and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch, chitin, xylan, CM-cellulose, casein and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-galactose, cellobiose, l-fucose, acetate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, fumarate, malate, succinate, formate, propionate, caprate, phenylacetate, glutarate, adipate, lactate, suberate, glycerol, d-adonitol, methanol, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-cysteine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and l-valine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: fructose, d-mannose, l-xylose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-lyxose, maltose, trehalose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-lactose, sucrose, benzoate, citrate, tartrate, gluconate, maleic acid, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, oxalate, pyruvate, ethanol, dulcitol, xylitol, d-sorbitol, inositol, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, dextran, inulin, salicin, glycogen, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive; gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulfide and indole production are all negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, glucose or amygdalin.</s><s>Major fatty acids are summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature 7 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>t</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>12<em>t</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.5 mol%.</s><s>Polar lipids detected are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Ho-11<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12197<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23411<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge of the aerobic treatment tanks of a municipal leachate treatment plant located in Daejeon, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>