<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8357_nm.13493" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13493" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13493" rank="species">Novosphingobium acidiphilum</organism><reference id="rid.8357"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Glaeser</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Langer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glaeser</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novosphingobium acidiphilum sp. nov., an acidophilic salt-sensitive bacterium isolated from the humic acid-rich Lake Grosse Fuchskuhle.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>323</fpage><lpage>330</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65852-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196772</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Novosphingobium acidiphilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Novosphingobium acidiphilum</em> (a.ci.di′phi.lum. N.L. neut. n. <em>acidum</em> an acid; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>acidiphilum</em> acid-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species shares all of the characteristics of the genus as summarized by Takeuchi <em>et al.</em> (2001).</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 1.4±0.4 μm long and 0.58±0.06 μm wide in the mid-exponential phase and motile in the early exponential phase.</s><s>Growth is observed on YPG, K7 and R2A agars, but not on nutrient, malt, PYE, CASO, McConkey, soil extract, PCA, Czapek-Dox or LB agars.</s><s>In liquid media, growth is observed at 25 °C in YPG, K7, R2A, M65, TS and NB media, but not in TSA or LB media.</s><s>On YPG agar adjusted to pH 5.5, small circular yellow colonies are formed after incubation for 2–3 days at 25 °C and colonies turn orange after additional incubation for 3 to 5 days.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, positive for cytochrome oxidase and catalase-negative.</s><s>Obligately aerobic and able to grow under microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>Endospores or capsules are not observed.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 32 °C, but not at 37 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH values of 4.5 and 7.0 in MES buffered K7 medium, but not at pH 3.5 or 7.5.</s><s>At pH 5.5, growth is observed with up to 0.5 % NaCl (w/v), but not with 0.75 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Best growth conditions in K7 medium are pH 5.5 to 6.0, 25 °C and without additional NaCl, with doubling times between 5.3 to 6.5 h during exponential growth.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, l-alanine-pNA, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-carboxy-pNA and l-proline-pNA.</s><s>Gives a positive result in tests for the assimilation of cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, maltose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, l-malate, 2-oxoglutarate and l-proline and is slightly positive for the assimilation of l-arabinose, d-fructose and l-leucine.</s><s>Negative result in tests for the assimilation of d-xylose, d-mannitol, citrate, dl-lactate, l-histidine and l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Polar lipid profiles consist of phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine and ethanolamine as major compounds, moderate amounts of a highly hydrophobic yellow pigment stainable with <em>α</em>-naphthol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, sphingoglycolipid, an unknown highly hydrophilic aminophosphoglycolipid and two unknown polar lipids, and minor to trace amounts of one unknown glycolipid, two unknown phospholipids, two unknown polar lipids, another highly hydrophobic yellow pigment.</s><s>No phosphatidylcholine is present and only a moderate content of sphingoglycolipids.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and two 2-hydroxy fatty acids are present, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone Q-10 (90 %).</s><s>The predominant polyamine is spermidine (31.8 μmol g<sup>−1</sup> dry weight) and small amounts of putrescine (0.1 μmol g<sup>−1</sup> dry weight) and spermine (0.2 μmol g<sup>−1</sup> dry weight) are present.</s><s>Acetone/methanol (7/2, v/v) extracted pigments are characterized by <em>λ</em><sub>max</sub> of 453 and 480 nm and cell-free extracts by <em>λ</em><sub>max</sub> at 432/433, 458 and 489/490 nm.</s><s>The main carotenoid is nostoxanthin.</s><s>In addition, seven minor carotenoids are present, including bacteriorubixanthinal.</s><s>The abundance of one unidentified carotenoid distinguishes the type strain from other species of the genus <em>Novosphingobium</em>.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain contains the specific nucleotide signatures defined for the genus <em>Novosphingobium</em> and exhibits a 21 bp signature gap also present in <em>N. nitrogenifigens</em> DSM 19370<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FSW06-204d<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19966<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7496<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55538<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from subsurface water of the south-west basin of the acidic humic acid rich lake Grosse Fuchskuhle, north-eastern Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>