<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4056_nm.6244" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6244" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6244" rank="subspecies">Corynebacterium michiganense tessellarius</organism><reference id="rid.4056"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carlson</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Corynebacterium plant pathogens, including a new pathogen of wheat, based on polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of cellular proteins.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>315</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium michiganense</i> subsp. <i>tessellarius</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium michiganense</i> subsp. <i>tessellarius</i> (tes.sel.lar.'i.us. L. mas. noun</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>tessellarius</i> a mosaic stone maker)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, pleomorphic rods that are nonmotile between 20 and 28°C and measure approximately 0.5 by 1.5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are circular (diameter, 2 to 4 mm), convex, glistening, and butyrous and have entire margins.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 24 and 28°C; strains grow at 10°C but not at 37°C.</s><s>All strains produce an apricot orange pigment, the intensity of which varies with the growth medium and the age of the culture.</s><s>Strains grow on NBY medium.</s><s>This taxon is distinguished from other corynebacteria on the basis of the G+C content (74 mol%) of its DNA, the presence of diaminobutyric acid in its peptidoglycan, and its distinct pattern of protein bands in polyacrylamide gels.</s><s>It is distinguished from the other subspecies of <i>C. michiganense</i> by colony pigment, colony morphology, ability to grow on the CNS medium and tetrazolium chloride medium (containing either triphenyltetrazolium chloride or iodonitrotetrazolium), and its host specificity (pathogenic to wheat [<i>T. aestivum</i> L.], causing foliar lesions in a mosaic pattern).</s><s>The type strain is strain 78181 (=ATCC 33566=PDDCC 7221).</s><s>The species description is based on six strains (Table 1) which have different bacteriocin production characteristics, but cannot otherwise be distinguished.</s><s>Thus, the species description is also the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>