<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1398_nm.2269" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2269" rank="family">Cardiobacteriaceae</organism><reference id="rid.1398"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>La Fontaine</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rood</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Kingella indologenes (Snell and Lapage 1976) to the genus Suttonella gen. nov. as Suttonella indologenes comb. nov.; transfer of Bacteroides nodosus (Beveridge 1941) to the genus Dichelobacter gen. nov. as Dichelobacter nodosus comb. nov.; and assignment of the genera Cardiobacterium, Dichelobacter, and Suttonella to Cardiobacteriaceae fam. nov. in the gamma division of Proteobacteria on the basis of 16S rRNA sequence comparisons.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>426</fpage><lpage>433</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2275858</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cardiobacteriaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cardiobacteriaceae</i> (Car.di.o.bac.te.ri.a´ce.ae. N. L. n. <i>Cardiobacterium</i>, bacterium of the heart; aceae, ending to denote a family; N.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Cardiobacteriaceae</i>, the family of cardiobacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods that are 0.5 to 1.7 μm in diameter and 1 to 6 μm long and have rounded ends.</s><s>Cells occasionally occur in pairs, rosette clusters, or chains.</s><s>Gram negative, but there is a tendency to resist Gram decolorization.</s><s>Nonmotile as determined by normal tests, but may exhibit twitching motility and possess N-methylphenylalanine-type pilins.</s><s>Aerobic and oxidase positive except for members of the anaerobic genus <i>Dichelobacter</i>.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>Fermentative type of chemoorganotrophic metabolism except for members of the genus <i>Dichelobacter</i>, which are arginine chemoorganotrophs.</s><s>Acid but not gas is produced from glucose, sucrose, maltose, mannose, and fructose in fermentative species.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced (as determined by the lead acetate method).</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45 to 60 mol%.</s><s>Species in the family possess the following rare or unique signatures in their 16s rRNAs: uracil at positions 18, 1051, and 1400 and adenine at position 917 (<i>E. coli</i> numbering).</s><s>The family comprises the following three genera: <i>Cardiobacterium</i> (the type genus), <i>Suttonella</i>, and <i>Dichelobacter</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>