<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6946_nm.3053" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3053" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3053" rank="species">Aeromonas culicicola</organism><reference id="rid.6946"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pidiyar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaznowski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Narayan</surname><given-names>N.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patole</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shouche</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas culicicola sp. nov., from the midgut of Culex quinquefasciatus.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1723</fpage><lpage>1728</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02019-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas culicicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas culicicola</i> (cu.li'ci.co.la. N.L. n. <i>Culicidae</i> name of a family of mosquitoes; L. suffix -<i>cola</i> inhabitant of; N.L. n. <i>culicicola</i> inhabitant of <i>Culicidae</i>, to denote the family of the insect hosts from which the species was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight, motile rods with a polar flagellum.</s><s>Oxidase-and catalase-positive, reduces nitrate to nitrite and is resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Shows positive reactions for DNase, Voges-Proskauer test, indole production from tryptophan, alkalinization of citrate, lysine decarboxylation, arginine dihydrolase, ONPG, gelatinase and amylase production.</s><s>No production of ornithine decarboxylase or urease.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 18 h at 30°C, but can also grow at 37°C in LB broth.</s><s>Haemolytic activity is observed after 18 h incubation at 37°C.</s><s>The type strain utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: starch, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-glycerol, glycogen, D-maltose, D-mannitol, melibiose, D-mannose, N-acetyl glucosamine, D-sucrose and D-ribose.</s><s>Uniform acid production is observed with all these substrates.</s><s>Does not produce acid from adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, arbutin, methyl aglucoside, methyl α-mannoside, α-gentiobiose, methyl β-xyloside, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, dfucose, L-fucose, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, melezitose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, xylitol or D-xylose.</s><s>The type strain is resistant to ampicillin and amikacin and sensitive to cefadroxil, cefriaxone, cefuroxime, ciprofloxacin and norfloxacin.</s><s>It shows intermediate resistance to cefoperazone, cefotaxime, cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, gentamicin, netilmicin and penicillin.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is highly similar to all known sequences of <i>A. jandaei</i>, with a single base difference at position 264, while DNA-DNA hybridization studies separate it from <i>A. jandaei</i> (54% similarity).</s><s>It shows highest similarity to <i>A. sobria</i> (61%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain has been deposited at the Microbial Type Culture Collection at Institute of Microbial Technology, Chandigarh, India, as strain MTCC 3249<sup>T</sup> and at the National Collection of Industrial Micro-organisms, National Chemical Laboratory, Pune, India, as strain NCIM 5147<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>