<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2763_nm.11417" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11417" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11417" rank="species">Rapidithrix thailandica</organism><reference id="rid.2763"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Srisukchayakul</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suwanachart</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sangnoi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanjana-Opas</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hosoya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arunpairojana</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rapidithrix thailandica gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine gliding bacterium isolated from samples collected from the Andaman sea, along the southern coastline of Thailand.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2275</fpage><lpage>2279</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65087-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911296</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rapidithrix thailandica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rapidithrix thailandica</em> (thai.lan.dic.a. N.L. fem. adj. <em>thailandica</em> pertaining to Thailand, from where the organisms were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are as those given in the genus description.</s><s>In addition, the optimal growth temperature is 25–30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5–10.</s><s>Colonies are light olive grey.</s><s>Peptone and ammonium are useful nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>Positive in tests for oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Negative in tests for catalase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Decomposes starch, gelatin, l-tyrosine, and Tweens 20 and 80.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-arabinose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, mannose, amygdalin, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, gentiobiose and l-fucose, but not from erythritol, l-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, fructose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, arbutin, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol or gluconate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is in the range 40–43 mol%.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TISTR 1750<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15448<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine algae from the Andaman Sea, Krabi Province, Thailand.</s><s>Strains TISTR 1736 (isolated from decayed wood from the Andaman Sea, Phuket Province, Thailand) and TISTR 1741 (isolated from seashell material from the Andaman Sea, Trang Province, Thailand) are reference strains.</s></p></content></protolog>