<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4197_nm.8392" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8392" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8392" rank="species">Sneathia sanguinegens</organism><reference id="rid.4197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Törnqvist</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>von Essen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of some strains from human clinical sources which resemble Leptotrichia sanguinegens: description of Sneathia sanguinegens sp. nov., gen. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>361</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00047</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11822670</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sneathia sanguinegens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sneathia sanguinegens</i> (sanguin.e.gens L. n. <i>sanguis</i> blood; L. part adj. <i>egens</i> needing; n. L. adj. <i>sanguinegens</i> needing blood; because the organism needs blood or serum)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Sneathia sanguinegens</i> consists of Gram-negative anaerobic or facultatively anaerobic, non-sporeforming, non-motile rodshaped cells.</s><s>Colonies on chocolate or blood agar are pin-point and convex after 72 hours.</s><s>Fastidious requiring blood or serum for growth.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Lactic acid and formic acid and minor amounts of acetic acid are the end products of glucose metabolism; succinic acid may be produced.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from mannose and raffinose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, maltose, melebiose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, or trehalose.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, phosphoamidase, and β-glucuronidase are detected.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, alanine arylamidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, α-arabinosidase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase-6-phosphate, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, leucine glycin arylamidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, proline arylamidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase and urease are not detected.</s><s>Activity may or may not be detected for ester lipase C8, esterase C4, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, phenyl alanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, serine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase.</s><s>Indole negative and Voges-Proskauer test negative.</s><s>Aesculin and hippurate are hydrolysed but not starch.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens (blood, amniotic fluid).</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 22–25 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 41628<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106906<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>