<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7324_nm.910" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.910" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.910" rank="species">Craurococcus roseus</organism><reference id="rid.7324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saitoh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Craurococcus roseus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Paracraurococcus ruber gen. nov., sp. nov., novel aerobic bacteriochlorophyll a-containing bacteria from soil.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1043</fpage><lpage>1047</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-1043</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734062</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Craurococcus roseus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Craurococcus roseus</i> (ro.se.us. L. adj. <i>roseus</i> rose-coloured, pink, pink bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony colour is pink.</s><s>Cell size is 0.8-2.0 µm.</s><s>Optimum growth condition is pH 7.5 and 28 to 32°C.</s><s>It can not grow at pH 6.8.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-ribose, D-mannose, D-fructose, L-rhamnose and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from lactose, maltose, sucrose, inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol and starch.</s><s>Good carbon sources for growth are D-xylose, fumarate and L-glutamate.</s><s>Moderate growth occurs with glycerol, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-fucose, DL-lactate, malonate, pyruvate, gluconate and L-malate.</s><s>D-Mannitol, D-sorbitol, methanol, ethanol, 1,2-propanediol, kerosene, acetate, butyrate, citrate, formate, glycolate, propionate, succinate, phthalate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate and benzoate are not utilized.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to chloramphenicol, penicillin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but are resistant to polymyxin B.</s><s>The absorption spectrum of bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> in the intact cells has maxima at 800 and 872 nm.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is NS130<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 9933<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>