<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7287_nm.7881" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7881" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7881" rank="species">Serpulina alvinipulli</organism><reference id="rid.7287"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Postic</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serpulina alvinipulli sp. nov., a new Serpulina species that is enteropathogenic for chickens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>669</fpage><lpage>676</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-669</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734021</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serpulina alvinipulli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serpulina alvinipulli</i> (al.vi.ni.pul.li. combination of L. gen. adj. <i>alvini</i> suffering from diarrhoea and L. gen. n. <i>pulli</i> of a chicken; <i>alvinipulli</i> of a diarrhoeic chicken, referring to the host animal from which the spirochaete was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenic.</s><s>When inoculated by crop gavage, <i>S. alvinipulli</i> cells colonize the caeca of 1-d-old chicks and 14-month-old hens and induce mild lymphocytic typhlitis and diarrhoea.</s><s>Cells grow by forming weakly haemolytic colonies on trypticase soy agar medium containing 5% defibrinated bovine blood. <i>S. alvinipulli</i> C1 cells have a typical spirochaete ultrastructure, i.e. an outer sheath, helical protoplasmic cylinder and periplasmic flagella wrapped around the protoplasmic cylinder and inside the outer sheath.</s><s>The cells measure 8-11 x 0.22-0.34 μm and have 22-30 (mean 24) flagella per cell (1.1-1.5 inserted at each cell end, with free ends overlapping in the middle of the cell).</s><s>Growing cells beneath an atmosphere containing O<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> (1:99) consume oxygen.</s><s>Cells possess the gene for NADH oxidase.</s><s>Grows well (3-10 x 10<sup>8</sup> cells ml<sup>-1</sup>, final population densities) in HS broth containing D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-maltose, D-glucosamine or N-acetyl-D-glucosamine as growth substrates.</s><s>Growth not detectable with these potential substrates: sucrose, D-galactose, D-trehalose, pyruvate, lactose, L-rhamnose, D-melibiose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-raffinose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-ribose, D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, D-mannitol, glycerol, acetate, lactate, succinate, pebble-milled cellulose, soluble starch, pectin, hog gastric mucin, glycogen, hyaluronic acid, polygalacturonic acid, 50 x MEM amino acids or glutathione. <i>S. alvinipulli</i> C1<sup>T</sup> cells cultured in BHIS (brain heart infusion supplemented with 10% heat-treated calf serum) broth give positive reactions in tests for hippurate hydrolysis, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, indoxyl acetate hydrolysis, arginine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase and glycine aminopeptidase; and negative reactions in tests for indole production, α-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, α-arabinosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine metabolism, leucine aminopeptidase, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine aminopeptidase, histidine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase and catalase.</s><s>Gram-negative, catalase-negative, aerotolerant anaerobe.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 39-42°C.</s><s>No growth at 32 or 47°C.</s><s>G+ C content of the DNA is 24.6 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Population doubling time in BHIS is 24 h.</s><s>Requires serum for growth in BHIS broth.</s><s>Shares high 16s rRNA sequence identity (98-99%) with other <i>Serpulina</i> species (<i>S. hyodysenteriae</i>, <i>S. innocens</i>, <i>S. pilosicoli</i>, <i>S. intermedia</i> and <i>S. murdochii</i>).</s><s>Shares 24-39% DNA relatedness with the other <i>Serpulina</i> species based on DNA-DNA relative reassociation studies.</s><s>Type strain: C1<sup>T</sup> (91-1207/C1<sup>T</sup>) (=ATCC 51933<sup>T</sup>)</s></p></content></protolog>