<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3409_nm.7871" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7871" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7871" rank="species">Treponema pectinovorum</organism><reference id="rid.3409"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Smibert</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burmeister</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema pectinovorum sp.nov. isolated from humans with periodontis</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>852</fpage><lpage>856</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-852</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema pectinovorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema pectinovorum</i> (pec.ti.no'vo.rum. M . L. noun <i>pectinum</i> pectin; L.v. <i>voro</i> to devour. M.L. adj. <i>pectinovorum</i> pectin destroying or devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is an obligately anaerobic motile helically coiled treponeme (Fig. 1).</s><s>In electron photomicrographs the helical protoplasmic cylinder is surrounded by an outer envelope, and in cells from cultures in the logarithmic growth phase there appear to be two periplasmic flagella (axial fibrils) which originate from each end of the cell (Fig. 2 ).</s><s>The periplasmic flagella overlap in the central area of the cell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are 7 to 15 μm long and 0.28 to 0.30 μm wide.</s><s>They are coiled and usually have straight, slightly pointed ends.</s><s>Secondary coils are observed in motile cultures.</s><s>Coccoid bodies occur in old cultures.</s><s>The organism is motile with both rotational and translational movement.</s><s>Serpentine movement can be observed in a semisolid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>In OT1 medium in bottle plate colonies usually appear in the agar after 4 to 5 days.</s><s>Colonies grow into the agar and are white and translucent with slightly denser centers.</s><s>The edges of the colonies may be entire.</s><s>The colonies spread out and become larger after additional incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>These organisms grow in PY-pectin broth containing either rumen fluid or a short-chain fatty acid mixture, such as the volatile fatty acid-heme supplement.</s><s>Serum and thiamine pyrophosphate are not required.</s><s>Growth only occurs in the presence of a fermentable energy source, such as pectin, polygalacturonic acid, galacturonic acid, or glucuronic acid.</s><s>Growth is greatly stimulated by the addition of a fresh filter-sterilized yeast autolysate to the medium.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>There is no growth at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>Broth cultures become turbid with a granular sediment that can be seen after 4 to 5 days of incubation.</s><s>Our cultures were stored frozen in liquid nitrogen or at -85°C in a mechanical freezer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and fermentation products.</s><s>Pectin is utilized, with a final pH that ranges from 5.3 to 5.9.</s><s>Polygalacturonic acid, galacturonic acid, and glucuronic acid are also fermented and may be substituted for pectin in PY-rumen fluid broth.</s><s>Growth and acid production occur in PY-rumen fluid broth supplemented with either autoclaved or filter-sterilized pectin.</s><s>Growth and acid production also occur in PY-rumen fluid broth containing 0.5% polygalacturonic acid.</s><s>The pH of this medium is 5.0 after 5 days of incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Adonitol. amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, starch, dulcitol, erythritol, esculin. fructose, galactose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, mucin, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, and glucose are not fermented; no growth occurs in PY-rumen fluid broth containing any of these substrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism produces neither catalase nor hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Hydrogen gas was not detected by gas chromatography of the atmospheric phase of cultures in rubber-stopper sealed tubes: gas was not detected in agar deep cultures. <i>T. pectinovorum</i> does not hydrolyze gelatin. esculin, glycogen, or starch.</s><s>Indol and acetylmethylcarbinol are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation products from PY pectin-rumen fluid broth are acetic acid (27.9 mM) and formic acid (8.5 mM).</s><s>Only traces of pyruvic and lactic acids are detected.</s><s>The products from polygalacturonic acid are acetic acid (39.5 mM) and formic acid (16.7 mM) with only traces of lactic and pyruvic acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine (G+C) content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of strain ATCC 33768<sup>T</sup> (=VPI D-36DR-2<sup>T</sup>) (T = type strain) is 39 molz, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 33768 (= VPI D-36DR-2). which was isolated from a subgingival sample from a patient with periodontal disease. <i>T. pectinovorum</i> does not conform to the descriptions of previously described treponeme species (1-3, 6, 7). "<i>Treponema denticola</i>" (G+C content, 37 mol%), "<i>Treponema vincentii</i>," "<i>Treponema skoliodontum</i>," "<i>Treponema refringens</i>" (G+C content 39 to 43 mol%), and <i>Treponema minutum</i> (G+C content. 37 mol%) differ from <i>T. pectinoiyorum</i> in not fermenting carbohydrates and in having requirements for serum and long-chain fatty acids (2,6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>"<i>Treponema phagedenis</i>" (G+C content, 38 mol%) ferments many carbohydrates but not pectin and has a requirement for serum (2, 6).</s><s>We have determined that "<i>T. phagedenis</i>," "<i>T . denticola</i>," "<i>T. vincentii</i>," "<i>T. skolidontum</i>," and "<i>T. refringens</i>" do not produce acid when they are grown in a medium containing pectin. <i>Treponema hyodysenteriae</i> (G+C content, 25.7 mol%) and <i>Treponema innocens</i> (G +C content 25.7 mol%) are much larger organisms, and both require serum (3). "<i>Treponema macrodentium</i>" requires short-chain fatty acids for growth and ferments many sugars.</s><s>Two other short-chain fatty acid-requiring species have been described.</s><s>One is <i>Treponema succinifaciens</i> ( G+C content, 36 mol%) from swine intestines, and the other is <i>Treponema bryntii</i> (G+C content, 36 mol%) from bovine rumens (1,7).</s><s>These species also ferment many carbohydrates but not pectin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large rumen spirochetes that ferment pectin but not glucose have been described (8, 9).</s><s>The end products of this fermentation are formate and acetate.</s><s>The G+C content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of strain 608 is 46 mol%, and the cells of this strain are 0.6 by 15 μm and have 32 or more periplasmic flagella (5).</s><s>This is quite different from <i>T. pectinovorum</i>, which has a G+C content of 39 mol%.</s><s>In addition, strain 692, a small rumen treponeme that utilizes pectin as a sole source of energy, has been described, and this organism produces formic and acetic acids as the main fermentation products (10).</s><s>This strain has four periplasmic flagella that originate from each end of the cell, whereas <i>T. pectinovorum</i> has only two periplasmic flagella.</s><s>Other pectin-requiring treponemes from bovine rumens have also been dexribed (5).</s><s>The G+C contents of the deoxyribonucleic acids of these organisms DNA range from 41 to 46 mol%.</s><s>Isolation from human gingival crevices of five strains of pectin-fermenting treponemes that also ferment glucuronic and galacturonic acids has been reported (F.</s><s>H.</s><s>Weber and E.</s><s>Canale-Parola, Abstr.</s><s>Annu.</s><s>Meet.</s><s>Am.</s><s>Soc.</s><s>Microbiol. 1983, 1123, p. 158).</s><s>The characteristics described for these isolates, including the end products offermentation and the G+C contents of the deoxyribonucleic acid5 (30 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation), are similar to those of <i>T. pectinovorum</i> described in this paper, with one difference.</s><s>The strains of Weber and Canale-Parola reportedly have only one periplasmic flagellum that originates from each end of the cell, whereas <i>T. pectinovorum</i> has two periplasmic flagella.</s><s>The new species described here is unique in only fermenting and growing in a medium containing pectin, polygalacturonic acid, galacturonic acid, or glucuronic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat. <i>T. pectinovorum</i> was found in human oral cavities.</s><s>It was found mainly in subgingival samples from patients with juvenile and severe periodontal disease and in subgingival samples from patients with experimentally induced gingivitis.</s><s>It was not the most frequently isolated oral treponeme because it was found in only 19% of the patients studied.</s><s>However, it was found in 33% of the patients with juvenile periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>T. pectinovorum</i> is easily recognized because it grows only in a medium containing pectin, polygalacturonic acid, galacturonic acid, or glucuronic acid and ferments these substrates, producing acetic and formic acids as the main end products.</s><s>In addition to using only these substrates, it requires rumen fluid or a mixture of volatile fatty acids for growth.</s><s>It does not require serum.</s></p></content></protolog>