<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1488_nm.12167" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12167" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3792" rank="species">Campylobacter cryaerophila</organism><reference id="rid.1488"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Neill</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>J.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Brien</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weatherup</surname><given-names>S.T.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ellis</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic position of Campylobacter cryaerophila sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>342</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-342</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter cryaerophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter cryaerophila</i> (cry.ae.ro.philá. Gr. adj. <i>cry</i> cold; Gr. n. <i>aero</i> air; L. adj. <i>phila</i> fond of; <i>cryaerophila</i> fond of cold and air)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative nonsporeforming rods (0.4 μm wide by 1.8 μm long); unusually long cells (&#x003E;20 μm) have been observed.</s><s>Cells are usually curved, S shaped, or helical.</s><s>Darting motility; single polar flagella (amphitricate).</s><s>Growth occurs at 30°C, and colonies grown under reduced oxygen tension for 48 to 72 h are small (1 mm in diameter), smooth, and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies may become flattened and irregular and may vary in size.</s><s>Strains in subculture grow in air, in air containing 10% CO<sub>2</sub>, and anaerobically.</s><s>Some strains grow between 5 and 40°C, but all strains grow at 15°C.</s><s>The strains are positive for catalase and oxidase activities and reduce nitrate (98.6% of the strains) and nitrite (85.9%).</s><s>The strains are tolerant to 2% NaCl, 4% glucose, 0.1% glycine, and pteridine vibriostatic compound 0/129.</s><s>The strains do not grow in medium containing 1.0% glycine and 1 mg of 2,3,5-triphenyl tetrazolium chloride per ml, and sodium selenite is not reduced.</s><s>No H<sub>2</sub>S is produced in triple sugar iron medium or medium containing cystine.</s><s>The strains produce alkaline reactions in Hugh-Leifson medium.</s><s>All strains are negative in methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests and do not produce indole, ornithine, lysine, and arginine decorboxylases, urease, ribonuclease, or deoxyribonuclease (97.9% of the strains).</s><s>The strains do not utilize citrate, malonate, or gluconate, do not liquify serum or gelatin, and do not hydrolyze czfsein, starch, hippurate, tributyrin, or esculin.</s><s>Growth does not occur in KCN or on deoxycholate agar, and all strains fail to catabolize carbohydrates.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to nalidixic acid (40 μg/ml) and resistant to carbenicillin (64 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have been isolated from reproductive tracts and aborted fetuses of several species of farm animals, from animal feces, and from milk of mastitis cows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean G+C content is 31 t 1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A169/B (= 02766) is the type strain of <i>C. cryaerophila</i> and has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures as strain NCTC 11885.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above for the species with respect to morphology and growth characteristics.</s><s>No growth occurs below 5°C or above 37°C; the optimum growth temperature is 30°C.</s><s>Strain A169/B<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) is catalase and oxidase positive and reduces nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative, and indole is not produced; ornithine, lysine, and arginine decarboxylases, urease, ribonuclease, and deoxyribonuclease are not produced.</s><s>Citrate, malonate, and gluconate are not utilized; serum and gelatin are not liquified, and casein, starch, hippurate, tributyrin, and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No acid is produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>No reaction is produced in litmus milk or Crossley milk, and an alkaline reaction occurs in Hugh-Leifson medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs on medium containing 8% glucose and pteridine vibriostatic compound 0/129.</s><s>No growth occurs on medium containing &#x003E;2% NaCl, 1.0% glycine, or 1 mg of 2,3,5-triphenyl tetrazolium chloride per ml.</s><s>Sodium selenite is not reduced, and no H<sub>2</sub>S is produced in triple sugar iron medium or medium supplemented with cystine.</s><s>No growth occurs on McConkey or desoxycholate agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibility: resistant to ampicillin (18 μg/ml), carbenicillin (64 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (4 μg/ml), dimetridazole (1 μg/ml), kanamycin (2 μg/ml), metronidazole (8 μg/ml), nalidixic acid (5 μg/ml), penicillin G (1 IU/ml), and polymyxin B (2 μg/ml); susceptible to strkptomycin (12 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 31.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A169/B<sup>T</sup> was isolated from an aborted bovine fetus.</s></p></content></protolog>