<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5791_nm.5816" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5816" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5816" rank="species">Arcanobacterium hippocoleae</organism><reference id="rid.5791"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rogerson</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arcanobacterium hippocoleae sp. nov., from the vagina of a horse.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>617</fpage><lpage>619</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931175</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arcanobacterium hippocoleae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arcanobacterium hippocoleae</i> (hip.po.co'le.ae. Gr. n. <i>hippos</i> horse; Gr. n. <i>colea</i> vagina; M.L. fem. gen. n. <i>hippocoleae</i> of the horse vagina)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-branching, irregular-shaped rods which stain Gram-positive, are non-acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are convex, circular, entire, shiny, opaque and grey.</s><s>Weakly haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose and lactose, but not from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, pullulan, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, D-ribose, D-raffinose, sucrose, sorbitol, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from maltose depending on the test system used.</s><s>α-Glucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase are detected, but not acid phosphatase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4, ester lipase C8, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, pyrolydonyl arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase, urease or glycyl tryptophan arylamidase.</s><s>N-Acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and alkaline phosphatase may or may not be detected depending on the test system used.</s><s>Aesculin (weak reaction) and hippurate are hydrolysed, but not gelatin.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Isolated from vaginal discharge from a horse.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 44697<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106850<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>