<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3261_nm.5615" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5615" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5615" rank="species">Streptococcus caprinus</organism><reference id="rid.3261"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brooker</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Donovan</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Skene</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muslera</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus caprinus sp. nov., a tannin-resistant ruminal bacterium from feral goats.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><source id="152">Letters in Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Lett Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0266-8254</issn><essn>1472-765X</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus caprinus</i> sp.nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus caprinus</i> (<i>caprinus</i>; L., of the goat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic coccus mainly occurring in short chains and isolated from the rumen of feral goats.</s><s>The species is able to grow and form clear zones on complex media containing tannic acid, and is able to grow in a complex growth medium with at least 2.5% (w/v) of condensed tannins derived from Acacia aneura.</s><s>The species grows on glucose, starch, cellobiose, galactose, mannose, trehalose, sucrose, lactose, fructose, maltose, raffinose and inulin as sole carbon sources, but is unable to grow on rhamnose, glycerol, xylose, sorbitol, inositol, L-arabinose or tannic acid.</s><s>L-Lactate is the predominant acid produced by Strep. caprinus from a medium containing glucose, although acetic acid and ethanol are also produced.</s><s>In a basal medium with glucose, <i>Strep. caprinus</i> is unable to use NH<sub>4</sub>Cl as a sole nitrogen source but does utilize trypticase or casamino acids.</s><s>The type strain (ACM 3969) is deposited in the Australian Collection of Microorganisms, Department of Microbiology, University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland.</s></p></content></protolog>