<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2007_nm.10959" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10959" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10959" rank="species">Prevotella stercorea</organism><reference id="rid.2007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hayashi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shibata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tomita</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella copri sp. nov. and Prevotella stercorea sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>946</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64778-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella stercorea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella stercorea</em> (ster.co′re.a. L. fem. adj. <em>stercorea</em> pertaining to faeces).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods that are anaerobic and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on EG agar plates after 48 h incubation at 37 °C under 100 % CO<sub>2</sub> gas are translucent, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Growth is inhibited on Bacteroides bile aesculin agar.</s><s>Negative for indole, does not hydrolyse aesculin or gelatin and no urease activity is detected.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, mannose and raffinose.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained using API ZYM for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-l-fucosidase; negative reactions are obtained for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-gluconidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained using An-Ident for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-l-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, indoxyl acetate hydrolase and alanine aminopeptidase; negative reactions are obtained for indole, <em>α</em>-arabinofuranosidase, <em>β</em>-gluconidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, arginine, leucine, proline, tyrosine, histidine, phenylalanine and glycine aminopeptidases and catalase.</s><s>The major metabolic end products are succinic and acetic acids; small amounts of iso-valeric acid are also produced.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (15 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (24 %) and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (26 %).</s><s>The principal respiratory quinones are menaquinones MK-12 (26 %) and MK-13 (50 %); minor menaquinones are MK-9 (1 %), MK-10 (5 %) and MK-11 (7 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CB35<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13469<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18206<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>