<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1985_nm.10834" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10834" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10834" rank="species">Lysinibacillus boronitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.1985"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ahmed</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamazoe</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujiwara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Lysinibacillus boronitolerans gen. nov. sp. nov., and transfer of Bacillus fusiformis to Lysinibacillus fusiformis comb. nov. and Bacillus sphaericus to Lysinibacillus sphaericus comb. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1117</fpage><lpage>1125</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63867-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473269</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysinibacillus boronitolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysinibacillus boronitolerans</em> (bo.ro′ni.to′le.rans. N.L. n. <em>boron -onis</em> boron; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>boronitolerans</em> boron-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics described for the genus, the species has the following features.</s><s>Cells are 3.0–5.0 μm long and 0.8–1.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire margins, flat/umbonate elevation, opaque and butyrous in texture and 2–3 mm in diameter after 2 days on NA (pH 7.0) plates at 37 °C.</s><s>Temperature for growth is 16–45 °C, with optimum growth at 37 °C; there is no growth at ≥50 °C and little growth at 16 °C after several days.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 5.5–9.5, with optimum growth at pH 7.0–8.0 (most rapid initial growth at pH 7.5) but no growth at pH 5.0.</s><s>Tolerates 0–100 mM boron in agar media, with optimum growth in the absence of boron and some growth at 150 mM boron after 2 days.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated up to 5 % (w/v), indicating that it is moderately halotolerant.</s><s>Growth is seen on marine agar 2216, TSA and NA with or without addition of boron or NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-xylose (weak) and aesculin (weak) (API 50CH); acid is not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Positive for Voges–Proskauer test, urease, l-arginine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase and citrate utilization and negative for hydrolysis of gelatin and l-lysine and l-ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Oxidizes the following substrates: d-alanine, glycogen, d-ribose, d-tagatose, inosine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, 2-aminoethanol, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, acetic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, l-glutamic acid, 2′-deoxyadenosine, l-serine, pyruvic acid, methyl pyruvic acid, TMP, monomethyl succinate, UMP, propionic acid, alaninamide, adenosine, AMP, lactamide, l-asparagine, thymidine, uridine, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, bromosuccinic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, dl-lactic acid, formic acid, gluconic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, i-erythritol, l-aspartic acid and <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (32 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (21 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (11 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (11 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (8 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (6 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2 %).</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains lysine, alanine, glutamic acid and aspartic acid as the diagnostic amino acids.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids given in the genus description, it also contains phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Strong enzyme activity is observed for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and esterase (C8), whereas weak activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM).</s><s>The type strain is resistant to linomycin, colistin, sulfamethizol, oxolinic acid, fusidic acid and metronidazol (ATB-VET).</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 36.5 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 10a<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17140<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15262<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1146<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain, isolated from soil collected in the experimental area of the University of Tokyo (Yayoi campus), Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>