<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1428_nm.1339" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1339" rank="genus">Sinorhizobium</organism><reference id="rid.1428"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical taxonomic study of fast-growing soybean rhizobia and a proposal that Rhizobium fredii be assigned to Sinorhizobium gen. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>392</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-392</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sinorhizobium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sinorhizobium</i>(Si.no.rhi.zóbium. L. n. <i>sinae</i>, China; Gr. n. <i>rhiza</i>, root; Gr. n. <i>bios</i>, life; M. L. neut. n. <i>Sinorhizobium</i>, rhizobia isolated from roots in China)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods 0.5 to 0.9 by 1.2 to 3.0 μm, usually containing granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile by means of one polar flagellum or one to more than three peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Aerobic, possessing a respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, semitranslucent, raised, and mucilaginous, usually 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 3 to 5 days of YMA.</s><s>Pronounced turbidity develops after 2 to 3 days in agitated broth.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 25 to 30°C, but most strains grow at 35°C and some strains grow at 10°C.</s><s>Optimum pH, 6 to 8.</s><s>Some strains grow at pH 5.0, and other strains grow at pH 10.5.</s><s>Most strains grow in the presence of 1.0% NaCl, but not</s></p><p class="description"><s>1.5% NaCl, although a few strains grow well on YMA containing 4.5% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D-Arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, D-galactose, glucose, L-glutamine, lactose, D-mannose, mannitol, D-ribose, sodium succinate, xylose, and D-turanose are utilized as sole carbon sources, but ammonium tartrate, ammonium oxalate, cellulose, dulcitol, fucose, glycine, sorbose, sodium algniate, and vanillic acid are not.</s><s>All strains produce acid on YMA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ammonium chloride and nitrates rather than amino acids are the preferred sole nitrogen sources, but some strains utilize certain amino acids.</s><s>Peptone is poorly utilized.</s><s>All strains require pantothenate and nicotinic acid, but their reactions to other vitamins are variable.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to doxycycline (1 μg/ml), tetracycline (1 μg/ml), aureomycin (1 μg/ml), terramycin (1 μg/ml), and streptomycin (125 μg/ml), but resistant to vancomycin (5 μg/ml), chloromphenicol (5 μg/ml), erythromycin (25 μg/ml), penicillin (5 μg/ml), medemycin (125 μg/ml), amophotericin B (125 μg/ml), and kanamycin (1 μg/ml).</s><s>Reactions to pesticides are variable, but all strains are susceptible to 38.08% dimetheate (250X), 50% phoxin (250X) and 40% omthoate (500X) , as well as to 0.01% potassium tellurite and calcium hypochlorite (2%).</s><s>All strains produce cytochrome oxidase and catalase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The members of this genus do not exhibit a wide host range, but effectively nodulate <i>Glycine soja</i>, <i>Glycine max</i> cv. TGm119, <i>G. max</i> cv. TGm120, <i>G. max</i> cv. TGm344, <i>G. max</i> cv. Kai-Yu No. 8, <i>Vigna unquiculata</i> cv. VITA-3, and <i>Cajanus cajan</i> cv. CITA-1.</s><s>An ineffective symbiosis is formed on <i>Vigna radiata</i>, <i>Macroptilium atropurpureum</i>, <i>Macroptilium lathyroides</i>, and <i>Sesbania cannabina</i> (2, 19,</s></p><p class="description"><s>25).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large plasmids have been demonstrated in most strains, and the structural nifgenes are contained on large plasmids (the only known exception is strain USDA 194) (9). <i>nif</i> genes and <i>nod</i> genes are located on a single plasmid (1).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 59.9 to 63.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>