<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4406_nm.7543" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7543" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7543" rank="species">Nocardiopsis kunsanensis</organism><reference id="rid.4406"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>E.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis kunsanensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic actinomycete isolated from a saltern.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1909</fpage><lpage>1913</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034504</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis kunsanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis kunsanensis</i> (kun.sa.nen'sis. M.L. adj. <i>kunsanensis</i> pertaining to Kunsan, a location in Korea where the species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, filamentous, catalase-positive and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are yellow and bear white aerial mycelia, which fragment into elongated non-motile spores with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Fragmentation of substrate mycelia does not occur.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is formed.</s><s>Grows optimally at 37 °C and at pH 9 with 10% NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow onCMwith 0 or 25% NaCl, nor at pH 5.</s><s>Unable to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Utilizes D-glucose and sucrose as sole carbon source, but not acetate, cellobiose, D-galactose, gluconate, phydroxybenzoate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltose, mannitol, paraffin, raffinose, L-rhamnose or trehalose.</s><s>Utilizes L-alanine, but not gelatin, proline or serine as sole carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>Degrades adenine, casein, starch, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine, gelatin and urea, but not aesculin.</s><s>Resistant to sodium azide (0.01%), crystal violet (0.0001%) and potassium tellurite (0.0001%), but not phenol (0.1%).</s><s>Contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, no diagnostic sugars, hexaor octa-hydrogenated menaquinones with 10 isoprene units, straight-chain saturated or monounsaturated, iso-, anteiso-, 10-methyl branched fatty acids with 13-18 carbons, and phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol (phospholipid type III).</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 71 mol%.</s><s>The species was isolated from a saltern sample collected from Kunsan, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The type and only strain of <i>Nocardiopsis kunsanensis</i> is strain HA-9<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 9831<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10721<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>