<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2774_nm.10132" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10132" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10132" rank="species">Phaeobacter inhibens</organism><reference id="rid.2774"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martens</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heidorn</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simon</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brinkhoff</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Roseobacter gallaeciensis Ruiz-Ponte et al. 1998 as Phaeobacter gallaeciensis gen. nov., comb. nov., description of Phaeobacter inhibens sp. nov., reclassification of Ruegeria algicola (Lafay et al. 1995) Uchino et al. 1999 as Marinovum algicola gen. nov., comb. nov., and emended descriptions of the genera Roseobacter, Ruegeria and Leisingera.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1293</fpage><lpage>1304</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63724-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738106</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phaeobacter inhibens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phaeobacter inhibens</em> (in.hi′bens. L. part. adj. <em>inhibens</em> inhibiting).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 1.4–1.9 μm×0.6–0.8 μm.</s><s>Colonies on agar are smooth and convex with regular edges that become brownish/ochre on ferric-citrate-containing media after 24 h incubation at 20 °C and dark brown after incubation for 48 h, with diameter up to 0.8 mm.</s><s>Tendency to aggregate in liquid MB 2216.</s><s>Cells grow at temperatures ranging from 4 to 36 °C, with an optimum between 27 and 29 °C, and pH ranging from 6.0 to 9.5 (optimum pH 7.5).</s><s>Cells grow in the presence of Na<sup>+</sup> concentrations of 0.01 and &#x003C;1.5 M, optimal salinity is between 0.51 and 0.68 M; no growth is observed without Na<sup>+</sup>.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive, but amylase-, gelatinase- and Tweenase-negative.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: (+)-d-xylose, (+)-d-glucose, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-d-galactose, (−)-d-fructose, (−)-d-ribose, (−)-d-mannitol, (−)-d-sorbitol, (−)-d-glucosamine, sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, trehalose, sodium acetate, sodium pyruvate, sodium malate, sodium citrate, disodium succinate, sodium lactate, sodium propionate, sodium butyrate, xylan, glycerol, betaine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glutamine, l-glutamic acid, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-trytophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>No growth is supported by the following substrates: (+)-l-arabinose, (+)-l-rhamnose, (−)-l-fucose, lactose, sodium formate, starch, inulin, Tween 80, DMS, methyl iodide or methyl chloride.</s><s>No vitamin requirements observed.</s><s>Cells produce the antibiotic tropodithietic acid during the exponential growth phase and are susceptible to penicillin G, streptomycin sulphate and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 55.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, T5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16374<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22475<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water of a tidal mud flat in the German Wadden Sea, a southern region of the North Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>