<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6372_nm.7128" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7128" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7128" rank="species">Streptomyces luteireticuli</organism><reference id="rid.6372"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic re-evaluation of whorl-forming Streptomyces (formerly Streptoverticillium) species by using phenotypes, DNA-DNA hybridization and sequences of gyrB, and proposal of Streptomyces luteireticuli (ex Katoh and Arai 1957) corrig., sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1519</fpage><lpage>1529</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130042</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces luteireticuli</em> corrig., sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces luteireticuli</em> (lu.te.i.re.ti′cu.li. L. adj. <em>luteus</em> yellow; L. n. <em>reticulum</em> net; N.L. gen. n. <em>luteireticuli</em> of a yellow net).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Streptomyces luteireticuli</em> is the same as that given by Shirling &#x0026; Gottlieb (1972) for ‘<em>S. luteoreticuli</em>’, with some additions from this study.</s><s>Spore-chain morphology is umbellate monoverticilate.</s><s>Mature spore-chains are generally short (three to ten or more spores per chain) when grown on oatmeal agar (ISP medium 3) and sometimes on inorganic salts/starch agar (ISP medium 4).</s><s>Sporulating aerial mycelium is usually thin or absent on yeast/malt agar (ISP medium 2) or glycerol/asparagine agar (ISP medium 5).</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Aerial mass colour is in the yellow or grey colour-series on ISP medium 3.</s><s>Nearest matching colours are pale yellow-green, pale yellow, yellowish-grey and light olive-brown.</s><s>Reverse-side colour of the colony is not distinctive (olive-brown to dark brown on ISP medium 2 and greyish-yellow or yellowish-brown to olive-brown on ISP media 3, 4 and 5).</s><s>Melanin pigments are not formed in peptone/yeast/iron agar (ISP medium 6), tyrosine agar (ISP medium 7) or tryptone/yeast broth (ISP medium 1).</s><s>Yellowish and greenish-yellow pigment is found in ISP media 2, 3, 4 and 5.</s><s>d-Glucose and i-inositol are utilized for growth.</s><s>Utilization of l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-fructose, rhamnose, sucrose and raffinose is doubtful or negative.</s><s>Utilization of d-fructose is weakly positive in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NBRC 13422<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 27446<sup>T</sup>=CBS 723.72<sup>T</sup>=DSM 40509<sup>T</sup>=ISP 5509=JCM 4788<sup>T</sup>=RIA 1383<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>