<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2814_nm.1315" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1315" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1315" rank="species">Agrobacterium larrymoorei</organism><reference id="rid.2814"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouzar</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrobacterium larrymoorei sp. nov., a pathogen isolated from aerial tumours of Ficus benjamina.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1023</fpage><lpage>1026</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agrobacterium larrymoorei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agrobacterium larrymoorei</i> (lar.ry.moore'i. M.L. gen. <i>larrymoorei</i> of Larry Moore, renowned plant pathologist who spent his career studying the genus <i>Agrobacterium</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacterium is a Gram-negative rod and a strict aerobe.</s><s>Cells are motile with peritrichous flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>Cell and colony morphology and metabolic activity are as described for the genus (Sawada et al., 1993).</s><s>However, colonies growing on Roy-Sasser medium (Moore et al., 2001) are cream-white with a red centre, ca. 1 mm in diameter, circular, convex and glossy.</s><s>The reaction of strains in litmus milk is alkaline with proteolysis (Bouzar et al., 1995).</s><s>Alkali is produced from tartaric acid, but not from malonic acid (Bouzar et al., 1995).</s><s>Strains do not produce 3-ketolactose from lactose, do not utilize citrate and do not grow at 35 °C (Bouzar et al., 1995).</s><s>The ferric ammonium citrate test is negative (Bouzar et al., 1995).</s><s>Strains produce acid from mannitol and grow on 2% NaCl (Bouzar et al., 1995).</s><s>Strains can be differentiated from those of one or more of the other four <i>Agrobacterium</i> species by their ability to metabolize the carbon substrates N-acetyl D-glucosamine, gentiobiose, <i>m</i>-inositol, lactulose, mono-methyl succinate, DL-lactic acid, D-saccharic acid, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate and by their inability to metabolize Tween 40, Tween 80, <i>i</i>-erythritol, α-lactose, D-raffinose, acetic acid, citric acid, D-glucosaminic acid, malonic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, hydroxy-L-proline and L-pyroglutamic acid.Akey characteristic that differentiates this species from other agrobacteria is its inability to metabolize <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid.</s><s>The type strain of <i>A. larrymoorei</i> is AF3.10<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 51759<sup>T</sup>=CFBP 5473<sup>T</sup>=NCPPB 4096<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>