<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.723_nm.3908" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3908" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3908" rank="species">Clostridium celerecrescens</organism><reference id="rid.723"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palop</surname><given-names>M.L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valles</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Piñaga</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flors</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of anaerobic, cellulolytic bacterium, Clostridium celerecrescens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>68</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-1-68</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium celerecrescens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium celerecrescens</i> (ce'le.re.cres.cens. L. adv. <i>celere</i>, fast; <i>crescens</i>, L. pres. part. of verb <i>crescere</i>, to grow; M.L. adj. <i>celerecrescens</i>, intended to reflect the fast growth of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 2- to 4-μm long by 0.5- to 0.8-μm wide.</s><s>Vegetative cells stain gram positive, although they decolorize readily in older cultures.</s><s>Endospores are spherical and terminal and produce swollen cells (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On cellulose agar medium, colonies appear after 10 to 14 days of incubation at 37°C and exhibit halos of cellulolysis.</s><s>Deep colonies are smooth, circular, approximately 0.5 mm in diameter, translucent, and unpigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. celerecrescens</i> ferments cellulose, cellobiose, glucose, fructose, galactose, mannitol, maltose, adonitol, rhamnose, xylose, ribose, mannose, raffinose, trehalose, arabinose, and esculin.</s><s>It weakly ferments lactose, melezitose, melibiose, sorbose, and sucrose.</s><s>It does not ferment dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, inulin, sorbitol, and starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation products in cellobiose and cellulose broth are ethanol, acetate, formate, butyrate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, caproate, lactate, succinate, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is liquefied and indole is produced.</s><s>Catalase, lipase, lecithinase, and urease are negative.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and casein hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Acetyl methyl carbinol is not produced.</s><s>Milk digestion and curd formation are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth temperature is between 30 to 37°C.</s><s>Growth rate decreases substantially at 23°C (Fig. 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum pH is near 7.0.</s><s>Growth rate decreases substantially under pH 7 and over pH 8 (Fig. 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 38 mol% G+C.</s><s>The source was a methanogenic culture started with a cow manure inoculum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 18A (=CECT 954) (Coleccion Espaiiola manure inoculum. de Cultivos Tipo)</s></p></content></protolog>