<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6826_nm.436" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.436" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.436" rank="species">Hydrogenothermus marinus</organism><reference id="rid.6826"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stöhr</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Waberski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Völker</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomm</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenothermus marinus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel thermophilic hydrogen-oxidizing bacterium, recognition of Calderobacterium hydrogenophilum as a member of the genus Hydrogenobacter and proposal of the reclassification of Hydrogenobacter acidophilus as Hydrogenobaculum acidophilum gen. nov., comb. nov., in the phylum 'Hydrogenobacter/Aquifex'.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1853</fpage><lpage>1862</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594618</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hydrogenothermus marinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hydrogenothermus marinus</i> (ma.ri'nus. L. adj. <i>marinus</i> of marine origin)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-negative rods, 2-4 μm long and 1-1.5 μm wide, with four to seven flagella inserted.</s><s>The strain grows chemolithoautotrophically under an atmosphere of H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> (80:20) with low concentrations of O<sub>2</sub> (0.5-8%, optimum at 1-2%).</s><s>No growth on meat peptone, tryptone, meat extract, yeast extract, lactose, D-galactose, α-D-glucose, D-ribose, D-fructose, sucrose, citric acid, α-D-maltose hydrate, starch, D-xylose, DL-alanine, L-proline, L-histidine hydrochloride, glycine, methanol, ethanol, acetic acid, pyruvate, disodium fumarate, DL-malate or ammonium formate as a source of energy or cellular carbon.</s><s>Catalase- and cytochrome-oxidase-positive.</s><s>No growth on peptone, yeast extract, tryptone, starch, glucose or maltose as sole electron donor.</s><s>Sulfur and thiosulfate are not utilized as electron donors or sources of energy.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is necessary for growth.</s><s>Nitrate and sulfate cannot serve as electron acceptors.</s><s>Growth occurs over the range 45 to 80 °C with an optimum at 65 °C at pH 5.7.</s><s>NaCl stimulates growth between 0.5 and 6%, with an optimum at 2.3%.</s><s>Isolated from sediment of a geothermally heated area, 3-4 m off the beach of Vulcano, Italy.</s><s>The type strain is strain VM1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12046<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10974<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>