<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6769_nm.2260" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2260" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2260" rank="species">Stenotrophomonas rhizophila</organism><reference id="rid.6769"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wolf</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hagemann</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stenotrophomonas rhizophila sp. nov., a novel plant-associated bacterium with antifungal properties.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1937</fpage><lpage>1944</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02135-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508851</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stenotrophomonas rhizophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stenotrophomonas rhizophila</i> (rhi.zo'phi.la. Gr. n. <i>rhizo</i> root; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; <i>rhizophila</i> root-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight or slightly curved rods.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish; the colour is not due to carotenoid pigments or to xanthomonadins.</s><s>Growth takes place at 4-37 °C but not at 40 °C.</s><s>Neither lipolytic nor β-glucosidase activity occurs.</s><s>The strains use xylose as a carbon source.</s><s>Strains are able to utilize (oxidize) the following carbon sources: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-fructose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-trehalose, turanose, methylpyruvate, mono-methyl succinate, acetic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, α-hydroxy butyric acid, β-hydroxy butyric acid, γ-hydroxy butyric acid, α-keto-butyric acid, α-keto glutaric acid, DL-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylgyline, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, L-serine, L-threonine, DL-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine and uridine.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 4.5% NaCl but is inhibited at 5% NaCl and above.</s><s>Produces the osmoprotective substances trehalose and glucosylglycerol at 3% NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to many antibiotics, e.g. penicillin, tobramycin, imipenem, and ceftazidime, but susceptible to chloramphenicol, kanamycin and trimethoprim}sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>Strains were plant-associated and isolated from the rhizosphere of oilseed rape and from the the rhizosphere and geocaulsophere (tuber) of potato.</s><s>Endophytic colonization was found.</s><s>Antagonistic activity was shown against plant-pathogenic fungi, e.g. <i>Verticillium dahliae</i>, <i>Rhizoctonia solani</i>, <i>Sclerotinia sclerotiorum</i> and the human-pathogenic fungus <i>Candida albicans</i>.</s><s>They are not active against bacteria.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Stenotrophomonas rhizophila</i> e-p10<sup>T</sup> (=DSM14405<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-473<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>