<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.660_nm.8804" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8804" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8804" rank="species">Psychrobacter arenosus</organism><reference id="rid.660"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter maritimus sp. nov. and Psychrobacter arenosus sp. nov., isolated from coastal sea ice and sediments of the Sea of Japan.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1741</fpage><lpage>1745</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63096-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388738</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychrobacter arenosus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychrobacter arenosus</em> (a.re.no′sus. L. masc. adj. <em>arenosus</em> sandy, dwelling in marine sediment sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmented, non-spore-forming, ovoid cells (1·4–1·7 μm long and 0·6–0·8 μm in diameter).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth; growth occurs in 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in 12 % NaCl.</s><s>Psychrotolerant.</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C, with an optimum growth temperature of 25–28 °C.</s><s>Does not grow at 39 or 40 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5·0–10·0, with optimum growth at pH 6·0–9·0.</s><s>Acid is formed from d-glucose, rhamnose, galactose, lactose and arabinose.</s><s>In addition to biochemical characteristics listed in the Table 1, the type strain is positive for l-leucine, but negative for l-ornithine, urease, l-serine, arginine dihydrolase, ONPG test, indole production, hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin and utilization of glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, mannitol, gluconate and phenylacetate in the API tests.</s><s>According to Biolog GN tests, the type strain is positive for hydrolysis of Tween 40 and Tween 80 and utilization of l-arabinose, l-asparagine and l-glutamic acid.</s><s>The following substrates are not used as sole carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, d-serine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Cellular fatty acid composition is displayed in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45·0 mol% (determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a marine sediment sand sample from the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s><s>The type strain is KMM 3659<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15389<sup>T</sup>=R7<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>