<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7372_nm.6272" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6272" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6272" rank="species">Corynebacterium terpenotabidum</organism><reference id="rid.7372"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakane</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nihira</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imai</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium terpenotabidum sp. nov., a bacterium capable of degrading squalene</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>223</fpage><lpage>229</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-223</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028267</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium terpenotabidum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium terpenotabidum</i> (terpeno.ta'bi. dum. L. fem. n. <i>terpeno</i> terpene; L. adj. <i>tabidum</i> dissolving; M.L. fem. adj. <i>terpenotabidum</i> terpene-dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, irregular rods 0.5-0.7 μm by 1.0-1.5 μm long in young cultures; some cells are arranged at an angle in a V formation.</s><s>In old cultures, cells are 0.5-0.-7 μm by 0.6-1.0 μm.</s><s>Rods are Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-sporulating and non-motile.</s><s>No mycelium is produced.</s><s>Colonies on PY-BHI agar are circular, have a rough surface and are greyish-white.</s><s>Methyl red test negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs under aerobic, but not anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Hugh-Leifson's test in glucose oxidation-fermentation (OF) medium is oxidative.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test positive.</s><s>Catalase and urease are produced, but oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed, but starch, gelatin, casein, cellulose, aesculin and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Fructose, glucose, mannose, lactate and ethanol are utilized as carbon sources, but galactose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, glycerol, sorbitol, mannitol, inositol, citrate, succinate, malonate, pimelate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, arginine, aspartate, histidine, methylamine, ethylamine and methanol are not.</s><s>Thiamin and biotin are required for growth.</s><s>Growth is observed in PY-BHI broth containing 8% NaCl, but not in 10% NaCl.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the only diamino acid, arabinose, galactose and mannose, as major cell wall sugars.</s><s>The muramic acids of peptidoglycan occur in the N-acetyl form.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated acids are palmitic acids and the unsaturated fatty acid are oleic acids.</s><s>High levels of TBSA are present.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, strain Y-11<sup>T</sup> (=IFO 14764<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>