<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7433_nm.2329" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2329" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2329" rank="species">Thiomicrospira chilensis</organism><reference id="rid.7433"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brinkhoff</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muyzer</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wirsen</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiomicrospira chilensis sp. nov., a mesophilic obligately chemolithoautotrophic sulfuroxidizing bacterium isolated from a Thioploca mat.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>875</fpage><lpage>879</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-875</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319513</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiomicrospira chilensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiomicrospira chilensis</i> (chi.len'sis. M.L. adj. <i>chilensis</i> from Chile, South America)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile and rod-shaped (0.3-0.5 x 0.8-2 μm).</s><s>Strictly aerobic and grows autotrophically on thiosulfate, tetrathionate, sulfur and sulfide but not on sulfite or thiocyanate.</s><s>Does not grow heterotrophically.</s><s>When thiosulfate is used as the primary energy source, sulfur and very small amounts of sulfite are produced.</s><s>During growth on reducedsulfur compounds, the pH decreases from neutrality to around 4.8.</s><s>Thiosulfate is completely oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth on thiosulfate occurs between pH 5.3 and 8.5 and at a temperature of 3.5-42°C; optimal growth occurs at pH 7.0 and at 32-37°C.</s><s>The optimal Na<sup>+</sup> concentration for growth is 470 mM; growth is possible between Na' concentrations of 100 and 1240 mM.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed by means of ribulose-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase.</s><s>Nitrate is not used as a terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>On thiosulfate agar, cells produce white to yellowish, smooth, entire colonies [diameter on 1.2 % (w/v) agar is 2-5 mm] in which sulfur is deposited and acid is produced.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49.9 mol%.</s><s>As determined by a 16s rRNA gene sequence analysis, <i>Thiomicrospira chilensis</i> belongs to the 𝛾-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is closely related to previously described members of the genus <i>Thiomicrospira</i>.</s><s>The type strain of the species, Ch-1<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 12352<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the nearly complete 16s rRNA gene sequence of <i>T. chilensis</i> is AF013975.</s></p></content></protolog>