<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9562_nm.14735" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14735" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14735" rank="species">Streptomonospora amylolytica</organism><reference id="rid.9562"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomonospora amylolytica sp. nov. and Streptomonospora flavalba sp. nov., two novel halophilic actinomycetes isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2471</fpage><lpage>2475</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007682-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622663</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomonospora amylolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomonospora amylolytica</em> (a.my.lo.ly.ti′ca. Gr. n. <em>amylos</em> starch; Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>amylolytica</em> producing lysis of starch).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows well on oatmeal agar and nutrient agar media supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl, but not on Czapek's agar or glycerol/asparagine agar supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced on all media tested.</s><s>Aerial and substrate mycelia are not fragmented.</s><s>White to yellow–white aerial mycelia form spore chains at maturity, with non-motile, oval to cylindrical spores (0.3–0.4×0.4–0.6 μm).</s><s>Single, oval spores are borne on sporophores of substrate mycelium.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are yellow–grey on inorganic salt-starch agar, yeast extract-malt extract agar and oatmeal agar, pale yellow on potato extract agar and ivory–olive–brown on nutrient agar.</s><s>Growth occurs with 5–20 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 10 %), at 20–45 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0).</s><s>Utilizes arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, rhamnose and sorbitol as sole carbon and energy sources, and arginine, hydroxyproline, lysine, proline, threonine and tryptophan as sole nitrogen, carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of starch, H<sub>2</sub>S production and milk coagulation and peptonization, but negative for gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of cellulose and urea, melanin production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, and galactose is the major diagnostic sugar in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>Polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.2 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 91353<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45171<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 208048<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from saline soil collected from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>