<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6491_nm.10225" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10225" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10225" rank="species">Bacillus safensis</organism><reference id="rid.6491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Satomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>La Duc</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venkateswaran</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus safensis sp. nov., isolated from spacecraft and assembly-facility surfaces.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1735</fpage><lpage>1740</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64189-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902000</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus safensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus safensis</em> [sa.fen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>safensis</em> arbitrarily derived from SAF (the spacecraft-assembly facility at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, USA), from where the organism was first isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are mesophilic, aerobic, chemoheterotrophic, Gram-positive, spore-forming rods that are motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.7 μm in diameter and 1.0–1.2 μm in length.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl and at pH 5.6.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–50 °C (optimum, 30–37 °C) but not at 4 or 55 °C.</s><s>Colonies are round, undulate, dull white, non-luminescent and have irregular margins on TSA plates incubated at 32 °C for 24 h.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphatase and esterase are produced, but H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, amylase, agarase, lecithinase, DNase, urease, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, tryptophan deaminase, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not.</s><s>Cells do not reduce nitrate, but do hydrolyse gelatin, aesculin and RNA.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis varies among strains.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Growth occurs on agar plates supplemented with 1 % glycine and ox gall, but does not occur in 0.0001 % lysozyme broth.</s><s>Negative for gas production from d-glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, glycerol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, galactose, fructose, mannose, inositol, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, d-turanose and d-tagatose, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Reactions for lactose, melibiose and gentiobiose vary among strains.</s><s>Citrate, malate, d-glucose, glycerol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, galactose, fructose, mannose, inositol, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-tagatose, gluconate, lactate, l-aspartate and l-glutamate are readily utilized as energy sources.</s><s>Erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, sorbose, dulcitol, sorbitol, inulin, lactose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, propionate and glycine are not utilized as energy sources.</s><s>Rhamnose utilization varies among strains.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41.0–41.4 mol%.</s><s>The chain composition of the whole-cell fatty acids is primarily C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> anteiso.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FO-36b<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1126<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100820<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the spacecraft-assembly facility of the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, USA.</s><s>Strains SAFN-001 (=ATCC BAA-1128=NBRC 100821), KL-052 (=ATCC BAA-1129=NBRC 100822) and 51-3C (=ATCC BAA-1127=NBRC 100823) are reference strains.</s></p></content></protolog>