<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1715_nm.11502" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11502" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11502" rank="species">Sphingobium olei</organism><reference id="rid.1715"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobium olei sp. nov., isolated from oil-contaminated soil</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2613</fpage><lpage>2617</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65187-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978228</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobium olei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobium olei</em> (o′le.i. L. gen. neut. n. <em>olei</em> of/from oil, as the organism was isolated from oil-contaminated soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and rod-shaped.</s><s>On NA, TSA and BHI agar, colonies are yellow and slightly elevated with entire margins.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive, grows at temperatures of 22–37 °C and tolerates 1.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Possesses the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of the genus <em>Sphingobium</em>.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid profile is presented in Table 2.</s><s>The respiratory quinone consists of ubiquinone with ten isoprene units (Q-10).</s><s>Contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, sphingoglycolipid and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>Major cellular polyamine is spermidine [23.0 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>] and trace amounts of 1,3-diaminopropane, putrescine and spermine [&#x003C;0.1 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>] are also present.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, hippurate and aesculin.</s><s>Assimilates d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, l-arabinose, arbutin, maltose, potassium gluconate, malic acid, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose, but not d-adonitol, adipic acid, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, phenylacetic acid, capric acid, d-cellobiose, trisodium citrate, dulcitol, erythritol, fructose, d- or l-fucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, d-lyxose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, turanose, l-xylose or xylitol.</s><s>Produces acid from starch, arbutin, d-fucose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose, but not from amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, turanose or xylitol.</s><s>Negative for oxidative fermentation of amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol and sucrose.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, leucine aminopeptidase and pyrazinamidase activities, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, 2-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, nitrate reductase and urease activities.</s><s>Produces acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction), but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB HF-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18999<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 54329<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from oil-contaminated soil near the oil refinery located in Kaohsiung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>