<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.377_nm.3167" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3167" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3167" rank="species">Erwinia alni</organism><reference id="rid.377"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Surico</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mugnai</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pastorelli</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannetti</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stead</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia alni, a new species causing bark cankers of alder, Alnus Miller species.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>720</fpage><lpage>726</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-720</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia alni</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia alni</i> (al'ni. L. fem. n. <i>alnus</i>, alder; L. gen. n. <i>alni</i>, of alder, referring to the plant from which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, oxidase negative, catalase positive, and fermentative (producing acid but not gas from glucose).</s><s>The cells are 0.5 to 0.8 by 1.2 to 2.3 μm, have rounded ends, occur singly or rarely in pairs, and are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Abundant growth occurs in NB and on NA, YDC, Miller-Schroth medium, and other common laboratory media.</s><s>Colonies on NSA are umbonate with translucent margins, whitish, and 2 to 2.5 mm in diameter after 5 days of incubation at 27°C.</s><s>The organism grows at 25,32, and 36°C but not at 5 and 42°C.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>The methyl red test and the Voges-Proskauer reaction are weakly positive.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>None of the strains produces polygalacturonase or pectate lyase on pectate gels at pH 5 and 8.</s><s>The strains do not induce a hypersensitive response in tobacco leaves and do not rot potato tuber slices.</s><s>After inoculation, pathogenic strains typically cause bark canker disease of alder.</s><s>They do not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, phenylalanine deaminase, β-galactosidase, and indole.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, starch, and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced from cysteine.</s><s>Citrate and malonate are not utilized.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze carboxymethyl cellulose and are slightly positive for urease activity.</s><s>Acids are produced from glucose, galactose, fructose, mannose, xylose, arabinose, sucrose, trehalose, maltose, salicin, glycerol, and mannitol oxidatively, but are not produced from lactose, raffinose, melibiose, erythrose, melezitose, sorbitol, inositol, adonitol, and dulcitol.</s><s>Good growth occurs in the presence of 2% sodium chloride.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fatty acids include 14:O 3OH, 12:0, 14:0,16:0, 16:1 ω7c, 18:1 ω7c, 17:0 cyclopropane, and 19:0 ω8c cyclopropane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50.1 to 50.7 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Erwinia alni</i> is strain PVFi 20.</s><s>This strain has all of the characteristics described above for the species.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 50.5 mol%. <i>Erwinia alni</i> PVFi 20<sup>T</sup> was isolated from Italian alder in Tuscany as the causal agent of the bark canker disease of alder.</s><s>After artificial inoculation, this strain typically produces the symptoms of bark canker disease of alder.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the NCPPB, Harpenden, United Kingdom, as strain NCPPB 3934 and in the International Collection of Micro-organisms from Plants, Auckland, New Zealand, as strain ICMP 12481.</s></p></content></protolog>