<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2861_nm.11203" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11203" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11203" rank="species">Marmoricola aequoreus</organism><reference id="rid.2861"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marmoricola aequoreus sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from marine sediment</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1391</fpage><lpage>1395</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64696-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625163</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marmoricola aequoreus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marmoricola aequoreus</em> (ae.qu.o.re′us. L. masc. adj. <em>aequoreus</em> belonging to the sea, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and non-motile cocci (0.5–0.7 μm in diameter) that occur singly, in pairs, as clusters or as short chains.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex and bright yellow in colour.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Growth is good at 10–37 °C, but poor at 4 °C, and does not occur at 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at an initial pH of 5.1–12.1, with an optimum at pH 7.1.</s><s>Good growth is observed at 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl, but poor at 6–7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Aesculin and casein are hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production is observed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine are not degraded.</s><s>Urease activity is not detected.</s><s>Acid is produced from dextran, maltose and salicin.</s><s>No acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-ribose, l-sorbose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, d-dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycerol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, 1,2-propanediol, d-sorbitol or d-xylitol.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are positive.</s><s>The following tests are weakly positive: esterase lipase (C8), crystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Esterase (C4), lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: d-cellobiose, dextran, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-ribose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, glycerol, d-mannitol, 1,2-propanediol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Assimilation of acetate, citrate, malate and succinate is detected.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: l-arabinose, d-arabinose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-sorbose, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, d-dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, <em>meso</em>-inositol and d-xylitol.</s><s>Tests for benzoate, formate and tartrate assimilation are negative.</s><s>ll-2,6-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid in the cell wall.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids contain phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain SST-45<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13812<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24464<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sandy sediment of Samyang beach in Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>