<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8546_nm.13539" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13539" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13539" rank="species">Prevotella histicola</organism><reference id="rid.8546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hooper</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella histicola sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1788</fpage><lpage>1791</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65656-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella histicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella histicola</em> [his.ti′co.la. N.L. masc. n. <em>histus</em> (from Gr. <em>histos</em>) tissue; L. suffix -<em>cola</em> (from <em>incola</em>) inhabitant; N.L. fem./masc. n. <em>histicola</em> inhabitant of tissue].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, variably pigmenting, Gram-negative bacilli that are 0.7×0.8–3.0 μm in size.</s><s>After 3 days incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, cream-coloured and opaque.</s><s>Some strains produce black colonies in the presence of metronidazole and other strains form bull's-eye colonies with reddish-brown pigmentation in the centres.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces moderate turbidity that is markedly enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are saccharolytic and are able to ferment fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, raffinose and sucrose, but not arabinose, cellobiose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Major amounts of acetic acid and succinic acid and trace to minor amounts of isovaleric acid and lactic acid are produced as end products of metabolism in peptone/yeast extract/glucose broth.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed; arginine, aesculin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The Rapid ID 32A profile is 4707 4502 22.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, T05-04<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19854<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55407<sup>T</sup>), and strains N12-20 and N19-30 were isolated from mucosal tissue from the human oral cavity.</s></p></content></protolog>