<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2464_nm.11377" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11377" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11377" rank="species">Marinobacter salicampi</organism><reference id="rid.2464"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter salicampi sp. nov., isolated from a marine solar saltern in Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2102</fpage><lpage>2105</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65197-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766879</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter salicampi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter salicampi</em> (sa.li.cam′pi. L. n. <em>sal</em> salt; L. n. <em>campus</em> field; N.L. gen. n. <em>salicampi</em> of a salt field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, straight or curved rods (0.4–0.8×1.0–7.0 μm).</s><s>Motile by means of a single flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MA supplemented with 6 % (w/v) NaCl are circular to slightly irregular, raised, smooth, yellowish white in colour and 0.8–1.2 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.5, but not at pH 5.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of approximately 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 15 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 16 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, l-tyrosine, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following substrates: l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol and <em>myo</em>-inositol.</s><s>Benzoate and salicin are not utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, polymyxin B and streptomycin, but not to lincomycin, novobiocin, neomycin or oleandomycin.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-9.</s><s>The major fatty acids (each constituting &#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58.1 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ISL-40<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12972<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 54357<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine solar saltern of the Yellow Sea at Byunsan, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>