<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3847_nm.1706" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1706" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1706" rank="species">Herbaspirillum seropedicae</organism><reference id="rid.3847"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>V.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olivares</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Döbereiner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Herbaspirillum; inclusion of [Pseudomonas] rubrisubalbicans, a milk plant pathogen, as Herbaspirillum rubrisubalbicans comb. nov.; and classification of a group of clinical isolates (EF group 1) as Herbaspirillum species 3.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>802</fpage><lpage>810</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-802</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Herbaspirillum seropedicae</i> (Baldani, Baldani, Seldin, and Dobereiner 1986)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Herbaspirillum seropedicae</i> (se.ro.ped'i.cae L. gen. n. <i>seropedicae</i>, of Seropkdica, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, where the species was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are vibroid and sometimes helical and become very motile when close to an O<sub>2</sub> source.</s><s>The cells have generally two polar flagella (occasionally one to three flagella) on one or on both poles.</s><s>On soft nutrient agar at 35°C, pronounced swarming occurs.</s><s>Most strains fix atmospheric N<sub>2</sub> under microaerobic conditions and grow well with N<sub>2</sub> as a sole nitrogen source.</s><s>The efficiency of N<sub>2</sub> fixation in semisolid NFb medium is 12 to 15 mg of N<sub>2</sub> per g of DL-malate.</s><s>Growth in the presence of N<sub>2</sub> is slower than the growth of <i>Azospirillum</i> spp., but the growth in the presence of mineral nitrogen or glutamate is much faster.</s><s>The organism does not grow in the presence of 2% NaCl.</s><s>Vitamins or growth substances are not required.</s><s>The organism is susceptible to chloramphenicol, tetracycline, gentamicin, kanamycin, erythromycin, and streptomycin and is resistant to penicillin.</s><s>The optimum temperature for N<sub>2</sub>-dependent growth is 34°C; no growth occurs at 22 and 38°C.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Good growth is observed between pH 5.3 and 8.0.</s><s>Nitrate is assimilated or dissimilated or both to NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> under O<sub>2</sub>, limitation.</s><s>No NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>-dependent anaerobic growth and no visible gas production from NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> occur in solid or semisolid medium.</s><s>The habitats are roots, stems and leaves of all kinds of members of the family <i>Gramineae</i> (13 species).</s><s>Members of this species could not be isolated from soil, and when inoculated in large numbers into soil, they cannot be reisolated after 3 weeks, except when sorghum plants are introduced (26). <i>H. seropedicae</i> can be differentiated from the other species by its auxanographic features (Table 2) and by the use of the HS DNA probe.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64 to 65%.The type strain is Z67=ATCC 35892=LMG 6513, with a G+C content of 64.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>