<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9245_nm.14512" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14512" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14512" rank="species">Porphyromonas bennonis</organism><reference id="rid.9245"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Summanen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Porphyromonas bennonis sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1727</fpage><lpage>1732</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001909-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542133</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Porphyromonas bennonis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Porphyromonas bennonis</em> (ben.no′nis. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>bennonis</em> of Benno, in honour of the contemporary Japanese microbiologist Yoshimi Benno, who has contributed significantly to our knowledge of anaerobic bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 0.7–1.0×1.0–6.0 μm in size.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies incubated on blood agar for 2 days are small, circular, entire, convex and slightly <em>β</em>-haemolytic.</s><s>Colonies are grey to cream; after 10 days incubation, colonies are weakly pigmented (beige to tan) and show no red fluorescence under long-wave UV light.</s><s>Gelatin-positive and bile-sensitive.</s><s>Indole-, nitrate- and lipase-negative.</s><s>Urease- and aesculin-negative.</s><s>Catalase-variable.</s><s>Asaccharolytic.</s><s>The major fermentation products from glucose metabolism are acetic acid and succinic acid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> DMA and/or C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (weakly positive), leucine arylamidase, chymotrypsin (weakly positive), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for cystine arylaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM system).</s><s>Esterase lipase, lipase and valine arylamidase activities are variable with the API ZYM system.</s><s>With Rosco diagnostic tablets, the strains are positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and ONPG, but negative for <em>α</em>-fucosidase, trypsin, urease and aesculin.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase phosphate, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase, and negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, mannosidase, raffinose fermentation, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (Rapid ID 32A).</s><s><em>β</em>-Lactamase is produced by 15 % of the strains.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WAL 1926C<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1629<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55979<sup>T</sup>), and other strains were isolated in mixed culture from various skin and soft-tissue infections of non-oral origin, mainly from abscesses in the buttock and groin areas.</s><s>Probably part of the indigenous bowel flora.</s></p></content></protolog>