<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6115_nm.9466" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9466" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9466" rank="species">Dyadobacter crusticola</organism><reference id="rid.6115"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Pichel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dyadobacter crusticola sp. nov., from biological soil crusts in the Colorado Plateau, USA, and an emended description of the genus Dyadobacter Chelius and Triplett 2000</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1295</fpage><lpage>1299</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63498-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879270</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dyadobacter crusticola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dyadobacter crusticola</em> (crus.ti′co.la. L. n. <em>crusta</em> crust; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> dweller; N.L. n. <em>crusticola</em> a dweller of crust).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are yellow, mucoid, convex, round and smooth.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative, are non-motile, curved to straight rods, straight to V-shaped and few were beaded rods.</s><s>Grows at 5–30 °C (but not at 37 °C) and is thus psychrotolerant in nature, with an optimum growth temperature of 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–8 (optimum 7), and it can tolerate up to 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells are positive for catalase, oxidase, lipase, phosphatase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, and negative for urease, gelatinase, DNase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, cellulose or starch but can hydrolyse aesculin weakly.</s><s>Also negative for methyl red, Voges–Proskauer reaction, indole and Simmons' citrate tests.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S gas and does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Cells produce acid from d-fructose but not from l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Able to ferment l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-maltose and d-xylose but not d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Is able to utilize d-cellobiose, glucose, dulcitol, d-glucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, lactic acid, d-laevulose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose and d-xylose as sole carbon sources but not adonitol, l-arabinose, acetate, citrate, dextran, ethanolamine, d-fructose, fumaric acid, d-galactose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, pyruvate, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, l-valine, adenine, cytosine, guanine, thymidine, nicotinic acid, oxalate, tartaric acid, indole or phenanthrene.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (per disc): carbenicillin (100 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (30 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg) but resistant to azithromycin (15 μg), aztreonam (30 μg), bacitracin (10 units), ceftriaxone (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), colistin (10 μg), erythromycin (2 μg), ethambutol (50 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), nitrofurantoin (150 μg), penicillin (10 U), streptomycin (10 μg), sulfisoxazole (300 μg), sulfthiazole (300 μg), trimethoprim (5 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The pigment present is a flexirubin type with absorption maxima at 428, 452 and 478 nm.</s><s>The fatty acids and their percentage contributions are listed in Table 2; polar lipids present are phosphatidyl serine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol (cardiolipin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CP183-8<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16708<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1036<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a BSC sample collected from the Colorado Plateau.</s></p></content></protolog>