<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5692_nm.4035" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4035" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4035" rank="species">Clostridium thermoalcaliphilum</organism><reference id="rid.5692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engle</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thermoalcaliphilum sp. nov., an anaerobic and thermotolerant facultative alkaliphile.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>111</fpage><lpage>118</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-111</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123553</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium thermoalcaliphilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium thermoalcaliphilum</i> (ther. mo. al. cal. i. phil' um. Gr. adj. <i>thermo</i>, hot; M.L. n. <i>alcali</i>, from the arabic <i>al-qili</i>, the ashes of the saltwort plant; M.L. adj. <i>philum</i>, from Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, dear, loving; M.L. adj. <i>themoalcaliphilum</i>, referring to the organism's optimal growth under alkaline growth conditions at elevated temperatures)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the properties of strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The morphological, pH, and temperature characteristics of isolate YL24-1 are the same as those described below for strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony and cell morphology.</s><s>Surface colonies are circular and white with a yellowish tint.</s><s>Colonies in agar are lens shaped.</s><s>Cells from liquid cultures in the exponential growth phase or prepared from 1- or 2-day-old colonies are highly motile rods that are 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter and 3 to 12 μm long (Fig. 2A).</s><s>Cells in early- and mid-stationary-phase cultures are significantly longer (12 to 20 μm) (Fig. 2B).</s><s>Like <i>C. paradoxum</i>, the organism tends to develop pseudofilaments when it is grown at pH values of 10.9 to 11.0 (15).</s><s>Swollen sporangium-like structures occur during growth at pH 10.1 to 11.0 (Fig. 2B, arrowheads, and Fig. 2D, arrow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall, Gram-staining reaction, and Gram type.</s><s>Transmission electron micrographs of ultrathin sections (Fig. 2D through F) show that strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup>  has a cell envelope structure different from that of <i>C. paradoxum</i> (15), especially at the cell division junction, which seems to be sheathed by an envelope structure (Fig. 2E and F).</s><s>Furthermore, peptidoglycan structure analysis shows that the cell wall type of strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup> is A4β (L-Orn-D-Asp), while the cell wall type of <i>C. paradoxum</i> is A1τ (<i>m</i>-diaminopimelic acid direct).</s><s>The Gram-staining reaction is negative irregardless of the growth stage; however, since no lipopolysaccharide- polymyxin B complex is detected, the organism is gram type positive (29, 31).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sporulation tests.</s><s>No endospores are formed after growth under various culture conditions, including after growth in agar roll tubes containing agar-solidified nutrient-deficient xylan media (at alkaline and neutral pH values) incubated for up to 1 week.</s><s>Heat-treated cultures at all growth stages do not grow when they are incubated at 48 to 50°C and pH 10.0 after the heat treatment.</s><s>Cultures in the exponential or stationary growth phase left at room temperature for more than 1 week frequently cannot be subcultured, indicating that spores were not formed.</s><s>The swollen structures observed (Fig. 2D), which somewhat resemble prespores in their overall shape, contain only irregular refractile substances and apparently are not heat-stable spores.</s><s>As the cultures become older, these structures eventually swell further and burst.</s><s>Transmission electron micrographs of ultrathin sections of the swollen structures do not indicate that <i>C. thermoalcalophilum</i> develops membrane structures that are associated with the formation of prespores (Fig. 2D) like those observed with <i>C. paradoxum</i> (15).</s><s>These results indicate that this organism does not form viable spores under the conditions tested, although on the basis of the 16s rRNA sequence analysis results, it is closely related to the sporeforming organism <i>C. paradoxum</i> (see below).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motility and flagellation.</s><s>The organism is motile from the early exponential growth phase through the stationary growth phase.</s><s>The cells have 2 to 12 peritrichous flagella (Fig. 2C).</s><s>The flagella are 10 to 15 μm long and 90 to 95 nm in diameter and have a wavelength of 2.5 to 3.0 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motility depends on the pH of the growth medium (Fig. 3) and the incubation temperature (Fig. 4).</s><s>The organism is motile at pH values ranging from 7.0 to 10.6; the optimum pH for motility is around 9.8, which coincides with the optimum pH for growth (Fig. 3A and B).</s><s>Less than 5% of the cells are motile in the absence of glucose; however, in the presence of 0.3% (wt/vol) glucose at pH 9.8 the percentage of motile cells is 65% (Fig. 3C).</s><s>When a culture that is growing exponentially at 50°C is used as the inoculum, motility occurs at temperatures ranging from 30 to 53°C (optimum temperature, 42 to 52°C) (Fig. 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth properties. (i) Growth requirements.</s><s>The organism is obligately anaerobic.</s><s>No growth occurs when an exponentially growing culture is inoculated into aerobically prepared YTG medium, nutrient broth, or agar-solidified media.</s><s>In the absence of yeast extract and tryptone, no growth occurs when an exponentially growing culture is inoculated into basic mineral media (pH 9.8) containing 0.1% (wt/vol) NH<sub>4</sub>Cl as the nitrogen source and 0.3% (wt/vol) glucose as the carbon and energy source.</s><s>However, some growth (OD<sub>600</sub> 0.15 U) does occur when 0.02% (wt/vol) yeast extract is added, indicating that yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>Tryptone but not with peptone can be used as a substitute for yeast extract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Temperature and pH ranges for growth.</s><s>The temperature range for growth at pH 10.1 is 27 to 57.5°C; the optimum temperature for growth is between 48 and 51°C (Fig. 4).</s><s>The pH range for growth is 7.0 to 11.0 at 50°C; the optimum pH for growth is between 9.5 and 10.0 (Fig. 3).</s><s>The same results are obtained in the presence (YTG medium) and absence (YT medium) of glucose (Fig. 3).</s><s>Under optimal conditions (pH 10.1, 50°C, YTG medium), the shortest doubling time that has been observed with strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup> is 19 min.</s><s>This value is similar to the observed doubling time for <i>C. paradoxum</i> and relatively small compared with the reported doubling times of most other glycolytic thermophiles (30).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Effect of NaCl and KCl on growth.</s><s>The Na<sup>+</sup> concentration range for growth is 5 mM to 1.25 M (Fig. 5).</s><s>The maximum tolerated Na<sup>+</sup> concentration (1.25 M) is much higher than the maximum tolerated Na<sup>+</sup>concentration for <i>C. paradoxum</i> (15) (about 0.75 M NaCl).</s><s>The range of Na<sup>+</sup> concentrations at which growth occurs in the presence of 25 mM K<sup>+</sup> (5 mM to 1.25 M) is a little wider than the range of Na<sup>+</sup> concentrations at which growth occurs in the presence of 100 mM K<sup>+</sup> (20 to 990 mM) (Fig. 5).</s><s>A higher maximum OD,, occurs in the presence of 25 mM K+ than in the presence of 100 mM K<sup>+</sup> for all of the Na<sup>+</sup> concentrations that have been tested.</s><s>Near the maximum tolerated NaCl concentration (1.25 M in the presence of 25 mM K<sup>+</sup> and of 990 mM in the presence of 100 mM K<sup>+</sup>), the morphology of the cells changes, leading to the formation of L-form cells after 24 h of incubation at 50°C.</s><s>At NaCl concentrations higher than the maxima, the cells begin to lyze within 2 h.</s><s>At the lower NaCl concentrations tested (less than 5 mM in the presence of 25 mM K<sup>+</sup> and less than 20 mM in the presence of 100 mM K<sup>+</sup>), the cells do not grow, and the normal morphology deteriorates with prolonged incubation (after 6 h), as the concentration of NaCl decreases.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate utilization and fermentation products.</s><s>In the presence of 0.1% (wt/vol) yeast extract (pH 9.6), <i>C. thermoalcaliphilum</i> utilizes glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, and Casamino Acids.</s><s>It does not utilize galactose, lactose, xylose, ribose, mannose, rhamnose, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, mannitol, glycerol, lactate, formate, methanol, xylan, cellulose, starch, pectin, and H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The fermentation products formed at pH 10.5 and 50°C from the utilization of yeast extract and 2.3 μmol of glucose per ml include 16.1 μmol of acetate per ml, 3.7 μmol of H<sub>2</sub> per ml, 1 μmol of isovalerate per ml, 0.7 μmol of lactate per ml, trace amounts (&#x003C;0.5 μmol/ml) of succinate and malate, and one unidentified product with a retention time of 14.7 to 14.8 min, but no significant amounts of bicarbonate and carbonate.</s><s>Differences in product formation occur among the four conditions which we tested (Table 2).</s><s>The unidentified product formed in the presence and absence of glucose has the same chromatographic properties as the product formed under similar conditions by <i>C. paradoxum</i> (15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical properties. (i) Dissimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>No sulfate reduction activity occurs in the presence of glucose, acetate, and lactate, thus making it unlikely that isolate JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup> is a sulfate-reducing organism.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Fatty acid analysis.</s><s>The main fatty acids are (in order of decreasing amount formed) i15:0, a15:0, i13:0, 16:0, i17:0, 14:0, and 18:O.</s><s>The ester-linked phospholipid fatty acid methyl ester profile for cells grown at pH 10.0 to 10.5 is quite similar to the profile of <i>C. paradoxum</i> grown at pH 7.5 (15) but is distinct from the profile of <i>C. paradoxum</i> cultured at pH 10.5.</s><s>It is interesting that <i>C. paradoxum</i> has a phospholipid fatty acid methyl ester profile similar to that of nonspore- forming strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup> at pH 7.0 to 8.0, pH values at which <i>C. paradoxum</i> does not form spores (15).</s><s>However, at the present time no further conclusion can be drawn from this information.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) API An-Ident tests.</s><s>An-Ident tests (API Analytab Products, Plainview, N.Y.) result in positive responses for indole acetate, α-glucosidase, arginine aminopeptidase, and arginine utilization.</s><s>Negative responses occur in tests for N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, leucine aminopeptidase, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase, glycine aminopeptidase, arabinosidase, indole production, and catalase.</s><s>Strain JW/YL23-2<sup>T</sup> differs from <i>C. paradoxum</i> (Table 3) in the results for four tests (the indole production, α-arabinosidase, arginine aminopeptidase, and catalase tests).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Susceptibility to antibiotics.</s><s>We tested the effect of antibiotics at 50°C.</s><s>At pH 7.5 and 10.1, C. thermoalcaliphilum is susceptible to 50 μg of penicillin G per ml, 50 μg of ampicillin per ml, 50 μg of metroimidazole per ml, 50 μg of gentamicin per ml, and 50 μg of rifampin per ml.</s><s>In agreement with 16s rRNA data, this suggests that this organism is a (eu)bacterial species.</s><s>For a more meaningful assessment, a detailed study of the thermostability of the antibiotics used at pH 10 and 50°C needs to be done.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) DNA G+C content.</s><s>The DNA G+C content, as determined by complete digestion of DNA with P1 nuclease and alkaline phosphatase followed by HPLC analysis (15, 19, 28), is 32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Maintenance.</s><s>Since so far no endospores have been observed and cultures stored at room temperature frequently become nonviable within 1 week, the cultures need to be preserved in liquid nitrogen or as 50% glycerol-containing culture suspensions at -18 or -75°C.</s><s>Such cultures are viable for at least 1 year.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain JWTyL23-2, which was isolated from a sewage plant in Atlanta, Ga., is the type strain of <i>C. thermoalcaliphilum</i> sp. nov. and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen as strain DSM 7309; its G+C content is 32 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>