<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9527_nm.14680" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14680" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14680" rank="species">Fritschea bemisiae</organism><reference id="rid.9527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thao</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horn</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dyszynski</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel chlamydiae in whiteflies and scale insects: endosymbionts ‘Candidatus Fritschea bemisiae’ strain Falk and ‘Candidatus Fritschea eriococci’ strain Elm</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1581</fpage><lpage>1587</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63454-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Fritschea bemisiae’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Fritschea bemisiae’ (Frit′sche.a. N.L. fem. n. <em>Fritschea</em> after Thomas R. Fritsche, American physician and parasitologist, whose studies initiated a major change in our perception of the natural history and diversity of the <em>Chlamydiae</em>. be.mi′si.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>bemisiae</em> of <em>Bemisia</em>, the genus of whitefly insects in which it was first discovered).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The host range currently includes the whitefly <em>Bemisia tabaci</em> (Sternorrhyncha, Aleyrodidae). ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Fritschea bemisiae’ can be detected and identified using EM, PCR amplification and DNA sequence analysis.</s><s>EM detection of ‘<em>Ca</em>.</s><s>F. bemisiae’ in the bacteriocytes of <em>B. tabaci</em> shows intracellular growth, small rod-like reticulate bodies and electron-dense elementary bodies (0·2–0·8 μm).</s><s>There is evidence for a single ribosomal operon in ‘<em>Ca</em>.</s><s>F. bemisiae’.</s><s>The G+C content is 40 mol% in a 16·6 kb ‘<em>Ca</em>.</s><s>F. bemisiae’ genome fragment containing the rRNA operon (GenBank accession no. AY140910).</s><s>Gene organization in this fragment is most similar to gene organization in strain UWE25 from the <em>Parachlamydiaceae</em>, the only genome sequenced to date from an organism in the order <em>Chlamydiales</em> not belonging to the <em>Chlamydiaceae</em>.</s><s>The rRNA operon does not include a tRNA.</s><s>Like <em>S. negevensis</em>, ‘<em>Ca</em>.</s><s>F. bemisiae’ has a group I intron in the 23S rRNA gene (position 1910, <em>E. coli</em> numbering).</s><s>Strain Falk is the reference strain of the species ‘<em>Ca</em>.</s><s>F. bemisiae’ and was reared in the laboratory of B.</s><s>W.</s><s>Falk at UC Davis, CA, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>