<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5987_nm.2974" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2974" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2974" rank="species">Vibrio hispanicus</organism><reference id="rid.5987"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomez-Gil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Gasca</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roque</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio hispanicus sp. nov., isolated from Artemia sp. and sea water in Spain.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>265</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02775-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742490</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio hispanicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio hispanicus</em> (his.pa′ni.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>hispanicus</em> from Spain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, small (2·2±0·659 μm), motile, curved rods with polar flagellation.</s><s>Bright yellow, small (1–3 mm), circular colonies are formed on TCBS agar.</s><s>Non-luminescent, translucent and non-swarming colonies are formed on marine agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in media that contain 0, 2·5, 6·0, 8·0 and 10 % NaCl (w/v), but not in 12·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4, 30, 35 and 40 °C.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, indole, citrate, methyl red, nitrite reduction and <em>α</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Fermentative, arginine dihydrolase-positive, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase- and l-tyrosine-negative.</s><s>Tryptophan deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S, gas from glucose production, Voges–Proskauer reaction, gelatinase and urease are negative.</s><s>Susceptible to vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10 and 150 μg and to polymixin B at 300 U, but resistant to streptomycin (25 μg) and gentamicin (10 μg).</s><s>Positive for <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-glucuronic acid (LMG 13213 is weakly positive), cellobiose, dl-lactic acid, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose (LMG 13240<sup>T</sup> and LMG 13213 are weakly positive), d-saccharic acid (LMG 13213 is weakly positive), d-trehalose, gentiobiose, inosine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid (LMG 13240<sup>T</sup> is weakly positive), l-glutamic acid, l-rhamnose, l-serine, maltose, methyl pyruvate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, psicose, sucrose, thymidine and uridine utilization as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Negative for 2,3-butanediol, 2-aminoethanol, acetic acid, adonitol, alaninamide, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>α</em>-d-lactose lactulose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, bromosuccinic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, dl-carnitine, d-alanine, d-arabitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-melibiose, d-serine, d-sorbitol, formic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, glycogen, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy l-proline, i-erythritol, itaconic acid, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-fucose, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-threonine, malonic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, monomethyl succinate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, phenylethylamine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, propionic acid, putrescine, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, turanose, Tween 40, Tween 80, urocanic acid and xylitol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid and alkaline phosphatases, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive; <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, cystine arylamidase, lipase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are negative.</s><s>Most abundant fatty acids (% of total fatty acids) are, in descending order (mean of three strains, minimum and maximum): summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH; 37·2, 35·8–39·1), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (25·7, 22·8–27·9), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (16·7, 15·5–17·8), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (5·9, 5·3–6·5), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (4·4, 4·2–4·8), summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I; 3·2, 3·1–3·4), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2·6, 2·5–2·8) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (1·1, 0·9–1·2).</s><s>Differences between strains analysed are: LMG 13240<sup>T</sup> does not utilize <em>α</em>-lactose, LMG 13211 does not utilize glycerol or amygdalin and LMG 13213 does not utilize succinic acid.</s><s>LMG 13213 is sensitive to ampicillin (30 μg; the others are intermediately resistant) and is intermediately resistant to kanamycin (30 μg; the others are resistant) and oxytetracycline (30 μg; the others are resistant); LMG 13211 is resistant to amikacin (30 μg; the others are intermediately resistant).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 42·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 13240<sup>T</sup> (=CAIM 525<sup>T</sup>=VIB 213<sup>T</sup>) and reference strains are LMG 13211 (=CAIM 523) and LMG 13213 (=CAIM 524).</s><s>All were isolated from <em>Artemia</em> sp. and its culture water in Barcelona, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>