<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12901_nm.22720" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22720" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22720" rank="species">Bradyrhizobium cytisi</organism><reference id="rid.12901"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chahboune</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carro</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peix</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barrijal</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bedmar</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bradyrhizobium cytisi sp. nov., isolated from effective nodules of Cytisus villosus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2922</fpage><lpage>2927</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027649-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bradyrhizobium cytisi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bradyrhizobium cytisi</em> [cy.ti′si. L. masc. <em>cytisus</em> a kind of clover and also a scientific generic name (<em>Cytisus</em>); L. gen. n. <em>cytisi</em> of a kind of clover, of <em>Cytisus</em>, referring to the isolation source of this micro-organism, nodules of <em>Cytisus villosus</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods.</s><s>Colonies are small and pearl white in YMA at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6–8 and 14–30 °C, with optimum growth at pH 6.8 and 28 °C.</s><s>Growth is not observed at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 0.25 % NaCl.</s><s>Strictly aerobic, with slow growth in YMA medium, forming colonies less than 1 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase and urease production.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is weak.</s><s>Assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-xylose, d-ribose, l-arabinose, mannitol, adonitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate and adipate as carbon sources is positive.</s><s>Assimilation of citrate, malate and pyruvate is weak.</s><s>Assimilation of cellobiose, maltose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, l-sorbose, lactose, sucrose, raffinose, dulcitol, caprate and phenylacetate is negative.</s><s>Assimilation of l-proline, l-glutamic acid, aspartic acid, l-serine and betaine as nitrogen sources is positive.</s><s>Assimilation of l-glycine and sarcosine as nitrogen sources is negative.</s><s>Acid production from d-ribose, d-fructose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-arabinose and d-mannose is positive.</s><s>Acid production from d-galactose and adonitol is negative.</s><s>Acid production from mannitol is variable.</s><s>Alkali production from pyruvate as a carbon source is negative or weak.</s><s>Alkali production from l-glutamate and l-aspartate as nitrogen sources is positive.</s><s>Alkali production from l-proline, l-serine and betaine as nitrogen sources is negative.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, penicillin, cloxacillin, polymyxin B, ciprofloxacin and erythromycin; sensitive to tetracycline, cefuroxime, neomycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Nodulates <em>Cytisus</em> but not <em>Glycine max</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CTAW11<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25866<sup>T</sup> = CECT 7749<sup>T</sup>), isolated from effective nodules of <em>Cytisus villosus</em> in Morocco.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain CTAW11<sup>T</sup> is 65.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>