<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2550_nm.11498" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11498" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11498" rank="species">Robiginitomaculum antarcticum</organism><reference id="rid.2550"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>T.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Robiginitomaculum antarcticum gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Hyphomonadaceae, from Antarctic seawater</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2595</fpage><lpage>2599</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65274-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978224</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Robiginitomaculum antarcticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Robiginitomaculum antarcticum</em> (ant.arc′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>antarcticum</em> of the Antarctic environment, from where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics reported for the genus, cells are 1.3–4.5 μm long and 0.4–1.0 μm wide, with a tapered end.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, viscous, rusty-coloured and 0.3–1.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 3–25 °C, optimally at 20 °C, but not above 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–10 and 0.5–5.0 % NaCl, optimally at pH 7 and at 2.0–2.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>In API 20NE strips, positive for nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity (substrate, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside).</s><s>Negative for urea hydrolysis, indole production, acid production from glucose, gelatin liquefaction and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase activities are present.</s><s>Negative for esterase (C4), acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (substrate, 2-naphthyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>In tests with GN2 microplates (Biolog), oxidizes the following carbon substrates: Tween 40 and Tween 80, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, quinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Does not utilize the following carbon substrates: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxy phenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), rifampicin (50 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg), but resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The cellular fatty acids comprise C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (41.9 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (21.4 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (14.3 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (7.7 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (3.5 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iC<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (3.0 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (2.8 %).</s><s>Traces (&#x003C;1 %) of the following fatty acids are also present: C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>9 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC3195<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42687<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 103098<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface seawater of Maxwell Bay, King George Island, West Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>