<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.32_nm.1923" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1923" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1923" rank="species">Neisseria iguanae</organism><reference id="rid.32"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Barrett</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schlater</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montali</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of Neisseria from iguanid lizards, Neisseria iguanae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>200</fpage><lpage>202</lpage><source id="152">Letters in Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Lett Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0266-8254</issn><essn>1472-765X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1472-765X.1994.tb00846.x</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Descrlptlon of <i>Neisserla iguanae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Neisserla iguanae</i> (M.L. fem. gen. sing. noun <i>iguanae</i>, of the iguana lizard, from Spanish fem. noun, iguana; <i>Neisseria</i> sp., Plowman et al. 1987)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small cocci about 0.8 μm in diameter; they are largely arranged as diplococci but show numerous tetrads in culture, nonmotile.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores were not observed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic, no growth under anaerobic conditions, mesophilic ; growth occurs between 25°C and 37°C, chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on 5% (v/v) sheep or horse blood agar are nonpigmented, round, transparent, domed, about 1 mm in diameter after 72 h at 35°C, and showed marked zones of alpha haemolysis.</s><s>Oxidase-positive, indole-negative, catalase-positive, urease- and deoxyribonuclease-negative.</s><s>Nitrates usually reduced, nitrite reduction variable.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, streptomycin and tetracyclin, resistant to novobiocin and trimethoprim.</s><s>Weak acidity usually from glucose, sucrose and gluconate, sometimes trehalose, not from fructose, maltose, lactose or galactose (API 50 CH).</s><s>Aesculin not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin not liquified, acetate and citrate not utilized.</s><s>Grows on G+C chocolate agar containing 0.5% (w/v) sodium taurocholate, but not on MacConkey or nutrient agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Notable among neisserias for being gluconate-positive, strongly positive for alkaline phosphatase 2 (FGN) and strongly alpha haemolytic on horse and sheep blood agar.</s><s>Distinguished from <i>Neisseria animalis</i> and <i>N. canis</i> by these properties, and in forming tetrads and failure to grow on nutrient agar although similar to these species in sometimes acidifying glucose and sucrose but not fructose or maltose, and in usually reducing nitrate and synthesizing polysaccharide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Associated with septicaemia and abscesses in iguanid lizards, and may be isolated from the oral cavity of healthy lizards (<i>Iguana iguana</i> and <i>Cyclura cornuta</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NVSL 85737.</s></p></content></protolog>