<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3240_nm.5868" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5868" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5868" rank="species">Arthrobacter psychrolactophilus</organism><reference id="rid.3240"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Loveland-Curtze</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheridan</surname><given-names>P.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutshall</surname><given-names>K.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenchley</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Biochemical and phylogenetic analyses of psychrophilic isolates belonging to the Arthrobacter subgroup and description of Arthrobacter psychrolactophilus, sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>171</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>363</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050722</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10369891</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter psychrolactophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter psychrolactophilus</i> (psy.chro.lac.to'phi.lus; <i>psychros</i> Gr.adj., cold; <i>lac</i> L.n.n., milk; <i>philos</i> Gr.m.n., friend, loving; <i>psychrolactophilus</i>, a cold, milk (sugar)-loving (bacterium))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Individual cells show a distinct rod/coccus cycle and have an average cell length of 1.4 μm during exponential growth and 0.5 μm during stationary phase.</s><s>Gram-positive; easily decolorized; strict aerobe.</s><s>Contains lysine as the diagnostic amino acid in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Nonspore-forming.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>No vitamin requirements; grows in mineral salts medium with ammonium chloride as sole source of nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on trypticase soy agar without dextrose are yellow; degree of pigmentation varies with growth temperature and age of the cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 60.6 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso- and isobranched fatty acids.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> (~ 73%), followed by anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> (~ 13%), iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> (~ 8%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (~ 2%), and iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> (~ 1.4%).</s><s>All other fatty acids are at levels below 1%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Able to grow at 0–5°C.</s><s>Growth range, 0–30°C.</s><s>Generation time at 10°C in trypticase soy broth with no added carbohydrate is 4.8 h.</s><s>Does not produce acid with glucose as carbon source.</s><s>Can utilize lactose, sorbitol, melibiose, cellobiose, glycerol, maltose, raffinose, xylose, galactose, sucrose, and glucose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Produces catalase.</s><s>Produces β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, amylase, and gelatinase.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, alkaline phosphatase, N-acetylglucosaminidase, urease, and DNase.</s><s>Habitat: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>16S rRNA gene sequencing analysis places this organism near <i>A. oxydans</i> and <i>A. polychromogenes</i>, although its 16S rRNA gene sequence is sufficiently different (94.4 and 94.3% sequence similarity, respectively) as to warrant a new species designation.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence is 92.3% similar to the type strain of the <i>Arthrobacter</i> genus, <i>A. globiformis</i> 8010.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Arthrobacter psychrolactophilus</i> has been deposited at the ATCC (accession no. 700733).</s></p></content></protolog>