<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12321_nm.20342" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20342" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20342" rank="species">Serinicoccus profundi</organism><reference id="rid.12321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serinicoccus profundi sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from deep-sea sediment, and emended description of the genus Serinicoccus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>19</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019976-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118285</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Serinicoccus profundi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Serinicoccus profundi</em> (pro′fun.di. L. gen. n. <em>profundi</em> of/from the depths of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-reaction-positive, moderately halophilic and aerobic.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>No spore formation.</s><s>Cells are non-motile cocci.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–14 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 3–5 %), at pH 6–11 (optimum pH 7) and at 10–35 °C (optimum 30 °C).</s><s>Colonies on ZBA are yellow, circular, convex, entire, glistening, opaque and butyraceous after 2 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S on triple-sugar iron agar.</s><s>DNA and Tween 80 are decomposed.</s><s>With API 20NE, positive for nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin decomposition, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase and utilization of d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, potassium gluconate and malic acid but negative for indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease and utilization of l-arabinose, d-mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, capric acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase; variable for esterase (C4), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase; negative for lipase (C14), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>With the Biolog GP2 MicroPlate, positive for oxidation of dextrin, glycogen, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, raffinose, d-ribose, stachyose, sucrose, trehalose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid, l-alaninamide, glycerol, adenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate and uridine 5′-monophosphate; weakly positive for oxidation of Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, d-fructose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-sorbitol, turanose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, succinic acid, 2,3-butanediol and 2′-deoxyadenosine.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc unless otherwise indicated) bacitracin (0.04 U), chloromycetin (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), minomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), novobiocin (30), rifampicin (5) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefalexin (30), cefazolin (30), cefuroxime (30), cephalothin (30), cephradin (30), lincomycin (2), oxacillin (1), penicillin G (10) and piperacillin (100).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylcholine and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MCCC 1A05965<sup>T</sup> (=0714S6-1<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21363<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 4.5582<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a deep-sea sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>