<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2606_nm.1517" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1517" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1517" rank="species">Hyphomicrobium denitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.2606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization and description of Hyphomicrobium denitrificans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>528</fpage><lpage>532</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hyphomicrobium denitrificans</i> Urakami, Sasaki, Suzuki, and Komagata sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyphomicrobium denitrificans</i> (de.ni.tri'fi.cans. M. L. part. adj. <i>denitrificans</i>, denitrifying)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, rod-shaped cells with pointed ends that are oval, egg-shaped, or bean shaped, 0.3 to 0.6 μm in diameter, and 1.0 to 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells produce mono- or bipolar filamentous outgrowths (hyphae) of varying lengths that are 0.3 to 0.4 μm in diameter.</s><s>The hyphae are not septate.</s><s>Cells multiply by budding at the tips of the hyphae.</s><s>Mature buds become motile, break off, and often attach themselves to surfaces or to other cells to form clumps.</s><s>Motility is lost soon after attachment.</s><s>Cells do not grow in nutrient broth or peptone broth.</s><s>Colonies on methanol-containing agar are shiny, smooth, raised, entire, white, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 3 to 6 days at 30°C.</s><s>A water-soluble fluorescent pigment is not produced on King A or King B medium containing 5% (wt/wt) methanol.</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate accumulate in the cells.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Nitrate respiration (anaerobic growth in the presence of nitrate) is strong.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Negative for gelatin and starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced.</s><s>Oxidase, urease, and catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is not produced from sugars oxidatively or fermentatively.</s><s>Methanol, monomethylamine, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, pectin, and acetate are utilized as sole sources of carbon, but methane is not utilized.</s><s>Some strains utilize formate and ethanol.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized; L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, inositol, glycerol, soluble starch, propionic acid, isobutyric acid, <i>n</i>-valeric acid, lactic acid, succinic acid, and oxalic acid.</s><s>Vitamins and amino acids are not required for growth.</s><s>Ammonia, nitrate, and urea are utilized as sole sources of nitrogen.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory and not fermentative.</s><s>Good growth occurs between pH 6.0 and 8.0 and at 30°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur in media containing 3% sodium chloride.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 60 to 61 mol% G+C.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids include large amounts of straight-chain unsaturated C<sub>18:1</sub> acid.</s><s>The hydroxy fatty acids include large amounts of 3-OH C1<sub>14:0</sub> and 3-OH C<sub>16:0</sub> hydroxy acids.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is ubiquinone Q-9.</s><s>Methanol is utilized by the serine pathway via activated formaldehyde incorporation.</s><s>The type strain of <i>H. denitrificans</i> is TK 0415 (= DSM 1869 = NCIB 11706 = Attwood and Harder strain X).</s></p></content></protolog>