<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.370_nm.365" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.365" rank="genus">Picrophilus</organism><reference id="rid.370"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleper</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pühler</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zillig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Picrophilus oshimae and Picrophilus torridus fam. nov., gen. nov., sp. nov., two species of hyperacidophilic, thermophilic, heterotrophic, aerobic archaea.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>814</fpage><lpage>816</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Picrophilus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Picrophilus</i> (Pi.cro.phi'lus. Gr. adj. <i>pikros</i>, acidic; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; N. L. masc. n. <i>Picrophilus</i>, acid-loving organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately aerobic, heterotrophic, moderately thermophilic, hyperacidophilic, irregular cocci, Different dividing states occur beside each other, as determined by microscopic examination (Fig. 1).</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 47 and 65°C and optimally at 60°C.</s><s>Grows at pH values between about 0 and 3.5 and optimally at pH 0.7.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0.1 to 0.5% yeast extract and optimally in the presence of 0.2% yeast extract; a lag phase occurs in the presence of 0.5% yeast extract.</s><s>Under optimal conditions, the generation time is 6 h.</s><s>Slow growth to a low density occurs on tryptone, and no growth occurs on many other carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The diameter of the cells is about 1 μm.</s><s>Division occurs by constriction.</s><s>The division intermediates resemble those of <i>Thermococcus</i> strains.</s><s>There is a regular filigree teragonal S layer, which probably has polysaccharide chains on the outside (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two species are known, type species <i>P. oshimae</i> and <i>P. torridus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>