<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9222_nm.14477" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14477" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14477" rank="species">Bacillus korlensis</organism><reference id="rid.9222"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus korlensis sp. nov., a moderately halotolerant bacterium isolated from a sand soil sample in China</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1787</fpage><lpage>1792</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004879-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542113</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus korlensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus korlensis</em> (kor.len′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>korlensis</em> pertaining to Korla, a city of Xinjiang Province in the north-west of China from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, rod-shaped, strictly aerobic, spore-forming, 1.8–3.0 μm long and 0.7–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Endospores are oval, lie subterminally, occasionally paracentrally, and usually cause the sporangia to swell.</s><s>Growth occurs at 7–45 °C; optimal temperature is 30–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–11.0, with optimal growth at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–8 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0–2 %).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and starch.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, gelatin, cellulose, chitin or tyrosine.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, citrate utilization, indole production and urease are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol (weakly), l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose (weakly), starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose and potassium gluconate (weakly), but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (weakly), acid phosphatase (weakly), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (weakly), <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, but not lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, kanamycin, erythromycin, gentamicin, penicillin G, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ZLC-26<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207172<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-51302<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sand soil sample collected from Korla, Xinjiang Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>