<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3324_nm.8362" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8362" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8362" rank="species">Fusobacterium periodonticum</organism><reference id="rid.3324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slots</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potts</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mashimo</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium periodonticum, a new species from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>62</volume><fpage>960</fpage><lpage>963</lpage><source id="345">Journal of Dental Research</source><abbrev>J Dent Res</abbrev><issn>0022-0345</issn><essn>1544-0591</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/00220345830620090901</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6575999</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium peridonticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium peridonticum</i> (Pe. ri. o'don. ti. cum. Gr.n. <i>peri</i> around + <i>odon</i>, <i>odontos</i> tooth; M.L. neutr. adj. <i>periodontium</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fusiform bacteria of the human oral cavity have undergone considerable taxonomic re-arrangements since the first description of these organisms.</s><s>The oral fusiforms were divided by Knorr into three species (<i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i>, <i>Fusobacterium polymorphum</i>, and <i>Fusobacterium plauti-vincenti</i>); by Slanetz and Rettger into four morphological and biochemical types; by Hine and Berry into three species (<i>Fusiformis nucleatum</i>, <i>Fusiformis polymorphum</i>, and <i>Fusiformis dentium</i>); by Spaulding and Rettger into two major biochemical and serological groups; and by Bϕe into two genera (<i>Fusobacterium</i> and <i>Leptotrichia</i>). <i>F. polymorphum</i> and <i>F. nucleatum</i> have been consolidated into the latter species, which also includes organisms previously described as <i>Fusiformis fusiformis</i>.</s><s>Oral fusiforms have recently been identified which were not members of the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i>, but belonged to the genera <i>Capnocytophaga</i> and <i>Bacteroides</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The definition of the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i> was, in the early 1970's, amended to include anaerobic, gram-negative, non-sporing rods which produce major amounts of butyric acid and do not produce isobutyric and isovaleric acids.</s><s>The isolates examined in this study fulfilled these criteria and were accordingly true strains of <i>Fusobacterium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA-DNA homology studies showed from 6% to 40% relatedness between <i>F. periodonticum</i> and type strains of fusobacterial species which are biochemically related.</s><s>It is generally accepted that groups of bacteria which demonstrate less than 60% homology should be considered for classification as separate species.</s><s>Using this criterion, the homology data indicated that <i>F. periodonticum</i> was a new species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The relatively high amount of C i17:0 and low amount of C n16:0 in <i>F. periodonticum</i>, especially when compared with the type strain of the common oral species <i>F. nucleatum</i>, indicated that <i>F. periodonticum</i> has additional properties which distinguish it from other fusobacterial species.</s><s>However, human oral strains of <i>F. nucleatum</i> can vary in their content of cellular fatty acids, a finding which may limit the taxonomic implications of the present cellular fatty acid data.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A small number of biochemical tests appears to be capable of distinguishing <i>F. periodonticum</i> from current <i>Fusobacterium</i> species.</s><s>Unlike <i>F. periodonticum</i>, the two reference strains of <i>F. nucleatum</i> used in this study do not ferment galactose: They only lower the pH values in fructose and glucose broths from 0.2 to 0.7 U, and exhibit no hydrolysis of hippurate. <i>F. simiae</i>, in contrast to <i>F. periodonticum</i>, does not ferment galactose, utilizes lactate, and is able to grow in 2% oxgall. <i>F. gonidiaformans</i> and <i>F. varium</i> produce abundant gas in deep glucose agar, <i>F. naviforme</i> does not form propionate from threonine, <i>F. glutinosum</i> ferments lactose, <i>F. glutinosum</i> utilizes lactate, and <i>Fusobacterium aquatile</i> hydrolyzes esculin - characteristics which distinguish these species from <i>F. periodonticum</i>.</s><s>Other known fusobacterial species, including <i>Fusobacterium necrogenes</i>, <i>Fusobacterium perfoetens</i>, <i>Fusobacterium prausnitzii</i>, <i>F. plauti</i>, <i>Fusobacterium bullosum</i>, and <i>F. russii</i>, differ from <i>F. periodonticum</i> by their inability to produce indole.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oral fusobacteria which ferment fructose, galactose, and glucose have previously been isolated by Spaulding and Rettgert and Baird-Parker.</s><s>According to the biochemical descriptions, these authors' isolates differed somewhat from <i>F. periodonticum</i>.</s><s>However, unavailability of the previous isolates prevents establishment of any definitive relationship between these organisms and <i>F. periodonticum</i>.</s><s>We have only a very limited amount of information on the incidence of <i>F. periodonticum</i> in the human oral cavity and at non-oral sites.</s><s>Also, the clinical importance of this organism is not known.</s><s>The isolation of <i>F. periodonticum</i> from severe periodontitis lesions in a juvenile diabetes patient, however, may suggest that the organism possesses pathogenic potential.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. periodonticum</i> is EK1-15 [American Type Culture Collection (ATCC) strain 33693].</s></p></content></protolog>