<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8392_nm.13617" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13617" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13617" rank="species">Sphingopyxis ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.8392"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingopyxis ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2342</fpage><lpage>2347</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64431-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842853</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingopyxis ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingopyxis ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, positive for catalase and oxidase, and rod-shaped (0.2–0.3 μm in diameter and 1.0−1.2 μm in length after 4 days culture on R2A agar).</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar plates for 4 days are smooth, circular, non-glossy, yellowish in colour and 1–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–42 °C and pH 5.0–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 5.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically in R2A broth medium supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Xylan, chitin, starch, cellulose and DNA are not degraded.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA and nutrient agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production and other physiological characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>In addition, the following substrates are utilized for growth: d-lyxose, l-xylose, d-fucose, l-rhamnose, propionate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, lactate, adipate, suberate, fumarate, succinate, amygdalin, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-proline and l-tryptophan.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: l-sorbose, d-arabinose, d-ribose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, pyruvate, formate, caprate, maleic acid, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, salicin, citrate, malonate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, oxalate, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, gluconate, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, glycogen, inulin, dextran, l-arginine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and tryptophan deaminase are produced, but not lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or urease.</s><s>Predominant respiratory lipoquinone is Q-10.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (46.4 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (34.6 %); 2-hydroxy fatty acid is also present.</s><s>Major polar lipids are sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and two unknown glycolipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 250<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12582<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23390<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>