<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2454_nm.11362" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11362" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11362" rank="species">Halobacillus campisalis</organism><reference id="rid.2454"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halobacillus campisalis sp. nov., containing meso-diaminopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan, and emended description of the genus Halobacillus</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2021</fpage><lpage>2025</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65188-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766866</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halobacillus campisalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halobacillus campisalis</em> (cam.pi.sa′lis. L. n. <em>campus</em> field; L. gen. n. <em>salis</em> of salt; N.L. gen. n. <em>campisalis</em> of a field of salt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci or oval (0.7–1.4×1.0–1.6 μm) on MA supplemented with 6 % (w/v) NaCl at 37 °C.</s><s>Gram-positive, but Gram-variable in old cultures.</s><s>Colonies are circular, slightly convex, smooth, glistening, light-yellow in colour and 1.5–2.0 mm after 3 days incubation at 37 °C on MA supplemented with 6 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> ions are required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C; growth occurs at 4 and 41 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.0–8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.5 but not at pH 5.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of approximately 8 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs without NaCl and in the presence of 22 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of &#x003E;23 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are present, but lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-cellobiose, d-mannose, trehalose, sucrose and maltose are utilized, but l-arabinose, d-xylose, acetate, citrate, succinate, benzoate, l-malate, pyruvate, salicin, formate and l-glutamate are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, lactose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose and l-rhamnose, but not from l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-ribose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to polymyxin B.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ASL-17<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13144<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 54360<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine solar saltern of the Yellow Sea in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>