<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5385_nm.3668" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3668" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3668" rank="species">Syntrophus aciditrophicus</organism><reference id="rid.5385"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bhupathiraju</surname><given-names>V.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McInerney</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophus aciditrophicus sp. nov., a new anaerobic bacterium that degrades fatty acids and benzoate in syntrophic association with hydrogen-using microorganisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>171</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>114</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050685</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9914307</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophus aciditrophicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophus aciditrophicus</i> (a.ci.di.tro'phi.cus., <i>acidum</i> L. nom. n., acid; <i>trephein</i> Gr.v. to feed; <i>trophicus</i> L. suffix relating to feeding; <i>aciditrophicus</i> M.L.adj. one that feeds on acids, acid-feeding)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, rod-shaped cells with rounded ends, 0.5– 0.7 μm wide and 1.0 x 1.6 μm.</s><s>Cells characteristically appear singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on crotonate medium are white, entire, lens-shaped, and 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth in liquid medium is uniform.</s><s>The temperature range is 25–42 °C, with the fastest growth occurring at 35 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Syntrophic metabolism.</s><s>Fumarate, iron(III), polysulfide, and oxyanions of nitrogen and sulfur do not support the growth of <i>S. aciditrophicus</i> with benzoate as the electron donor.</s><s>The following compounds support growth of <i>S. aciditrophicus</i> in association with a hydrogen/formate-using partner: benzoate, butyrate, hexanoate, heptanoate, octanoate, palmitate, stearate, <i>trans</i>-2-pentenoate, <i>trans</i>-2-hexanoate, <i>trans</i>-3-hexanoate, 2-octenoate, and methyl esters of butyrate and hexanoate.</s><s>Crotonate is the only compound that supports growth of <i>S. aciditrophicus</i> in pure culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds do not support growth in the presence or absence of a hydrogen/formate-using partner: acetoin, formate, propionate, halogenated benzoic acids, hydroxylated benzoic acids, phenols, other aromatic compounds, various organic acids, sugars, amino acids, methyl laurate, methyl myristate, methyl stearate, oxalate, 4-pentenoate, and pimelate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular fatty acids of strain SB<sup>T</sup> include C<sub>18:1</sub> (presumably <i>cis</i>-11; 42.9% of the total fatty acids), C<sub>16:0</sub> (27.0%), <i>cis</i>-9 C<sub>16:1</sub> (19.2%), 3-OH C<sub>16:0</sub> (3.5%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (1.8%), C<sub>14:0</sub> (1.2%), and <i>cis</i>-9 C<sub>18:1</sub> (0.5%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43.1 ± 0.1 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: sewage sludge from a municipal sewage treatment plant in Norman, Oklahoma, USA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SB<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700169.</s></p></content></protolog>