<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5744_nm.1832" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1832" rank="genus">Variovorax</organism><reference id="rid.5744"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comamonadaceae, a new family encompassing the acidovorans rRNA complex, including Variovorax paradoxus gen. nov., comb. nov., for Alcaligenes paradoxus (Davis 1969).</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>445</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-445</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Variovorax</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Variovorax</i> (Va.ri.o'vo.rax. L. adj. <i>varius</i>, various; L. adj. <i>vorax</i>, voracious; M.L. masc. n. <i>Variovorax</i>, [bacteria] devouring a variety [of substrates])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods that are 0.5 to 0.6 by 1.2 to 3.0 μm and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of degenerate peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are yellow because of the presence of carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Some strains are capable of lithoautotrophic growth in which hydrogen is used as an energy source; these strains have been described as biotype I.</s><s>The strains that are unable to use hydrogen have been described as biotype II (6).</s><s>Oxidative carbohydrate metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Good growth is obtained on media containing carbohydrates, organic acids (including amino acids), or peptone.</s><s>The mean G+C contents of the DNAs range from 66.8 to 69.4 mol%.</s><s>In DNA-rRNA hybridizations, <i>Variovorax</i> strains have <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> values of 79.0 to 81.O°C versus rRNA from <i>Variovorax paradoxus</i> ATCC 17713t1<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The genus <i>Variovorax</i> belongs to the <i>Comamonadaceae</i> and is equidistantly related to the other taxa in this family (e.g., the genera <i>Acidovorax</i>, <i>Comamonas</i>, <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, and <i>Xylophilus</i>).</s><s>The only species is <i>Variovorax paradoxus</i> (Davis 1969) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>