<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3830_nm.1266" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1266" rank="genus">Brevundimonas</organism><reference id="rid.3830"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torck</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Pseudomonas diminuta Leifson and Hugh 1954 and Pseudomonas vesicularis Büsing, Döll, and Freytag 1953 in Brevundimonas gen. nov. as Brevundimonas diminuta comb. nov. and Brevundimonas vesicularis comb. nov., respectively.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>499</fpage><lpage>510</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-499</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8068543</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brevundimonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brevundimonas</i> (Brev.un.di'mo.nas. L. adj. <i>brevis</i>, short; L. fem. n. <i>unda</i>, wave; Gr. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; M.L. fem. n. <i>Brevundimonas</i>, bacterium with short-wavelength flagella)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative short rods that are 1 to 4 μm long and 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Motile by means of one polar flagellum that has a short wavelength (0.6 to 1 μm).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Indole is not formed.</s><s>Pantothenate, biotin, and cyanocobalamin are required as growth factors.</s><s>Aerobic with a respiratory type of metabolism (Q1O is an intermediate electron carrier); never fermentative.</s><s>Growth occurs on blood media at 30 and 37°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4°C, and no autotrophic growth occurs with H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is accumulated as reserve material and is not hydrolyzed extracellularly.</s><s>Acid is produced from primary alcohols by all strains that can utilize alcohols.</s><s>Lecithinase (egg yolk) and lipase (Tween 80) are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>The strains exhibit a limited nutritional spectrum; only DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, L-glutamate, and L-proline are used by 90% or more of the strains as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>As determined by MI galleries, the following substrates are used by none of the strains or by at most 10% of the strains (although some of these characteristics are useful for differentiating between named and unnamed strains [Table 3]): glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl-β-xyloside, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl-α-D-mannoside, methyl-α-D-glucose, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, D-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, D-melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, propionate, isobutyrate, heptanoate, <i>n</i>-caproate, caprylate, pelargonate, caprate, oxalate, malonate, maleate, glutarate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, glycolate, D-malate, DL-glycerate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, levulinate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, citrate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, terephthalate, glycine, L-norleucine, DL-2-aminobutyrate, L-cysteine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, trigonelline, L-ornithine, L-lysine, L-citrulline, DL-kynurenine, betaine, creatine, β-alanine, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-4-arninobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, 2-aminobenzoate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, urea, acetamide, sarcosine, ethylamine, butylamine, amylamine, ethanolamine, benzylamine, diaminobutane, spermine, histamine, tryptamine, and glucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition, the following substrates are not used: ethyleneglycol, propyleneglycol, 2,3-butyleneglycol, eicosanedioate, benzoylformate, phenylethanediol, naphthalene, phenol, quinate, testosterone, kynurenate, anthranilate, hippurate, nicotinate, saccharate, mucate, DL-α-aminovalerate, methylamine, <i>n</i>-dodecane, <i>n</i>-hexadecane, methanol, isopropanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, and geraniol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzyme activities are always present, as determined by MI ZYM tests: alkaline and acid phosphatase, ester lipase (C8) (except <i>Brevundimonas</i> sp. strain LMG 9567t1), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, and phosphoamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzyme activities are always absent, as determined by API ZYM tests: lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase (can be used to differentiate the unnamed <i>Brevundimonas</i> sp. [Table 3]), N-acetyl-β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negative reactions are also obtained for lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, and phenylalanine deaminase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus belongs to the a subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>; it constitutes a separate rRNA branch that is equidistant from the rRNA clusters consisting of the family <i>Acetobacteraceae</i>, the genus <i>Rhodobacter</i>, the <i>Rhodospirillum</i>-<i>Azospirillum</i> group, the <i>Bradyrhizobium</i>-<i>Rhodopseudomonas</i> group, the <i>Agrobacterium</i>-<i>Rhizobium</i> group, and the <i>Sphingomonas</i>-<i>Rhizomonas</i> group.</s><s>The closest natural relatives are organisms that are now classified as members of the genus <i>Caulobacter</i>.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced or is rarely reduced.</s><s>All strains are characterized by two major fatty acids, 16:O and 18:1 (summed feature 7) and the following minor components: 12:O 30H, 14:0, 15:0, 16:1, 17:0, 17:1, and an unknown fatty acid with an equivalent chain length of 18.080.</s><s>Isolated from water and clinical specimens.</s><s>The G+C contents range from 65 to 68 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Brevundimonas diminuta</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>