<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12676_nm.5031" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5031" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4996" rank="species">Geobacillus thermoleovorans</organism><reference id="rid.12676"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dinsdale</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halket</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coorevits</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Landschoot</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Geobacillus thermoleovorans and Geobacillus thermocatenulatus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1802</fpage><lpage>1810</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025445-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20817844</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Geobacillus thermoleovorans</em> (Zarilla and Perry 1988) Nazina <em>et al.</em> 2001</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Geobacillus thermoleovorans</em> [ther.mo′le.o.vo′rans. Gr. n. <em>therme</em> heat; L. n. <em>oleum</em> oil; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; N.L. pres. part. <em>thermoleovorans</em> indicating heat-requiring bacteria capable of utilizing oil (hydrocarbons)].</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Bacillus thermoleovorans</em> Zarilla and Perry 1988.</s><s>Effective publication: Zarilla &#x0026; Perry (1987).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, rod-shaped cells, 0.7–1.5×2–6 µm.</s><s>Some strains are peritrichously motile.</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores are borne terminally and subterminally and do not swell the sporangia.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, but growth is weak in the absence of oxygen.</s><s>Colonies are circular, creamy white in colour, with smooth and glossy or rough surfaces, entire or irregular margins, 0.5–5 mm in diameter, following incubation at 60 °C for 18–24 h.</s><s>Grows between 37–40 °C and 65–70 °C, with optimum growth at 60 °C; no growth at 30 or 80 °C.</s><s>Grows sparsely at pH 5 and 9; optimum growth at pH 6–7.</s><s>Tolerates 0.5–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, gelatin is hydrolysed and nitrate is reduced; the ONPG test is variable, the Voges–Proskauer test is variable and weak when positive and citrate utilization (Simmons’), arginine dihydrolase, hydrogen sulfide production, indole production, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease production are negative.</s><s>In the API 50CHB gallery, acid without gas is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, d-mannose and ribose.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from salicin and acid production is variable from cellobiose, galactose, glycogen, mannitol, melezitose (weak when positive), melibiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose (weak when positive), methyl d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, raffinose, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, inulin, 2- or 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, methyl d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are assimilated: cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, lactose, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl β-d-glucopyranoside, palatinose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose; assimilation is variable from aesculin, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-lyxose, 1-<em>O</em>- and 3-<em>O</em>-methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl α-galactopyranoside (weak when positive), 1-<em>O</em>-methyl β-glucopyranoside, raffinose and d-xylose and negative for adonitol, l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, l-fucose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose and xylitol.</s><s>The following organic acids are assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, fumarate, d-gluconate, dl-glycerate, dl-β-hydroxybutyrate (3-hydroxybutyrate), l-malate and succinate; assimilation is variable for 2-keto-d-gluconate (weak when positive), dl-lactate, d-malate (weak when positive), phenylacetate and quinate and negative for <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, 4-aminovalerate, benzoate, caprate, caprylate, citrate, <em>m</em>-coumarate, d-galacturonate, gentisate, d-glucuronate, glutarate, 3- and 4-hydroxybenzoate, itaconate, α-ketoglutarate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, malonate, mucate, 3-phenylpropionate, propionate, protocatechuate, d-saccharate, d-, l- and <em>meso</em>-tartrate and tricarballylate.</s><s>The following amino acids are assimilated: d-glucosamine, l-glutamate and l-histidine; assimilation is variable for d- and l-alanine, histamine (weak when positive), l-proline (weak when positive) and l-serine and negative for l-aspartate, betaine, ethanolamine, putrescine, trigonelline, tryptamine, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain displays the following reactions.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein, negative for ONPG and positive for the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, glycogen, mannitol, melezitose (weakly), melibiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, raffinose, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose; acid is not produced from cellobiose, lactose, methyl d-glucoside or <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of aesculin, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose (weak), 1-<em>O</em>-methyl β-glucopyranoside, raffinose, d-xylose, dl-lactate, phenylacetate, quinate, d- and l-alanine, l-proline and l-serine and negative for assimilation of d-lyxose, 1-<em>O</em>- and 3-<em>O</em>-methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl α-galactopyranoside, 2-keto-d-gluconate, d-malate and histamine.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from pasteurized milk, geothermally heated pools and springs and associated soil, marine sediment of a hydrothermal vent and crude oil.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 52–53 mol% (52.4 mol% for the type strain; HPLC).</s><s>The EMBL/GenBank/DDBJ accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain (DSM 5366<sup>T</sup>) is Z26923.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: LEH-1<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 9823<sup>T</sup>  = ATCC 43513<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 5366<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>