<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3837_nm.2055" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2055" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2055" rank="species">Thauera aromatica</organism><reference id="rid.3837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anders</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaetzke</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuchs</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic position of aromatic-degrading denitrifying pseudomonad strains K 172 and KB 740 and their description as new members of the genera Thauera, as Thauera aromatica sp. nov., and Azoarcus, as Azoarcus evansii sp. nov., respectively, members of the beta subclass of the Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>333</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-327</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537067</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thauera aromatica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thauera aromatica</i> (ar.o.ma' ti.ca. M. L. adj. <i>aromatica</i>, aromatic, because the organism was isolated on media containing aromatic compounds as sole carbon sources)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells are 1.0 to 2.5 μm long and 0.5 to 1.5 μm wide, have rounded ends, and accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Cells are slightly motile.</s><s>Colonies on defined medium containing benzoate are 1 mm in diameter and white after 4 to 5 days of aerobic growth at 28°C.</s><s>No growth or poor growth occurs at 37°C and on complex media.</s><s>Grows aerobically or anaerobically with nitrate on minimal media.</s><s>Cells do not reduce selenate or ferment sugars.</s><s>Many aromatic compounds are used as sole carbon sources under denitrifying conditions.</s><s>The aromatic substrates are metabolized to CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>During growth with aromatic compounds nitrite is an intermediate and is reduced mainly to N<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>No vitamins are required for growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is around 28°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between 7 and 7.4.</s><s>Cells are catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Phylogenetically, <i>T. aromatica</i> is a member of the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>This organism was isolated from anaerobic sludge by using media containing phenol and nitrate.</s><s>The type strain is K 172 (= DSM 6984).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 67 mol% G+C.</s><s>For additional characteristics of the type strain see above and Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>