<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5866_nm.3854" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3854" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3854" rank="species">Helicobacter trogontum</organism><reference id="rid.5866"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mendes</surname><given-names>E.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Queiroz</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moura</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter trogontum sp. nov., isolated from the rat intestine.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>916</fpage><lpage>921</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-916</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863417</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter trogontum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter trogontum</i> (tro-gon'tum. Gr. part. adj. <i>trogon</i>, gnawing; N. L. gen. pl. n. <i>trogontum</i>, of gnawing animals, since the organism was first isolated from rats)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are fusiform to slightly spiral and 0.6 to 0.7 μm wide by 4 to 6 μm long, have periplasmic fibers coiled around the protoplasmic cylinder, and have morphology typical of "<i>F. rappini</i>." In older cultures, coccoid forms with overlapping periplasmic fibers are common.</s><s>Cells are gram negative and nonsporulating.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of tufts consisting of three to seven sheathed flagella at each end.</s><s>Colonies are pinpoint, but cultures often appear to be thin spreading layers on agar media.</s><s>Microaerobic growth occurs at 37 and 42°C but not at 25°C.</s><s>No growth occurs on brucella agar plates containing 1% glycine or 1.5, 2, or 3% NaCl.</s><s>The organisms have catalase, oxidase, urease, gamma-glutamyl transpeptidase, and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, and H<sub>2</sub>S is not detected on lead acetate discs.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase is produced by one of the three strains examined.</s><s>The bacteria are susceptible to metronidazole but resistant to cephalothin and nalidixic acid.</s><s>Cells have been isolated from colonic mucosa of rats.</s><s>The type strain, LRB 8581, was isolated from the colon of a rat.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700114.</s><s>The essentially complete 16s rRNA sequence has been deposited in the GenBank database under accession number U65103.</s></p></content></protolog>