<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6233_nm.1904" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1904" rank="genus">Methylovorus</organism><reference id="rid.6233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Govorukhina</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylovorus, a new genus of restricted facultatively methylotrophic bacteria.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>158</fpage><lpage>162</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-158</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylovorus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylovorus</i> (me.thyl.o.vorus. M.L. n. <i>methyl</i>, the methyl radical; L. adj. <i>vorus</i>, consuming)</s></p><p class="description"><s>When grown on methanol-mineral salt medium, cells are straight or slightly curved rods, usually 0.5 to 0.6 μm in diameter and 1.0 to 1.3 μm in length, which occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Endospores are absent.</s><s>No complex intracellular membranes.</s><s>No sheath or prosthecae detected.</s><s>No capsules formed, but slime may be produced by some strains.</s><s>Colonies on methanol-mineral salt agar incubated for 2 days at 30°C are circular, 1 to 2 mm in diameter, with entire edge, convex, and are translucent to opaque, pink, creamy or milky in color.</s><s>Pyocyanin and fluorescein are not produced.</s><s>Cells multiply by binary fission.</s><s>No aggregation or pigmentation occurs in liquid medium.</s><s>No growth or extremely poor growth occurs on nutrient agar and in nutrient broth at 30 to 37°C; no growth occurs under an atmosphere of CH<sub>4</sub> plus O<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub> plus CO<sub>2</sub> plus O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth, 7.0 to 7.2; temperature, 35 to 37°C.</s><s>Obligate aerobes with respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Methanol and glucose are utilized as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>In addition, some strains are able to grow slowly on methylated amines, inuline, and betaine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates, ammonium salts, methylated amines, glutamate, and peptone serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Acetoin, indole, H<sub>2</sub>S, and NH<sub>3</sub> are not produced in test medium.</s><s>Milk is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urease, catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Peroxidase, variable.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, negative.</s><s>The strains may hydrolyze starch but not cellulose, gelatin, or Tween 80.</s><s>They produce acid (but not gases) from glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All the strains assimilate methanol carbon through the RuMP pathway and ammonia via the glutamate cycle (glutamate synthase and glutamine synthetase).</s><s>Neither α-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase nor the glyoxylate shunt enzymes are present.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is primarily of the nonhydroxylated straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types with C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>16:1ω7</sub>.</s><s>The strains do not contain branched C17 fatty acid.</s><s>The major phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The strains also possess diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>G+C mol% of DNA is 55 to 57%, estimated via melting point (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacteria of this kind have been isolated from activated sludge, mud, soil, and pond water.</s><s>The type species is <i>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>