<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6294_nm.7848" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7848" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7848" rank="species">Clevelandina reticulitermitidis</organism><reference id="rid.6294"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bermudes</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margulis</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Morphology as a basis for taxonomy of large spirochetes symbiotic in wood-eating cockroaches and termites: Pillotina gen. nov., nom. rev.; Pillotina calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx gen. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Hollandina gen. nov., nom.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>302</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clevelandina reticulitermitidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clevelandina reticulitermitidis</i> (re. ti .cu.li. ter.mi. 'ti.dis. M. L. gen. <i>reticulitermitidis</i>, named for the host termite genus <i>Reticulotermes</i>, in which it is found)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells are slightly oblong and 0.52 to 0.61 μm (narrowest point) to 0.67 to 0.73 μm (widest point) in diameter.</s><s>Approximately 45 flagella 17 to 20 nm in diameter are distributed throughout the periplasm.</s><s>The angle subtended by the flagella is 260 to 270°; concavity absent; no flagellar bundle.</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane ranges from 0.0 to 18.6 nm (average, 11.5 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness varies between 0.0 and 2.8 (average, 1.7).</s><s>The inner coat of the outer membrane, which ranges from 25 to 27 nm thick (average, 25.3 nm), forms a chambered appearance in cross section, Chambers vary from 20 to 22 nm wide (average, 21 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness varies from 3.8 to 4.1 (average, 3.9).</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the inner membrane (calyx) varies between 12 and 20 nm (average, 14.6 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the inner membrane to the inner membrane thickness is between 1.8 and 3.8 (average, 2.8).</s><s>The oblong protoplasmic cylinder ranges from 0.34 to 0.42 μm (narrowest point) to 0.42 to 0.53 μm (widest point) in diameter.</s><s>The ratio of the protoplasmic cylinder diameter to the cell diameter varies from 0.66 to 0.73 (average, 0.68).</s><s>The type specimen (Fig. 7A) of <i>Clevelandina reticulitermitidis</i> is from <i>Reticulitermes tibialis</i> from Joshua Tree National Monument, Nev. (this termite was incorrectly identified as <i>Reticulitermes hesperus</i> by Margulis et al. [26]).</s></p></content></protolog>