<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5924_nm.8511" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8511" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7697" rank="subspecies">Bifidobacterium animalis lactis</organism><reference id="rid.5924"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Masco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zink</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomic analysis of Bifidobacterium animalis and Bifidobacterium lactis reveals relatedness at the subspecies level: reclassification of Bifidobacterium animalis as Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. animalis subsp. nov. and Bifidobacterium lactis as Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis subsp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1137</fpage><lpage>1143</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03011-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium animalis</em> subsp. <em>lactis</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Strains display characteristics typical for the species <em>B. animalis</em> as described above. The optimum growth temperature is 39–42 °C. No growth occurs on agar plates exposed to air, but 10 % oxygen in the headspace atmosphere above liquid media is tolerated. Growth occurs in milk or milk-based media. The molar ratio of acetate to lactate from glucose metabolism is about 10 to 1 under anaerobic conditions, e.g. lactate production is replaced by formate production. Strains have been isolated from fermented milk samples, human and infant faeces, rabbit and chicken faeces and from sewage. The DNA G+C content is 61·0±0·5 mol%. Type strain: <em>Bifidobacterium animalis</em> subsp. <em>lactis</em> UR1<sup>T</sup> (LMG 18314<sup>T</sup>=DSM 10140<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10602<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>