<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3606_nm.6484" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6484" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6484" rank="species">Rhodococcus gordoniae</organism><reference id="rid.3606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mishra</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Perry</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus gordoniae sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from clinical material and phenol-contaminated soil</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>407</fpage><lpage>411</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02756-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023952</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodococcus gordoniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodococcus gordoniae</em> (gor.don′i.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>gordoniae</em> of Gordon, named after Ruth Gordon, a celebrated microbial systematist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon information taken from this study and from Spark <em>et al.</em> (1993).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive actinomycete that forms branched filaments that fragment into coccobacillary elements.</s><s>Acid-fast when grown on 7H10 agar and stained using the modified Kinyoun procedure.</s><s>Neither aerial hyphae nor diffusible pigments are formed.</s><s>Produces raised, shiny, pink- to coral-pigmented colonies with filamentous edges on blood and chocolate agar plates incubated at 36 °C.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar supplemented with crystal violet; grows poorly on Lowenstein–Jensen medium with 5 % (w/v) sodium chloride.</s><s>Degrades tyrosine but not casein, hypoxanthine or xanthine.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin weakly and is indole- and urease-negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite and grows in the presence of lysozyme.</s><s>Does not exhibit equi-factors.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, salicin, d-sorbitol, d-sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose, but not from d-cellobiose, inositol, d-maltose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Resistant to clindamycin and norfloxacin but susceptible to amikacin, amoxicillin/clavulinate, ampicillin, ampicillin/sulbactam, cephalothin, cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, ciprofloxacin, doxycycline, erythromycin, gentamicin, imipenem, minocycline, oxacillin, penicillin, rifampicin, sulfamethoxazole, tetracycline, trimethoprin/sulfamethoxazole and vancomycin.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Characterized by the presence of <em>meso</em>-A<sub>2</sub>pm, arabinose and galactose in whole-organism hydrolysates, contains <em>N</em>-glycolated muramic acid residues, predominant proportions of dehydrogenated menaquinones with eight isoprene units and mycolic acids that co-migrate with those of the type strain of <em>R. rhodochrous</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain W 4937<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44689<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13296<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a blood culture of a previously healthy patient who died of pneumonia-associated adult respiratory distress syndrome.</s><s>Strain MTCC 1534 (=DSM 44690), which is clearly very closely related to strain W 4937<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from a markedly different habitat, namely phenol-contaminated soil.</s><s>This organism can degrade phenol as a sole carbon source at very high concentrations (&#x003E;25 mM) in a minimal medium (data not shown).</s></p></content></protolog>