<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.910_nm.3176" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3176" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3176" rank="subspecies">Erwinia carotovora betavasculorum</organism><reference id="rid.910"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thomson</surname><given-names>S.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hildebrand</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schroth</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification and nutritional differentation of the Erwinia sugar beet pathogen from members of Erwinia carotovora and Erwinia chrysanthemi.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>1037</fpage><lpage>1042</lpage><source id="190">Phytopathology</source><issn>0031-949X</issn><essn>1943-7684</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia carotovora betavasculorum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Characteristics of <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i> NCPPB 2795 (designated as the type strain) that agree with those of <i>E. carotovora</i> are as follows: cells are predominantly single; Gram-negative; straight rods with cell sizes ranging from 0.5 to 1.0 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm; endospores are not produced; peritrichous flagella; facultative anaerobic; indole, phosphatase, and pigment not produced; and resistant to erythromycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional properties of <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i> NCPPB 2795 are as follows: growth occurs at 36°C, reducing substances are formed from sucrose, and the DNA base composition is 54.4 mol% G±C.</s><s>Organic substrates utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy include: L-arabinose, D-asparagine, D-aspartate, L-aspartate, cellobiose, ethanol, D-fructose, fumarate, D-galactose, galacturonate, D-glucose, α-methylglucoside, gluconate, α-ketoglutarate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, inosine, inositol, D-lactate, L-lactate, β-lactose, L-malate, mannitol, D-mannose, D-maltose, mucate, palatinose, rhamnose, D-ribose, saccharate, salicin, L-serine, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose, but not <i>cis</i>-aconitate, adipate, adonitol, β-alanine, anthranilate, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, L-arginine, azelate, benzoate, betaine, butyrate, ϒ-amino butyrate, caprate, caproate, caprylate, cellobiose, choline, citraconate, citrate, citronellal, DL-citrulline, creatine, L-cysteine, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, esculin, D-fructose, L-fucose, gallate, geraniol, D-glutamate, glutarate, glycine, glycolate, heptanoate, DL-homocysteine, DL-homoserine, L-isoleucine, isostearate, itaconate, kynurenate, kynurenine, laurate, lauryl alcohol, L-leucine, D-lysine, D-lyxose, malonate, melezitose, melibiose, mesaconate, D-methionine, myristate, nicotinate, D-norvaline, L-norvaline, octanol, oleate, orcinol, oxalate, pelargonate, phenylacetate, L-phenylalanine, phytate, phytol picolinate, pimelate, DL-pipecolate, propionate, propylene glycol, D-quinate, quinolinate, rutin, saligenin, sarcosine, sebacate, D-serine, shikimate, sorbate, sorbitol, L-sorbose, suberate, D-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, L-threonine, trigonelline, valerate, D-valine, L-valine, L-xylose, or xylitol.</s></p></content></protolog>