<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4763_nm.5529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5529" rank="species">Enterococcus canis</organism><reference id="rid.4763"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Graef</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Enterococcus canis sp. nov. from dogs and reclassification of Enterococcus porcinus Teixeira et al. 2001 as a junior synonym of Enterococcus villorum Vancanneyt et al 2001.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1069</fpage><lpage>1074</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02549-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892128</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus canis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus canis</em> (ca′nis. L. gen. n. <em>canis</em> of a dog).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, facultatively anaerobic, Gram-positive, slightly elongated cocci that occur in pairs, short chains or small groups.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are circular, smooth and surrounded by narrow, sharply demarcated zones of <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 37 °C, slower at 42, 30 and 25 °C and unaffected by the absence or presence of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Strains grow in 6·5 % NaCl broth.</s><s>On Edward's <em>Streptococcus</em> selective medium, brownish aesculin-degrading colonies are formed.</s><s>No growth is seen after 1 day on Slanetz–Bartley medium, but after 2 days, pinpoint-sized colonies are formed without any evidence of tetrazoliumchloride reduction.</s><s>Abundant growth and blackening are observed in aesculin bile agar.</s><s>Starch is not digested.</s><s>Positive results are obtained in API tests for leucine arylamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase (hydrolysis of l-pyrroglutamic acid-AMC in Crystal, with some weak reactions) and in the following Crystal reactions: hydrolysis of l-valine-AMC, l-phenylalanine-AMC, 4MU-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-tryptophan-AMC, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-cellobioside.</s><s>Acid is produced in the API 20 STREP and/or API 50 CH kits in tests with glycerol (often delayed), l-arabinose, ribose, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate (often weak).</s><s>Most strains react positively in tests with <em>α</em>-methyl-d-glucoside (10/13 strains), d-arabinose (11/13 strains) and d-xylose (8/13 strains).</s><s>Few strains are positive for acid production from sucrose (2/13 positive), trehalose (1/13 positive) and starch (4/13 strains with weak reactions).</s><s>Strain- or method-dependent reactions are observed with arginine (negative in API 20 STREP and Rosco; 6/13 strains positive in Crystal galleries) and VP (negative in API 20 STREP, 2/13 strains positive with Rosco tablets).</s><s>Strains are negative in API tests for hippurate, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and alkaline phosphatase, and in Crystal tests for hydrolysis of l-valine-AMC, 4MU-phosphate, 4MU-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, l-isoleucine-AMC and urease.</s><s>Acid is produced from erythritol, l-xylose, adonitol, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-mannoside, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d- and l-fucose, d-tagatose, d- and l-arabitol and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41·7–43·0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 12316<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46666<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from anal swabs and chronic otitis externa in dogs.</s></p></content></protolog>