<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6106_nm.9498" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9498" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9498" rank="species">Rhodococcus triatomae</organism><reference id="rid.6106"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus triatomae sp. nov., isolated from a blood-sucking bug</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1575</fpage><lpage>1579</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63571-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014484</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodococcus triatomae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodococcus triatomae</em> (tri.a.to′mae. N.L. gen. n. <em>triatomae</em> of <em>Triatoma</em>, a zoological genus of blood-sucking bug from which the micro-organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces white to creamy colonies with slightly irregular edges on Columbia blood agar.</s><s>In the early growth phase, the cells are thin and filamentous, showing elementary branching.</s><s>At a later stage of growth, the filaments fragment into rod- to coccoid-shaped elements characteristic of the genus <em>Rhodococcus</em>.</s><s>The filaments as well as the rod- or coccoid-shaped elements stain Gram-positive and are slightly acid–alcohol-fast.</s><s>Grows at temperatures in the range 22–42 °C.</s><s>Has the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of <em>Rhodococcus</em>.</s><s>Upon pyrolysis, its mycolic acids release fatty acids C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> as the major cleavage products.</s><s>The fatty acid profile mainly consists of straight-chain saturated, unsaturated and 10-methyl-branched fatty acids.</s><s>Hydrolyses adenine and testosterone, but not casein, elastin, aesculin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, citrate and glucose, but not adonitol, adipate, isoamyl alcohol, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, cellobiose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, galactose, gluconate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, myo-inositol, lactate, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, 1,2-propanediol, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, sorbitol, trehalose or xylose, as carbon sources for energy.</s><s>Utilizes acetamide, but not alanine, gelatin, proline, serine, ornithine or arginine, as simultaneous carbon and nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IMMIB RIV-085<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50202<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44892<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>A reference strain is IMMIB RIV-095 (=CCUG 50203=DSM 44893).</s></p></content></protolog>