<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8226_nm.13641" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13641" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13641" rank="species">Streptomyces lunalinharesii</organism><reference id="rid.8226"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de Souza</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coelho</surname><given-names>R.R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macrae</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soares</surname><given-names>R.M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa Morato Nery</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Azevedo Soares Semêdo</surname><given-names>L.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alviano</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomes</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces lunalinharesii sp. nov., a chitinolytic streptomycete isolated from cerrado soil in Brazil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2774</fpage><lpage>2778</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65768-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces lunalinharesii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces lunalinharesii</em> (lu′na.lin.ha′re.si.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>lunalinharesii</em> of Luna Linhares, named after Luiz Fernando de Toledo Luna Linhares, a Brazilian soil microbiologist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>An aerobic, Gram-positive, chitinolytic actinomycete that forms a grey-coloured aerial mycelium and yellow–brown substrate mycelium and presents spiny spores in spiral chains.</s><s>The colour of the substrate mycelium is not pH-sensitive and results from the production of a yellow–brown diffusible pigment the colour of which is also not pH-sensitive.</s><s>Cell-wall hydrolysates contain ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant amino acids in the cell-wall hydrolysate are alanine and glycine, followed by glutamic acid, leucine, threonine, methionine and lysine.</s><s>Very good growth occurs on yeast extract/malt extract agar and on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Antimicrobial activity is exhibited against <em>Aspergillus niger</em> and <em>Candida albicans</em> but is not observed against <em>Kocuria rhizophila</em>, <em>Streptomyces murinus</em>, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> or <em>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</em>.</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin, methacyclin hydrochloride, ampicillin sodium salt, cycloheximide, streptomycin sulfate (all at 100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and penicillin G sodium salt (10 IU ml<sup>−1</sup>) and degrades keratin, l-tyrosine, hypoxanthine, allantoin, casein, elastin, gelatin and starch.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and hence serves as the type strain description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RCQ1071<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1231<sup>T</sup> =CIP 108852<sup>T</sup> =DSM 41876<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an acid orthic ferralsol from central Brazil under cerrado vegetation.</s></p></content></protolog>