<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7612_nm.14043" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14043" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14043" rank="species">Emticicia ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.7612"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>F.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emticicia ginsengisoli sp. nov., a species of the family ‘Flexibacteraceae’ isolated from soil of a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1100</fpage><lpage>1105</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65386-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450696</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Emticicia ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Emticicia ginsengisoli</em> (gin.seng.i.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil from a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, rod-shaped, 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter and 3–5 μm in length.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 4 and 30 °C, with optimum growth at 20–25 °C.</s><s>The pH growth range is between pH 5.0 and 8.5, with an optimum between pH 6.5 and 7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 1.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not with 2.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs on LB agar, MacConkey agar or TSIA, but can occur on R2A, NA, TSA, MHA, R3A, 1/100 LB agar, 1/100 NA, 1/100 MacConkey agar, 1/100 TSA, 1/100 TSIA, 1/10 MHA and 1/100 MHA.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive and reduces nitrate and nitrite under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of DNA, casein, collagen, chitin, starch, CM-cellulose, xylan and aesculin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: l-xylose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose and inulin.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-xylose, d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, cellobiose, pyruvate, formate, acetate, propionate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, capric acid, malate, fumarate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, gluconate, dulcitol, inositol, d-adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methanol, glycerol, salicin, amygdalin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, dextran, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive results are obtained in the Voges–Proskauer test and for gelatinase activity, but negative results are obtained for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulphide production and indole production.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (20 μg), lincomycin (5 μg), neomycin (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (20 U), streptomycin (5 μg) and tetracycline (1 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 40.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 085<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12588<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23396<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>