<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10761_nm.17856" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17856" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17856" rank="species">Corynebacterium mustelae</organism><reference id="rid.10761"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frodl</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium mustelae  sp. nov., isolated from a ferret with lethal sepsis</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>871</fpage><lpage>873</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010942-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661496</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium mustelae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium mustelae</em> (mus.tel′ae. L. n. <em>mustela</em> a weasel, and also a scientific zoological genus name; L. gen. <em>mustelae</em> of a weasel, of <em>Mustela</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a ferret, <em>Mustela putorius furo</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-spore-forming, typically club-shaped rods that occur as single cells, in pairs or in small clusters.</s><s>Colonies are greenish beige, with irregular edges, up to 1–2 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation and express a characteristic ‘humid cellar’-like odour.</s><s>Non-lipophilic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from ribose, glucose, fructose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, gentiobiose, tagatose, l-fucose and 5-ketogluconate, but not from glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, galactose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, lyxose, d-fucose, arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Activity of the following enzymes is detected: pyrazinamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, aesculinase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine and cystine arylamidases and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Activity of the following enzymes is not detected: nitrate reductase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, urease, alkaline and acid phosphatases, lipase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The Christie–Atkins–Munch-Petersen (CAMP) reaction is negative.</s><s>The cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and mycolic acids are also present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; the predominant unsaturated fatty acid is oleic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 3105<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 57279<sup>T</sup> =DSM 45274<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from necropsy lung tissue of a ferret with lethal sepsis.</s></p></content></protolog>