<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2907_nm.7298" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7298" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7298" rank="species">Streptomyces thermocoprophilus</organism><reference id="rid.2907"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Al-Tai</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Somasundaram</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces thermocoprophilus sp. nov., a cellulase-free endo-xylanase-producing streptomycete.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>505</fpage><lpage>509</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758853</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces thermocoprophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces thermocoprophilus</i> (ther.mo.co.pro.phi'lus. Gr. n. <i>therme</i> heat; Gr. n. <i>copro</i> dung; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>thermocoprophilus</i> dung-loving thermophile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, moderately thermophilic actinomycete which forms a highly branched substrate mycelium and aerial hyphae which differentiate into long chains of straight spores which are cylindrical and have smooth surfaces (1.1~1.7x0.5 μm).</s><s>The aerial spore mass colour is grey.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are formed on some standard media such as inorganic salts starch agar.</s><s>Melanin pigments are produced on peptone iron and tyrosine agars.</s><s>Casein, starch, xanthine and xylan are degraded but not adenine.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth but not carboxymethylcellulose, D-raffinose, starch or sucrose.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 50 °C and in the presence of ampicillin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), erythromycin (15 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and sodium chloride (7%, w/v) but not at 10 or 55°C.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gentamicin sulphate (15 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), kanamycin sulphate (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), neomycin sulphate (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and tetracycline hydrochloride (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Antimicrobial activity is shown against <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> NCIB 3610 but not towards <i>Escherichia coli</i> NCIB 9132 or <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> ATCC 12600, or against representative strains of <i>Candida albicans</i>, <i>Curvularia lunata</i>, <i>Pestalotiopsis gnepini</i>, <i>Pyricularia oryzae</i> and <i>Trichoderma viride</i>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 68.6 mol%.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a sample of poultry faeces collected from the poultry farm at the University of Malaya.</s><s>The type strain is B19<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41700<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is also evident from the phylogenetic tree that <i>S. thermogriseus</i> Y-14046<sup>T</sup> and <i>S. thermovulgaris</i> DSM 40444<sup>T</sup> are closely related.</s><s>These strains show a similarity of 99.5%, which corresponds to seven differences out of 1445 nucleotides.</s><s>However, all of the differences occur in the conserved regions of the 16S rDNA.</s><s>Further comparative studies are needed to determine the relationship between these two strains.</s></p></content></protolog>