<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.23_nm.11830" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11830" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3378" rank="species">Pasteurella bettii</organism><reference id="rid.23"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stevens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus rossii sp. nov., Actinobacillus seminis sp. nov., nom. rev., Pasteurella bettii sp. nov., Pasteurella lymphangitidis sp. nov., Pasteurella mairi sp. nov., and Pasteurella trehalosi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella bettii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella bettii</i> (betti'i. M.L. gen. n. <i>bettii</i>, of Bett, named for a gentleman named Bett [Catalog of Strains, 8th ed., American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., 19681, whose identity has not been traced)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenon 13 of Sneath and Stevens (46); “<i>Pasteurella</i> sp. <i>bettii</i>” of Kilian et al. (22), Cells are small nonmotile bacilli and coccobacilli that are often &#x003C;1 μm long.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic and facultatively anaerobic, mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on sheep blood agar are round, greyish, semitransparent, about 2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C, and without hemolysis but sometimes with greening of the erythrocytes.</s><s>Notable for fermenting carbohydrates slowly and weakly, for not acidifying galactose, and for giving negative oxidase and urease reactions (46).</s><s>Other properties are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human Bartholin gland abscesses and human finger infections (Catalog of Strains, 8th ed., American Type Culture Collection).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypically similar to <i>P. ureae</i> and <i>A. actinomycetemcomitans</i> (46).</s><s>DNA-DNA pairing values of 20 to 40% have been reported to a number of <i>Pasteurella</i> species and to <i>Haemophilus parainfluenzae</i> (28, 33, but values of less than 10% have been reported to <i>P. ureae</i> and species of the genus <i>Actinobacillus</i>(13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 38.6 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method) (28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 10535 (= ATCC 23273 = CDC 41-5568 = A99 and A271 = 50) (28, 46).</s><s>In our hands this strain was positive for the tests marked d in Table 2, except for acid production from maltose.</s></p></content></protolog>