<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9166_nm.14366" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14366" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14366" rank="species">Sphingomonas aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.9166"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from tidal flat sediment.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1359</fpage><lpage>1363</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65528-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502316</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas aestuarii</em> (a.es.tu.a′ri.i. L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of a tidal flat).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped, forming yellow, round colonies with a diameter of 1.0 mm after 2 days incubation on R2A agar plates at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth also occurs on TSA, LA, MA and NA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl and 20–35 °C, with optimal growth occurring at 0 % (w/v) NaCl and 30 °C.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, indole is not produced and glucose fermentation does not occur.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive and arginine dihydrolase- and urease-negative.</s><s>Gelatin hydrolysis occurs, but starch hydrolysis does not.</s><s>According to the API 20NE and API 50CH systems, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, starch, gentiobiose, turanose and 5-ketogluconate are assimilated, but glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid are not assimilated.</s><s>Assays using the API ZYM system demonstrated activities for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>In contrast, lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities were not observed.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 11-Me-C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Also present are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH, summed feature 3 (containing C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The polar lipid fraction consists of DPG, PC, PDE, PE, PG, SGL and PL.</s><s>The polyamine pattern contains the predominant compound <em>sym</em>-homospermidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is K4<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22050<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19475<sup>T</sup>), isolated from tidal flat sediment in Yeosu (3 ° 47′ 26″ N 12 ° 34′ 01″ E), Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>