<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3838_nm.3118" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3118" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3118" rank="species">Buttiauxella brennerae</organism><reference id="rid.3838"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>M체ller</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>K채mpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Buttiauxella agrestis with recognition of six new species of Buttiauxella and two new species of Kluyvera: Buttiauxella ferragutiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella gaviniae sp. nov., Buttiauxella brennerae sp. nov., Buttiauxella izardii sp. nov., Buttiauxella noackiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella warmboldiae sp. nov., Kluyvera cochleae sp. nov., and Kluyvera georgiana sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>50</fpage><lpage>63</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-50</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11534554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Buttiauxella brennerae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Buttiauxella brennerae</i> (bren'ner.ae. M. L. fem. gen. n. <i>brennerae</i> of Brenner, in honor of Frances W. Hickman-Brenner, an American microbiologist, for her contributions to the study of many genera of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> [4, 9, 10, 16], including the description of the genus <i>Kluyvera</i> [II]) is referred to as DNA hybridization group 4 in this study. Biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 2. Tests that can be used to differentiate <i>B. brennerae</i> from other <i>Buttiauxella</i> species are the arabinose, arginine dihydrolase, fucose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, 5-ketogluconate, lysine decarboqlase, and malonate tests. Isolated from mollusks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain. <i>B. brennerae</i> type strain S1/6-571 (= ATCC 51605 = DSM 9396 = serial no. 145) was isolated from a snail sampled in Braunschweig, Germany.</s><s>Its colonies are circular, convex, greyish, and smooth on nutrient agar and blood agar.</s><s>They are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 1 day and 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 2 days.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 to 36째C, and no growth occurs at 42째C.</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics given for the genus in Table 7 and for the species in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>