<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.52_nm.8370" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8370" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8370" rank="species">Fusobacterium ulcerans</organism><reference id="rid.52"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Adriaans</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium ulcerans sp. nov. from tropical ulcers</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>447</fpage><lpage>448</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium ulcerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium ulcerans</i> (ul' ce. rans. L. part. adj. <i>ulcerans</i>, making sore, causing to ulcerate, referring to the source of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial and cellular morphology. <i>Fusobacterium ulcerans</i> is a gram-negative, nonsporing, obligately anaerobic, rod-shaped organism 0.5 to 4.5 μm long.</s><s>Most of the strains consist of long cells with pointed ends; type strain NCTC 12111 is 0.5 to 3 μm long and 0.3 μm wide.</s><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates are 2 to 3 mm in diameter, circular, entire, domed to low convex, cream colored, and nonhemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A second morphological type, represented by strain NCTC 12112, is also a gram-negative, pleomorphic, pointed, rod-shaped organism that is 0.8 to 4.5 μm long and 0.2 μm wide and has a large round swelling (diameter, 0.5 μm) in the center of each cell.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar plates are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, and low convex.</s><s>They are translucent or white in color, butyrous, and nonhemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are uniformly gram negative.</s><s>They are nonmotile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 37°C, with colonies appearing in 36 to 48 h.</s><s>Cultures in brain heart infusion broth produce generalized turbidity after incubation for 3 to 4 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chromatographic and biochemical results.</s><s>Fermentation of peptone-yeast-glucose (PYG) broth produces large amounts of butyric acid and small to moderate amounts of acetic, propionic, lactic, and succinic acids.</s><s>These chromatographic findings suggest that these bacteria belong to the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i>.</s><s>All strains convert threonine to propionic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both colonial types produce large amounts of gas when a suspension of a test organism is grown in deep culture in freshly prepared fastidious anaerobe agar (Lab M, Salford, Manchester, England).</s><s>After 24 to 36 h of incubation in air, gas bubbles disrupt the agar.</s><s>No H<sub>2</sub>S is detected.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose by all of the strains, and strain NCTC 12112 ferments glucose and mannose.</s><s>No acid is produced from fructose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, arabinose, raffinose, or rhamnose.</s><s>Indole, catalase, lecithinase, urease, lipase, and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Esculin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced by all of the strains.</s><s>No digestion of gelatin or chopped meat occurs.</s><s>A comparison of these results with results for other <i>Fusobacterium</i> species which <i>F. ulcerans</i> closely resembles is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin (2 U/ml) and phosphamycin (300 μg/disk) and are resistant to rifampin (7.5 μg/disk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the deoxyribonucleic acids are 29.2 mol% for strain NCTC 12111<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) and 29.5 mol% for strain NCTC 12112.</s><s>The soluble cellular proteins are identical for strain NCTC 12111<sup>T</sup> and strain NCTC 12112 but differ from the soluble cellular protein of other species of <i>Fusobacterium</i> (1) (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pleomorphic, anaerobic, gram-negative rods isolated from ulcers fulfill the criteria for membership in the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i>.</s><s>However, the ulcer isolates differed from previously described species in several ways.</s><s>First, the colonial morphology suggests that they resemble <i>Fusobacterium varium</i> (first group) or <i>F. mortiferum</i> (second group).</s><s>However, based on Gram staining, the cellular morphology clearly differs.</s><s>Second, the biochemical results differ from those for species with similar biochemical reactions (for instance, <i>Fusobacterium necrogenes</i>).</s><s>Finally, the soluble cellular proteins differ from those of previously described species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ultrastructural features of the ulcer isolates and the fusobacteria observed in the skin biopsies were very similar (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although there was some variation in the morphology and biochemical characteristics of our isolates, we believe that these bacteria belong to a new species of <i>Fusobacterium</i>.</s><s>Therefore, we propose the name <i>Fusobacterium ulcerans</i>, with type strain NCTC 12111.</s></p></content></protolog>