<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6322_nm.11451" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11451" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11451" rank="species">Salimicrobium luteum</organism><reference id="rid.6322"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Marinococcus albus Hao et al. 1985 as Salimicrobium album gen. nov., comb. nov. and Bacillus halophilus Ventosa et al. 1990 as Salimicrobium halophilum comb. nov., and description of Salimicrobium luteum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2406</fpage><lpage>2411</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65003-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911318</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salimicrobium luteum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salimicrobium luteum</em> (lu′te.um. L. neut. adj. <em>luteum</em> yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci (0.7–2.4 μm).</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular to slightly irregular, raised, smooth, glistening, yellow and 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 37 °C on 8 % NaCl MA.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C; growth occurs at 10 and 44 °C, but not at 4 and 45 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5–8.0; growth occurs at pH 6.5, but not at pH 6.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 10 % (w/v) NaCl; growth does not occur in the presence of &#x003C;2 % (w/v) NaCl and &#x003E;27 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions on 8 % NaCl MA, with or without nitrate.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, xanthine and l-tyrosine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are present, but lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Pyruvate is utilized as a sole carbon and energy source, but l-arabinose, d-xylose, acetate, citrate, succinate, benzoate, l-malate, formate and l-glutamate are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-mannose and d-ribose, but not from d-cellobiose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, <em>myo</em>-inositol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Susceptible to penicillin G, chloramphenicol, ampicillin, cephalothin, novobiocin, kanamycin, lincomycin, oleandomycin and carbenicillin, but not to polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, tetracycline or neomycin.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 47.9 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BY-5<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 3989<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108918<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine solar saltern in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>