<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4659_nm.7356" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7356" rank="genus">Kitasatospora</organism><reference id="rid.4659"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ōmura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kitasatosporia, a new genus of the order Actinomycetales.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>1013</fpage><lpage>1019</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7142001</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kitasatosporia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kitasatosporia</i> (Ki.ta.sa.to.so'ri.a: Kitasatoa, Japanese bacteriologist; Gr.n. <i>sporus</i> a seed; M. L. frem. n. <i>sporia</i> spore)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The salient characteristics of <i>Kitasatosporia</i> gen. nov. and of <i>K. setalba</i> sp. nov. are as follows: colony, ivory and leathery; fragmentation of vegetative mycelia, none; morphology of aeroal mycelia, Rectus-flexibilis; aerial mass color, white to gray; spore chains, more than 20 spores(0.7×0.8～1.6μm) per chain formed from aerial mycelia; sporangium and zoospore, none; cell wall type, a new type con. taining LL-DAP, <i>meso</i>-DAP, glycine and galactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain KM-6054 is well developed on both synthetic and complex media.</s><s>No fragmentation of the vegetative mycelium is observed(Plate 1).</s><s>The aerial mycelium, which has more than 20 spores per chain, is classified in the section Rectus-flexible (Plate 2).</s><s>The spores are cylindrical shape and O.7× 0.8～1.6μmin size.</s><s>The spore surface is smooth with some wrinkled forms.</s><s>Sporangia, zoospores and sclerotia are not observed.</s><s>The colony of strain KM-6054 is leathery.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural and Physiological Characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cultural characteristics of strain KM-6054 are shown in Table 1.</s><s>White or light gray aerial mycelium is formed on yeast extract-malt extract agar, oatmeal agar, inorganic salts-starch agar and glucose-asparagine agar.</s><s>However, the strain does not form aerial mycelium on glucose-peptone agar and nutrient agar.</s><s>It produces a small amount of yellow soluble pigment in inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Physiological characteristics and utilization of carbon sources of strain KM-6054 are shown in Tables 2 and 3, respectively.</s><s>Melanin is not produced, Both peptonization and coagulation of milk are positive.</s><s>The culture grows at 22～37°C.</s><s>The strain utilizes D-glucose, L-arabinose and D-xylose</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemical Analyses</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall was found to contain similar amounts of LL-and <i>meso</i>-DAP, glycine and galactose.</s><s>These analytical data indicate that there is no known genus in which strain KM-6054 should be classified.</s><s>From the analysis of phospholipids,the strain belongs to PII type.</s><s>The glycolate test was negative.</s><s>Staining Reactions The mycelium grown under submerged conditions was Gram-positive and was not acid-fast.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptibility to Antibiotics</s></p><p class="description"><s>The susceptibility was evaluated by MICs.</s><s>Strain KM-6054 is sensitive to streptomycin(5μg/ml), penicillin G (5μg/ml) and chloranlphenicol(10 μg/ml).</s><s>It is resistant to colistin (&#x003E;100μg/ml) and nystatin(&#x003E; 100μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>NaCl Tolerance</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract-malt extract agar medium was used for NaCl tolerance test.</s><s>The strain grows on the agar medium containing less than 2% Na.</s><s>No growth was observed at the concentration of 3%.</s><s>Type Strain The type strain is <i>K. setalba</i> KM-6054(American Type Culture Collection 33774).</s><s>Because the species description is based on a single strain(type strain), the species description given here also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>