<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1318_nm.7687" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7687" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7687" rank="species">Bifidobacterium coryneforme</organism><reference id="rid.1318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Electrophoretic patterns of proteins in the genus Bifidobacterium and proposal of four new species.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium coryneforme</i> (ex Scardovi and Trovatelli 1969) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium coryneforme</i> (cor.v.ne.for'me. Gr. n. <i>coryne</i> a club; L. n. <i>forma</i> shape, form; M.L. adj. <i>coryneformis</i> club shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain in prereduced anaerobically sterilized peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth are 0.7-to 1.2-μm by 0.9- to 3.0-+m, coccoid, oval, or club-shaped rods that occur singly, in pairs, and in clumps.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h at 37°C are punctiform to 1 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, translucent to semiopaque, grayish white, shiny, and smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in broth with a fermentable carbohydrate produces dense turbidity with a smooth or “cottony” sediment and a final pH of 4.3 to 5.3.</s><s>Slight turbidity and a small amount of sediment are produced in peptone-yeast extract broth that does not contain a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Other characteristics of the type strain and other strains of this species are given in Tables 1</s></p><p class="description"><s>through 3 and 5, in Fig. 10 and 13, and by Scardovi and Trovatelli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 25911, was isolated from the intestine of a bee.</s></p></content></protolog>