<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.77_nm.2739" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2739" rank="genus">Rhizobacter</organism><reference id="rid.77"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuwata</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobacter daucus gen. nov., sp. nov., the causal agent of carrot bacterial gall.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>233</fpage><lpage>239</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-233</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Rhizobacter gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(Rhi.zo.bacter. <i>rhizo</i>, root system; <i>bacter</i>, a rod; <i>Rhizobacter</i>, root rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight to slightly curved, nonsporeforming, encapsulated, gram-negative rods.</s><s>Motile with polar flagella or lateral flagella or both.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules are formed.</s><s>Chemoorganolrophic.</s><s>Aerobic with respiratory metabolism of glucose.</s><s>Utilizes D-glucose as a sole source of carbon and energy.</s><s>White or yellowish white, plicated, tough or viscid colonies on agar plates.</s><s>Floccular growth consisting of globular units iin liquid media; fingerlike projections never occur.</s><s>Positive for production of oxidase, catalase, and H<sub>2</sub>S from cysteine, nitrate reduction, the <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside test, and growth inhibition by KCN.</s><s>Negative for denitrification, the methyl red test, and production of arginine dihydrolase, nitrogenase, fluorescent pigment, indole, and acetoin.</s><s>Susceptible to 10 μg of vibriostatic agent O/129 phosphate.</s><s>Hydrolyzes starch, dextrin, and glycogen.</s><s>Cannot utilize benzene derivatives as carbon sources.</s><s>Does not require NaCl and growth factor.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q8.</s><s>Yellow pigment differs from xanthomonadins.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67 to 71 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhizobacter daucus</i> Goto et Kuwata 1988.</s></p></content></protolog>