<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6866_nm.2258" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2258" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2258" rank="species">Stenotrophomonas africana</organism><reference id="rid.6866"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Drancourt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bollet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stenotrophomonas africana sp. nov., an opportunistic human pathogen in Africa.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995819</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stenotrophomonas africana</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stenotrophomonas africana</i> (a. fri. ca' na. L. adj. <i>aficana</i>, from Africa, the continent where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Stenotrophomonas africana</i> is a curved, gram-negative, nonsporulating bacterium whose cells are typically 0.5 pm wide and 1.5 pm long.</s><s>It is motile by means of two polar flagella.</s><s>Tests for oxidase and indole are negative, but catalase is present.</s><s>It forms grey to green colonies lacking an ammonia odor.</s><s>The biochemical pattern is identical to that of <i>Stenotrophomonas maltophilia</i>, except for the lack of assimilation of <i>cis</i>-aconitate.</s><s>Antibiotic susceptibility is restricted to netilmicin, ciprofloxacin, trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole and colimycin.</s><s>A total of 24 of 1,377 16s rDNA base positions determined are different from those of <i>Stenotrophomonas maltophilia</i>, and the level of DNA hybridization between the species is 35 %. <i>Stenotrophomonas africana</i> has been isolated once from the CSF of an African patient who tested positive for HIV antibodies and exhibited primary meningoencephalitis.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Stenotrophomonas africana</i> is strain MGB, which has been deposited in the Collection de I'Institut Pasteur, Paris, France, as strain 10-48-54.</s></p></content></protolog>