<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.156_nm.4442" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4442" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4442" rank="species">Succiniclasticum ruminis</organism><reference id="rid.156"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Succiniclasticum ruminis gen. nov., sp. nov., a ruminal bacterium converting succinate to propionate as the sole energy-yielding mechanism.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-297</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537062</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Succiniclasticum ruminis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Succiniclasticum ruminis</i> (ru'mi.nis. L. neut. gen. n. <i>ruminis</i>, of the rumen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative and non-motile, do not produce spores, and are short rods which are 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide and up to 1.8 μm long (Fig. 2).</s><s>The thicker rods tend to have rounded ends, while the narrower ones often have one end, or occasionally both ends, somewhat tapered and can be slightly curved.</s><s>Large clumps of cells are often observed in liquid media or in the water of syneresis of cultures grown on agar slopes.</s><s>These clumps are easily dispersed by shaking.</s><s>After incubation on rumen fluid-succinate agar slopes for about 18 h, surface colonies have diameters of up to 0.5 mm.</s><s>They are somewhat irregularly round with smooth edges, convex, practically colorless, and slightly opaque with a glistening appearance.</s><s>Submerged colonies that develop after inoculation into molten agar are lens-shaped discs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>The following substrates do not support growth: glucose, galactose, mannose, rhamnose, fructose, xylose, arabinose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, mannitol, glycerol, aspartic acid, the sodium salts of DL-lactic and pyruvic acids, the disodium salts of oxalic, malonic, oxaloacetic, malic, fumaric, glutaric, and methylmalonic acids, the trisodium salts of citric and trans-aconitic acids, and yeast extract (which contains amino acids).</s><s>Prolonged incubation (9 days) with fumarate, malate, aspartate, citrate, or <i>trans</i>-aconitate does not induce utilization.</s><s>When acetate and butyrate are present in the rumen fluid of the medium, they are not assimilated to a measurable extent.</s><s>Succinate is the only substrate tested that is fermented.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 40 mM succinate plus 10 mM fumarate gives about the same maximal optical density as growth in the presence of succinate alone, but the maximal value is reached 1 to 2 h later.</s><s>Very little growth occurs in medium containing 40 mM succinate and 40 mM fumarate.</s><s>There is very little growth in medium from which either rumen fluid or yeast extract is omitted (Fig. 3).</s><s>Succinate concentrations of 40, 70, and 100 mM result in progressively slower growth, but the final optical densities are correspondingly higher.</s><s>Succinate is converted quantitatively to propionate, and no other end products are detected.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> is probably released, but CO<sub>2</sub> release has not been measured.</s><s>Growth in medium from which CO<sub>2</sub> and NaHCO<sub>2</sub> are omitted (poorly buffered medium with NaCl added) is appreciably less (the optical density is one-half as great) and slower than growth in medium containing CO<sub>2</sub> and NaHCO<sub>2</sub> (well-buffered medium).</s><s>This could be due to pH.</s><s>In well-buffered medium, which contains 40 mM succinate, the pH increases about 0.1 U, while the pH increases about 0.5 U in poorly buffered medium after growth has ceased.</s><s>Growth in medium prepared under anoxic conditions is about the same irrespective of whether a reducing agent (cysteine or sulfide) is added.</s><s>However, when air is added to medium without a reducing agent, little growth occurs.</s><s>At 39°C the maximum optical density is about twice the optical density at 45°C after about the same period of incubation.</s><s>There is no growth at 22°C.</s><s>Tween 80 has no effect on growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characterization tests and G+C content.</s><s>Strain SE 10<sup>T</sup> is not proteolytic; it neither liquefies gelatin nor hydrolyzes casein, and it does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Propionate is not formed from threonine.</s><s>It does not produce catalase or urease or reduce nitrate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 52 mol% (values for three separate determinations: 51.1, 52.0, and 52.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SE 10 is the type strain and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen</s></p><p class="description"><s>as strain DSM 9236.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolation of other strains.</s><s>Following the characterization of the unusual bacterium described above, I isolated bacteria having similar properties from the rumina of cows fed production diets containing silage or cows on pasture (16).</s><s>I concluded that this organism is common in the rumen biota.</s><s>Two of these bacterial strains are being characterized now.</s><s>One of them was isolated from rumen ingesta (2 X 10<sup>-7</sup> dilution) from a silage-fed cow different from the cow from which SE 10<sup>T</sup> was isolated, while the other was isolated from a cow (10<sup>-8</sup> dilution of ingesta) on pasture supplemented with concentrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Role in rumen digestion.</s><s>The relevance of <i>Succiniclasticum ruminis</i> clearly lies in the fact that this organism specializes in fermenting succinate and converting it quantitatively to propionate, the most important precursor of glucose in ruminants.</s><s>The low energy yield when anaerobes convert succinate to propionate (14) should make this bacterium highly efficient in this conversion (there is a high rate of substrate turnover for a low rate of cell growth).</s><s>Despite this, <i>Succiniclasticum ruminis</i> appears to occur in high numbers (at least 10<sup>8</sup> cells per g of ingesta) in the rumina of cows fed production diets containing grass silage (and usually about an equal amount of concentrate on a dry matter basis) as the main roughage source and in the rumina of cows on pasture.</s><s>This implies that the growth rate of this organism is high enough so that the organism can compete successfully for essential growth factors and may depend on limited competition for succinate from other bacteria.</s><s>The level of succinate production in the rumina of cows fed grass silage diets is probably high because the level of <i>Prevotella ruminicola</i>, a succinate producer, tends to be greater than 50% (15) of the “total culturable” bacteria and that of cows on pasture tends to be greater than 40% (16).</s><s>Because <i>Succiniclasticum ruminis</i> has not been detected in ruminants fed other diets, it is possible that this organism typically occurs only in animals fed particular types of diets and perhaps even in particular animal species.</s><s>This appears to be the case with <i>V. parvula</i> (formerly <i>V. gazogenes</i>) (9), a succinate and lactate fermenter that has not been found to be numerically important except in sheep rumina.</s><s>Similarly, lactate-fermenting sarcinas have been found to be important only in cows fed production diets containing grass silage (18).</s><s>More work will have to be done before it can be determined whether the presence of <i>Succiniclasticurn ruminis</i> in the rumen biota is related to diet.</s></p></content></protolog>