<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4677_nm.1819" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1819" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1819" rank="species">Macromonas bipunctata</organism><reference id="rid.4677"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dubinina</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grabovich</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation, cultivation and characteristics of Macromonas bipunctata</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>748</fpage><lpage>755</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Macromonas bipunctata</i> sp. nov. (Gicklhorn) Utermohl and Koppe 1924</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are single or in pairs, pear shaped, cylindrical, or of a curved form, 2.2-4.0 x 3.3-6.5 μ in size. They move by means of a bundle of twined cilia, which may be seen in a light microscope. They are gram-negative. Colonies are nonpigmented, slightly opalescent, flat on the surface of the medium, measuring 0.5-4.00 mm; in the depth of the agar, they form tetrahedrals measuring 0.3-1.0 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology: They are strict aerobes, optimum temperature is 28°; growth is weak at 15 and 37°C; pH limits for growth are 6.0-9.0, optimum pH is 7.5-8.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganoheterotrophy.</s><s>For growth, the cells use a limited number of substrates, mainly organic acids: acetate, succinate, malate, fumarate, oxaloacetate, pyruvate, and benzoate..</s><s>Ability to use oxalate, lactate, α-ketoglutarate, aconitate, glyocylate, and ethanol varies 1n the different strains.</s><s>They are capable of growing on casein hydrolysate and yeast extract.</s><s>Sugars, alcohols, and amino acids are not used.</s><s>Vitamins are required for growth.</s><s>They use ammonia salts, glutamate, casein, hydrolysate, and peptone as sources of nitrogen; some strains use cysteine, cystine, alanine, and serine.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Casein and starch are not hydrolyzed; nitrites, sulfates, thiosulfate, and fumarate are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>They have urease and catalase activity.</s><s>They do not form hydrogen sulfide from cysteine and thiosulfate in the medium.</s><s>They do not form indole.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is accumulated within the cells on a medium with sulfides but not with thiosulfate.</s><s>GTs is 67.3-68.3 mole %.</s><s>Source: precipitates of effluents from aerotanks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Typical Strain D-405.</s><s>This strain was isolated from precipitates in sewage equipment.</s><s>Its description agrees with the species description with the following specifications: In addition to the listed substrate sources, it uses α-ketoglutarate, lactate, ethanol, glyocylate, propionate, and oxylate; of the amino acids, it uses aspartate, alanine, and serine as sources of nitrogen.</s><s>GTs content is 67.6 mole %.</s><s>The strains is registered as No. 1366 in the All-Union Collection of Microorganisms at the Institute of Biophysics of Microorganisms of the Academy of Sciences of the USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>