<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3852_nm.8211" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8211" rank="family">Cryomorphaceae</organism><reference id="rid.3852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mancuso Nichols</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Brumimicrobium glaciale gen. nov., sp. nov., Cryomorpha ignava gen. nov., sp. nov. and Crocinitomix catalasitica gen. nov., sp. nov., novel flavobacteria isolated from various polar habitats.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1343</fpage><lpage>1355</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02553-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130017</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cryomorphaceae</em> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cryomorphaceae</em> (Cry.o.mor.pha′ce.ae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Cryomorpha</em> the type genus of the family; -<em>aceae</em> ending to denote a family; N.L. neut. pl. n. <em>Cryomorphaceae</em> the <em>Cryomorpha</em> family).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Includes species with a mostly rod-like to filamentous morphology.</s><s>Cells are non-motile or move by gliding and normally contain carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Strictly aerobic or facultatively anaerobic (fermentative) chemoheterotrophic metabolism.</s><s>Species can have complex growth requirements requiring sea-water salts, organic compounds as sole nitrogen sources, yeast extract and vitamins for growth.</s><s>The type genus is <em>Cryomorpha</em>.</s><s>Also contains the genera <em>Brumimicrobium</em> and <em>Crocinitomix</em>.</s><s>Located within class <em>Flavobacteria</em>, branching phylogenetically between the families <em>Flavobacteriaceae</em> and <em>Bacteroidaceae</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>