<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12570_nm.21817" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21817" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21817" rank="species">Demequina globuliformis</organism><reference id="rid.12570"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ue</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Demequina globuliformis sp. nov., Demequina oxidasica sp. nov. and Demequina aurantiaca sp. nov., actinobacteria isolated from marine environments, and proposal of Demequinaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1322</fpage><lpage>1329</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024299-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656823</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Demequina globuliformis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Demequina globuliformis</em> (glo.bu.li.for′mis. L. dim. n. <em>globulus</em> a small sphere, globule; L. adj. suffix <em>-formis -is -e</em> (from L. n. <em>forma</em> figure, shape, appearance), -like, in the shape of; N.L. masc. adj. <em>globuliformis</em> globule-shaped).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-stain-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, facultatively anaerobic, oxidase and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells are cocci to short ovoid rods, 0.50–1.00 µm in diameter or 0.50–1.00 µm in length and 0.50–0.95 µm in width.</s><s>Colonies are cream–yellow on LB plates.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Indole production and hydrolysis of starch and gelatin are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C with optimum growth occurring at 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5–11 with optimum growth occurring between pH 7.5 and 8.</s><s>Based on API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, but negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Decomposition of adenine, l-tyrosine, casein, hypoxanthine and xanthine is negative.</s><s>Can also utilize l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, maltose monohydrate, glucose and sucrose as sole carbon source, but cannot utilize d-mannitol.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl d-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl d-mannoside, α-methyl d-glucoside, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from glycerol.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are of the anteiso-branched and straight-chain types.</s><s>The fatty acids (&#x003E;1 %) comprise C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The components of the peptidoglycan are Lys, Orn, Ala, Ser and Glu in a molar ratio of 0.3 : 0.4 : 1.1 : 1.8 : 1.0.</s><s>The major menaquinone is demethylmenaquinone DMK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and the minor menaquinones are DMK-8(H<sub>4</sub>), DMK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and DMK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Nitrate reduction to nitrite is negative.</s><s>Fermentation of glucose is positive.</s><s>Can grow in the presence of 15 % sodium chloride.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol; unknown compounds were also detected.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 67.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM24-125<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 106266<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 19747<sup>T</sup>  = MBIC 08349<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sea sand.</s></p></content></protolog>