<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12548_nm.21409" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21409" rank="species">Marinomonas brasilensis</organism><reference id="rid.12548"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chimetto</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brocchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinomonas brasilensis sp. nov., isolated from the coral Mussismilia hispida, and reclassification of Marinomonas basaltis as a later heterotypic synonym of Marinomonas communis</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1170</fpage><lpage>1175</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024661-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20562247</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinomonas brasilensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinomonas brasilensis</em> (bra.si.len′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>brasilensis</em> of or belonging to Brazil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, halophilic, motile, straight rods, approx. 1 µm wide and 1.5–3 µm long.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, undulate, convex, smooth, beige in colour and 1 mm in diameter after 1 day of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Prolific growth occurs at 20–35 °C and in the presence of 1–11 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth is observed in the absence of NaCl or in ≥14 % NaCl or at ≤7 °C or ≥40 °C.</s><s>The type strain exhibits alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase, urease and tryptophan deaminase enzyme activities, but not lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or gelatinase activities.</s><s>It produces acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction), but not H<sub>2</sub>S or indole.</s><s>It does not ferment glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin or arabinose.</s><s>It is negative for reduction of nitrate to nitrite or N<sub>2</sub> gas.</s><s>It is able to assimilate citrate, Tweens 40 and 80, d-fructose, α-d-glucose, d-mannose, sucrose, monomethyl succinate, dl-lactic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, inosine and uridine.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Weakly positive reactions for assimilation of α-cyclodextrin, l-arabinose, cellobiose, turanose, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, urocanic acid and glycerol.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactose lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate and trisodium citrate.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, corresponding to 86 % of the total profile.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in small amounts (&#x003C;5 %): unknown fatty acid ECL 11.799, C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>The phenotypic profile is at present based on one strain.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R-40503<sup>T</sup> ( = R-278<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25434<sup>T</sup> = CAIM 1459<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mucus of the endemic coral <em>Mussismilia hispida</em> located in the São Sebastião channel, São Paulo, Brazil.</s></p></content></protolog>