<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8010_nm.3655" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3655" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3655" rank="species">Syntrophobacter pfennigii</organism><reference id="rid.8010"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wallrabenstein</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hauschild</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophobacter pfennigii sp. nov., new syntrophically propionate-oxidizing anaerobe growing in pure culture with propionate and sulfate.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>164</volume><fpage>346</fpage><lpage>352</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02529981</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophobacter pfennigii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophobacter pfennigii</i>. ( a formal description of this strain follows: <i>Syntrophobacter pfennigii</i>. pfen.ni'gi.i. M. L. gen. n. after Prof. Dr. Norbert Pfennig, a German microbiologist who has contributed substantially to the understanding of syntrophic relationships and of the physiology of sulfate-reducing bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod- to egg-shaped cells, 2.2-3.0 x 1.0-1.2 mm in size, with rounded ends, single, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Endospores not formed.</s><s>Gas vesicles visible in the late growth phase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Growth by fermentation or by reduction of sulfate.</s><s>Pure cultures oxidize propionate or lactate with sulfate as electron acceptor.</s><s>No growth with glucose, fructose, xylose, arabinose, ethanol, methanol, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, oxaloacetate, malate, acrylate, butyrate, valerate, caproate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub>+acetate and formate+acetate are not used by the pure culture.</s><s>Propionate and lactate are fermented to acetate and CO<sub>2</sub> in the presence of hydrogen- and/or formate-utilizing methanogenic bacteria (e.g. <i>Methanospirillurn hungatei</i>).</s><s>The coculture also oxidizes propanol.</s><s>Sulfite or thiosulfate serve as alternative electron acceptors, nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Growth requires mineral media with a strong reductant (dithionite).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selective enrichment in reduced freshwater mineral medium with propionate as substrate, pH range: 6.2-8.0; optimum at pH 7.0-7.3.</s><s>Temperature range: 30-37 °C; optimum at 37°C.</s><s>DNA base ratio: 57.3 ± 0.2 mol% G+C.</s><s>Cytochromes b and c, menaquinone-7, and desulforubidin present.</s><s>Habitat: Anaerobic sewage sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain KoProp1, DSM 10092, deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung für Mikroorganismen und Zell-kulturen GmbH (Braunschweig, Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>