<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.314_nm.7646" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7646" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7646" rank="species">Microsphaera multipartita</organism><reference id="rid.314"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoshimi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Microsphaera multipartita gen. nov., sp. nov., a polysaccharide-accumulating gram-positive bacterium from activated sludge</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>519</fpage><lpage>525</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microsphaera multipartita</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microsphaera multipartita</i> (mul.ti.par.ti'ta. M. L. adj. <i>multus</i>, many; M. L. v. partitre, divide; M. L. fem. part. pass. multipartita, microorganism having many divisions inside the cell)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology of this species and its chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those described above for the genus.</s><s>The colonies are circular, smooth, convex, and white at the early stage of growth.</s><s>After about 2 weeks of incubation the colonies are cream colored.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 25°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.0.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of an NaCl concentration of 7% or more.</s><s>The doubling time is about 11 h in liquid medium.</s><s>The polysaccharide content of the cells may be high (sometimes more than 50% [wt/wt] depending on the culture conditions).</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Good carbon sources are sugars and alcohols and include D-xylose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, ethanol, and propanol.</s><s>Starch, pyruvate, alanine, glutamate, glutamine, and histidine are also utilized.</s><s>Not utilized are glycogen, methanol, acetate, malate, succinate, arginine, and asparagine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Occurs in activated sludge cultured in fed-batch reactors under aerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Y-104, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (RIKEN) as strain JCM 9543.</s></p></content></protolog>