<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3344_nm.8117" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8117" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8117" rank="species">Flavobacterium thalpophilum</organism><reference id="rid.3344"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pickett</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium thalopophilum, a new species recovered from human clinical material.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>677</fpage><lpage>682</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-677</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium thalpophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium thalpophilum</i> (thal.po'phi.lum. Gr. n. <i>thalpos</i> warmth; Gr. n. adj. <i>philon</i> loving; M. L. n. adj. <i>thalpophilum</i> warmth-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics for which all seven strains of the species gave either positive results or negative results are given below.</s><s>Characteristics for which the seven strains gave different results are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods of regular shape with rounded ends.</s><s>Nonmotile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular, low convex, smooth, opaque colonies develop on nutrient agar after 2 days; colonies nonhemolytic on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar; on nutrient agar, eventual production of a yellow pigment which is not fluorescent.</s><s>No production of brown pigment on tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at room temperature and at 37 and 42°C, but not at 5°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of urease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not tolerate KCN at a concentration of 0.0075% (wt/vol).</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 20 and Tween 80.</s><s>No production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite; no reduction of nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of indole or hydrogen sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on Mac-Conkey agar, but not on cetrimide agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No digestion of casein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of esculin and tributyrin, but not starch or tyrosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No utilization of citrate or malonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No oxidation of gluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of arginine deimidase, arginine deiminase, lysine decarboxylase, or ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of 3-ketolactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of selenite and no deamination of phenylalanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of phosphatase and β-D-galactosidase (when tested by method 1 of Cowan [4] and the method of Holmes et al. [6], respectively).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from dulcitol, ethanol, inositol, mannitol, or sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of gas from glucose in peptone water medium; production of acid in only open tubes of Hugh-Leifson oxidation-fermentation glucose medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of the following substrates (using API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 8.5 ; L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide; 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 5.4; naphthol-AS-B1-phosphodiamide; 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside; 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide; 4-methylumbelliferyl-cellobiopyranoside; L-pyrrolidonyl-β-naphthylamide; L-lysyl-β-naphthylamide; L-hisidyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-aspartyl-β-naphthylamide; L-arginyl-β-naphthylamide; L-alanyl-β-naphthylamide; γ-Lglutamyl-β-naphthylamide; S-benzyl-L-cysteylβ-naphthylamide; DL-methionyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide hydrobromide; glycyl-L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide; L-leucyl-glycyl-β-napthylamide; L-seryl-L-tyrosyl-β-naphthylamide; L-glutamine-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; α-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide; L-ornithyl-β-naphthylamide; L-seryl-β-naphthylamide; L-threonyl-β-naphthylamide; L-tryptophyl-β-naphthylamide; and N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginine-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No hydrolysis of the following substrates (using API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl butyrate; 2-naphthyl myristate; L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide; N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide; N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide; naphthol-AS-B1-β-D-glucuronic acid; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-xylopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-xylopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-fucopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-L-fucopyranoside; <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide; L-hydroxyprolyl-β-naphthylamide; N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide; L-isoleucyl-β-naphthylamide; L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, amikacin, gentamicin, kanamycin, tobramycin, chloramphenicol, and tetracycline (strain K-1232 is susceptible).</s><s>Susceptible to rifampin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA: is 45.0 ± 0.8 mol%, and the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 43.8 mol%, as estimated by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source of type strain: wound (human).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following two additional strains of <i>F. thalpophilum</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: C499 (= K-1207) as NCTC 11430 and K-1232 as NCTC 11431.</s></p></content></protolog>