<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6937_nm.1650" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1650" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1650" rank="species">Burkholderia thailandensis</organism><reference id="rid.6937"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brett</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>DeShazer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woods</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia thailandensis sp. nov., a Burkholderia pseudomallei-like species.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>320</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-357</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542103</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia thailandensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia thailandensis</i> (thai.lan.den'sis. M.L. adj. thailandensis pertaining to Thailand from where the organism was originally isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and motile due to the presence of a polar tuft of two to four flagella.</s><s>The organism is nutritionally diverse and grows at temperatures ranging from 25 to 42°C.</s><s>The production of siderophore, lipase, lecithinase and protease are apparent at both 25 and 37°C (2). <i>B. thailandensis</i> colonies are smooth and glossy with a pink pigmentation on modified Ashdown's selective medium while <i>B. pseudomallei</i> colonies are rough and wrinkled with a dark purple pigmentation (2).</s><s>The API 20NE and API 50CH biochemical profiles for <i>B. thailandensis</i> strains are similar to those for <i>B. pseudomallei</i> strains (22).</s><s>Notable exceptions, however, include the capacity to assimilate L-arabinose, 5-keto-gluconate and adonitol and the inability to utilize erythritol and dulcitol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Previous studies describing the presence of <i>B. thailandensis</i> during epidemiological surveys in Thailand have been unable to correlate human disease with this organism (22).</s><s>These findings support our animal studies which clearly demonstrate that <i>B. thailandensis</i> strains are avirulent for Syrian golden hamsters (2). <i>B. thailandensis</i> isolates are resistant to aminoglycosides but sensitive to tetracycline, ceftazidime and trimethoprim.</s><s>The type strain, E264, was isolated from a rice field soil sample in central Thailand (16).</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700388.</s></p></content></protolog>