<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.524_nm.1328" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1328" rank="genus">Ensifer</organism><reference id="rid.524"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The genus name Ensifer Casida 1982 takes priority over Sinorhizobium Chen et al. 1988, and Sinorhizobium morelense Wang et al. 2002 is a later synonym of Ensifer adhaerens Casida 1982. Is the combination Sinorhizobium adhaerens (Casida 1982) Willems et al. 2003 legitimate? Request for an Opinion.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2107</fpage><lpage>2110</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02665-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657154</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Ensifer</em> Casida 1982, 339<sup>VP</sup></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Rods, 0·5–1·0×1·0–3·0 μm.</s><s>Commonly pleomorphic under adverse growth conditions.</s><s>Some species multiply by budding.</s><s>Cells usually contain granules of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate that are refractile under phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Motile by means of one polar or subpolar flagellum or one to six peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Fimbriae have been described for a few strains.</s><s>Aerobic, possessing a respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 25–30 °C, but a wide range of temperatures can be tolerated: most strains can grow at 35 °C, some strains can grow at 10 °C and others grow at temperatures up to 42–44 °C.</s><s>Tolerate 1·0 % NaCl; some strains grow well on media containing 4·5 % NaCl.</s><s>The optimum pH is 6–8, but some strains can grow at pH 5·0 and others at pH 10·5.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, semi-translucent, raised and mucilaginous and usually 2–4 mm in diameter within 3–5 days on yeast/mannitol/mineral-salts agar.</s><s>Generation times are 3–6 h.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, utilizing a wide range of carbohydrates and salts of organic acids as carbon sources, producing acid without gas formation.</s><s>Cellulose and starch are not utilized.</s><s>Produce an acidic reaction in mineral-salts medium containing mannitol.</s><s>Growth on carbohydrate media is often accompanied by copious extracellular polysaccharide slime production.</s><s>Do not utilize cellulose or starch.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrate, nitrite and most amino acids can serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>All strains require pantothenate and nicotinic acid.</s><s>Peptone is poorly utilized.</s><s>Casein and agar are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Strains produce cytochrome oxidase and catalase.</s><s>3-Ketolactose is not produced from lactose.</s><s>Some species are recorded as resistant to a wide variety of antibiotics.</s><s>Strains of most species identified so far are characteristically able to invade temperate-zone and tropical-zone leguminous plants (family <em>Leguminosae</em>) and to incite the production of root nodules, inside which the bacteria occur as intracellular nitrogen-fixing microsymbionts.</s><s>In root nodules, the bacteria occur as endophytes exhibiting pleomorphic forms.</s><s>Strains of nitrogen-fixing isolates exhibit varying degrees of host specificity.</s><s>Strains of at least one species, the type species, are capable of the predation of other bacteria.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57–66 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The type species is <em>Ensifer adhaerens</em> Casida 1982<sup>VP</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>