<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4434_nm.4620" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4620" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4620" rank="species">Mycoplasma agassizii</organism><reference id="rid.4434"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>M.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McLaughlin</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumacher</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jacobson</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adams</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma agassizii sp. nov., isolated from the upper respiratory tract of the desert tortoise (Gopherus agassizii) and the gopher tortoise (Gopherus polyphemus).</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>413</fpage><lpage>418</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321087</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma agassizii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Mycoplasma agassizii (aga'ssi.z.ii. M.L. gen. n. <i>agassizii</i> of Agassiz, named after J. Louis R. Agassiz, a notable Swiss born American naturalist who fist described the North American Testudinata (Agassiz, 1857) and after whom the desert tortoise was named (Cooper, 1863))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid to pleomorphic with no cell wall but with a clearly defined three-layer membrane.</s><s>Nonhelical and non-motile.</s><s>Some strains appear to possess a rudimentary tip structure.</s><s>Colonies on agar are variable, with both mulberry and fried-egg characteristics.</s><s>Mulberry colonies are common on primary isolation plates.</s><s>Primary isolation requires 3-6 weeks of incubation.</s><s>It does not grow well above 30 °C.</s><s>Best growth is achieved with SP-4 medium.</s><s>Cells pass through 0.45 μm filters and some, but not all strains also pass through 0.22 μm filters.</s><s>No reversion to bacterial forms is seen.</s><s>It is inhibited by digitonin and requires serum or sterol for growth.</s><s>Glucose is fermented, but arginine and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Phosphatase is not produced.</s><s>It haemagglutinates guinea pig and tortoise erythrocytes.</s><s>Most, but not all strains haemadsorb guinea pig and tortoise erythrocytes.</s><s>It contains conserved mycoplasmal genus-specific sequences in the 16S rRNA gene and is serologically distinct from other <i>Mycoplasma</i> species.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence is unique.</s><s>The habitat is the respiratory tract of the desert tortoise and gopher tortoise, with the most common sites of isolation being the nares and choana.</s><s>It is virulent and has been demonstrated in experimental infections to cause upper respiratory tract disease in both the desert tortoise and gopher tortoise.</s><s>Type strain is PS6<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700616<sup>T</sup>) and is also available from the Mollicutes Culture Collection (Curators Dr J.</s><s>K.</s><s>Davis and M.</s><s>K.</s><s>Davidson, University of Florida).</s></p></content></protolog>