<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11568_nm.18603" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18603" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18603" rank="species">Natronomonas moolapensis</organism><reference id="rid.11568"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minegishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Usami</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dyall-Smith</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Natronomonas moolapensis sp. nov., non-alkaliphilic isolates recovered from a solar saltern crystallizer pond, and emended description of the genus Natronomonas</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1173</fpage><lpage>1176</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010132-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667395</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Natronomonas moolapensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Natronomonas moolapensis</em> (moo.la.pen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>moolapensis</em> from Moolap, the place where the saltern crystallizer is situated from which the first isolates were recovered).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and have varying morphologies (short rods, flat tetragonal shapes or cocci) with dimensions ranging from 0.7 to 1.7 μm.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium are red with entire edges.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Cells are oxidase- and catalase-negative using conventional testing.</s><s>Strain 4.03.5 can reduce nitrate to nitrite, but cannot utilize DMSO as an alternative electron acceptor, while strain 8.8.11<sup>T</sup> cannot utilize either nitrate or DMSO as alternative electron acceptors.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5, 25–45 °C and 14–36 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cells lyse immediately in distilled water, and a minimum ∼14 % salts is required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at around pH 7–7.5 and at 18–20 % NaCl.</s><s>Capable of growing in defined media but can use relatively few substrates.</s><s>Grows best on pyruvate, and can use acetate, butanol, butyrate, ethanol, glucose (strain 4.03.5 only), glycerol, lactate, propanol and propionate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Incapable of utilizing alanine, arabinose, arginine, aspartate, benzoate, betaine, cellobiose, citrate, formate, fructose, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconuronate, glucose (strain 8.8.11<sup>T</sup> only), glycine, glycolate, lactose, leucine, lysine, malate, malonate, mannitol, mannose, methanol, ribose, serine, succinate, sucrose, tartrate, threonine, urea, valine and xylose (all at 10 mM) and cellulose, chitin and starch (0.1 % w/v) as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acid is not produced from carbohydrate utilization.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and indole production.</s><s>Gas vesicles in some cells.</s><s>Sensitive to mycostatin, novobiocin, rifampicin and simvastatin and resistant to ampicillin, anisomycin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, cycloheximide, erythromycin, kanamycin, neomycin, streptomycin and tetracycline at 50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Phylogenetically affiliated to the <em>Halobacteriaceae</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 8.8.11<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14361<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7526<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18674<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>An additional reference strain is 4.03.5 (=JCM 14360 =DSM 18672).</s><s>Both strains were isolated from Cheetham Salt Works, Geelong, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>