<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2357_nm.1046" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1046" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1046" rank="species">Rhodobacter veldkampii</organism><reference id="rid.2357"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter veldkampii, a new species of phototrophic purple nonsulfur bacteria</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>115</fpage><lpage>116</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodobacter veldkampii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobacter veldkampii</i> (veld. kamp' i. i. M. L. gen. noun <i>veldkampii</i> of Veldkamp; named for Hans Veldkamp, a Dutch microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short, rod-shaped to ovoid, and 0.6 to 0.8 μm wide by 1.0 to 1.3 μm long, show a pronounced tendency to form chains of cells, do not produce slime, and are nonmotile.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are present as vesicles.</s><s>The color of cell suspensions after anaerobic growth in the light is yellowish brown; small amounts of oxygen cause a color change from brown to red.</s><s>Absorption spectra of cells grown anaerobically in the light have maxima at 373, 448, 477, 510, 589, 803, and 855 nm, indicating the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photoautotrophic growth with sulfide as an electron donor and photoheterotrophic growth with a variety of organic carbon compounds as carbon sources and electron donors are possible under anaerobic conditions in the light.</s><s>Molecular hydrogen cannot be used as an electron donor.</s><s>Growth is also possible aerobically in the dark.</s><s>The carbon sources utilized include acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, caprylate, pelargonate, pyruvate, lactate, malate, succinate, fumarate, glucose, alanine, cysteine, yeast extract, and Casamino Acids; slow growth is possible with glutamate and aspartate.</s><s>Not utilized are formate, methanol, ethanol, propanol, citrate, tartrate, glycerol, sorbitol, mannitol, fructose, and benzoate.</s><s>Ammonia, dinitrogen, and nitrate are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Growth depends on the presence of reduced sulfur compounds, such as cysteine, cystine, and sulfide; however, sulfite, methionine, and sulfate are not assimilated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>During phototrophic growth with sulfide as the electron donor, sulfide is oxidized to elemental sulfur, which is only slowly oxidized further to sulfate after sulfide depletion in batch cultures; in sulfide-limited chemostat cultures sulfate is the major oxidation product.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biotin, thiamine, and <i>p</i>-aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors; 0.01% yeast extract can replace this requirement.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature, 30 to 35°C; optimum pH, 7.5.</s><s>NaCl is not required for optimal growth, and is inhibitory at concentrations above 2%.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is a storage product.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 64.4 to 67.5 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 51 (Hansen), which has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 35703.</s></p></content></protolog>