<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12861_nm.22668" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22668" rank="genus">Aureimonas</organism><reference id="rid.12861"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rathsack</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reitner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Aurantimonas altamirensis (Jurado et al. 2006), Aurantimonas ureilytica (Weon et al. 2007) and Aurantimonas frigidaquae (Kim et al. 2008) as members of a new genus, Aureimonas gen. nov., as Aureimonas altamirensis gen. nov., comb. nov., Aureimonas ureilytica comb. nov. and Aureimonas frigidaquae comb. nov., and emended descriptions of the genera Aurantimonas and Fulvimarina</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2722</fpage><lpage>2728</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027029-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21186293</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aureimonas</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aureimonas</em> (Au.re.i.mo′nas. L. adj. <em>aureus</em> golden; Gr. fem. n. <em>monas</em> a unit; N.L. fem. n. <em>Aureimonas</em> golden-coloured bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, short rods of mean size 1.0×2.0µm.</s><s>Colonies are yellow in colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–40 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and in 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cells are catalase-, urease- and oxidase-positive but negative for l-alanine-aminopeptidase.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of DNA and starch, but negative for hydrolysis of tyrosine, Tween 80 and casein.</s><s>Cells are able to assimilate glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol and malic acid.</s><s>Negative for nitrite reduction, production of indole from tryptophan, fermentation of glucose, arginine dihydrolase activity, hydrolysis of β-glucosidase and assimilation of capric acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Positive for utilization of d-arabitol, l-arabinose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, α-d-glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, acetic acid, adonitol, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanyl-glycine, hydroxy-l-proline and l-proline.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is Q10.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise DPG, PME, PC, PG, PE, two lipids, two unidentified aminolipids and SQDG.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> with significant proportions of C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and cyclo-C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em>.</s><s>Members of the genus have been isolated predominantly from non-marine habitats.</s><s>The genus comprises three species <em>Aureimonas altamirensis</em>, <em>Aureimonas ureilytica</em> and <em>Aureimonas frigidaquae</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Aureimonas altamirensis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>