<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9685_nm.14828" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14828" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14828" rank="species">Streptomyces marokkonensis</organism><reference id="rid.9685"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouizgarne</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lanoot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Loqman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ouhdouch</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces marokkonensis sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil of Argania spinosa L.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2857</fpage><lpage>2863</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011387-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628602</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces marokkonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces</em> <em>marokkonensis</em> (ma.rok.ko.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>marokkonensis</em> pertaining to Marokko, the Dutch name of Morocco, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile actinomycete that forms a branched substrate mycelium and greyish white aerial mycelium with long spore chains of the <em>Spiralis</em> type with more than 20 cylindrical, non-flagellated spores with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Aerial spore mass colour is grey on yeast extract-malt extract agar (ISP medium 2), oatmeal agar (ISP medium 3), inorganic salts-starch agar (ISP medium 4), Bennett's agar (Jones, 1949) and nutrient agar and white–grey on glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP medium 5), glucose asparagine agar, sucrose nitrate agar, glucose Czapek's agar and Olson's agar.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed on ISP medium 4 or 5, and melanin pigments are not produced on tryptone-yeast extract agar (ISP medium 1), peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP medium 6) or tyrosine agar (ISP medium 7).</s><s>Temperature range for growth determined on yeast extract-malt extract agar is 15–40 °C, with optimal growth at 28–30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 4.5–10.</s><s>No growth is observed in the presence of sodium azide (0.01 %, w/v) or potassium tellurite (0.01 %, w/v) or in the presence of NaCl concentrations greater than 9 %.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Coagulation of skimmed milk and liquefaction of gelatin are positive.</s><s>Casein, gelatin and starch are degraded but not aesculin, xanthine or urea.</s><s>d-Glucose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, d-xylose, glycerol and maltose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>l-Arabinose and inositol are utilized poorly and raffinose and sodium citrate are not utilized.</s><s>Resistant to the <em>β</em>-lactams penicillin G (10 IU), amoxicillin (10 IU), oxacillin (1 IU), ampicillin (10 IU) and cefalotin (30 IU) and the sulfamides trimetoprim sulfoxide (10 U) and sulfamide (25 IU); sensitive to the aminoside antibiotics kanamycin (30 IU), amikacin (30 IU), neomycin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), gentamicin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), streptomycin (20 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and tobramycin (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and also to erythromycin (15 IU), novobiocin (30 IU), bacitracin (10 IU) and polymyxin B (300 IU).</s><s>Shows activity against the yeasts <em>Candida albicans</em>, <em>Candida tropicalis</em> and <em>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</em>, the moulds <em>Fusarium oxysporum</em> f. sp. <em>albedinis</em>, <em>Fusarium oxysporum</em> f. sp. <em>lycopercidi</em>, <em>Verticillium dahliae</em> and <em>Aspergillus niger</em>, the Gram-positive bacteria <em>Staphylococcus aureus</em>, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em>, <em>Bacillus cereus</em> and <em>Micrococcus luteus</em> and the Gram-negative bacteria <em>Escherichia coli</em>, <em>Salmonella typhi</em> and <em>Klebsiella pneumoniae</em>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 70 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Ap1<sup>T</sup> (=R-22003<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23016<sup>T</sup> =DSM 41918<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from rhizosphere soil of <em>Argania spinosa</em> L. in the south of Morocco.</s></p></content></protolog>