<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9715_nm.14866" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14866" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14866" rank="species">Algoriphagus olei</organism><reference id="rid.9715"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Langer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Algoriphagus olei sp. nov., isolated from oil-contaminated soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2909</fpage><lpage>2915</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009415-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628616</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Algoriphagus olei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Algoriphagus olei</em> (o′le.i. L. gen. neut. n. <em>olei</em> of/from oil, as the type strain was isolated from oil-contaminated soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile rods (0.4–0.6×0.8–2.5 μm).</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h incubation on nutrient agar and TS agar at 32 °C.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard media at 32 °C are pinkish red, smooth, shiny and convex with a spreading edge, 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 32 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 8.0; growth occurs at pH 7 and 9, but not at pH 6.0 or 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No anaerobic growth is seen on plain nutrient agar or tripticase soy agar supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules is observed.</s><s>Shows aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase-, catalase- and aesculin-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain is shown in Table 1.</s><s>The quinone system comprises menaquinone MK-7 as the predominant component.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of phosphatidylethanolamine, an unknown polar lipid, an unknown phospholipid and an unknown aminophospholipid.</s><s>The main cell polyamine is <em>sym</em>-homospermidine; lesser amounts of spermine and spermidine are found.</s><s>The red pigment consists of at least two highly hydrophobic components which contain a sugar moiety.</s><s>Positive for the following substrates in the Biolog GN-II system: cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-threonine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Negative for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20E and 20NE) for <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG), oxidase, aesculin, indole production, and assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose, but negative reactions for nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, acetoin production, gelatinase, oxidation of d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, amygdalin and l-arabinose, fermentation of glucose, and assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but negative for lipase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Sensitive to cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, clindamycin, tetracycline, minocycline, vancomycin, teicoplanin, rifampicin, nor/quinolones 2G, levofloxacin, fusidic acid, nitrofurantoin and quinupristin-dalfopristin.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, gentamicin, Coag-oxacillin and oxacillin.</s><s>Further physiological characteristics are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-Hsuan-617<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17886<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 57471<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an oil-contaminated soil near an oil refinery located in Kaohsiung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>