<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12_nm.12196" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12196" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1960" rank="species">Iodobacter fluviatile</organism><reference id="rid.12"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical taxonomy of violet-pigmented, Gram-negative bacteria and description of Iodobacter fluviatile gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>450</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Iodobacter fluviatile</i> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Iodobacter fluviatile</i>  has all the characters defining the genus. In addition, it has the following properties: positive for growth in 1% NaCl; positive for oxidase; production of acid from fructose, glucose, maltose, mannose, trehalose, and <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine; utilization of malate as the sole carbon source; and hydrolysis of gelatin. Negative for growth in 4% NaCl and at pH 3; production of acid from arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, and xylose; utilization of lactate, proprionate, or tartrate as the sole carbon source; hydrolysis of aesculin, arginine, and starch; production of hydrogen cyanide; reduction of nitrite; production of gas from nitrate. Sensitive to the following antibiotics: chloramphenicol, chlortetracycline, furazolidone, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, oxytetracycline and tetracycline; slightly sensitive to neomycin, streptomycin, and sulfafurazole; resistant to ampicillin, cephaloridine, colistin, penicillin G, and vibriostatic agent 0/129. Variable properties (with proportion of strains giving positive results shown in parentheses) are: spreading colonies (89%), gelatinous colonies (4%), and zoning of pigment (6%) on iNA; violacein production (83%); formation of chains of cells (34%) and filaments (15%); growth at 30°C (83%), in 2% NaCl(9%), and at pH 4 (19%) and pH 9 (98%); growth on minimal medium (96%) and 4NA (45%); production of acid from gluconate (96%)and glycerol (13%);utilization of acetate (89%),citrate (85%), fumarate (89%), glycerate (60%),pyruvate (79%),and succinate (94%); hydrolysis of casein (90%); hemolysis (92%); egg yolk reaction (13%); nitrate reduction (98%). The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the DNA from three strains ranged from 50 to 52 mol% as determined by melting temperature (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from running fresh water in England and Scotland, and reported (19) from Antarctic lakes.</s><s>Strains of this species are infrequently isolated, and the selective medium of Ryall and Moss (12) is recommended, with subsequent cultivation on 1/4NA or in 1/4NB.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCTC 11159 (strain COO9 in the present study) and has the characters of the species.</s><s>With respect to variable characters, tests are positive for production of spreading colonies and violacein; growth at 30°C, on minimal medium, and at pH 5; production of acid from gluconate; utilization of acetate, citrate, fumarate, glycerate, pyruvate, or succinate as the sole carbon source; hydrolysis of casein; hemolysis; and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Tests were negative for production of gelatinous colonies; zoning of pigment; formation of chains of cells; filamentous forms; growth in 2% NaCl, at pH 4, and on 4NA; production of acid from glycerol; and egg yolk reaction.</s></p></content></protolog>