<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1688_nm.11490" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11490" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11490" rank="species">Rhodobacter changlensis</organism><reference id="rid.1688"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter changlensis sp. nov., a psychrotolerant, phototrophic alphaproteobacterium from the Himalayas of India</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2568</fpage><lpage>2571</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65110-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978219</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodobacter changlensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodobacter changlensis</em> (chang.len′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>changlensis</em> pertaining to Changla Pass, the location from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are oval to rod-shaped, 0.8–1.0 μm wide and 2–4 μm long, are non-motile and divide by binary fission, and occasionally form chains.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>Phototrophic cultures are yellowish brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 380, 407, 450, 470, 512, 590, 806 and 851 nm, confirming the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and most probably carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>The organism is psychrotolerant (range 5–32 °C; optimum at 28±2 °C), has a pH optimum at 6.5–7.5 and does not require NaCl for growth.</s><s>Photo-organoheterotrophy with a few organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Grows well on pyruvate, 2-oxoglutarate, mannitol and sorbitol as carbon sources.</s><s>Growth is also observed on succinate, glucose, glutamate, casein hydrolysate, yeast extract and peptone.</s><s>Chemoautotrophic growth is not possible in the presence of thiosulfate/hydrogen as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Fermentative growth is not possible in the presence of pyruvate as fermentable carbon source.</s><s>Biotin, niacin and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s><s>DNA base composition is 69.4 mol% G+C (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA139<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18774<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 53722<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14338<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a snow sample collected from Changla Pass in the Indian Himalayas.</s></p></content></protolog>