<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6162_nm.5563" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5563" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5563" rank="species">Vagococcus fluvialis</organism><reference id="rid.6162"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ash</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallbanks</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>16S ribosomal ribonucleic acid sequence analyses of lactococci and related taxa. Description of Vagococcus fluvialis gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>67</volume><fpage>453</fpage><lpage>460</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2479630</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vagococcus fluvialis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vagococcus fluvialis</i> (flu. vi. alis. L. adj. <i>fluvialis</i> belonging to a river)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid, elongated in the direction of the chain, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Grow at 10° and 40°C, in 4% NaCl and in 0.1% methylene blue milk.</s><s>Does not grow at 45°C, in 6.5% NaCl or at pH 9.6.</s><s>Does not survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, glucose, fructose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, ribose, salicin and trehalose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from glycerol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, sorbitol, sucrose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, arabitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, galactose, glycogen, inulin, inositol, lactose, D-lyxose, melibiose, rhamnose, L-sorbose, starch, D-tagatose, D-xylose, L-xylose, xylitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside and β-methylxyloside.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Hippurate and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Some strains produce arginine dehydrolase, β-galactosidase and pyrrolidonylarylmidase.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase and leucine arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield serological group N antiserum.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is LYS-D-ASP.</s><s>Contains poly (glycerophosphate) lipoteichoic acids solely substituted with D-alanine ester.</s><s>The major glycolipid is Gal (α 1-2) Glc (α 1-3) acyl, Gro.</s><s>Long chain fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types with hexadecanoic and octadecenoic (Δ<sup>9</sup>) acids predominating.</s><s>The G plus C content of DNA is 33.6 mol% as determined by melting temperature.</s><s>Isolated from faeces and water.</s><s>The type strain is NCDO 2497 (= M-29C).</s><s>Other reference collection strains include NCDO 2498 (=M-40D) and NCDO 2499 (= M-128F).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>In most respects the characteristics of the type strain corresponds to that of the species.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, sorbitol, sucrose and D-turanose.</s><s>β-Galactosidase is produced.</s><s>Arginine dehydrolase and pyrrolidonylarylamidase negative.</s></p></content></protolog>