<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4346_nm.3050" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3050" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3050" rank="species">Aeromonas allosaccharophila</organism><reference id="rid.4346"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martinez-Murcia</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Esteve</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas allosaccharophila sp. nov., a new mesophilic member of the genus Aeromonas.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>91</volume><fpage>199</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.1992.tb05209.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1378035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas allosaccharophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas allosaccharophila</i> (a.lo.sa.ca.ro'phi.la. Gr.adj. <i>allos</i>: different; Gr.n. <i>saccharo</i>, sugar; Gr.adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M L. adj. <i>allosaccharophila</i>, different-sugar-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight bacilli and motile: a diffusible brown pigment is not produced: chemoorganotrophic, with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism; reduces nitrate to nitrite; oxidase and catalase positive; growth occurs in 0-3% (w/v) NaCl; resistant to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (vibriostatic agent O/129); acid and gas are produced from glucose; lysine is decarboxylated (Moeller's medium); indole and β-galactosidase are positive; H<sub>2</sub>S from thiosulphate and Voges-Proskauer are negative; growth occurs at 4-42°C, and also at pH 9.0, but not at pH 4.5; acid is produced from sucrose, D-cellobiose, maltose, D-trehalose, D-galactose, D-mannose, glycerol, and D-mannitol, but not from adonitol, salicin, arbutin, D-xylose, lactose, <i>m</i>-erythritoi, duicitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, or D-sorbitol; sole carbon and energy sources include L-arabinose, sucrose, D-cellobiose, maltose, otrehalose, D-galactose, D-mannose, glycerol, D-mannitol, L-histidine, L-arginine, L-proline, L-glutamate, D-gluconate, fumarate and succinate; no growth occurs on salicin, lactose, <i>m</i>-erythritol, dulcitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, ethanol, L-citruiline, L-leucine, L-alanine, glycine, L-serine, L-glutamine, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, propionate, γ-aminobutyrate, D-glucuronate, α-ketoglutarate, or putrescine; gelatin, casein, egg-yolk, Tween-80, starch and DNA are degraded, but not urea, sodium dodecyl sulphate or elastin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is susceptible to gentamicin (10 mg/l), nitrofurantoin (10 mg/l), polymyxin B (300 IU), oxolinic (10 mg/l) and nalidixic (50 mg/l) acids, chloramphenicol (25 mg/l), kanamycin (50 mg/l), fosfomicin (50 mg/l), erythromycin (15 mg/l), and rifampicin (30 mg/l), but not to ampicillin (50 mg/l), trimethropim (25 mg/l), sulfadimethoxine (12 mg/l) or streptomycin (25 mg/l).</s><s>Additional characteristics which vary among strains are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It was isolated from diseased elvers of an eel-farm located in Valencia (Spain) and from diarrhoeic stools of a female patient in South Carolina (U.S.A.).</s><s>The G + C content of strain CECT 4199 is 59.5%.</s><s>The type strain is CECT 4199 (= strain 289).</s></p></content></protolog>