<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9925_nm.14893" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14893" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14893" rank="species">Microbispora siamensis</organism><reference id="rid.9925"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Boondaeng</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tokuyama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kitpreechavanich</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbispora siamensis sp. nov., a thermotolerant actinomycete isolated from soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3136</fpage><lpage>3139</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009613-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643881</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbispora siamensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbispora siamensis</em> (si.a.men′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>siamensis</em> pertaining to Siam, the old name of Thailand, the source of the soil from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>An aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile and thermotolerant actinomycete that forms non-fragmented branched vegetative hyphae.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are colourless to yellow.</s><s>During sporulation, the surface of the colony is pale pink.</s><s>Yellow and green soluble pigments are produced in ISP 2 and ISP 3 media, respectively.</s><s>Spores arranged in longitudinal pairs are formed on short sporophores that branch alternately from aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spores are oval and have smooth surfaces.</s><s>Substrates utilized as sole carbon sources include: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and sucrose, but not dulcitol, inositol, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Citric acid, l-malic acid and succinic acid are used, but not benzoic acid, fumaric acid or mucic acid.</s><s>Tests for cellulose degradation, gelatin liquefaction, nitrate reduction and milk peptonization are negative.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 25–50 °C, but no growth occurs at 55 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Strain DMKUA 245<sup>T</sup> contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Madurose is detected in whole-cell hydrolysates, indicating a cell wall chemotype IIIB (Lechevalier &#x0026; Lechevalier, 1970).</s><s>The phospholipid profile consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and ninhydrin-positive glycophospholipids and indicates a phospholipid type IV chemotype.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DMKUA 245<sup>T</sup> (=BCC 14407<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104113<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>