<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14702" rank="species">Rhodoluna planktonica</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhodoluna planktonica’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhodoluna planktonica’ [plank.to′ni.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>planktonica</em> living in the plankton, planktonic (from Gr. adj. <em>planktos</em> wandering)]. Represented by the aerobic, red-pigmented strain MWH-Dar1, which was isolated from a eutrophic pond in Tanzania. The strain is contained in a mixed culture with only a small fraction of a non-actinobacterial strain. Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-Dar1 (GenBank accession no. AJ565415) and the presence of the oligonucleotide sequence 5′-CGAGACCTGAAGGCATCTTTGGGTCT-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 183–193) within the 16S rRNA gene. This diagnostic oligonucleotide sequence is also present in two partial (430 nt) 16S rRNA gene sequences of uncultured bacteria (GenBank accession nos EF149338 and EF149356), which were retrieved from surface microlayers of freshwater habitats populated by mosquito larvae (<em>Anopheles</em> spp.) in Kenya. These two short sequences share similarities of 98.3 % with the sequence of strain MWH-Dar1.</s></p></content></protolog>