<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1930_nm.8594" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8594" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8594" rank="species">Glycomyces algeriensis</organism><reference id="rid.1930"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Glycomyces and description of Glycomyces algeriensis sp. nov., Glycomyces arizonensis sp. nov. and Glycomyces lechevalierae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2343</fpage><lpage>2346</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63089-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545481</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glycomyces algeriensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glycomyces algeriensis</em> (al.ger.i.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>algeriensis</em> from Algeria, the place of origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>White to yellowish white, waxy, plicate growth on most media.</s><s>Sparse white aerial hyphae are produced on some media.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Menaquinones present include MK-10, MK-11 and MK-12.</s><s>Adenine, allantoin and casein are hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are not hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is weakly reduced.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, malate, mucate, oxalate and propionate are weakly assimilated.</s><s>Benzoate, citrate, lactate, succinate and dl-tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, rhamnose, salicin and xylose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose or trehalose.</s><s>Growth occurs on 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRRL B-16327<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44727<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil collected in a potato field in Oran, Algeria.</s></p></content></protolog>