<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2673_nm.6507" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6507" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6507" rank="species">Tsukamurella inchonensis</organism><reference id="rid.2673"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brzezinka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella inchonensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>522</fpage><lpage>527</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-522</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590680</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella inchonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella inchonensis</i> (in. cho. nen' sis. M. L. adj. <i>inchonensis</i>, referring to Inchon, the city in South Korea where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid-alcohol-fast bacilli.</s><s>They do not form spores, capsules, or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Visible growth from dilute inocula occurs within 2 days; colonies on Loewenstein-Jensen medium are eugonic, brownish orange, and rough.</s><s>Growth occurs at 24, 31, 37, and 45°C.</s><s>The organism has <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as a wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose as determined with whole-cell hydrolysates; i.e., the cell wall chemotype is chemotype IV.</s><s>It has a type α, α' mycolate pattern; MK-9 is the major menaquinone, and minor amounts of MK-10 and MK-8 are also present.</s><s>This organism produces acetamidase, allantoinase, thermostable catalase, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, urease, and phosphatase but not arylsulfatase, benzamidase, nitrate reductase, and succinamidase.</s><s>It grows on MacConkey agar without crystal violet and tolerates 5% NaCl andp-nitrobenzoic acid.</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, cellobiose (only one strain), melezitose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, citrate, gluconate, lactate, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butandiol, 1,2-propandiol, and paraffin are utilized as sole carbon sources, but arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, lactose, raffinose, adonitol, erythritol, benzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and adipate are not utilized.</s><s>Acetamide, alanine, proline, and serine are utilized as both nitrogen and carbon sources.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, urea, esculin, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed, but adenine, tyrosine, xanthine, casein, gelatin, elastin, guanine, keratin, and testosterone are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, galactose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, cellobiose (one strain delayed), melezitose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, mannose, and fructose, but not from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, lactose, raffinose, adonitol, and inulin.</s><s>The strains which we tested are resistant to streptomycin, isoniazid, ethambutol, rifampin, <i>p</i>-aminosalicylic acid, protionamide, capreomycin, and cycloserine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>T. inchonensis</i> is strain DSM 44067.</s></p></content></protolog>