<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3461_nm.6134" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6134" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6134" rank="species">Leifsonia poae</organism><reference id="rid.3461"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Subbotin</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia poae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from nematode galls on Poa annua, and reclassification of 'Corynebacterium aquaticum' Leifson 1962 as Leifsonia aquatica (ex Leifson 1962) gen. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov. and Clavibacter xyli Davis et al. 1984 with two subspecies as Leifsonia xyli (Davis et al. 1984) gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>371</fpage><lpage>380</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826825</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leifsonia poae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leifsonia poae</i> (po'a.e. M.L. gen. n. <i>poae</i> of Poa, generic name of the annual meadow grass, <i>Poa annua</i>, the source of the type strain of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colonies on CB agar are yellowish to deep yellow with age, circular, somewhat convex, glistening, opaque and butyrous.</s><s>The young culture (16-24 h) consists of Gram-positive, curved long cells or filaments (length 8-15 μm, width 0.6-0.9 μm) with primary branching; after 3-4 d cultivation on CB agar, they break up into shorter irregular fragments (length 2.0-2.5 μm), which are usually motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Cells with clubbed ends are frequently seen.</s><s>In old cultures, pleomorphic rods are predominant and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains with diphtheroid arrangements.</s><s>Growth occurs between 7 and 37 °C; the optimum is 24-28 °C.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase, tested by using 1% (w/v) tetramethyl-<i>p</i>-phenylenediamine solution, is negative.</s><s>D-Arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, dulcitol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, methyl α-dglucopyranoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources in mineral medium supplemented with 0.1% (w/v) yeast extract and 0.1%(w/v) casitone.</s><s>Adonitol, dextran, D-fucose, inositol, inulin, lyxose, melezitose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, sorbitol, sorbose, ribose and trehalose are not utilized as the only carbon source in the same medium.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, mannose and sucrose, but not from melibiose.</s><s>An alkaline reaction is observed with α-keto-1-glutarate, malate, malonate and propionate, but no reaction occurs with citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, oxalate, succinate or tartrate.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are decomposed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, xanthine, casein, Tween 40, Tween 60 and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Sensitive to 5% (w/v) NaCl, doxycycline (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and erycycline (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), but tolerant to potassium tellurite at 0.02% (w/v) and the following antibiotics:ampicillin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), chloramphenicol (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gentamicin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gramicidin G (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), lincomycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), neomycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), penicillin G (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), rifampicin (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and tetracycline (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Cell wall sugars consist of a predominant amount of rhamnose and minor amounts of glucose, galactose and mannose.</s><s>No teichoic acids are present in the cell wall.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-11.</s><s>Other salient chemotaxonomic characteristics are as given above in the genus description.</s><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-1401<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Isolated from <i>Poa annua</i> root gall induced by the grass root gall nematode <i>Subanguina radicicola</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>