<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1363_nm.6104" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6104" rank="genus">Clavibacter</organism><reference id="rid.1363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillaspie</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clavibacter: a new genus containing some phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria, including Clavibacter xyli subsp. xyli sp. nov., subsp. nov. and Clavibacter xyli subsp. cynodontis subsp. nov., pathogens that cause ratoon stunting disease of sugarcane and bermudagrass stunting disease.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clavibacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clavibacter</i> (Cla.vi.bac'ter. L. n. <i>clava</i> cudgel; Gr. masc. n. <i>bakter</i> rod; N. L. masc. n. <i>Clavibacter</i> club-shaped rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, non-acid-fast, pleomorphic rods which are often arranged at an angle to give V formations; a marked rodcoccus cycle is not observed.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is ca. 20 to 29°C; maximum growth temperature is ca. 29 to 35°C.</s><s>Growth occurs on suitable solid medium in air.</s><s>Nutritionally exacting.</s><s>Slow and weak oxidative production of acids from some carbohydrates.</s><s>Some organic acids are utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Nitrite is not utilized.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase, tyrosinase, urease, and lipase generally are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains 2,4-diaminobutyric acid.</s><s>Major amounts of rhamnose but not arabinose are found in the cell wall.</s><s>Does not contain mycolic acids.</s><s>Non-hydroxylated fatty acids consist predominantly of <i>anteiso</i>- and <i>isomethyl</i> branched chains; minor amounts of straight-chain saturated acids are found.</s><s>Respiratory quinones are menaquinones.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is about 70 ± 5 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Clavibacter michiganense</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics which can be used to differentiate the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains from the reference strains, which include most of the type strains of the phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria, are listed in Table 3.</s><s>The slow growth and fastidious nature of the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains relative to the reference strains are obvious differential characteristics; the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains grow only in media that were specifically developed for them in both this study and previous studies (10, 30).</s><s>The inability of all sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains to produce acid from sucrose and the distinct serological properties of these organisms (11) also distinguish them from all other strains examined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In our opinion, the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains clearly form distinct taxa in the new genus <i>Clavibacter</i> on the basis of their morphological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>We believe that the differences between the strains from sugarcane and the strains from Bermudagrass are insufficient to warrant establishment of separate species.</s><s>However, the two groups are distinct and thus, in our opinion, warrant subspecies status.</s><s>Characteristics of the sugarcane strains which distinguish them from the Bermudagrass strains are their characteristic protein bands in polyacrylamide gels, slower growth rate on SC agar, small maximum colony size on SC agar, white color (as opposed to yellow pigmentation), and inability to utilize citrate and malate.</s><s>Descriptions of the new taxa are given below.</s></p></content></protolog>