<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4598_nm.8354" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8354" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8354" rank="species">Fusobacterium equinum</organism><reference id="rid.4598"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lovet</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium equinum sp. nov., from the oral cavity of horses.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1959</fpage><lpage>1963</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760934</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium equinum</i> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium equinum</i> (e.quin'um. L. adj. <i>equinum</i> of horses)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On sheep-blood agar after 2 d, colonies are circular with an entire to undulate margin, convex to umbonate, 1-2 mm in diameter and creamish in colour.</s><s>Gram staining of single colonies on primary plates reveals pleomorphic Gram-negative rods (coccobacilli to rods, with rounded ends and curved rods often with irregular staining) but, on subculture, coccobacilli and short rods predominate.</s><s>When subcultured to cookedmeat medium and following overnight incubation, a large amount of flocculent deposit results.</s><s>In Gram staining from broth, short rods are the predominant forms.</s><s>The terminal pH in glucose liquid medium ranges from pH 6.8 to 7.0.</s><s>On GLC analysis, acetic, propionic and butyric acids are produced (respective means 23.1, 15.0 and 36.5 μmol ml<sup>-1</sup>) and lactate and threonine are converted to propionate.</s><s>The isolates produce indole and grow in bile to 2<sup>+</sup> to 4<sup>+</sup> turbidity and are non-motile, fail to hydrolyse aesculin and starch and fail to liquefy gelatin or liquefy it weakly (VPB 4027<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The isolates fail to ferment aesculin, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, starch and sucrose.</s><s>Strains VPB 4027<sup>T</sup> and VPB 4014 possess the constitutive enzymes acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase, butyrate esterase and caprylate esterase.</s><s>Trypsin, chymotrypsin and other enzymes detected by API ZYMare not expressed constitutively in this system.</s><s>They do not haemagglutinate chicken erythrocytes.</s><s>Their mobility for glutamate dehydrogenase is 2.3 cm compared with 3.0 cm for <i>Fusobacterium necrophorum</i> ATCC 25286<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>They are lipase- and lecithinase-positive.</s><s>On broth disc sensitivity tests, all isolates are sensitive to penicillin G, amoxycillin, chloramphenicol, doxycycline and metronidazole; all strains except VPB 4076 and VPB 4014 are sensitive to erythromycin.</s><s>The G­C content of DNA is 29-31 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The mean DNA-DNA hybridization of strains VPB 4014 and VPB 4027<sup>T</sup> with the other equine isolates is respectively 88 and 82%.</s><s>With the exception of VPB 4022, the isolates have DNA-DNA hybridization with labelled DNA from either VPB 4027<sup>T</sup> or VPB 4014 of 80%, which shows that the isolates form a tight genetic cluster.</s><s>This is supported by 16S rDNA phylogenetic analysis with other members of the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VPB 4027<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 13176<sup>T</sup>=JCM11174<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from pus obtained from a discharging sinus associated with a purulent paraoral lesion in a horse. <i>Fusobacterium equinum</i> can be distinguished phenotypically from those members of the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i> that convert threonine and lactate to propionate by a combination of characteristics included in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>