<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6443_nm.8259" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8259" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8259" rank="species">Flexibacter ovolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6443"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bergh</surname><given-names>Ø.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Michaelsen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Knappskog</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flexibacter ovolyticus sp. nov., a pathogen of eggs and larvae of Atlantic halibut, Hippoglossus hippoglossus L.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>451</fpage><lpage>458</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-451</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503974</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flexibacter ovolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flexibacter ovolyticus</i> (ō'vō.lyt.ic'us. L.n. <i>ovum</i>, egg, Gr.n. <i>lysis</i>, loosening or dissolution; <i>ovolyticus</i>, egg damaging)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram-negative, long, slender rods (0.4 by 2 to 20 μm) which occasionally grow to filaments that are 70 to 100 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are Kovacs oxidase positive and pale yellow.</s><s>Microcysts are not formed.</s><s>The cells exhibit gliding motility, do not adsorb Congo red, and do not possess a flexirubin type of pigment. <i>F. ovolyticus</i> is strictly aerobic and does not produce acid from carbohydrates.</s><s>It degrades gelatin, tyrosine, DNA, and Tween 80, but starch, cellulose, and chitin are not degraded. <i>F. ovolyticus</i> possesses catalase and nitrate reductase activities.</s><s>H2S is not produced, and 50% seawater is required for growth.</s><s>Alternatively, media based on artificial seawater containing at least 1% NaCl may be used. <i>F. ovolyticus</i> grows at 4°C, but not at 30°C.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of strains EKC001, EKD002<sup>T</sup>, and VKBOO4 range from 30.3 to 32.0 mol%.</s><s>Additional characteristics of <i>F. ovolyticus</i> are shown in Tables 1, 2, and 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain EKD002 (=NCIMB 13127) was isolated in 1989 from the adherent epiflora of halibut eggs at the Austevoll Aquaculture Research Station in western Norway.</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to the species description.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 30.3 mol%.</s><s>In addition to the type strain, strains EKCOOl and -004 have been deposited in the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria as strains NCIMB 13128 and NCIMB 13129, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>