<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5867_nm.5554" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5554" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5554" rank="species">Enterococcus villorum</organism><reference id="rid.5867"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Descheemaeker</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goossens</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus villorum sp. nov., an enteroadherent bacterium associated with diarrhoea in piglets.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>393</fpage><lpage>400</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321084</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus villorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus villorum</i> (vil.lo'rum. L. n. <i>villus</i> rough hair, anatomical term for flocculate structures in the small intestine; gen. pl. <i>villorum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are Gram-positive, non-sporulating and nonmotile cocci.</s><s>Colonies grow on azide-containing enterococcal selective media, on bile/aesculin agar and in 6.5% NaCl broth.</s><s>Colonies on Slanetz-Bartley medium are pink and develop slowly.</s><s>All strains are alpha-haemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains react positively in the following tests : Voges-Proskauer, β-glucosidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase, leucine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, hydrolysis of aesculin, 4-methylumbelliferyl (MU) β-D-glucoside, 4-MU Nacetyl β-D-glucosaminide, L-phenylalanine 7-amido-4- methyl-coumarin (AMC), L-pyroglutamic acid AMC, L-tryptophan AMC, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucoside, pnitrophenyl β-D-cellobioside, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl β-dgalactoside and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl α-D-galactoside.</s><s>All strains produce acid from amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, glycerol (weak and only visible after 2 d), D-glucose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-fructose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, ribose, salicin and trehalose.</s><s>All strains are negative in the amylase plate test, in tests for catalase, hippurate hydrolysis, alkaline phosphatase, β-glucuronidase, bmannosidase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, hydrolysis of L-valine AMC, 4-MU α-dglucoside, L-arginine AMC, 4-MU phosphate, 4-MU β-D-glucuronide, L-isoleucine AMC, <i>p</i>nitrophenyl phosphate, proline- and leucine-<i>p</i>nitroanilide, urease and acid production from adonitol, D- and L- arabitol, D- and L-arabinose, D-cyclodextrin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, dulcitol, erythritol, D- and L-fucose, amethyl D-glucoside, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, maltotriose, mannitol, α-methyl D-mannoside, melezitose, pullulan, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-tagatose, xylitol, L-xylose and β-methyl dxyloside.</s><s>Four strains produce acid from D-xylose and three strains react positively in the p-nitrophenyl α-dmaltoside test.</s><s>These tests were the only variable reactions noted.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to the aminoglycoside antibiotic tobramycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms examined were isolated from pigs and originate from three different countries.</s><s>Adhesion to enterocytes is a prominent characteristic of at least three of the strains studied.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 12287<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from the gut of a piglet in Canada and was associated with neonatal diarrhoea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 35.1-35.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection (Laboratorium voor Microbiologie Gent, Gent, Belgium) and the type strain has been deposited in the Czech Collection of Microorganisms (Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic).</s></p></content></protolog>