<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1801_nm.4749" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4749" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4749" rank="species">Ureaplasma diversum</organism><reference id="rid.1801"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Howard</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gourlay</surname><given-names>R.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for a second species within the genus Ureaplasma, Ureaplasma diversum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>446</fpage><lpage>452</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-4-446</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ureaplasma diversum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ureaplasma diversum</i> sp. nov. (L. adj. diversus different, distinct, heterogeneous; referring to the difference in polypeptides and G+C content, compared to <i>U . urealyticum</i>, and to the heterogeneous antigenic structure of the species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results presented here indicate that strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>A417 should be classified in the genus <i>Ureaplasma</i>, but that this strain and other similar isolates from cattle are sufficiently distinct from the type strain of <i>U . urealyticum</i> and other similar human isolates to be regarded as a second species within the genus <i>Ureaplasma</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology of cells of strain A417 and the form of the colony, the absence of a cell wall, the resistance to penicillin and thallium acetate, the inability to grow at 25°C, the susceptibility to digitonin, the requirement for cholesterol, and the ability to pass through membrane filters indicate that strain A417 should be classified in the family <i>Mycoplasmataceae</i> (7).</s><s>The possession of urease activity, the occurrence of optimum growth at pH 6.0 to 7.0, and the relatively small colony size indicate that this isolate should be classified in the genus <i>Ureaplasma</i> (35).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Since <i>U. urealyticum</i> is considered to be a species comprised of several serovars, it is clear that serological difference alone is not sufficient for proposing new isolates, from whatever source, as separate species.</s><s>Nevertheless, it would seem to be necessary to show that a proposed second species was serologically distinct from the named species <i>U . urealyticum</i>.</s><s>Strain T960, the type strain of <i>U . urealyticum</i>, is a member of serovar VIII.</s><s>Other strains representing serovars I to VII were described at the same time as the type strain (35).</s><s>Some crossreactions occur between certain of the strains proposed as representative of serovars (1, 3, 6), and other strains have been isolated from humans that probably represent further serovars (26, 31).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bovine ureaplasmas appear to exist as three serological clusters defined by rabbit antisera (18, 29) and as three serovars defined by gnotobiotic calf sera (16).</s><s>The three clusters defined by rabbit antisera and the serovars defined by calf sera coincide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A417 is distinct from strain T960 and from members of other <i>U . urealyticum</i> serovars by a variety of serological tests, including MI, GI, and IF.</s><s>In fact, no significant cross-reactions have been demonstrated among the eight <i>U . urealyticum</i> serovars and representative bovine isolates (16, 19, 29).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA from <i>U. urealyticum</i> strain T960 was reported to be 27.1 mol% by Black et al. ( 2 ) .</s><s>Subsequently, the G+C content of strain A417 was reported to be 29.0 mol%.</s><s>In the latter study, strain T960, which was included to make comparisons possible, was reported to have a G+C content of 27.4 mol% (20), a value virtually the same as that published previously.</s><s>Although strains T960 and A417 have G+C contents that are different, the difference is not great.</s><s>However, the range of values for eight <i>U . urealyticum</i> strains is 26.9 to 28.0 mol% ( 2 ) , and this does not overlap the range (28.7 to 30.2 mol%) found for 10 bovine isolates (20, 22).</s><s>These findings indicate that bovine isolates are a population distinct from those isolates classified as <i>U . urealyticum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Furthermore, the polypeptides of strains T960 and A417 are distinct when compared by PAGE.</s><s>This method is considered to be suitable for distinguishing microorganisms at the level of species (7, 24).</s><s>Other human isolates have been shown to have many polypeptides in common with strain T960, whereas other bovine isolates examined have many polypeptides in common with strain A417 but not with the human isolates (23, 34).</s><s>Although some bovine isolates are distinct from strain A417 on the basis of serology, their polypeptides appear similar, and the bovine ureaplasmas are probably best regarded as belonging to one of three groups of the same species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thus, it is proposed that strain A417, which has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures, London, England, as NCTC 10182, should be the type strain of the new species <i>Ureaplasma diversum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>