<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8629_nm.13626" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13626" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13626" rank="species">Streptacidiphilus anmyonensis</organism><reference id="rid.8629"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ko</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptacidiphilus anmyonensis sp. nov., Streptacidiphilus rugosus sp. nov. and Streptacidiphilus melanogenes sp. nov., acidophilic actinobacteria isolated from Pinus soils.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1566</fpage><lpage>1570</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65480-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599696</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptacidiphilus anmyonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptacidiphilus anmyonensis</em> (an.myon.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>anmyonensis</em> of Anmyon, where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms cream-coloured colonies that carry moderate to abundant, white to greyish-white aerial hyphae on acidified oatmeal, ISP 4, ISP 2 and modified Bennett's agar plates.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is brownish grey or brown on acidified oatmeal agar and ISP 2 agar, but cream on ISP 4 agar and modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Aerial hyphae differentiate into long flexuous chains of spores (0.6×0.9 μm); the spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not produced on any of the above-mentioned media.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 3.0–8.0 and 28–35 °C.</s><s>Starch and Tween 80 are degraded, but xanthine and Tweens 20 and 40 are not.</s><s>Glycerol, d-gluconic acid, d(+)-glucosamine hydrochloride, <em>myo</em>-inositol, melibiose, d-sorbitol, sucrose and d(+)-xylose (each at 1 %, w/v) and l-arginine (at 0.1 %, w/v) are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but l-aspartic acid and sodium oxalate (each at 0.1 %, w/v) are not.</s><s>l-Isoleucine is used as a sole nitrogen source.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic properties are typical of those for the genus <em>Streptacidiphilus</em>.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (18.4 % of the total fatty acid composition), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (11.4 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (19.1 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14.7 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (7.4 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (7.5 %).</s><s>Contains hexahydrogenated and octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units [MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>); 24.1 and 55.8 % of the total, respectively] as the predominant isoprenologues.</s><s>The diamino acid of the peptidoglycan is ll-diaminopimelic acid (89 % of the total diaminopimelic acid composition), although a minor amount of the <em>meso</em> isomer (11 %) is also detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species currently includes the type strain AM-11<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 103185<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19278<sup>T</sup>) and strains AM-02, AM-06, AM-08, AM-10, AM-17, AM-18, AM-23, AM-24, AM-25 and AM-30, isolated from <em>Pinus</em>-associated soils from Anmyeon, near the coastal areas of Tae-An, Chungnam, Republic of Korea (Cho <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s></p></content></protolog>