<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2526_nm.11446" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11446" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11446" rank="species">Anderseniella baltica</organism><reference id="rid.2526"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brettar</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bötel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Höfle</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anderseniella baltica gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium of the Alphaproteobacteria isolated from sediment in the central Baltic Sea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2399</fpage><lpage>2405</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65007-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911317</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anderseniella baltica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anderseniella baltica</em> (bal′ti.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>baltica</em> from the Baltic Sea, referring to the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the species description.</s><s>Colonies are small, opaque, circular, smooth, convex and entire.</s><s>Forms dark-red colonies and light to intense orange–red liquid cultures (&#x003E;1 week, 25 °C, half-strength marine broth).</s><s>Cells are partially branching (width 0.5–1.0 μm, length 1.0–5.0 μm).</s><s>Cells form star-like aggregates in liquid culture.</s><s>Grows at oxic to low oxic conditions.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Temperature for growth ranges from 10 to 37 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Salinity range for growth is from 0.8 to 6 % of final concentration of artificial sea salt; addition of NaCl alone is not sufficient for growth.</s><s>Grows at pH 7–7.5; no growth occurs at pH 5.7 or 9.7.</s><s>Grows on 1 % yeast extract and 1 % peptone, but not on aesculin, casein or <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin, tyrosine, DNA, cellulose, chitin or pectin.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Does not grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Acid production is not observed using the API 50 CH test system.</s><s>All API 20NE tests are negative.</s><s>In the API ZYM test system, alkaline phosphatase, esterases (C4 and C8) and leucine arylamidase are positive; all other tests are negative.</s><s>In the Biolog GN2 system, positive results are obtained for l-arabinose, glycerol, alaninamide and the organic acids succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinamic acid and urocanic acid; all other tests are negative.</s><s>In general, the use of organic acids is better than for other substrates.</s><s>All unmentioned tests of the API and Biolog GN2 test systems are negative.</s><s>A detailed overview of all positive and negative test results for the biochemical tests is given in Supplementary Table S1 (in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BA141<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109499<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24028<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface layer of anoxic sediment in the central Baltic Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>