<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4667_nm.928" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.928" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.928" rank="species">Gluconobacter asaii</organism><reference id="rid.4667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Claus</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic characteristics correlated with deoxyribonucleic acid sequence similarities for three species of Gluconobacter: G. oxydans, Henneberg 1897 De Ley 1961, G. frateurii sp. nov., emend G. asaii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>174</fpage><lpage>184</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gluconobacter asaii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gluconobacter asaii</i> (a.sa'i.i. M.L. n. <i>asaii</i>, of Toshinobu Asai, eminent Japanese microbiologist who was the first to distinguish gluconobacters from other acetic acid bacteria, who named this genus, and who spent most of his professional life studying these microorganisms [2])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are as given previously for the genus (7).</s><s>In addition, all strains in this species form a DNA-DNA homology group when colony variant a of strain ATCC 49206<sup>T</sup> (= IFO 3276<sup>T</sup>) is used as the reference strain (14).</s><s>When our methods are used, all strains grow to an OD of 1.0 U or more after 24 h of incubation and three passages (24 h of incubation each) in nicotinate-deficient media (except strain IFO 3297a, which can be characterized by its unique alkalinization of media during growth on mannitol, ribitol, or arabitol), and all strains fail to grow beyond an OD of 0.5 U after 24 h when either ribitol or arabitol is used as the primary carbon source (Table 4).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 52 to 55 mol% (14).</s><s>Representative strains are ATCC 49206<sup>T</sup> (referred to as genetically identical colony variants IFO 3276a and IFO 3276b by Micales et al. [14]) and ATCC 43781 (referred to as strain RS203b by Micales et al. [14]).</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 49206 (= IFO 3276).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Further description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain IFO 3276<sup>T</sup> (as received) contained two genetically identical colony variants, which were called IFO 3276a and 3276b by Micales et al. (14).</s><s>When grown as described in Materials and Methods, colony variant a forms cream-colored, opaque colonies that have convex elevations, glistening, smooth surfaces, entire edges, and diameters of 0.25 mm; when observed from underneath, the colonies exhibit brightly highlighted edges that extend about one-fourth of the way across the colony diameter.</s><s>In contrast, when colony variant b is grown in the same way, it forms more translucent colonies having diameters of 0.50 mm and lacking brightly highlighted edges when viewed from underneath.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony variants a and b were easily separated by Micales et al. (14), and each variant kept its colony characteristics through many transfers and storage on either slants or 66% glycerol during the study reported here.</s><s>The DNA-DNA homology study (14) demonstrated that colony types a and b are genetically identical colony variants, and our studies show that they have the same diagnostic phenotypic characteristics.</s><s>Note, however, that colony variant purity has not been easy to maintain or reachieve.</s><s>For example, when colony variant a was purified, stored in liquid nitrogen for 5 years, and then recently streaked for purity, about 25% of the separated colonies were colony variant b; after eight subsequent transfers, we were unable to achieve separation of the two colony variants.</s><s>Strain IFO 3276<sup>T</sup> (containing colony variants a and b) has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49206<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to having the characteristics described previously for the genus (7), strain ATCC 49206<sup>T</sup> (colony variant IFO 3276a) has six differential characteristics.</s><s>The following three characteristics were previously demonstrated by Micales et al.: (i) 14% DNA-DNA homology with the type strain of the type species of the genus, strain ATCC 19357 (Micales, M.S. thesis); (ii) 22% DNA-DNA homology with the group II (<i>G. frateurii</i>) reference strain IFO 3264<sup>T</sup> (14); and (iii) 70% DNA-DNA homology with strain RS203b (14), another group 111 strain (<i>G. asaii</i>) recently deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 43781.</s><s>Three other characteristics of colony variant IFO 3276a were demonstrated in the work reported here.</s><s>When colony variant IFO 3276a is grown according to our methods, it grows to an OD of 1.9 U or more after three passages (24 h of incubation each) in nicotinate-deficient media (Table 5); it grows to an OD of 0.31 U or less after 24 h of incubation in media containing ribitol (Table 3); and it fails to grow on arabitol as the primary carbon source (Table 3).</s><s>The latter three characteristics were also found with colony variant IFO 3276b (Jones-Mason, M.S. thesis), except that the growth of colony variant b on ribitol was slightly greater (OD varied from 0.36 to 0.47 U in three separate experiments).</s><s>In addition to the six differential characteristics noted above, Mason (Jones-Mason, M.S. thesis) demonstrated that colony variant IFO 3276a has the additional properties described below (when it is grown according to our methods).</s><s>When <i>myo</i>-inositol, glucose, and xylitol are used separately as the primary carbon sources, this strain grows to OD values of more than 0.9, 1.6, and 2.3 U, respectively, within 24 h.</s><s>However, this colony variant does not grow to OD values of more than 0.25 U after 24 h in media containing sucrose as the primary carbon source.</s><s>In media containing 17% glucose or 1.0% NaCl, the colony variant grows to OD values of 1.40 or 2.13 U, respectively, after 48 h of incubation.</s></p></content></protolog>