<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9585_nm.14775" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14775" rank="species">Ferruginibacter lapsinanis</organism><reference id="rid.9585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ferruginibacter alkalilentus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Ferruginibacter lapsinanis sp. nov., novel members of the family ‘Chitinophagaceae’ in the phylum Bacteroidetes, isolated from freshwater sediment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2394</fpage><lpage>2399</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009480-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ferruginibacter lapsinanis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ferruginibacter lapsinanis</em> (lap.si′na.nis. L. n. <em>lapsus</em> <em>-us</em> gliding; L. adj. <em>inanis</em> void; N.L. masc. adj. void of gliding motility)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown on R2A at 30 °C for 5 days are single, short rods, 1−2 μm long and 0.3−0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies are circular and convex with an entire margin, slimy, translucent, glossy, rusty in colour, and reach 1−2.2 mm in diameter after 5 days incubation.</s><s>Growth occurs at 18−30 °C and at pH 6−8 with less than 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth on either MacConkey agar or nutrient agar (Difco).</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, nitrite reduction and acetoin production from pyruvate are not observed.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, skim milk and urea are hydrolysed, but hydroxyethylcellulose, DNA, starch and xylan are not.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose or d-sucrose.</s><s>Activity for arginine dihydrolase is present, but activities for lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are not. l-Leucyl-2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthylphosphate (pH 8.5) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate (weakly) are hydrolysed, but <em>N</em>-benzoyl-dl-arginine 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthylbutyrate, l-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-glutarylphenylalanine 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl-<em>α</em>-l-fucopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, l-naphthyl-<em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide and l-valyl-2-naphthylamide are not.</s><s>Only citrate among the substrates tested is utilized as sole carbon source and the following compounds are not: acetate, adipate, adonitol, l-alanine, amygdalin, d-arabinose, benzoate, caprate, d-cellobiose, dextran, formate, d-fructose, l-fucose, fumarate, d-galactose, gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucose, glutarate, glycogen, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, inulin, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, dl-lactate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, malate, maleate, malonate, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, oxalate, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, pyruvate, d-raffinose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-serine, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, suberate, succinate, d-sucrose, tartrate, d-trehalose, tyrosine, valerate, xylitol and l-xylose.</s><s>Additional characteristics are listed in Tables 1–3 and the genus description, or described elsewhere in the text.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HU1-HG42<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22305<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24324<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from freshwater sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>