<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8396_nm.13235" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13235" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13235" rank="species">Bacillus cecembensis</organism><reference id="rid.8396"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uttam</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus cecembensis sp. nov., isolated from the Pindari glacier of the Indian Himalayas.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2330</fpage><lpage>2335</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65515-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842851</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus cecembensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus cecembensis</em> (ce.cem.ben′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>cecembensis</em> arbitrary name derived from the acronym CCMB for the Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology, where the type strain was characterized).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are irregular, opaque and flat and cells are Gram-positive, motile, rod-shaped (3.5 μm long and 1.25 μm wide), peritrichously flagellated and possess round, terminally located spores.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C with optimum growth at 25 °C.</s><s>Positive for catalase, lipase, phosphatase, urease, ornithine decarboxylase, nitrate reduction and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (nitrate reduction and <em>β</em>-galactosidase negative on HiMedia kits) but negative for oxidase, lysine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deamination, indole production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests and hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin and starch.</s><s>Utilizes trehalose, glucosamine and citrate but not d-glucose, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, galactose, mannose, d-mannitol, d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-rhamnose, dulcitol, <em>myo-</em>inositol, sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, d-glucuronic acid, sucrose, dextran, sodium gluconate, malonate, l-isoleucine, l-glutamine, l-alanine, l-threonine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-lysine, l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-histidine, l-leucine or l-aspartic acid.</s><s>Cells are resistant to (μg per disc unless indicated) nalidixic acid (30) and streptomycin (10) but sensitive to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), bacitracin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefazolin (30), cefuroxime (30), cefoperazone (75), cefotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), colistin (10), co-trimoxazole (25), doxycycline (10), erythromycin (15), gentamicin G (30), kanamycin (30), leucomycin (30), lomefloxacin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), norfloxacin (10), novobiocin (30), oleandomycin (15), penicillin G (10), polymyxin B (50 U), rifampicin (30), roxithromycin (30), spectinomycin (100), tetracycline (30), tobramycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains lysine, glutamic acid and alanine, representing peptidoglycan type A4<em>α</em>.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and a compound that co-migrates with phosphatidylcholine; the predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is detailed in Table 2.</s><s>Phylogenetically, a member of <em>Bacillus</em> RNA group 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PN5<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23935<sup>T</sup> =MTCC9127<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15113<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from soil samples collected at an altitude of approximately 3500 m near the Pindari glacier of the Indian Himalayas.</s></p></content></protolog>