<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4564_nm.1673" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1673" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1673" rank="species">Ralstonia basilensis</organism><reference id="rid.4564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Diels</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergeay</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of metal-resistant bacteria from industrial biotopes as Ralstonia campinensis sp. nov., Ralstonia metallidurans sp. nov. and Ralstonia basilensis Steinle et al. 1998 emend.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1773</fpage><lpage>1782</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of Ralstonia basilensis Steinle et al. 1998</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are short, motile rods (0.8x1.2-2.2 μm), single, in pairs or in short chains, forming round (sometimes with a slightly scalloped margin), smooth, convex and transparent colonies of about 0.5 mm diameter after 24 h of incubation on TSA at 30 °C. Oxidase- and catalase-positive. Grows at 4, 20, 30 and 37 °C, but no growth detected at 41 °C. No nitrate or nitrite reduction (except strain SV884, which reduces nitrate but not nitrite). No indole production from tryptophan. No glucose fermentation. Enzyme activities detected: alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase (weak) and naphthoL-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase. Enzyme activities not detected: arginine dihydrolase, urease (ER8 and KS1 give a weak reaction after 48 h), α-glucosidase, protease, β-galactosidase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, achymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase. Assimilation of D-gluconate, caprate, adipate, L-malate, citrate and phenylacetate. No assimilation of D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl D-glucosamine or maltose. The DNA G­C content is 65.0-65.5 mol%. Major fatty acid components are 14:0 (4.5%), 16:0 (20.6%), 17:0 cyclo (1.3%), 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> (24.7%), 16:1 2OH (1.8%), 18:1 2OH (4.8%), summed feature 2 (9.0%) and summed feature 3 (32.9%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RK1<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 18990<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19474<sup>T</sup>=DSM 11853<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a freshwater pond sediment at Amponville, France, after enrichment in a fixed-bed reactor with 2,6-dichlorophenol as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Its DNA G+­C content is 65.0 mol% and its phenotypic characteristics are as described above for the species.</s><s>The accession number of the 16S rRNA gene sequence of DSM 11853<sup>T</sup> is AF312022.</s></p></content></protolog>