<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12448_nm.21274" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21274" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21274" rank="species">Halogranum amylolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.12448"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>H.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goa</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halogranum gelatinilyticum sp. nov. and Halogranum amylolyticum sp. nov., isolated from a marine solar saltern, and emended description of the genus Halogranum</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>911</fpage><lpage>915</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024976-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495026</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halogranum amylolyticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halogranum amylolyticum</em> [a.my.lo.ly′ti.cum. Gr. n. <em>amylon</em> starch; N.L. neut. adj. <em>lyticum</em> (from Gr. neut. adj. <em>lutikon</em>) able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. neut. adj. <em>amylolyticum</em> starch-dissolving, referring to the property of being able to hydrolyse starch].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, pleomorphic – showing different shapes (irregular cocci and ovals, mean cell dimensions 1–2 µm) under optimal growth conditions – and stain Gram-negative.</s><s>Colonies on agar plates containing 3.4 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–50 °C (optimum 37 °C), in the presence of 1.4–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 3.4 M NaCl) and 0–1.0 M MgCl<sub>2</sub> (optimum 0.05 M MgCl<sub>2</sub>), and at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum pH 6.5).</s><s>Cells lyse in distilled water and the minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 8 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from sodium thiosulfate.</s><s>Indole formation is positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch but not gelatin, casein or Tween 80.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, starch, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, pyruvate, dl-lactate, succinate, l-malate, fumarate, glycine, l-alanine, l-glutamate and l-ornithine.</s><s>No growth occurs on d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-xylose, citrate, l-arginine, l-aspartate or l-lysine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, maltose, sucrose and lactose.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), anisomycin (20), aphidicolin (20) and rifampicin (5).</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).</s><s>The polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me, trace PGS, and one major glycolipid and one minor glycolipid chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1 and DGD-1, respectively; two trace unidentified glycolipids may be present.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.0 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TNN58<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.10121<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16428<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Tainan marine solar saltern near Lianyungang city, Jiangsu province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>