<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2790_nm.2943" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2943" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2943" rank="species">Teredinibacter turnerae</organism><reference id="rid.2790"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Distel</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morrill</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>MacLaren-Toussaint</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franks</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Waterbury</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Teredinibacter turnerae gen. nov., sp. nov., a dinitrogen-fixing, cellulolytic, endosymbiotic gamma-proteobacterium isolated from the gills of wood-boring molluscs (Bivalvia: Teredinidae).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2261</fpage><lpage>2269</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02184-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508896</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Teredinibacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Teredinibacter</i> (Ter.e.din.i.bac'ter. N.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Teredinidae</i> a family of wood-boring bivalve molluscs (shipworms); N.L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, equivalent of <i>bacterium</i>, a staff or rod; N.L. masc. n. <i>Teredinibacter</i> a rod isolated from members of the family <i>Teredinidae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rigid, Gram-negative rods of 0.4-0.6 μm in width and 3-6 μm in length during exponential-phase growth on SBM medium with cellulose as a carbon source.</s><s>Division is by binary fission in a single plane.</s><s>Motile by means of single polar flagellum.</s><s>In stationary-phase cultures, cells often become pleomorphic, appearing spiraled or as very long rods.</s><s>Occur in nature as long rods associated with the gill system of teredinid molluscs.</s><s>Aerobic chemoheterotrophs that grow in a simple mineral medium containing seawater and a suitable carbon and energy source (e.g. cellulose, simple sugars and organic acids).</s><s>Require a source of combined nitrogen if vigorously aerated but will fix dinitrogen when grown in the absence of combined nitrogen under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>Analysis of their 16S rDNA indicates that the genus belongs to a unique clade of the <i>γ-Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Type species is <i>Teredinibacter turnerae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>