<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12339_nm.20368" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20368" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20368" rank="species">Marinobacterium coralli</organism><reference id="rid.12339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chimetto</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brocchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacterium coralli sp. nov., isolated from mucus of coral (Mussismilia hispida)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>60</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021105-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20154332</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacterium coralli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacterium coralli</em> (co.ral′li. L. gen. n. <em>coralli</em> of coral, from which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, moderately halophilic, aerobic, motile, straight rods approximately 1 μm wide and 2–5 μm long.</s><s>Catalase-negative and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, slightly undulate, convex, smooth, beige translucent in colour and 0.8 mm in size after 1 day of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Prolific growth occurs between 20 and 40 °C and at NaCl concentrations ranging from 1 to 7 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth is observed in 0 % NaCl, in ≥10 % NaCl, at ≤7 °C or at ≥43 °C.</s><s>Shows alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities and produces acetoin (Voges–Proskauer).</s><s>Capable of assimilating methyl pyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline and phenylethylamine.</s><s>Weak reactions were observed for hydrolysis of Tween 40 and Tween 80 and for assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, citric acid, alaninamide, l-asparagine and l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Negative for: esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, gelatinase and tryptophan deaminase activities; H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production; reduction of nitrate and nitrite to N<sub>2</sub> gas; fermentation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose; and assimilation of citrate, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate and trisodium citrate.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in small amounts: C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (Supplementary Table S1 available in IJSEM Online).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R-40509<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25435<sup>T</sup> =CAIM 1449<sup>T</sup>), isolated from mucus of the endemic coral <em>Mussismilia hispida</em> located in the São Sebastião channel, SP, Brazil.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.5 mol%.</s><s>The phenotypic profile of <em>M. coralli</em> is at present based on one strain.</s><s>As more strains of this species are isolated and tested, the profile may change slightly.</s></p></content></protolog>