<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7371_nm.8189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8189" rank="species">Riemerella columbina</organism><reference id="rid.7371"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torck</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Riemerella columbina sp. nov., a bacterium associated with respiratory disease in pigeons</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>295</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Riemerella columbina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Riemerella columbina</i> (co.lum.bi'na. L. fem. adj. <i>columbina</i> pertaining to pigeons)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>R. columbina</i> is as for the genus, with the following specifications which allow differentiation of the newly described species from the type species <i>R. anatipestifer</i>.</s><s>On Columbia blood agar, all strains showed good growth when incubated aerobically at 37°C and microaerobically at 24, 37 and 42°C and produced a grey-white or beige pigment (<i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains are nonpigmented).</s><s>None of the strains grew anaerobically at 37°C and no growth was observed on litmus lactose agar (variable features for <i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains).</s><s>All strains tested hydrolysed aesculin (negative for <i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains).</s><s>When using the API ID32E system, all strains showed a positive β-glucosidase activity (negative for <i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains; this reaction was, however, negative for <i>R. columbina</i> strains in the API ZYM system).</s><s>None of the strains produced indole and all strains showed chymotrypsin activity (variable reactions for <i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains).</s><s>Using the BSS test, all strains produced acid from D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose and dextrin (variable reactions for <i>R. anatipestifer</i>).</s><s>A variable reaction (negative or weakly positive reaction) was obtained for the acid production of D-fructose and L-sorbose.</s><s>The dominant fatty acid content consists of the branched-chain fatty acids 13:0 iso, 13:0 anteiso, 15:0 iso, 15:0 anteiso, 15:0 iso 3-OH and 17:0 iso 3-OH and 'summed feature 4'.</s><s>Isolated from respiratory disease in pigeons.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 11607<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from a pigeon palatine cleft in Germany.</s><s>Its G + C content is 36 mol %.</s></p></content></protolog>