<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12400_nm.21225" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21225" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21225" rank="species">Leucobacter salsicius</organism><reference id="rid.12400"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yun</surname><given-names>J-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>K-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leucobacter salsicius sp. nov., from a salt-fermented food</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>502</fpage><lpage>506</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021360-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20363927</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leucobacter salsicius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leucobacter salsicius</em> (sal.si′ci.us. L. masc. adj. <em>salsicius</em> salted, salty).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms circular, cream-coloured colonies with entire margins.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-reaction-positive, non-motile (on semi-solid agar medium) rods, 1.0–1.5 μm long.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–30 °C and at pH 7.0–8.0 and in the presence of 0–4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 10.0 mM Cr(VI).</s><s>Produces esterase C4, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Does not produce alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase C8, lipase C14, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate to nitrite and does not produce indole.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, aesculin, Tweens 20, 40 and 60 and <em>p-</em>nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, urea, gelatin or Tween 80.</s><s>Negative for d-glucose fermentation, l-arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, d-ribose, d-glucose, inositol, d-sorbitol, aesculin, salicin, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, starch, turanose, d-lyxose, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate but not erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol or gluconate.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains DAB, alanine, glycine, glutamic acid and GABA.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.8 mol%.</s><s>Polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M1-8<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 21127<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16362<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from jeotgal, a Korean salt-fermented food containing tiny shrimps.</s></p></content></protolog>