<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6004_nm.1328" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1328" rank="genus">Ensifer</organism><reference id="rid.6004"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Casida</surname><given-names>L.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ensifer adhaerens gen. nov., sp. nov.: a bacterial predator of bacteria in soil.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>345</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ensifer</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ensifer</i> (L. adj. <i>ensifer</i> sword bearing; M. L. mas. noun <i>Ensifer</i> sword bearer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative, but may stain poorly.</s><s>Rods 0.7 to 1.1 by 1.0 to 1.9 μm, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of a tuft of three to five flagella that are attached subterminally.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reproduction by budding at one end of the cell, with the bud then elongating to give asymmetric polar growth.</s><s>Separation of the cells occurs by binary fission.</s><s>After fission, growth resumes as new buds at the newly formed poles of both the mother and daughter cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Attaches end-wise to various living gram-positive and gram-negative host bacteria.</s><s>There is no specialized terminal structure on the cell for attachment purposes.</s><s>Rosettes are not formed.</s><s>Depending on the pH (pH 6 is best), the nutritive level of the environment, and the species of host cell, the host cells may be killed, and often they are also lysed. <i>M. luteus</i> is a good host for demonstrating this phenomenon.</s><s>Attachment to and lysis of bacterial cells occur naturally in soil and in vitro with pure cultures.</s><s>Not an obligate predator and not fastidious in its nutritional requirements.</s><s>On agar media produces a diffusible factor for lysis of host cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 6 days, colonies 10 to 15 mm in diameter are produced on heart infusion agar prepared at Moth the recommended strength.</s><s>The colonies are grayish white, convex, circular with undulate margins, slimy, moist, and opaque; they may appear almost translucent due to excessive slime production.</s><s>Growth on agar slants is abundant, opaque, grayish white, smooth, flat, slimy, and moist.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth occurs at around 27°C; good growth occurs at 20 and 37°C.</s><s>Aerobic; does not grow anaerobically in the presence of light.</s><s>Pellicle and sediment (little turbidity) are produced in PYG broth.</s><s>Weakly catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced.</s><s>Nitrification is negative for ammonia and nitrite.</s><s>Acetylene is not reduced.</s><s>The metabolism (4) of glucose and galactose is oxidative; no growth occurs under petrolatum; in the absence of petrolatum, gas is not produced, and only trace amounts of acid, if any, are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Definite but slow growth occurs during sequential transfers on 1.5% Noble agar in distilled water.</s><s>Host cells are not required, and agar is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>This growth is equivalent to that obtained on soil extract agar.</s><s>Grows well on most media.</s><s>A good synthetic medium contains 0.1% glucose, 0.1% NH<sub>4</sub>NO<sub>3</sub>, 0.1% KH<sub>2</sub>PO<sub>4</sub>, 0.1% MgSO<sub>4</sub>-7H20, 0.1% NaCl, 0.1% L-glutamic acid, and 1.5% agar (pH 7.0).</s><s>Utilizes a variety of organic carbon sources, including glucose, galactose, mannose, rhamnose, xylose, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, L-glutamic acid, L-alanine, L-asparagine, and L-glutamine.</s><s>Acetate is used only slowly and does not inhibit glucose utilization.</s><s>Grows on pure gelatin without hydrolysis.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 4% NaCl; good growth is obtained with 2% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on blood agar; nonhemolytic.</s><s>Good growth also occurs on Desoxycholate agar; initially the growth is whitish purple and then changes to buff.</s><s>Does not survive 30 s of heating in tap water at 71°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>Attaches to other bacteria in soil and sometimes lyses them.</s><s>Can be present (attached to the cells) in cultures of other bacteria isolated from soil; can be removed from these cultures by growth on media containing 4% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 67 mol% (as determined by the thermal melting point) or 63 mol% (as determined by buoyant density).</s></p></content></protolog>