<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.734_nm.9417" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9417" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9417" rank="species">Bacillus malacitensis</organism><reference id="rid.734"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ruiz-García</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urdaci</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus axarquiensis sp. nov. and Bacillus malacitensis sp. nov., isolated from river-mouth sediments in southern Spain.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1279</fpage><lpage>1285</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63567-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus malacitensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus malacitensis</em> (ma.la.ci.ten′sis. L. adj. masc. <em>malacitensis</em> pertaining to Flavia Malacita, the Roman name for Málaga in southern Spain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, round-ended rods (2·0×0·5 μm), occurring singly or in pairs and occasionally in short chains or filaments.</s><s>They are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>The endospores are mainly ellipsoidal and lie in subterminal positions in non-swollen sporangia.</s><s>They do not contain parasporal crystals or accumulate PHB.</s><s>When grown on TSA the colonies are cream-coloured, slightly irregular in shape and bulge upward.</s><s>When the medium is supplemented with salt the colonies become mucous.</s><s>In liquid medium a thin film is formed at the surface whilst the rest of the medium is uniformly cloudy.</s><s>The bacterium grows within the temperature range of 15 to 45 °C and pH values of between 5 and 10.</s><s>It is halotolerant, being capable of growing in salt concentrations (mixture of sea salts) of 0 to 12 % w/v.</s><s>Optimum growth is at 32 °C, pH 7·2 and 0·5 % sea salts.</s><s>It produces surfactants.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>It reduces nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>Starch, DNA, Tween 20, Tween 80, gelatin, casein and lecithin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Haemolysis and ONPG hydrolysis are positive.</s><s>Tyrosine and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Reactions for pigment production on tyrosine medium, gas from carbohydrates, H<sub>2</sub>S from sodium thiosulphate, arginine dihydrolase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase are negative.</s><s>Dihydroxyacetone production, indole and methyl-red are negative.</s><s>Phenylalanine and tryptophan deaminase are not produced.</s><s>Growth on MacConkey agar and growth with citrate as sole carbon and energy source are not viable.</s><s>It grows in the presence of lysozyme and in media without yeast extract.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer is positive.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Acids are produced from the following sugars: glycerol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, glucose, fructose, mannose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch and glycogen.</s><s>It does not produce acids from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>It is susceptible to amoxicillin (2 μg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (30 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), colistin (10 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), norfloxacin (5 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), trimethoprim/sulfametoxazol (1·25/23·7 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>It is resistant to aztreonan (30 μg) and ceftazidime (30 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids (%) are 15 : 0 anteiso (37·5), 17 : 0 iso (15·9) and 17 : 0 anteiso (15·8).</s><s>It has menaquinone MK-7 as principal quinone compounds.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 41·0 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CR-95<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5687<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22477<sup>T</sup>), isolated from brackish sediments taken from the mouth of the river Vélez in the province of Málaga in southern Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>