<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12785_nm.22570" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22570" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22570" rank="species">Aquimarina addita</organism><reference id="rid.12785"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquimarina addita sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2445</fpage><lpage>2449</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027433-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075902</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquimarina addita</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquimarina addita</em> (ad.di′ta. L. fem. part. adj. <em>addita</em> added, joined to the genus).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-reaction-negative, catalase- and oxidase-positive, and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Cells are non-motile rods with rounded ends (approximately 0.3–0.5×1.4–2.2 µm).</s><s>Colonies are orange, convex, translucent, glistening, circular with entire margins and become adherent to the agar surface after prolonged incubation on MA.</s><s>No gliding motility on agar plates.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent (negative for the KOH test and no bathychromatic shift of the absorbance spectrum).</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Does not grow on cetrimide agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Does not grow under microaerophilic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–8 (optimum, pH 6) and at 4–30 °C (optimum, 25 °C).</s><s>Requires sea salts for growth (range 3–7 %; optimum, 3 %) and cannot grow on sea salts-free ZoBell’s medium supplemented with NaCl only.</s><s>Does not require yeast extract for growth.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Does not produce acetoin, indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Does not utilize citrate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Decomposes aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, but not agar, adenine, alginic acids, casein, crystalline cellulose, chitin, elastin, pectin, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Does not degrade egg yolk but a clear zone is formed around colonies.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities, weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8) and trypsin activities, but negative for β-galactosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Cannot use any carbohydrate in the API 50CH system as sole carbon source.</s><s>Produces acid weakly from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin), melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and turanose, but not from erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and summed feature 9 (comprising 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and/or iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JC2680<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14156<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 17106<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample from Jeju Island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>