<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3518_nm.10671" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10671" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4023" rank="species">Clostridium stercorarium</organism><reference id="rid.3518"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Thermobacteroides leptospartum and Clostridium thermolacticum as Clostridium stercorarium subsp. leptospartum subsp. thermolacticum subsp. nov., comb. nov. and C. stercorarium subsp. thermolacticum subsp. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1127</fpage><lpage>1131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411681</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> (ster.cor.ar.i'um. L. adj. <i>stercorarium</i> pertaining to dung, referring to the source of the isolate, a compost heap)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the data of Madden (1983), Le Ruyet et al. (1985), Toda et al. (1988) and data presented in this paper.</s><s>Cells are rods (0.25-0.8x2-15 μm), and may be motile by peritrichous or single laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Spores may be present.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and obligate anaerobes.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is between 60 and 65 °C at pH 7.0-7.5.</s><s>Ferments cellulose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, xylose and mannose but not mannitol, sorbitol, gelatin or casein.</s><s>Acetate, lactate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub> and small amounts of L-alanine are produced during glucose fermentation.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The G­+C content range of the DNA is 39-43 mol%.</s><s>Belongs to cluster III of the order <i>Clostridiales</i>, domain <i>Bacteria</i>.</s><s>The species is divided into three subspecies, <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> subsp. <i>stercorarium</i> subsp. nov., comb. nov., <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> subsp. <i>thermolacticum</i> subsp. nov., comb. nov. and <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> subsp. <i>leptospartum</i> subsp. nov., comb. nov.</s><s>All three subspecies are isolated from compost.</s><s>The type species is <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> and the type strain is NCIB 11754<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>