<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8248_nm.14183" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14183" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14183" rank="species">Lysobacter oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.8248"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aslam</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yasir</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter oryzae sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of rice (Oryza sativa L.)</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>675</fpage><lpage>680</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000588-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329586</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, pertaining to the isolation of the type strain from the rhizosphere of rice).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, short rod-shaped, non-spore-forming, non-motile (but have gliding activity) and are 0.3–0.5 μm wide×1.8–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells occur singly and in pairs.</s><s>Colonies grown on half-strength R2A agar at 28 °C for 3 days are 1–2 mm in diameter, pale yellow, smooth and circular.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–42 °C, optimum temperature for growth is 28 °C.</s><s>The pH growth range is between 5.5 and 11.0, with an optimum of pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl in half-strength R2A medium and no growth occurs in 1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> of tetracycline, kanamycin, streptomycin and rifampicin, but sensitive to 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> ampicillin.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, hippurate and gelatin but does not hydrolyse elastin, guanine, adenine, aesculin, starch or Tween 20.</s><s>Utilizes 5-bromo-3-indoxyl-nonanoate, 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside and 4-nitrophenyl-<em>α</em>-d-maltopyranoside as a single carbon source but not the following: l-arabitol, galacturonic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, sodium pyruvate, d-mannitol, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, citrate, phenylacetic acid, adonitol, palatinose, l-tryptophan, 5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl-<em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, 4-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, 4-nitrophenyl-<em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside, sodium malonate, d-glucose, d-mannose, sucrose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, trehalose, d-rhamnose, inositol, cellobiose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin, sucrose or l-arabinose.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or nitrogen gas.</s><s>Positive in tests for activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C-4), esterase lipase (C-8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsinase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but not for lipase (C-14), cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Q-8 is the major quinone.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidyl-<em>N</em>-methylethanolamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YC6269<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22249<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21044<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of rice managed under no-tillage practice in Jinju, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>