<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5069_nm.1566" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1566" rank="genus">Rhodoplanes</organism><reference id="rid.5069"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoplanes gen. nov., a new genus of phototrophic bacteria including Rhodopseudomonas rosea as Rhodoplanes roseus comb. nov. and Rhodoplanes elegans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>665</fpage><lpage>673</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodoplanes</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodoplanes</i> (Rho.do.plan'es. Gr. n. <i>rhodos</i>, rose; Gr. n. <i>planes</i>, a wanderer; Gr. n. <i>Rhodoplanes</i>, a red wanderer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative rods.</s><s>Multiply by budding and asymmetric cell division.</s><s>Motile by means of polar, subpolar, or randomly distributed flagella.</s><s>Facultative phototrophs growing anaerobically in the light or aerobically in darkness.</s><s>Anaerobic growth in darkness by nitrate respiration is also possible; denitrification positive.</s><s>Photosynthetic cultures are pink, while aerobic chemotrophic cultures are colorless.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cells contain intracytoplasmic membranes of the lamellar type together with bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids of the normal spirilloxanthin series.</s><s>Mesophilic, neutrophic, and nonhalophilic.</s><s>Growth in the presence of NaCl at a concentration of 1% or more is inhibited.</s><s>Photoorganotrophy with simple organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with thiosulfate as the electron donor in the presence of 0.01% yeast extract.</s><s>Sulfide may not be utilized.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin and Tween 80 is negative.</s><s>Ubiquinone-10 and rhodoquinone-10 are present as major quinones.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA ranges from 66 to 70 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetic position is the alpha-2 subclass of <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats: freshwater and wastewater environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: <i>Rhodoplanes roseus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>