<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5979_nm.8520" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8520" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8520" rank="species">Brevibacterium celere</organism><reference id="rid.5979"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alexeeva</surname><given-names>Y.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhukova</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorshkova</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nicolau</surname><given-names>D.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium celere sp. nov., isolated from degraded thallus of a brown alga</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2107</fpage><lpage>2111</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02867-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545442</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium celere</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium celere</em> (ce′le.re. L. neut. adj. <em>celere</em> rapid, indicating the rapid growth on nutrient media).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming rods with coryneform morphology.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, with entire margins, whitish yellow in colour and of a smooth and butyrous consistency.</s><s>Salt-tolerant.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 12–42 °C.</s><s>No growth is detected at 4 °C or at 45 °C.</s><s>Alkali-tolerant.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–10, with optimum growth at pH 8·5–9·0.</s><s>The organism is catalase- and oxidase-positive and exhibits aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Gelatin, laminaran and alginate are hydrolysed, but casein and starch are not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Tests for urease and pyrazinamidase are negative.</s><s>No acid is formed from glucose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, galactose, xylose or sorbose.</s><s>According to the Biolog results, the following substrates are utilized: dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-fucose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxyproline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine and glycerol.</s><s>In addition, strain KMM 3581 utilizes d-arabitol and i-erythritol.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin (10 μg) and oleandomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Not susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), lincomycin (15 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), benzylpenicillin (10 μg), neomycin (30 μg), streptomycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg) or polymyxin B (25 μg).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are odd-numbered, i.e. 15 : 0ai and 17 : 0ai.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid (peptidoglycan type A1<em>γ</em>).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KMM 3637<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15453<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-809<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the brown alga <em>Fucus evanescens</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>