<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5855_nm.6146" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6146" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6146" rank="species">Okibacterium fritillariae</organism><reference id="rid.5855"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krausova</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gavrish</surname><given-names>E.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yashina</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Okibacterium fritillariae gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel genus of the family Microbacteriaceae</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>987</fpage><lpage>993</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02033-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Okibacterium fritillariae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Okibacterium fritillariae</i> (fri.til.la'ri.ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>fritillariae</i> of Fritillaria, generic name of plant, the source of isolation of the type strain of the species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>General morphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are as given above in the genus description.</s><s>The colonies are yellow, circular, somewhat convex, glistening, opaque, butyrous.</s><s>Cells are irregular rods (length 0.7-1.5 μm, width 0.4-0.6 μm).</s><s>In older cultures, ovoid or irregular coccoid cells predominate and occur singly or in pairs with diphtheroid arrangements.</s><s>No marked motility or primary branching.</s><s>Growth occurs between 7 and 37 °C, optimum is 24-27 °C.</s><s>A wide range of carbon sources are used for growth in amineral medium supplemented with 0.1% (w/v) yeast extract and 0.1% (w/v) casitone.</s><s>Polyols are usually not used as a carbon source in the same medium.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-arabinose, D-glucose, mannose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>Slow hydrolytic activity against many substances, but starch and aesculin are decomposed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is weakly produced.</s><s>Both strains tolerated 6% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Generally susceptible to antibiotics.</s><s>The physiology details of the two strains studied in this work are as given above.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine, alanine, glycine, glutamate and homoserine.</s><s>Rhamnose is the predominant sugar of the cell wall.</s><s>G+C content of DNA is about 67 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-2059<sup>T</sup>=IFO 16404<sup>T</sup>, isolated from seeds of <i>Fritillaria ruthenica</i> Wikstr.</s></p><p class="description"><s>While this report was being reviewed, the description of <i>Mycetocola</i> gen. nov. within the family <i>Microbacteriaceae</i>, containing lysine in its peptidoglycan, was published (Tsukamoto et al., 2001). <i>Mycetocola</i> spp. significantly differ from our strains phylogenetically (95.4-95.8% of the 16S rDNA sequence similarity) and phenotypically, mainly by the presence of an unknown amino acid in peptidoglycan (one molecule per unit), the molar ratios of glutamate, glycine, alanine and lysine, and also the lack of homoserine; the major menaquinone MK-10 and minor menaquinones MK-9 and MK-11; a lower G+C content of DNA (63.9-65.2 mol%); and cell shape and size (0.2-0.4x2.0-3.5 μm).</s></p></content></protolog>