<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10352_nm.16867" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16867" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16867" rank="species">Altererythrobacter marensis</organism><reference id="rid.10352"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Altererythrobacter marensis sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>307</fpage><lpage>311</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011031-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651736</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Altererythrobacter marensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Altererythrobacter marensis</em> (ma.ren′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>marensis</em> of Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, catalase-positive (weak) and oxidase-positive motile rods (1.0–2.0 μm long and 0.5–0.7 μm wide).</s><s>The methanol-soluble pigment is characterized by absorption maxima at 307, 340, 381 and 451 nm.</s><s>Does not contain bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> as a photosynthetic pigment.</s><s>On marine agar 2216 (Difco), colonies are yellow, opaque, circular, convex with entire margins and 0.8–1.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 4–42 °C (optimum 30 °C), at pH 6.1–11.1 (optimum pH 7.1) and on TSA supplemented with 0–9 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0–4 % NaCl).</s><s>Degrades Tween 80 but not cellulose, hypoxanthine, xanthine, DNA, starch, casein, tyrosine or chitin.</s><s>With API 20NE, positive for aesculin hydrolysis and malate assimilation but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, gelatin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase but negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is UQ-10.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (summed feature 7, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>12<em>t</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSW-14<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22370<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21428<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater collected around Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>