<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12738_nm.22514" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22514" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22514" rank="species">Solimonas aquatica</organism><reference id="rid.12738"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>N.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Solimonas aquatica sp. nov., reclassification of Sinobacter flavus Zhou et al. 2008 as Solimonas flava comb. nov. and Singularimonas variicoloris Friedrich and Lipski 2008 as Solimonas variicoloris comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genus Solimonas and its type species Solimonas soli</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2284</fpage><lpage>2291</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023010-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20971835</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Solimonas aquatica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Solimonas aquatica</em> (a.qua′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>aquatica</em> living, growing or found in the water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>After 24 h of incubation on R2A agar at 25 °C, cells are 0.3–0.8 µm in diameter and 1.0 µm long.</s><s>Colonies are semi-opaque, convex, round and smooth with entire edges, 1.2–1.5 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 4 days of incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at 20–40 °C (optimum, 25 °C), at pH 7.0–8.0 (optimum, pH 7.5) and in the presence of up to 1 % NaCl (optimum, 0.5 %).</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for lipase and DNase activities and hydrolysis of starch and skimmed milk.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of glucose, maltose, gluconate, adipate and malate and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification, activities of arginine dihydrolase, urease and β-galactosidase and assimilation of arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In the API ZYM kit, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present and alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, C14 lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: Tweens 40 and 80, α-d-glucose, maltose, gluconate, α-ketobutyric acid, pyruvic acid, adipic acid, malic acid and d-saccharic acid.</s><s>l-Aspartic acid, l-lysine and l-methionine are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: dextrin, α-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, maltotriose, d-ribose, d-salicin, xylose, arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-tryptophan, l-valine, l-isoleucine, urea, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to gentamicin, rifampicin, kanamycin, tetracycline, penicillin G, ampicillin, novobiocin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, ceftizoxime and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) also include summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NAA16<sup>T</sup> ( = BCRC 17835<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24500<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a freshwater spring in Kaoshiung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>