<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8502_nm.13396" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13396" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13396" rank="species">Lewinella antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.8502"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lewinella antarctica sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from Antarctic seawater.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>65</fpage><lpage>68</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000794-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lewinella antarctica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lewinella antarctica</em> (ant.arc′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>antarctica</em> southern and, by extension, of the Antarctic, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, chemoheterotrophic, obligately aerobic, psychrotolerant, oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Devoid of flagellar and gliding motility.</s><s>Cells are short to elongated rods, 0.9–1.4 μm wide and 2.4–21.2 μm long.</s><s>Colonies grown on MA for 5 days at 20 °C are circular, pulvinate, entire, butyrous, orange-coloured and 0.2–0.6 mm in diameter.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 3–25 °C, with optimum growth at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.0–10.0 and 0.5–5.0 % NaCl, optimally at pH 6 and 3.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Absorption spectra show peaks for cellular pigments at 472 nm (major peak) and 503 nm.</s><s>Starch and elastin are degraded, but agar, casein, CM-cellulose and chitin are not degraded.</s><s>In API 20NE strips, nitrate reduction and hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin are positive, <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity (substrate <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside) is weakly positive and arginine dihydrolase, acid production from glucose, indole production and urea hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Positive results are obtained (in the API ZYM system) for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase (weakly positive), but negative results are obtained for <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (substrate 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside), <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are oxidized (Biolog GN2 MicroPlates): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>None of the other carbon substrates in Biolog GN2 MicroPlates is oxidized.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), rifampicin (50 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg), but resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg) and penicillin G (10 μg, weakly).</s><s>In cultures grown on MA for 5 days at 20 °C, the cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, 10-methyl C<sub>19 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC3223<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42688<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 103142<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface seawater from Maxwell Bay, King George Island, western Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>