<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2083_nm.6393" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6393" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6393" rank="species">Mycobacterium porcinum</organism><reference id="rid.2083"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nemoto</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yugi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium porcinum sp. nov., a porcine pathogen.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>162</fpage><lpage>165</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-162</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium porcinum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium porcinum</i> (por'ci num. L. adj. <i>porcinum</i> pertaining to swine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the type strain are as follows.</s><s>Acid-fast rods (1.5 to 6 μm long by 0.5 μm wide); colonies on egg media are smooth to rough and non-photochromogenic and colonies on modified Sauton agar medium (2) are rough and dry.</s><s>Growth occurs after 3 days on egg media and at 28, 37, and 42 but not 45°C.</s><s>Resistant to the following agents (on Ogawa egg medium or Löwenstein-Jensen medium): <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoic acid (0.5 mg/ml), 5% NaCl, thiophene-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide (1 μg/ml), rifampin (25 μg/ml), ethambutol (5 μg/ml), sodium <i>p</i>-aminosalicylate (2 mg/ml), sodium salicylate (0.5 mg/ml), and hydroxylamine hydrochloride (0.5 mg/ml).</s><s>Tolerant to 0.2% picric acid, 0.2% sodium nitrite, and 0.1% sodium salicylate on modified Sauton agar medium.</s><s>Degrades <i>p</i>-aminosalicylate to form black formazan, but does not degrade salicylate.</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Tween 80 is not hydrolyzed after 14 days.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite after 24 h.</s><s>Arylsulfatase positive after 3 days; catalase positive (foam height more than 100 mm); β-galactosidase negative; acid phosphatase negative; β-esterase positive, but α-esterase negative or, if not negative, weakly positive.</s><s>Amidase pattern: acetamidase, urease, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase , allantoinase, and succinamidase positive; benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, salicylamidase, and malonamidase negative.</s><s>Pattern of utilization of nitrogen compounds as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources: glutamate, serine, glucosamine, acetamide, monoethanolamine, and trimethylenediamine are utilized; benzamide is not utilized.</s><s>Pattern of utilization of carbohydrates as sole sources of carbon in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen: acetate, citrate, succinate, malate, pyruvate, benzoate, fumarate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, propylene glycol, 1,3-butylene glycol, 2,3-butylene glycol, glucose, fructose, mannose, trehalose, inositol, and mannitol are utilized; malonate, 1,4-butylene glycol, sucrose, galactose, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, and sorbitol are not utilized.</s><s>Acetamide, benzamide, urea, nicotinamide, pyrazinamide, nitrate, and nitrite are utilized as sole nitrogen sources in the presence of glycerol carbon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The nine other strains examined had identical characteristics, except that one produced cells longer than 7 μm and six produced smooth colonies on egg media (however, all 10 strains formed rough dry colonies on modified Sauton agar medium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The source of all 10 strains was the lymph nodes of swine which showed tuberculosis-like lymphadenitis.</s><s>The type strain is E10241-1 (= ATCC 33776).</s></p></content></protolog>