<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3879_nm.9503" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9503" rank="genus">Segniliparus</organism><reference id="rid.3879"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toney</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daneshvar</surname><given-names>M.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cooksey</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carr</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Charles</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel mycolic acid-containing bacteria in the family Segniliparaceae fam. nov., including the genus Segniliparus gen. nov., with descriptions of Segniliparus rotundus sp. nov. and Segniliparus rugosus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1615</fpage><lpage>1624</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63465-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014491</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Segniliparus</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Segniliparus</em> (Seg.ni.li.pa′rus. L. adj. <em>segnis</em> slow; Gr. adj. <em>liparos</em> fat/fatty; N.L. masc. n. <em>Segniliparus</em> the slow fatty one, the one with slow fats, to indicate the possession of slowly reacting fatty acids, i.e. late-eluting mycolic acids detected with HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, brightly staining, acid–alcohol-fast, rod-shaped cells.</s><s>No spores or aerial mycelium, non-motile, occasional v-shaped rods but no true branching.</s><s>Grows in 3–4 days on LJ, 7H10 and 7H11 at 33 °C.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, non-photochromogenic and do not produce a diagnostic odour.</s><s>Cell wall contains mycolic acids, tuberculostearic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Arylsulfatase activity and growth tolerance with sodium chloride are positive in 14 days.</s><s>Niacin production is negative.</s><s>Semi-quantitative catalase produces &#x003E;45 mm bubbles.</s><s>Cells grow on mycobacterial media and TGY but growth on HI is poor.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed but acetamide, adenine, casein, citrate, aesculin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>d-Glucose, maltose and trehalose are used as carbon sources and produce acid, whereas adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, i-erythritol, galactose, i-myo-inositol, lactose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin and sodium citrate are not.</s><s>Utilization of d-fructose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol and sucrose is variable.</s><s>Have <em>β</em>-glucosidase and pyrazinamidase activities.</s><s>Susceptible to amikacin and sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>Strains have the same fatty acid composition, with prominent fatty acids of C10 : 0, C14 : 0, C16 : 0 and tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>The GLC thermal cleavage product of the mycolic acids is a C24 : 0 acid-methyl ester.</s><s>The HPLC mycolic acid pattern consists of two or three late-emerging groups of peaks with the final peak co-eluting with the high-molecular-mass internal standard.</s><s>TLC demonstrates two or three non-polar, high-molecular-mass, non-oxygenated, <em>α</em><sup>+</sup>-, <em>α</em>- or <em>α</em>′-mycolic acid chemical functional groups.</s><s>Species DNA may or may not amplify with TB11 and TB12 primers for the proposed, selected, actinomycete-specific 65 kDa HSP region.</s><s>Species do not produce an <em>R. equi</em>-specific <em>choE</em> virulence factor.</s><s>Genomic DNA G+C content is 68·0–72·0 mol%.</s><s>The first two described species, <em>Segniliparus rotundus</em> and <em>S. rugosus</em>, are 98·9 % similar by 16S rRNA gene sequence comparison.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence phylogenetic analysis demonstrates the proposed genus on an extended, distinct tree clade with <em>R. equi</em> as the nearest genetic neighbour, although DNA–DNA hybridization is &#x003C;2 % with this species.</s><s>Environmental habitat is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of the genus is <em>Segniliparus rotundus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>