<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7227_nm.3826" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3826" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3826" rank="species">Sulfurospirillum arcachonense</organism><reference id="rid.7227"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sulfurospirillum arcachonense sp. nov., a new microaerophilic sulfur-reducing bacterium.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1212</fpage><lpage>1217</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1212</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336931</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sulfurospirillum arcachonense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sulfurospirillum arcachonense</i> (ar.ca.cho.nen'se. M. L. adj. <i>arcachonense</i>, pertaining to the city of Arcachon, French Atlantic coast, the locality from which the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Curved cells are 0.3 μm wide and 1.0 to 2.5 μm long.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile by polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies in deep agar cultures are whitish, round, and filamentous with elemental sulfur as an electron acceptor.</s><s>With oxygen or fumarate, colonies are lens shaped and yellow-brownish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range is 6.1 to 8.2; optimum, 7.0 to 7.4.</s><s>The temperature range is 8 to 30°C; growth optimum, 26°C.</s><s>The salinity range is 0.6 to 4.0% NaCl; optimum growth occurs in the presence of 1.2 to 2.0% NaCl.</s><s>At least 0.1% MgCl<sub>2</sub> ∙ 6H<sub>O</sub> was required.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Microaerophilic growth: in agitated cultures growth at 15% oxygen and in nonagitated cultures growth at 20% oxygen in the gas phase with succinate as the electron donor; no growth at &#x003E;1% oxygen in the gas phase with formate as the electron donor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oxygen or elemental sulfur served as an electron acceptor; fumarate was fermented.</s><s>Nitrate, nitrite, thiosulfate, sulfate, Fe(III) oxyhydroxide, and dimethyl sulfoxide are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Formate, acetate, propionate, succinate, fumarate, lactate, α-ketoglutarate, glutamate, citrate, malate, alanine, and yeast extract are oxidized with oxygen as the electron acceptor.</s><s>With elemental sulfur as the electron acceptor, hydrogen, formate, lactate, pyruvate, α-ketoglutarate, glutarate, glutamate, and yeast extract serve as electron donors.</s><s>An organic carbon source is required.</s><s>Vitamins are not required.</s></p><p class="description"><s>MK-6 and MMK-6 are the sole quinones, with MK-6 predominating.</s><s>The fatty acids comprise 14:0 (2.7%), 14:1 (3.2%), 16:0 (31.0%), 16:1 (40.8%), 18:0 (20.8%), and 18:1 (0.6%), with trace amounts of 15:0, 17:0, and 3OH 14:0.</s><s>The polar lipids comprised phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine, together with a third phospholipid tentatively identified as lysophosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The G+ C content of the DNA is 32.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from oxidized surface sediment of a <i>Z. noltii</i>-over-grown intertidal mud flat near Arcachon, France.</s><s>Strain F1F6 (DSMZ 9755) is the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>