<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6297_nm.4124" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4124" rank="genus">Anaerofilum</organism><reference id="rid.6297"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zellner</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Messner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerofilum pentosovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., and Anaerofilum agile sp. nov., two new, strictly anaerobic, mesophilic, acidogenic bacteria from anaerobic bioreactors.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>871</fpage><lpage>875</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-871</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863411</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerofilum</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerofilum</i> (An.ae.ro'fi.lum. Gr. pref. <i>an</i>, not; Gr. n. <i>aer</i>, air; Gr. adj. <i>anaero</i>, absence of air, referring to the anaerobic mode of living; M.L. n. <i>filum</i>, thread, referring to the very thin rod-shaped cells; M.L. n. <i>Anaerofilum</i>, anaerobic thin rods)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-sporeforming, straight, thin rods.</s><s>The cell wall architecture is typical of gram-positive bacteria.</s><s>A murein layer is present, but is unusually thin.</s><s>The peptidoglycan of strain F<sup>T</sup> contains Lglycine, D-glutamate, L-lysine, and D-alanine.</s><s>The interpeptide linkage is formed by L-serine.</s><s>Cells are fragile and form spheroplasts during the stationary growth phase.</s><s>Cells are motile and peritrichously flagellated or nonmotile.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>No microaerophilic or aerobic growth occurs.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Strains are mesophilic (temperature range, 2 17 to &#x003C;45°C).</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>A variety of mono- and disaccharides are fermented.</s><s>The major fermentation products from glucose include lactic acid, acetate, ethanol, formate, 2,3-butandiol, and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Propionate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, succinate, diacetyl, and acetoin are not produced from glucose.</s><s>Sulfate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Isobutyrate and/or isovalerate may be produced by amino acid degradation (isoleucine, valine).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNA of known strains range from 54 to 55 mol%.</s><s>The habitats are anaerobic sewage sludge of municipal and industrial wastewater treatment plants.</s><s>Two species are known, <i>Anaerofilum pentosovorans</i> and <i>Anaerofilum agile</i>; <i>A. pentosovorans</i> is designated the type species because it grows better.</s></p></content></protolog>