<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4239_nm.4296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4296" rank="species">Mogibacterium pumilum</organism><reference id="rid.4239"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakazawa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poco</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hashimura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ikeda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalfas</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundqvist</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Mogibacterium pumilum gen. nov., sp. nov. and Mogibacterium vescum gen. nov., sp. nov., and reclassification of Eubacterium timidum (Holdeman et al. 1980) as Mogibacterium timidum gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>679</fpage><lpage>688</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758875</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Mogibacterium pumilum sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Mogibacterium pumilum (pu.mi'lum. L. adj. <i>pumilum</i> small or tiny, referring to the tiny colonies formed by this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short, Gram-positive rods, obligately anaerobic, non-motile and non-sporing.</s><s>Individual cells are about 0.2-0.3 by 1.0 μm, occurring singly, in short chains or in clumps.</s><s>On BHI-blood agar plates they form minute colonies &#x003C;1 mm in diameter even after prolonged incubation in an anaerobic glove box, which are circular, convex and translucent.</s><s>Growth in PY broth media is very poor with or without carbohydrates.</s><s>No haemolysis occurs around colonies on BHI-blood agar plates.</s><s>The cells are inert in most biochemical tests.</s><s>Starch and aesculin are not hydrolysed and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>No liquefaction of gelatin occurs.</s><s>Indole, urease and catalase tests are also negative.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>All strains are nonfermentative and do not utilize adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, aesculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>They produce phenyl acetate (about 3 mM) as the sole metabolic end product in PY or PYG broth.</s><s>The G+C content is 45±46 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is D2-18<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700696<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from human periodontal pockets.</s></p></content></protolog>