<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1541_nm.10636" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10636" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10636" rank="species">Blastococcus jejuensis</organism><reference id="rid.1541"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Blastococcus jejuensis sp. nov., an actinomycete from beach sediment, and emended description of the genus Blastococcus Ahrens and Moll 1970</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2391</fpage><lpage>2396</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64268-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012568</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Blastococcus jejuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Blastococcus jejuensis</em> (je.ju.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>jejuensis</em> of Jeju, Republic of Korea, the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, Gram-positive.</s><s>Cells are cocci that occur in pairs or rods.</s><s>Bud formation is observed for rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, transparent and apricot in colour.</s><s>Starch and casein are hydrolysed, but elastin is not.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, glucose fermentation and indole production from tryptophan are not observed.</s><s>Activities of arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are not present.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin degradation and gelatin hydrolysis are not detected.</s><s>Caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate are not assimilated.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, results for leucine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are positive and weakly positive, respectively, whilst results for esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, with the optimum at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH values in the range 6.1–10.1, with the optimum at pH 7.1.</s><s>Growth was observed in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl but not 2 % NaCl.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole carbon and energy sources: mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl-d-glucoside, palatinose, l-rhamnose, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, succinic acid, l-asparagine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine and d-glucose 6-phosphate, but not Tween 40, d-ribose, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid or methylsuccinate.</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains phosphatidylcholine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid and arabinose and galactose as diagnostic sugars.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KST3-10<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-24440<sup>T</sup>=KCCM 42251<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sand sediment from Gwakji beach on Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>