<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1725_nm.8793" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8793" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8793" rank="species">Pseudomonas antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.1725"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrophilic pseudomonads from Antarctica: Pseudomonas antarctica sp. nov., Pseudomonas meridiana sp. nov. and Pseudomonas proteolytica sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>713</fpage><lpage>719</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02827-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143013</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas antarctica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas antarctica</em> (an.tarc′ti.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>antarctica</em> pertaining to Antarctica).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms circular, convex, smooth and translucent colonies with a diameter of 1–2 mm.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile with a polar flagellum, rod-shaped and psychrophilic (grow at 4–30 °C), can tolerate 3 % NaCl (w/v) and grow at an optimum pH of 7.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, urease and phosphatase and weakly positive for lipase; reduces nitrate to nitrite; negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, arginine dihydrolase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, indole production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin, starch or cellulose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose and d-mannitol, but not from l-arabinose, lactose, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, adonitol, citrate, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lactic acid, d-mannose, d-mannitol, pyruvate, d-ribose, sorbitol, trehalose, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-lysine, l-serine, l-tyrosine and l-tryptophan as sole carbon sources, but not l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, cellulose, dextran, dulcitol, fumaric acid, inulin, lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, melezitose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbose, sucrose, succinic acid, thioglycollate, d-xylose, l-aspartic acid, l-aspargine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-threonine or l-valine.</s><s>Sensitive to the antibiotics ampicillin, amoxycillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, chlortetracycline, colistin, cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, kanamycin, gentamicin, lincomycin, nitrofurazone, nitrofurantoin, nystatin, oxytetracyclin, penicillin, polymyxin B, rifampicin, tetracycline and tobramycin, but resistant to furazolidone, furoxone and trimethoprim.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 60·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CMS 35<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4992<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15318<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>