<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6622_nm.1890" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1890" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1895" rank="species">Thiobacillus rapidicrescens</organism><reference id="rid.6622"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Katayama-Fujimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawashima</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsuzaki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuraishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reidentification of Thiobacillus perometabolis ATCC 27793 and Thiobacillus sp. strain A2 with reference to a new species Thiobacillus rapidicrescens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>532</fpage><lpage>538</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-532</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus rapidicrescens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus rapidicrescens</i> (ra.pi.di.cres'cens. L . adj. <i>rapidus</i> rapid; L. part. adj. <i>crescens</i> growing; M. L . part. adj. <i>rapidicrescens</i> rapid growing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In their morphological, physiological, and chemotaxonomic characteristics, <i>Thiobacillus</i> sp. strain A2<sup>T</sup> and <i>T. perometabolis</i> THI 024 were quite similar to each other and distinct from the known <i>Thiobacillus</i> species.</s><s>We propose a new species, <i>Thiobacillus rapidicrescens</i>, for <i>Thiobacillus</i> sp. strain A2<sup>T</sup> and <i>T. perometabolis</i> THI 024; the description of this species is based on the characteristics of the type strain, strain A2 (= THI 041).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology.</s><s>Rod-shaped cells (average dimensions, 0.4 to 0.5 μm wide by 1.1 to 1.7 μm long) with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of tufts of polar flagella.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Not acid-alcohol- fast.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial appearance.</s><s>Colonies on BY medium are circular, wrinkled with raised centers, lobate, spreading, brownish yellow, opaque, and about 3 to 4 mm in diameter after 2 days of incubation.</s><s>Colonies on thiosulfate medium are circular, convex, smooth, entire, creamy white, and opaque, developing a brown center with age; these colonies are about 2 mm in diameter after 1 week of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and physiological properties. <i>T. rapidicrescens</i> is facultatively anaerobic and in heterotrophic medium supplemented with nitrate grows anaerobically and evolves gas actively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is a facultative chemolithotroph.</s><s>Thiosulfate is utilized for growth as an energy source.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is oxidized slowly.</s><s>Tetrathionate or thiocyanate does not support growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Potassium nitrate and ammonium chloride are utilized as nitrogen sources, but urea is not.</s><s>Glutamate and aspartate are utilized as both nitrogen and carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alanine, serine, leucine, isoleucine, aspartate, glutamate, proline , histidine, phenylalanine, arabinose, ribose, glucose, galactose, fructose, maltose, sucrose, gluconate, glycerol, mannitol, formate, acetate, propionate, <i>n</i>-butyrate, lactate, pyruvate, malate, succinate, α-ketoglutarate, glutarate, adipate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, nbutanol, benzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and phydroxybenzoate are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Heterotrophic growth is not stimulated by the presence of thiosulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 17 to 40°C, but not at 10 or 42°C; optimum growth occurs between 30 and 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.5 to 9.5, and optimum growth occurs at pH 7.5 to 8.0 in BY medium and at pH 8.0 to 9.0 in SM basal salts-thiosulfate medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth factor is not required.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content: 67.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ubiquinone system: ubiquinone 10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism has octadecenoic acid plus cy. clopropane acid of C<sub>19</sub> as major nom-hydroxylated cellular fatty acids and 3-hydroxydecanoic acid as a hydroxylated fatty acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this organism is strain THI 041; this strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under accession number ATCC 25364.</s><s>An additional strain, <i>T. rapidicrescens</i> THI 024, has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under accession number ATCC 27793 (1)</s></p></content></protolog>