<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1318_nm.7701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7701" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7701" rank="species">Bifidobacterium minimum</organism><reference id="rid.1318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Electrophoretic patterns of proteins in the genus Bifidobacterium and proposal of four new species.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium minimum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium minimum</i> (min'i.mum. L. adj. <i>minimus</i> least, referring to the small size of the cells)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This taxon previously was referred to as the “minimum” homology group of Scardovi and Trovatelli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain in peptone-yeast extract or peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth cultures are 0.5- to 0.6-μm by 0.5- to 2.8-μm, oval, club-shaped, or short rods that occur in short chains and in clumps.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies in prereduced anaerobically sterilized agar streak tubes are 1 mm in diameter; circular; entire; convex; translucent; gray, white, or buff; shiny; and smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in broth with a fermentable carbohydrate produce dense turbidity with a flocculent sediment and a final pH of 4.1 to 4.4.</s><s>Little or no growth is produced without a fermentable carbohydrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the type strain and other strains of this species are given in Tables 1 . 2, and 5 , in Fig. 11 and 12, and by Scardovi and Trovatelli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 27538, was isolated from wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>