<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9163_nm.14360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14360" rank="species">Halomonas fontilapidosi</organism><reference id="rid.9163"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González-Domenech</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas fontilapidosi sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, denitrifying bacterium.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1290</fpage><lpage>1296</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004275-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502304</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas fontilapidosi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas fontilapidosi</em> (fon.ti.la.pi.do′si. L. n. <em>fons</em> -<em>tis</em> spring; L. adj. <em>lapidosus</em> stony; N.L. gen. n. <em>fontilapidosi</em> of the stony spring, i.e. from Fuente de Piedra, the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.96×1.73 μm (means of five measurements).</s><s>The cells are motile by a single polar flagellum and contain poly-<em>β</em>-alkanoate granules.</s><s>It does not produce exopolysaccharide or form endospores.</s><s>Cell colonies are circular, convex and creamy-brown in colour.</s><s>Its growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>It is moderately halophilic and incapable of growing without NaCl; it grows at sea-salt concentrations of between 3 and 25 % w/v (optimum 7.5–10 % w/v) and NaCl concentrations of between 3 and 20 % w/v (optimum 5–7.5 % w/v).</s><s>It grows within a temperature range of 15–45 °C and at pH values of between 5 and 9, the optimum values being 32–45 °C and pH 6–8.</s><s>It resists heating to 80 °C for 10 min.</s><s>It is chemo-organotrophic and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Its metabolism is of the respiratory type with oxygen, nitrate and nitrite as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>It produces gas from nitrate and nitrite in anaerobiosis.</s><s>Respiration with fumarate is negative.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine, DNase and phenylalanine deaminase but not phosphatase.</s><s>Gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>It does not produce acids from adonitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose or trehalose.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, O/F, ONPG and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Reduction of selenite, nitrate and nitrite is positive.</s><s>It hydrolyses tyrosine and produces pigment from it.</s><s>It hydrolyses Tween 20 and lecithin, but not aesculin, starch, Tween 80, urea, gelatin, casein or blood.</s><s>It does not grow on either MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar.</s><s>The following compounds are acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, l-arabinose, citrate, d-fructose, lactose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, lactate, maltose, d-mannose, sorbitol, starch and succinate.</s><s>The following compounds are not acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, aesculin, cellobiose, ethanol, formate, fumarate, dl-glycerol, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, malonate, propionate, d-salicin and trehalose.</s><s>dl-Isoleucine and l-serine are used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-histidine, l-methionine and l-valine are not used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>It is susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), cefalothin (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 IU), norfloxacine (10 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), sulfamide (250 μg), trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1.25/23.75 μg), tobramycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>It is resistant to polymyxin B (300 IU).</s><s>Principal fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The predominant respiratory lipoquinone is ubiquinone with nine isoprene units (Q-9).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 5CR<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7341<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24455<sup>T</sup>), isolated from saline soil at Fuente de Piedra (Málaga, Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>