<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4077_nm.9106" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9106" rank="genus">Conglomeromonas</organism><reference id="rid.4077"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Skerman</surname><given-names>V.B.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williamson</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Conglomeromonas largomobilis gen. nov., sp. nov., a sodium-sensitive, mixed-flagellated organism from fresh waters.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>300</fpage><lpage>308</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-300</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Conglomeromonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Conglomeromonas</i> (Con. glom. e. ro. monas, L. pp. <i>conglomeratus</i> to form in a [rounded] mass; Gr. fem. n. <i>monas</i> a unit, monad; M. L. fem. n. <i>Conglomeromonas</i> monad forming in a [rounded] mass)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus, with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>Colonies grown on LWA for 72 h at 28°C are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, colorless, translucent, low convex, and round with an entire edge and smooth surface, and they readily coalesce.</s><s>Each colony contains relatively few cells.</s><s>The intracellular matrix is water clear and of low viscosity.</s><s>The cells are mainly in the unicellular phase and may be motile, but some multicellular conglomerate forms may be produced, particularly when colonies are well separated and the agar surface is well dried.</s><s>On media containing sodium ions, the colonies are composed almost entirely of one or more conglomerates.</s><s>Conglomerates are usually the same diameter as the colonies of the unicellular forms, but occasionally are larger.</s><s>They are colorless, opaque, raised, and round with a rough furrowed surface and irregular edge.</s><s>Conglomerates have a dry appearance, are movable intact, and are difficult to emulsify.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C.</s><s>Growth occurs on LWA, PYEA, 0.1% peptone agar, glucose-ammonium sulfate agar, and citrate-ammonium sulfate agar.</s><s>No growth occurs in phenol- and alkylamine-mineral salts media or in nitrogen-free media.</s><s>Slower growth occurs in the presence of 2% NaCl but is always in the conglomerate form and is pale pink in color.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 5% NaCl.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, aminopeptidase, phosphatase, deoxyribonuclease, and urease are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Citrate and promalonate are utilized.</s><s>Iron is deposited on ferric ammonium citrate agar.</s><s>Starch and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Chitin, alginate, cellulose, gelatin, tributyrin, and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Esculin may be hydrolyzed.</s><s>Horse erythrocytes are not hemolyzed.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Carrot plugs are not digested.</s><s>Inspissated serum is not liquefied.</s><s>Ethanol and gluconate are not oxidized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The methyl red reaction is late and weak, and the Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Acid (but no gas) is produced in Hayward fermentation medium from galactose, glucose, mannitol, and melibiose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, arabitol, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, ethanol, fructose, inulin, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, D-ribose, salicin, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid may be produced from glycerol, sorbitol, cellobiose, mannose, rhamnose, inositol, and lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain UQM 2041<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>