<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3356_nm.2871" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2871" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2871" rank="species">Moritella japonica</organism><reference id="rid.3356"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moritella japonica sp. nov., a novel barophilic bacterium isolated from a Japan Trench sediment.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>295</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12501424</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moritella japonica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moritella japonica</i> (ja.pon.i.ca. L. gen. n. <i>japonica</i> named after the Japan Trench, from where this strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped; cell widths ranges from 0.8 to 1.0 μm, and cell lengths range from 2 to 4 μm.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative and motile by means of a single unsheathed polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Marine Agar 2216 after incubation at 10°C at atmospheric pressure are entire, smooth, and cream-colored.</s><s>The bacterium is halophilic and psychrophilic.</s><s>Best growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of ca. 3%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is from 10 to 15°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 0 to 20°C.</s><s>It is a facultatively anaerobic chemoorganotroph having respiratory and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, but no gas is.</s><s>The organism does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>The lysine decarboxylase test is positive.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from D-fructose, glycerol, and D-glucose.</s><s>No acid is produced from arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, myo-inositol, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 45 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-7.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are 14:0, 16:0, 16:1, and 22:6 (DHA).</s><s>The type strain is strain DSK1, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection os Microorganisms as strain JCM 10249.</s></p></content></protolog>