<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5539_nm.5197" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5197" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5197" rank="species">Planococcus psychrophilus</organism><reference id="rid.5539"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vairamani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabhakar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planococcus antarcticus and Planococcus psychrophilus spp. nov. isolated from cyanobacterial mat samples collected from ponds in Antarctica.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>261</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00792-001-0250-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12072961</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planococcus psychrophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planococcus psychrophilus</i> (<i>Psychrophilus</i> adj. derived from Latin meaning cold loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped, single, Gram positive, non-spore-forming, and motile.</s><s>Colonies on peptone–yeast extract medium are orange, smooth, convex, circular, and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits absorption maxima at 440, 465, and 487.5 nm.</s><s>Pigment synthesis is not dependent on the growth phase or the growth conditions.</s><s>Cultures can grow from 2° to 30°C and pH 6 to 12, and they tolerate up to 12% NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth was observed at 22°C and pH 7.</s><s>It is catalase, oxidase, lipase, gelatinase, β-galactosidase, and arginine dihydrolase positive, but negative with respect to urease and phosphatase, nitrate to nitrite reduction, indole production, the methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests, and levan formation.</s><s>It can hydrolyze esculin and Tween 80 but not starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It can utilize rhamnose, melibiose, trehalose, xylose, glycerol, lysine, sodium acetate, sodium succinate, inositol, glutamic acid, and pyruvate, but not glucose, lactose, sorbose, arabinose, cellobiose, sucrose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose, lactose, lactic acid, adonitol, maltose, glucosamine, sorbitol, melizitol, β-hydroxybutyric acid, dulcitol, dextran, PEG, glycine, sodium citrate, cellulose, inulin, alanine, phenylalanine, methionine, glutamine, arginine, serine, potassium hydrogen phthalate, myristic acid, creatinine, tyrosine, or glycogen as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Further, it does not produce acid or gas from glucose, sucrose, cellobiose, lactose, sodium glutamate, or sodium thioglycollate.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is L-lys- D-glu, and the major menaquinones are MK-7 and MK-8.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sup>14:0</sup>, iso-C<sup>15:0</sup>, anteiso-C<sup>15:0</sup>, iso-C<sup>16:0</sup>, C<sup>16:0</sup>, C<sup>16:1</sup>, iso-C<sup>16:1</sup>, anteiso-C<sup>17:0</sup>, C<sup>17:0</sup>, iso-C<sup>17:1</sup>, anteiso-C<sup>17:1</sup>, C<sup>18:0</sup>, and C<sup>18:1</sup>.</s><s>The polar lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 44.5 mol% G+C.</s><s>It is closely related phylogenetically to <sup>P. mcmeekinii</sup>, <sup>P. alkanoclasticus</sup>, <sup>P. antarcticus</sup>, and <sup>P. okeanokoites</sup>, as determined by 16S rDNA analysis, but it exhibits very low DNA–DNA similarity.</s><s>It is sensitive to penicillin, chlortetracycline, chloramphenicol, neomycin, streptomycin, novobiocin, tetracycline, bacitracin, furazolidone, colistin, kanamycin, lincomycin, cotrimoxazole, ampicillin, amoxicillin, trimethoprim, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, nystatin, gentamicin, and polymyxin B, but resistant to carbenicillin, tobramycin, oxytetracycline, nitrofurazone, and nitrofurantoin.</s><s>It was isolated from a cyanobacterial mat sample from McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s><s>The type strain is CMS 53or<sup>T</sup> (MTCC 3812; DSM 14507).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of CMS 53orT is AJ 314746.</s></p></content></protolog>