<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2240_nm.5574" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5574" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5574" rank="species">Leuconostoc argentinum</organism><reference id="rid.2240"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fantuzzi</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gonzalez</surname><given-names>F.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>du Toit</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leuconostoc argentinum sp. nov., isolated from Argentine raw milk.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>347</fpage><lpage>351</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-347</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leuconostoc argentinum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leuconostoc argentinum</i> (ar.gen.ti'num. L. adj. <i>argentinum</i>, pertaining to Argentine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Nonmotile, nonsporulating, catalase negative, and oxidase negative.</s><s>Spherical and sometimes lenticular cells occur usually in pairs and short chains.</s><s>Colonies on MRS agar are round, smooth, greyish white, and usually small (less than 1.00 mm in diameter).</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 39°C; the optimum temperature is 27 to 30°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Heterofermentative, producing gas from glucose.</s><s>More than 97% of the lactate is produced as the D-(-)isomer.</s><s>Arginine and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Indole is not formed, and nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Polysaccharides are not produced from sucrose.</s><s>Milk is coagulated without added yeast extract, but only after extended incubation (48 h).</s><s>All strains produce acid from galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, maltose, N-acetylglucosamine, lactose, melibiose, and sucrose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from D-fructose and D-raffinose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from L-arabinose, D-xylose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, cellobiose, trehalose, β-gentiobiose, and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from ribose, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, D-tagatose, glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, indin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, and 5-ketogluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 40.5 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from Argentine raw milk.</s><s>Represents 7 to 10% of the <i>Leuconostoc</i> spp. isolated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LL76.</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to the description of the species, except that acid is typically produced from α-methy-D-glucoside, trehalose, and D-turanose and acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-xylose, cellobiose, and β-gentiobiose.</s></p></content></protolog>