<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10571_nm.3336" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3336" rank="genus">Tatumella</organism><reference id="rid.10571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pantoea citrea, Pantoea punctata and Pantoea terrea to the genus Tatumella emend. as Tatumella citrea comb. nov., Tatumella punctata comb. nov. and Tatumella terrea comb. nov. and description of Tatumella morbirosei sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>484</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012070-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Tatumella</em> Hollis, Hickman &#x0026; Fanning 1982</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tatumella</em> (Ta.tum.el′la. N.L. fem. dim. n. <em>Tatumella</em> named to honour Harvey Tatum, an American bacteriologist who made many contributions to our understanding of the classification and identification of fermentative and nonfermentative bacteria of medical importance.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the data of Hollis <em>et al.</em> (1981), Kageyama <em>et al.</em> (1992) and this paper.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-capsulated, non-spore-forming small rods that are 0.6–1.2×0.9–3.0 μm in size.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of polar, subpolar or lateral flagella or non-motile at 36 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, fermentative, catalase-positive (weak and slow) and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Non-pigmented, or pale beige to pale orange.</s><s>Glucose dehydrogenase, gluconate dehydrogenase and 2-ketogluconate dehydrogenase are produced.</s><s>Reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Indole, urease and gelatin tests are negative.</s><s>Positive for Voges–Proskauer (Coblentz), methyl red and citrate (Simmons); phenylalanine, arginine dihydrolase and ONPG tests are variable.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S (TSI), lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, KCN test, lipase and DNase.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, d-ribose, trehalose and d-xylose (variable reaction for <em>T. morbirosei</em>), but not from amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, glutarate, glycogen, histamine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, propionate, l-rhamnose, sorbitol or l-sorbose. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, 4-aminobutyrate, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-fructose, fumarate, <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, inosine, 5-ketogluconate, d-mannose, l-proline, d-psicose, d-ribose, succinic acid, trehalose, thymidine and uridine are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>Susceptible to many antibiotics.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical samples, fruit and soil.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 49.8 to 53 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Tatumella ptyseos</em> Hollis, Hickman &#x0026; Fanning 1982.</s></p></content></protolog>