<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1332_nm.76" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.76" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.76" rank="species">Acidianus infernus</organism><reference id="rid.1332"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segerer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neuner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kristjansson</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stetter</surname><given-names>K.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidianus infernus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Acidianus brierleyi comb. nov.: facultatively aerobic, extremely acidophilic thermophilic sulfur-metabolizing archaebacteria.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>559</fpage><lpage>564</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidianus infernus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidianus infernus</i> (in.fer'nus. L. masc. adj. <i>infernus</i> emerged from Hades, referring to the place of isolation at the Solfatara Crater, where Dante suggested the gate to hell was in his Divina Commedia)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Acidianus infernus</i> exponentially growing cells are about 0.5 to 1.5 μm wide in an aerobic cultures and 0.8 to 2 μm wide in aerobic cultures, becoming smaller in the stationary growth phase.</s><s>Packed cells from aerobic cultures are ochre colored, and packed cells from extremely anaerobic cultures are greenish black.</s><s>Growth is obligately chemolithotrophic and So dependent by oxidation or reduction of S<sup>0</sup>.</s><s>Cells grow at temperatures ranging from 65 to 96°C, with optimum growth at around 90°C, as shown for strain S<sup>0</sup>4a<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>No growth is detected at 60 and 98°C.</s><s>The pH suitable for growth ranges from 5.5 to 1.0, with the optimum pH around 2 (isolate S<sup>0</sup>4a<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>No growth is obtained at pH 0.5 or 6.0.</s><s>Strains S<sup>0</sup>4a<sup>T</sup>, Vc11, and Vc16 exhibit a broad salt tolerance, with an optimum around 0.2% NaCl; this tolerance is independent of the salinity of their place of origin.</s><s>Anaerobically grown cultures of isolate S<sup>0</sup>4a<sup>T</sup> at pH 2 can be used for at least 2 years as inocula, when they are stored at 4°C.</s><s>However, we were unable to obtain growth from aerobically grown cultures after storage at pH 2 and 4°C for 2 months.</s><s>Viability of aerobic cultures can be increased to about 4 months by raising the pH to 5.5 by adding CaCO<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>Cells lyse at pH values greater than 8.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolates were obtained from hot water, mud, and marine sediments at geothermal springs in Italy, the Azores, Iceland, and the United States.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain S<sup>0</sup>4a<sup>T</sup> (= DSM 3191).</s></p></content></protolog>