<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3168_nm.3634" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3634" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3634" rank="species">Pelobacter acetylenicus</organism><reference id="rid.3168"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentation of acetylene by an obligate anaerobe, Pelobacter acetylenicus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>142</volume><fpage>295</fpage><lpage>301</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00693407</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pelobacter acetylenicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pelobacter acetylenicus</i> (a.ce.ty.le'ni.cus. M.L. adj. referring to acetylene utilization)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, 0.6-0.8 x 1.5-4 μm in size, with slightly pointed ends, single, in pairs, or in chains.</s><s>Motile in young cultures, Gram-negative, non-sporeforming.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph, acetylene, acetoin, ethanolamine, choline, 1,2-propanediol and glycerol used as substrate, the latter two in the presence of acetate.</s><s>Substrates fermented to acetate and ethanol or the respective higher acids and alcohols.</s><s>Ethanol oxidized to acetate in the presence of hydrogen-scavenging anaerobes.</s><s>Grows in freshwater medium as well as in the presence of 2% (w/v) sodium chloride.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate, sulfite, or nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Indole not formed, gelatine or urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No catalase activity, no cytochromes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrates that did not support growth included ethylene, acetaldehyde (1-5 mM), potassium cyanide, acetonitril, acetamide, ethylene glycol, di-ethylene glycol, polyethyleneglycol, glycolate, glyoxylate, glycolaldehyde, betain, methanol (5 mM), trimethoxybenzoate, formate, malate, fumarate, lactate, pyruvate, tartrate, citrate, aspartate, glutamate, casamino acids, yeast extract, xylose, arabinose, fructose, glucose, mannose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, salicin, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, sorbose, rhamnose, trehalose.</s><s>All substrates were given 10 mM or 0.1% (w/v) unless stated otherwise.</s><s>Selective enrichment from anoxic sediments in mineral medium with acetylene (10-20% in the gas phase) as sole substrate, pH range: 6.5-7.5.</s><s>Temperature range: 15- 40°C, optimum at 28- 34°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 57.1±0.2 mol% G+C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats: anoxic muds of freshwater and marine origin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: WoAcy 1, DSM 2348, deposited in Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen, G6ttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>