<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9228_nm.14487" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14487" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14487" rank="species">Vibrio breoganii</organism><reference id="rid.9228"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beaz Hidalgo</surname><given-names>R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balboa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prado</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romalde</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio breoganii sp. nov., a non-motile, alginolytic, marine bacterium within the Vibrio halioticoli clade</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1589</fpage><lpage>1594</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003434-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542146</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio breoganii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio breoganii</em> [bre.o.ga′ni.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>breoganii</em> of Breogan, a mythical Celtic king of Galicia (north-west Spain), from where the strains were isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, non-flagellated rods (0.5–0.75×1.0–2.0 μm).</s><s>Forms non-pigmented, translucent, non-swarming, round, smooth colonies that are 0.3–0.7 mm in diameter on MA plates after 24 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>All strains apart from strain RD 2G5, which forms colonies with a translucent yellow appearance, form opaque, round (0.7–1.0 mm diameter), green colonies on TCBS agar.</s><s>No growth occurs without NaCl in the culture medium.</s><s>Mesophilic and chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1.5–6.0 % NaCl (w/v) and at 4 °C, but not at salinities above 8.0 % NaCl or above 37 °C.</s><s>Susceptible to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 μg per disc); all strains apart from C 5.5 are resistant to ampicillin (10 μg per disc).</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Ferments glucose without producing gas and positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>Indole, urease, Voges–Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S, gelatinase, amylase, use of citrate, lipase and DNase tests are all negative.</s><s>Positive for methyl red, ONPG and alginase activity tests.</s><s>API ZYM reaction tests are positive for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Produces acid from d-xylose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, gentiobiose, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Does not produce acid from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-adonitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain RD 15.11<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7222<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23858<sup>T</sup>) and six reference strains [RD 2G5 (=CECT 7367 =LMG 24484), VB 16.3, C5.5, RD 2B2, C 4.15 and CMJ 13.7] were isolated from the clams <em>Ruditapes decussatus</em> and <em>Ruditapes philippinarum</em> in Galicia, north-west Spain.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain RD 15.11<sup>T</sup> is 44.4 mol%.</s><s>Strain RD 15.11<sup>T</sup> produces acid from melibiose, l-xylose, arbutin, glycogen and d-lactose, but not from sucrose, d-ribose, d-mannose or l-rhamnose.</s></p></content></protolog>