<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11601_nm.18638" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18638" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18638" rank="species">Endozoicomonas montiporae</organism><reference id="rid.11601"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Endozoicomonas montiporae sp. nov., isolated from the encrusting pore coral Montipora aequituberculata</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1158</fpage><lpage>1162</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014357-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666790</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Endozoicomonas montiporae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Endozoicomonas montiporae</em> (N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>montiporae</em> of <em>Montipora</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a coral belonging to the genus <em>Montipora</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile rods (0.5–0.7 μm in diameter and 1.0–3.0 μm long).</s><s>Colonies on MA are beige, circular and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter on MA after 72 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–35 °C, at pH 6–10 and in the presence of 1–3 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25 °C, at pH 8.0 and in the presence of 2–3 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells are aerobic.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, DNase and hydrolysis of Tween 20.</s><s>Negative for lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of casein, starch and Tweens 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Positive for the following: nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following: indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon substrates (Biolog GN2) are oxidized: dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, melibiose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, inosine, uridine, thymidine and glycerol.</s><s>Does not oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin, sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim and tetracycline.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), summed feature 8 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone 9 and the DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-33<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24815<sup>T</sup> =BCRC 17933<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the encrusting pore coral <em>Montipora aequituberculata</em> collected from seawater off southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>