<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3467_nm.8116" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8116" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8116" rank="species">Flavobacterium tegetincola</organism><reference id="rid.3467"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McCammon</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Antarctic Flavobacterium species: description of Flavobacterium gillisiae sp. nov., Flavobacterium tegetincola sp. nov., and Flavobacterium xanthum sp. nov., nom. rev. and reclassification of [Flavobacterium] salegens as Salegentibacter salegens gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1055</fpage><lpage>1063</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843045</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium tegetincola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium tegetincola</i> (te.get'n.col.a. L. n. <i>teges</i> a mat or rug; L. gen. n. L. <i>incola</i> an inhabitant; M.L. gen. n. <i>tegetincola</i> the mat-inhabitant, pertaining to its cyanobacterial mat habitat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 2-5 μm in length and 0.4-0.5 μm in width.</s><s>Motile by gliding.</s><s>Cell masses from aerobic cultures are yellow.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments not detected.</s><s>Colonies have a butyrous consistency, are circular and convex in shape, and possess an entire edge.</s><s>Peptone and Casamino acids, but not sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride or L-glutamate, serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Vitamins are not required for growth.</s><s>Nonhalophilic but can grow on seawater-containing media and tolerates up to 5% NaCl.</s><s>On solid media growth occurs at 0-27 °C with optimal growth at about 20 °C while no growth occurs at 30 °C or above.</s><s>Strictly aerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Produces acid from D-glucose, D-fructose and D-mannitol, but not from L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-fructose, L-rhamnose, D-xylose, sucrose, trehalose, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, adonitol, D-sorbitol, inositol or glycerol.</s><s>Degrades Tween 80, but not gelatin, casein, aesculin, starch, agar, alginate, chitin carboxymethylcellulose, pectin, DNA, urea, uric acid or xanthine.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activity are absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole from L-tryptophan, H<sub>2</sub>S production, Voges-Proskauer, oxidase and Simmons' citrate tests are negative.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Can utilize d-glucose as a sole carbon source.</s><s>DNA G+­C content is 34 mol% (determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Type strain is ACAM 602<sup>T</sup>, isolated from cyanobacterial mat material collected from Ace Lake, a marine salinity meromictic lake located in the Vestfold Hills area of Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>