<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6427_nm.3104" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3104" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3104" rank="species">Arsenophonus triatominarum</organism><reference id="rid.6427"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hypsa</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dale</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>In vitro culture and phylogenetic analysis of "Candidatus Arsenophonus triatominarum," an intracellular bacterium from the triatomine bug, Triatoma infestans.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1140</fpage><lpage>1144</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1140</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336921</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of "<i>Candidatus</i> Arsenophonus triatominarum" sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>"<i>Candidatus</i> Arsenophonus triatominarum" (tri'.to’min.a.rum. N. L. <i>Triatominae</i>, subfamily of reduviid bugs; triatominarum, of the <i>Triatominae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>For the features outlined in this study, the description of "<i>Candidatus</i> Arsenophonus triatominarum" is in agreement with the description for the genus <i>Arsenophonus</i> (15).</s><s>Cells are nonmotile, non-sporeforming, nonflagellated, highly filamentous rods (&#x003E; 15 pm in length, 1 to 1.5 pm in diameter) which divide by septation.</s><s>Bacteria are gram negative and retain carbol fuchsin during Gimenez staining.</s><s>They grow intracellularly in <i>A. albopictus</i> cell culture and cannot be cultivated in cell-free MM medium.</s><s>On the basis of their 16s rDNA sequence, these bacteria, along with <i>A. nasoniae</i>, form a distinct lineage within the γ-3 subdivision of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>In the absence of a method for cryopreserving TII for deposition, we designate the intracellular endosymbiont from <i>T. infestans</i> the type strain for "<i>Candidatus</i> Arsenophonus triatominarum". "<i>Candidatus</i> Arsenophonus triatominarum" is found in the following <i>T. infestans</i> tissues: hemolymph, heart, salivary glands, neural ganglion, visceral muscles, nephrocytes, ovaries, testes, and dorsal vessels.</s><s>The bacterium lives in the cytoplasm of host cells and displays pleiomorphy with forms ranging from spherical to highly filamentous.</s></p></content></protolog>