<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12737_nm.22513" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22513" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22513" rank="species">Ochrobactrum pecoris</organism><reference id="rid.12737"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scholz</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tomaso</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hotzel</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Melzer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum pecoris sp. nov., isolated from farm animals</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2278</fpage><lpage>2283</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027631-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952542</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ochrobactrum pecoris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ochrobactrum pecoris</em> (pe′co.ris. L. gen. n. <em>pecoris</em> of livestock).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (approx. 2 µm long), Gram-negative and oxidase-positive and showing an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Grows on R2A agar, TSA, nutrient agar and MacConkey agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Colonies are beige, translucent and shiny on R2A agar, with entire edges and a diameter of approximately 2 mm within 24 h.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) phenylphosphonate and for weak hydrolysis of bis-pNP phosphate and l-proline pNA.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of aesculin, pNP β-d-galactopyranoside, pNP β-d-glucuronide, pNP α-d-glucopyranoside, pNP β-d-glucopyranoside, pNP phosphorylcholine and 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate.</s><s>Positive for utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol (weak), d-mannose, maltose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, citrate (weak), 4-aminobutyrate, propionate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-lactate, l-malate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, β-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine and ornithine.</s><s>Negative for utilization of <em>p</em>-arbutin, rhamnose, salicin, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, adipate, itaconate, mesaconate, suberate, phenylacetate, melibiose and azelate.</s><s>The quinone system is ubiquinone Q-10 with minor amounts of Q-11 and Q-9.</s><s>The polyamine pattern consists of major amounts of spermidine, putrescine and <em>sym</em>-homospermidine and minor amounts of 1,3-diaminopropane and spermine.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Moderate amounts of two unidentified aminolipids, AL1 and the <em>Ochrobactrum</em>-specific AL2, and small amounts of several unknown lipids are also present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is composed largely of C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 08RB2639<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23868<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 60088<sup>T</sup>  = CCM 7822<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sheep in Bosnia.</s><s>A second strain, 08RB2781-1 ( = DSM 23868  = CCM 7823), was isolated from a domestic boar in Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>