<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10765_nm.17860" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17860" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17860" rank="species">Kocuria atrinae</organism><reference id="rid.10765"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kocuria atrinae sp. nov., isolated from traditional Korean fermented seafood</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>914</fpage><lpage>918</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014506-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661502</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kocuria atrinae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kocuria atrinae</em> (a.tri′na.e. N.L. n. <em>Atrina</em> a scientific zoological genus; N.L. gen. n. <em>atrinae</em> of <em>Atrina</em>, isolated from <em>Atrina pectinata</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, non-motile and coccoid with a diameter of 1.0–1.5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow, circular, smooth and opaque after 2 days incubation on MA at 30 °C.</s><s>Cells grow at 25–37 °C, at pH 7–9 and in the presence of 0–4 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth conditions on MA or in MB medium are 30–37 °C, pH 8–9 and 0–2 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite, does not produce indole and is unable to ferment d-glucose.</s><s>Positive for l-arginine dihydrolase, urease, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not gelatin or PNPG.</s><s>According to growth on Biolog GP2 plates, assimilates dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, d-fructose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, putrescine, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, thymidine 5′-monophosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, but not <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methylglucose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-xylose, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, lactamide, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P30<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19594<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15914<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a traditional fermented seafood in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>