<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5656_nm.1756" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1756" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1756" rank="species">Brackiella oedipodis</organism><reference id="rid.5656"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gilhaus</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beer</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mietke</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gelderblom</surname><given-names>H.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Voigt</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reissbrodt</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brackiella oedipodis gen. nov., sp. nov., gram-negative, oxidase-positive rods that cause endocarditis of cotton-topped tamarin (Saguinus oedipus).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>179</fpage><lpage>186</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837301</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brackiella oedipodis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brackiella oedipodis</i> (oe.di.po'dis. N.L. gen. n. <i>oedipodis</i> referring to the first isolation source, the tamarin <i>Saguinus oedipus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Brackiella oedipodis</i> is the same as that given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies on tryptic soy blood agar are greyish-white, slightly rough with a diameter of 1-2 mm after 2 d growth at 37 °C with no haemolysis.</s><s>Similar growth observed on tryptic soy agar (light-white colonies of the same size), bile-chrysoidinglycerol agar according to Ziesché et al. (1985) (greenblue colonies of about 1 mm in diameter), King A agar (no pigmentation and no fluorescence under UV 365 nm), Tween 80 agar, gelatinase agar, starch agar, CDM-H agar (a chemically defined medium; Flossmann et al., 1984).</s><s>Good growth in nutrient broth and in tryptic soy broth at 37 °C for 24 h.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar, King B agar, cetrimide agar, acetamide agar, milk agar or in 6.5% NaCl broth.</s><s>Grows at temperatures of 30-37 °C, but not at 4, 20 or 42 °C.</s><s>The following biochemical tests are positive: L-alanine aminopeptidase, methyl red, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrolysis of starch, and production of acid from D-mannose and maltose.</s><s>The following biochemical characteristics are negative: indole production, Voges-Proskauer, Simmon's citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S (Kligler) production, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, growth on KCN, aesculin hydrolysis, Tween 80 hydrolysis, DNase, lipase, gelatinase, β-D-galactosidase, pyrase, β-D-glucuronidase, yellow pigment production, use of malonate, tartrate (Jordan) or acetate, production of gas or acid from glucose, and production of acid from methyl α-D-glucoside, adonitol, cellobiose, D-sorbitol, dulcitol, D-xylose, erythritol, glycerol, lactose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, mannitol, melibiose, mucate, myo-inositol, raffinose, saccharose, salicin and trehalose.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized using the Biolog system were (measured after 3 d at 37 °C): Tween 40, Tween 80, methyl pyruvate, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, formic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, D-alanine, lglutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid and L-serine.</s><s>Susceptible to the following antimicrobial agents: amikacin, ampicillin, cefotaxime, cefotiam, cefoxitin, ceftazidime, chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, gentamicin, kanamycin, mezlocillin, mezlocillin}sulbactam, nalidixic acid, tetracycline, streptomycin, sulfamerazine and trimethoprim}sulfamerazine.</s><s>Isolated from the heart of a cotton-topped tamarin that had died suddenly during a tooth extraction.</s><s>The heart showed clear signs of endocarditis for which <i>Brackiella oedipodis</i> may be the causal agent.</s><s>Type strain, and so far the only strain reported, is LMG 19451<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13743<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13739<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>