<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7004_nm.1244" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1244" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1244" rank="species">Sphingopyxis witflariensis</organism><reference id="rid.7004"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Witzenberger</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neef</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingopyxis witflariensis sp. nov., isolated from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2029</fpage><lpage>2034</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02217-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingopyxis witflariensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingopyxis witflariensis</i> (wit.fla.ri.en'sis M.L. adj. <i>witflariensis</i> of Witflaria, referring to the German city of Wetzlar from where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0.5-0.8 x 1.0-2.0 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly and are motile, Gram-negative and oxidase-and catalase-positive, with an oxidative, chemoheterotrophic metabolism.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 (92%) is the major respiratory lipoquinone type; small amounts of ubiquinone Q-9 (8%) are also present.</s><s>Spermidine is the major polyamine.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and sphingoglycolipid; small amounts of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine are also present.</s><s>The fatty acids 17:1<i>ω</i>6<i>c</i>, 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 15:0, 16:0 and summed feature 3 (16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> and iso 2-OH 15:0, 11.4%) are produced, in addition to the three hydroxylated fatty acids 2-OH 14:0, 2-OH 15:0 and 2-OH 16:0.</s><s>Colonies are circular, opaque, slightly raised and bright yellow with entire margins on standard bacteriological media.</s><s>The visible absorption spectra of the yellow pigment (acetone extract) shows two peaks, at λ<sub>max</sub> 452 and 478 nm, and a slight inflexion at 425 nm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15-37 °C on standard media such as Tryptone soy agar, nutrient agar or Luria-Bertani medium, as well as on the nutrient-reduced media R2A agar and PTYG agar.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar and Czapek-Dox agar.</s><s>Does not grow at 42 °C.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Tests for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease andH<sub>2</sub>S are negative.</s><s>Gelatin, starch and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, D-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl D-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, D-arabitol or D-mannose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon: D-glucose, D-maltose, azelate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, suberate, L-alanine, L-histidine, L-leucine and L-proline.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: Nacetylgalactosamine, N-acetylglucosamine, larabinose, L-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-mannose, α-D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, glycerol, D-fructose, D-mannitol, maltitol, putrescine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, mesaconate, acetate, propionate, adipate, fumarate, glutarate, itaconate, DL-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-aspartate, β-alanine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-serine, L-histidine, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>L-Alanine pNA, γ-lglutamate pNA, L-proline pNA, <i>p</i>NP α-D-glucopyranoside, bis-<i>p</i>NP phosphate, bis-<i>p</i>NP phosphorylcholine and 2-deoxythymidine-2'-<i>p</i>NP phosphate are hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <i>p</i>NP β-D-galactopyranoside, ONPG, <i>p</i>NP β-D-glucuronide, <i>p</i>NP β-D-glucopyranoside and <i>p</i>NP β-D-xylopyranoside.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxycillin} clavulanic acid, ampicillin, colistin sulfate, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin and polymyxin B.</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin, chloramphenicol, furazolidone, fusidic acid, nitrofurantoin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The type strain is strain W-50<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14551<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107174<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from activated sludge of a wastewater plant in Wetzlar, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>