<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5843_nm.10063" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10063" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10063" rank="species">Fabibacter halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.5843"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>S.C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plakhotnikova</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobretsov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawlik</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Fabibacter halotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov. and Roseivirga spongicola sp. nov., and reclassification of [Marinicola] seohaensis as Roseivirga seohaensis comb. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1059</fpage><lpage>1065</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64104-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627655</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fabibacter halotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fabibacter halotolerans</em> (ha.lo.to′le.rans. Gr. masc. n. <em>hals</em> salt; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>halotolerans</em> salt-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are pink, circular, 2.0–4.0 mm in diameter, convex with a smooth surface and an entire margin.</s><s>No diffusible pigment.</s><s>Has fast-gliding motility.</s><s>Growth occurs between 12 and 36 °C (optimum of 28–30 °C) and between pH 5.0 and 10.0.</s><s>Does not require sodium for growth, but can tolerate up to 12 % NaCl.</s><s>In disc-diffusion tests, susceptible to ampicillin (1 μg), chloramphenicol (1 μg), penicillin (1 μg), streptomycin (0.1 μg) and tetracycline (5 μg), but not to kanamycin (tested up to 100 μg).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 42.5±0.3 mol%.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are i15 : 0, i15 : 1, i15 : 0 3-OH, i16 : 0 3-OH, i17 : 0 3-OH and SF 3(comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s><s>These fatty acids represent 80.7 % of the total.</s><s>Produces acetoin, but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>DNA and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but not agar, casein, carboxymethylcellulose, chitin or gelatin.</s><s>Starch is weakly hydrolysed. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are positive.</s><s>No activities of <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase or urease.</s><s>Growth occurs on the following sole carbon sources in the API 20E, 20NE and 50CH systems: d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-maltose and starch.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following sole carbon sources in the API 20E and 50CH systems: amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, aesculin ferric citrate, d-galactose, d-glucose, gentiobiose, maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-raffinose, salicin, sucrose, starch and d-trehalose.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon sources in the MicroLog 3 system: l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, d-cellobiose, dextrin, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-glucose 6-phosphate, l-glutamic acid, glycogen, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-raffinose, succinamic acid, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose and l-threonine.</s><s>A full list of carbon sources included in the API and MicroLog 3 systems is given in Supplementary Tables S2 and S3 in IJSEM Online.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, UST030701-097<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-41220<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13334<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the marine sponge <em>Tedania ignis</em> in the Bahamas.</s></p></content></protolog>