<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1893_nm.10938" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10938" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10938" rank="species">Pedobacter panaciterrae</organism><reference id="rid.1893"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter panaciterrae sp. nov., isolated from soil in South Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>386</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64693-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267983</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter panaciterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter panaciterrae</em> (pa.na.ci.ter′rae. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name of ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panaciterrae</em> of soil from a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 6 days incubation at 25 °C on R2A, colonies are 1.8–2.0 mm in diameter, smooth, convex, round, glossy and white.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5–1.0 μm wide and 1.8–2.2 μm long), facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–8.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.5–7.0.</s><s>Tolerates 1 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 2 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase, but negative for lipase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, but not chitin, starch, carboxymethylcellulose, xylan, casein, collagen or aesculin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-mannose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, amygdalin, inositol, glycerol, inulin and dextran.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-galactose, d-fructose, d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, pyruvate, formate, acetate, propionate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, caprate, maleate, fumarate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, gluconate, dulcitol, d-adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methanol, glycogen, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-cysteine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer test and ONPG reaction are positive; tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease and gelatinase and production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-melibiose and d-sucrose, but not from d-glucose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 44.2 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, Gsoil 042<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12594<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23400<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>