<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2339_nm.1884" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1884" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1884" rank="species">Thiobacillus halophilus</organism><reference id="rid.2339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Thiobacillus halophilus sp. nov., a sulphur-oxidising autotrophic eubacterium from a Western Australian hypersaline lake.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>156</volume><fpage>277</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00262998</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus halophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus halophilus</i> (hal.o.phil.us. L.n. halophil...salt loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is based on the type strain deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, Germany (DSM 6132).</s><s>Cells are Gram negative rods.</s><s>This organism has an obligate requirement for salt and will tolerate up to 4 M NaCl; although its optimum is about 1 M.</s><s>It is obligately chemolithotrophic and autotrophic, being able to grow aerobically on thiosulphate, tetrathionate and sulphur, reducing the pH of the growth medium to pH 5.5 - 6.0.</s><s>It oxidises thiosulphate, tetrathionate, sulphide, hexathionate, trithionate and sulphur.</s><s>Ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase is present in the organism.</s><s>It cannot grow on formate or methylamine.</s><s>On agar medium containing thiosulphate, colonies are circular, small (1 to 3 mm diameter), opaque, smooth, convex and become yellow/white with deposited sulphur.</s><s>The temperature for optimum growth is 30-32°C.</s><s>The best growth occurs at pH 7.0-7.3.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but anaerobic growth does not occur on thiosulphate.</s><s>The DNA contains 45.0 tool% G+C.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a salt lake in the wheatbelt of Western Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>