<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7491_nm.2645" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2645" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2645" rank="species">Pseudomonas migulae</organism><reference id="rid.7491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Verhille</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baida</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dabboussi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamze</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas gessardii sp. nov. and Pseudomonas migulae sp. nov., two new species isolated from natural mineral waters.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1559</fpage><lpage>1572</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1559</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555337</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas migulae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas migulae</i> (mi'gu.lae. M.L. gen. n. <i>migulae</i> after W. Migula, who defined the morphological properties of the genus <i>Pseudomonas</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth and circular.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative and possess a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Cells produce the characteristic fluorescent pigment on King B medium and on S1 medium (Gould et al., 1985) and possess catalase and oxidase activities.</s><s>No phenazine pigments are produced on King A medium.</s><s>Strains tolerate low salt concentrations (up to 0.8%) but higher concentrations (5 and 7%) inhibit growth.</s><s>The 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium chloride, fibrinolysin and haemolysin tests are negative.</s><s>No tetrathionate reductase or Tween esterase activities are reported.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction (acetoin) is negative.</s><s>Strains do not liquefy gelatin.</s><s><i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside is not assimilated.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Levan is produced from sucrose and strains possess an arginine decarboxylase activity.</s><s>Cetrimide (N-acetyl N,N,N-trimethylammonium) and L-tyrosine can be used for growth.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine catabolism do not occur.</s><s>Cells have no elastase, DNase, coagulase, phenylalanine deaminase, lecithinase or β-xylosidase (<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside) activities.</s><s>No indole is formed from tryptophan.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4°C but is invariably negative at 41°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-trehalose, D-mannose, D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-arabitol, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-saccharate, mucate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, L-malate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, tricarballylate, citrate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, 2-keto-D-gluconate, D-gluconate, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, betaine, benzoate, putrescine, DL-α-amino-<i>n</i>-butyrate, histamine, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, ethanolamine, D-glucosamine, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-serine, malonate, propionate and L-tyrosine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: L-sorbose, D-melibiose, sucrose, D-raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, 1 -O-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl α-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, 1-O-methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, aesculin, palatinose, α-L-rhamnose, α-L-fucose, D-melezitose, L-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, D-tagatose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltitol, D-turanose, D-sorbitol, adonitol, hydroxyquinoline β-glucuronide, D-lyxose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, 1-O-methyl α-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl D-glucopyranose, Ltartrate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, L-tryptophan, gentisate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, Lhistidine, tryptamine and itaconate.</s><s>All strains have the following enzyme activities: esterase-C6, esterase-C8, L-phenylalanine arylamidase, L-lysine arylamidase, L-his tidine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, L-arginine arylamidase, L-alanine arylamidase, methionine arylamidase, glycyl-glycine arylamidase, glycyl-phenylalanine arylamidase, leucyl-glycine arylamidase, L-seryl-L-tyrosine arylamidase, L-glutamine arylamidase, L-ornithine arylamidase, L-proline arylamidase, L-serine arylamidase, L-tryptophan arylamidase, β-alanine arylamidase, α-L-aspartyl-L-alanine arylamidase, glycyl-Lalanine arylamidase, glycyl-L-tryptophan arylamidase, L-leucyl-L-alanine arylamidase, L-seryl-L-methionine arylamidase, N-carboxybenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginine arylamidase and L-histidyl-L-phenylalanine arylamidase.</s><s>None of the strains possess the following enzymic activities: α-D-galactosidase, β-D-galactosidase, phospho-β-D-galactosidase, α-L-arabinosidase, α-D-glucosidase, β-D-glucosidase, β-D-galacturonohydrolase, β-D-glucuronidase, α-maltosidase, pmaltosidase, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminidase, α-L-fucosidase, β-D-fucosidase, β-L-fucosidase, β-D-lactosidase, α-D-mannosidase, β-D-mannosidase, α-D-xylosidase, β-D-xylosidase, esterase-C14, esterase-C16, esterase-C18, N-benzoyl-leucine arylamidase, L-arginyl-L-arginine arylamidase, α-L-glutamyl-α-L-glutamic arylamidase, L-histidyl-L-leucyl-L-histidine arylamidase, L-histidyl-L-serine arylamidase, L-leucyl-L-leucyl-L-valyl-L-tyrosyl-L-serine arylamidase, L-prolyl-L-arginine arylamidase, L-valyl-L-tyrosyl-L-serine arylamidase, N-benzoyl-L-alanine-4-methoxayrylamidase, N-acetyl-glycyl-L-lysine arylamidase and L-lysyl-L-serine-4-methoxayrylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperatures for growth range from 4 to 35°C, with an optimum at 30°C.</s><s>Strains examined in this study were isolated exclusively from natural mineral waters.</s><s>No clinical significance is known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following 10 strains are included in <i>Pseudomonas migulae</i> sp. nov.: the type strain, CIP 105470<sup>T</sup> (=CFML 95-321<sup>T</sup>), CFML 95-341, CFML 95-320, CFML95-318, CFML95-327, CFML95-316, CF 95-333, CFML 95-324, CFML 95-317 and CFML 95-263.</s><s>The above strains have been deposited in the Collection de la Faculte de Medecine, Lille, France (CFML) and the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur, Paris, France (CIP).</s></p></content></protolog>