<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1016_nm.7261" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7261" rank="species">Streptomyces sclerotialus</organism><reference id="rid.1016"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Chainia species to the genus Streptomyces with emended description of species</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>55</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Streptomyces sclerotialus</i> Pridham.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces sclerotialus</i> (<i>scle. rot. i'a. lus.</i> L.neut. n. <i>sclerotium</i>, sclerotium; M. L. adj. <i>sclerotialus</i>, pertaining to sclerotia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from information derived from several sources (<i>Thirumalachar</i>, 1955; <i>Thirumalachar</i> and <i>Sukapure</i>, 1964; <i>Williams</i> et al, 1983; <i>Ruan</i> et al., 1985).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic organism with extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Spiral spore chains of smooth surfaced spores borne on the aerial mycelium.</s><s>Colonies yellow-brown with a white aerial spore mass.</s><s>Sclerotia formed.</s><s>Melanin pigments not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adenine, aesculin, allantoin, arbutin, casein, chitin, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, testosterone, L-tyrosine, urea and xanthine are degraded but lecithin, pectin and xylan are not.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is</s></p><p class="description"><s>produced but nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol and D-xylose are all used as sole carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is formed from adonitol, meso-etythritol, mesoinositol, D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose and D-xylose but not from dulcitol or D-sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows on DL-α-amino-n-butyric acid, L-arginine, L-histidine, L-phenylalanine, potassium nitrate, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine, but not on L-cysteine, L-hydroxyproline or L-methionine as sole nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 37 and 45°C but not at 10°C.</s><s>Tolerant to phenol (0.1%, w/v), sodium azide (0.01%, w/v) and sodium chloride (10%, w/v).</s><s>Sensitive to rifampicin and sodium chloride (13%, w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not show antimicrobial activity against <i>Aspergillus niger</i> LIV 131, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> NClB 3610, <i>Candida albicans</i> CBS 562, <i>Escherichia coli</i> NCIB 9132, <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> NClB 196, <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> NCIB 9046, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i> CBS 1171 or <i>Streptomyces murinus</i> ISP 5091.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid (<i>Becker</i> et al., 1965; <i>Pridham</i> and <i>Lyons</i>, 1969) and is of the A3γ type (<i>Stackebrandt</i> et al., 1981).</s><s>The organism also contains major amounts of octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units (<i>Alderson</i> et al., 1985).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil, Poona, India.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 15721 (= DSM 43032 = IFO 12246 = ISP 5269 = KCC 3039 = RIA 1317).</s></p></content></protolog>