<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9229_nm.14488" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14488" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14488" rank="species">Serratia nematodiphila</organism><reference id="rid.9229"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>M.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kan</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.-Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serratia nematodiphila sp. nov., associated symbiotically with the entomopathogenic nematode Heterorhabditidoides chongmingensis (Rhabditida: Rhabditidae)</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1603</fpage><lpage>1608</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003871-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19578149</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Serratia nematodiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Serratia nematodiphila</em> (ne.ma.to.di′phi.la. N.L. n. <em>nematodum</em> nematode; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>nematodiphila</em> nematode-loving, referring to its living in the intestine of the nematode <em>Heterorhabditidoides chongmingensis</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods, 0.8–1.3×0.6–0.7 μm (transmission electron micrographs of cells are given in Supplementary Fig. S3, available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Possesses a single flagellum.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are red, circular and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 4–42 °C (optimum, 30–37 °C), pH 5–11 (optimum, pH 6.0–10.0) and 2–7 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs on trypticase soy agar, nutrient agar, cetrimide agar, Simmons' citrate agar and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase and DNase activities are present.</s><s>Produces amylase.</s><s>Methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucosidase is present, but phenylalanine decarboxylase, arginine decarboxylase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production and the methyl red test, but the Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive.</s><s>Starch, Tween 80, casein, gelatin and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but cellulose is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose, d-fructose, d-glucose, sucrose, salicin, l-fucose, d-ribose, xylitol, d-mannose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-galactose and d-sorbitol, but not from d-xylose, d-lactose, starch, diarabinose, d-rhamnose, l-sorbose, raffinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, adonite, melezitose, melibiose, amygdalin or d-erythrose.</s><s>Utilizes adonitol, d-xylose, maltose, d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-lactose, sucrose, d-erythrose, starch, diarabinose, salicin, l-fucose, raffinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, d-mannose, inositol, adonite, melezitose, melibiose, d-mannitol, d-galactose, juranose, amygdalin, erythritol, dextrin, inulin and citrate, but does not utilize acetate, malonate, tartrate or sodium pyruvate.</s><s>Whole-cell fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, cyclo-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, cyclo-C<sub>19 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH and traces (&#x003C;1 %) of C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>19 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, unknown (ECL 14.502), summed feature 2 and summed feature 3.</s><s>Resistant to ceftazidime and vancomycin, but sensitive to gentamicin, streptomycin, kanamycin, penicillin G, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, tetracycline, ofloxacin, amoxicillin, cefamezin, rifampicin, carbenicillin and polymyxin B.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.52 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DZ0503SBS1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22130<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.6853<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the intestine of <em>H. chongmingensis</em> (Rhabditida: Rhabditidae).</s><s>Experimental support in favour of symbiosis has been demonstrated by Zhang <em>et al.</em> (2008).</s></p></content></protolog>