<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9048_nm.13250" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13250" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13250" rank="species">Burkholderia contaminans</organism><reference id="rid.9048"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vanlaere</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baldwin</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gevers</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henry</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Brandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>LiPuma</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahenthiralingam</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Speert</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dowson</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxon K, a complex within the Burkholderia cepacia complex, comprises at least two novel species, Burkholderia contaminans sp. nov. and Burkholderia lata sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>102</fpage><lpage>111</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001123-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126732</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia contaminans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia contaminans</em> [con.ta′mi.nans. L. part. adj. <em>contaminans</em> contaminating, polluting, referring to the metagenome that was recovered from the Sargasso Sea, but which probably represented a sample contaminant; ST102 isolates and other Bcc isolates grew very poorly in seawater, suggesting that the open ocean is not a natural habitat of Bcc species (Mahenthiralingam <em>et al.</em>, 2006)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-sporulating rods.</s><s>Colonies are moist, showing a metallic sheen.</s><s>All known strains grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Known strains grow on <em>B. cepacia</em>-selective agar and some strains turn that medium alkaline.</s><s>Growth is observed at 30, 37 and 42 °C.</s><s>Most strains are yellow pigmented and are haemolytic, a characteristic not commonly observed among Bcc species.</s><s>The strains assimilate glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate, but not maltose.</s><s>Acidification of glucose, maltose, lactose, xylose, sucrose and adonitol is observed.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is strain dependent, but mostly not present.</s><s>Activities of oxidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, aesculin hydrolase and lysine decarboxylase and gelatin liquefaction are present, but no ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophanase, arginine dihydrolase or urease activity.</s><s>The G+C content is 67 mol%.</s><s>Strains have mostly been isolated from clinical samples, but also from environmental samples.</s><s>Strains have been involved in a widespread outbreak in the USA due to a contaminated nasal spray (Mahenthiralingam <em>et al.</em>, 2006) and as contaminants in a water reservoir supplying a renal dialysis machine in Brazil (Souza <em>et al.</em>, 2004).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain J2956<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23361<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 55526<sup>T</sup>) and was recovered from milk of a sheep with mastitis in Spain during an outbreak in 1999–2000 (Berriatua <em>et al.</em>, 2001).</s><s>The <em>recA</em> RFLP type and a false-positive PCR test first suggested that this isolate belonged to <em>B. cenocepacia</em>.</s><s>The type strain is identical in 14 allele sequences to the metagenome SAR-1 and can be used as a cultured surrogate for research using the SAR-1 metagenome (Mahenthiralingam <em>et al.</em>, 2006).</s><s>Phenotypic and biochemical characteristics are as described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>