<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9085_nm.14266" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14266" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14266" rank="species">Clostridium sufflavum</organism><reference id="rid.9085"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishiyama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaku</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium sufflavum sp. nov., isolated from a methanogenic reactor treating cattle waste.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>981</fpage><lpage>986</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001719-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406778</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium sufflavum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium sufflavum</em> (suf.fla′vum. L. neut. adj. <em>sufflavum</em> light yellow, referring to the production of a yellow pigment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, peritrichously flagellated, slightly curved rods with oval ends and are 0.5–0.6 μm in diameter and 2.0–5.0 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on PY4S agar are white, translucent and irregular with smooth surfaces.</s><s>When grown on filter paper as an insoluble cellulose substrate, cells produce a yellow pigment.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative, but react Gram-positively in the KOH test.</s><s>Although spore formation is not observed for cells grown in PYG liquid and in PY4S agar-slant cultures and cells do not grow after treatment at 80 °C for 10 min, thermotolerant cells do occur when growth takes place in media with filter-paper fragments.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–33 °C (optimally at 33 °C) and pH 5.9–8.2 (optimally at pH 7.4).</s><s>NaCl tolerance is very low: growth does not occur in PYG liquid medium containing NaCl at 5 g l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, catalase and nitrate-reducing activities.</s><s>Xylose, fructose, glucose, cellobiose, xylooligosaccharide, cellulose (filter-paper fragments and ball-milled filter paper) and xylan are utilized as growth substrates.</s><s>Ribose, carboxymethylcellulose and sorbitol are weakly utilized.</s><s>Arabinose, galactose, mannose, rhamnose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, inulin, pectin, inositol, mannitol, amygdalin and salicin are not utilized.</s><s>Acetate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> are produced as major fermentation products from the saccharides used.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, hydrogen sulfide, lecithinase and lipase are not produced.</s><s>Milk is unchanged and no growth occurs in chopped-meat broth.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> DMA.</s><s>No respiratory quinones are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CDT-1<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14807<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19573<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rice-straw residue collected from a methanogenic reactor treating waste originating in cattle farms in Japan.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>