<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4418_nm.2140" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2140" rank="genus">Thioflavicoccus</organism><reference id="rid.4418"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thioflavicoccus mobilis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel purple sulfur bacterium with bacteriochlorophyll b.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Thioflavicoccus gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Thioflavicoccus (Thi'o.fla'vi.coc'cus. Gr. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; L. masc. adj. <i>flavus</i> golden-yellow, beige; L. masc. n. <i>coccus</i> sphere; M.L. masc. n. <i>Thioflavicoccus</i> beige-yellow coccus with sulfur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical with diplococcus-shaped division stages, motile by flagella, and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative; belong to the γ-<i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Contain internal photosynthetic membranes of tubular shape.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <i>b</i> and carotenoids.</s><s>Obligately phototrophic and strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic growth under anoxic conditions in the light, with sulfide and elemental sulfur as electron donors.</s><s>During oxidation of sulfide, elemental sulfur is transiently stored inside the cells in the form of highly refractile globules; the final oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, simple organic substrates are photoassimilated.</s><s>Mesophilic bacteria, growing well at 20-30 °C and neutral pH (pH range 6.5-7.5) and requiring sodium chloride for optimum growth.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 66.5 mol% (Bd).</s><s>The type species is <i>Thioflavicoccus mobilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>