<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6315_nm.9586" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9586" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9586" rank="species">Staphylococcus simiae</organism><reference id="rid.6315"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pantůček</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petráš</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koukalová</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Štetina</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chrastinová</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vokurková</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Růžičková</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doškař</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hájek</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus simiae sp. nov., isolated from South American squirrel monkeys</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1953</fpage><lpage>1958</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63590-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166694</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Staphylococcus simiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Staphylococcus simiae</em> (si′mi.ae. L. gen. fem. n. <em>simiae</em> of/from a monkey).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci of classical staphylococcal appearance, i.e. they occur singly, in pairs and in irregular clusters.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming and 0·7–0·8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies reach 1–1·5 mm in diameter on glucose/yeast extract/peptone agar after 24 h at 36·5 °C and are circular, smooth, flat with low-convex centres, glistening, white and have continuous margins.</s><s>The strains grow anaerobically in thioglycolate medium.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15 and 45 °C and in 12 % NaCl.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to lysostaphin, novobiocin and nitrofurantoin and are resistant to bacitracin and polymyxin B.</s><s>They are catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, coagulase-negative and clumping-factor-negative.</s><s>All strains produce alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, urease, leucine arylamidase, esterase and esterase-lipase and reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>They exhibit weak <em>δ</em>-haemolysis activity.</s><s>None of them produce acetoin, heat-stable or heat-labile nuclease, arginine arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, lipase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Test-dependent results are obtained for the production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, i.e. weakly positive when ONPG is used as a substrate and variable when 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside is used; the type strain is <em>β</em>-galactosidase-negative.</s><s>Similarly, cells are <em>β</em>-glucosidase-positive when 2-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside is used as a substrate and negative when 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside is used.</s><s>All strains are positive for aerobic acid production from d-fructose, d-glucose, galactose, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-turanose.</s><s>A delayed positive test result (2 days) is obtained for acidification of melezitose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Negative results are obtained for aerobic production of acid from d-cellobiose, d-raffinose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-ribose, xylitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and for anaerobic fermentation of d-mannitol.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for acid production from l-arabinose (3/8 positive, type strain negative), sorbitol (3/8 positive, type strain negative) and d-xylose (3/8 positive, type strain negative), for production of arginine dihydrolase (5/8 positive, type strain positive) and lecithinase (4/8 positive, type strain weakly positive) and for hydrolysis of casein (6/8 positive, type strain weakly positive), gelatin (6/8 positive, type strain positive) and Tween 80 (5/8 positive, type strain positive).</s><s>No hydrolysis of elastin, aesculin, starch and tyrosine is observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCM 7213<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22723<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the faeces of a squirrel monkey.</s><s>Its characteristics are in full agreement with those given in the species description.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 33·8 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>