<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12896_nm.22714" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22714" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22714" rank="species">Olivibacter oleidegradans</organism><reference id="rid.12896"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Szabó</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Szoboszlay</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kriszt</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Háhn</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harkai</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baka</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Táncsics</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaszab</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Privler</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kukolya</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Olivibacter oleidegradans sp. nov., a hydrocarbon-degrading bacterium isolated from a biofilter clean-up facility on a hydrocarbon-contaminated site</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2861</fpage><lpage>2865</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026641-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257685</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Olivibacter oleidegradans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Olivibacter oleidegradans</em> [o.le.i.de.gra′dans. L. n. <em>oleum</em> oil; L. part. adj. <em>degradans</em> returning to the original order, referring to the ability of the type strain to degrade oil (hydrocarbons); N.L. part. adj. <em>oleidegradans</em> capable of degrading oil (hydrocarbons)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, obligately aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods (0.6×1.8–2.0 µm) that lack flagella.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar plates are smooth, circular, convex, non-luminescent, opaque and yellowish after 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Good growth is observed on TGE agar, TSA and nutrient agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15–45 °C and at pH 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30–37 °C and pH 6.5–7.0.</s><s>Unable to grow in the presence of 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Assimilates amygdalin, arbutin, d-adonitol, d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, aesculin, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, gluconate, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin and trypsin.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for gelatin hydrolysis, urease, Tween hydrolysis, leucine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), β-glucuronidase and α-fucosidase and for assimilation of adipate, malonate, caprate, citrate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, d-arabitol, d-fucose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, dulcitol, erythritol, phenylacetate, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, itaconate, lactate, l-alanine, l-fucose, l-histidine, l-proline, l-serine, l-sorbose, l-xylose, 2-keto-d-gluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, l-proline, propionate, suberate, valerate and xylitol.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Menaquinone 7 (MK-7) is the predominant respiratory quinone; MK-6 is present as a minor component.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, two aminophospholipids, three phospholipids, four lipids and an atypical glycolipid are present as polar lipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TBF2/20.2<sup>T</sup> ( = NCAIMB 02393<sup>T</sup>  = CCM 7765<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an on-site, <em>ex situ</em> groundwater-cleaning biofilter facility on a former airbase in Hungary.</s></p></content></protolog>