<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10084_nm.15033" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15033" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15033" rank="species">Bacillus trypoxylicola</organism><reference id="rid.10084"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aizawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwabuchi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sunairi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus trypoxylicola sp. nov., xylanase-producing alkaliphilic bacteria isolated from the guts of Japanese horned beetle larvae (Trypoxylus dichotomus septentrionalis)</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>61</fpage><lpage>66</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005843-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus trypoxylicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus</em> <em>trypoxylicola</em> [try.po.xy.li′co.la. N.L. masc. n. <em>Trypoxylus</em> systematic genus name of the Japanese horned beetle (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae), the source of the type strain; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> an inhabitant of a place, a resident; N.L. masc. n. <em>trypoxylicola</em> the Japanese horned beetle dweller].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-stain-positive, aerobic, non-motile and rod-shaped (0.6 μm wide and 0.8 to 2.0 μm long).</s><s>Spores are terminal in position and ellipsoidal; slightly swollen sporangia are observed.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, flat and round with entire margins after 3 days cultivation at 30 °C on ATS agar (pH 9.0).</s><s>Growth occurs between 17 and 37 °C; optimum growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 8–10, with optimum growth at pH 9.</s><s>Growth occurs at higher concentrations of KCl (0–17 %, w/v) than of NaCl (0–5 %, w/v).</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of xylan, but negative for hydrolysis of gelatin, casein and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, catalase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and leucine, trypsin and valine arylamidases, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lipase (C4), lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, tryptophan deaminase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and proteinase (API ZYM, API 20E and API 20NE systems).</s><s>Negative for the Voges–Proskauer test, indole production, hydrogen sulfide production and reduction of nitrate and nitrite (API 20E and API 20NE systems).</s><s>Negative for the phenylalanine deamination test.</s><s>Positive for acid production from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch and glycogen, but negative for acid production from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, inulin, melezitose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50CH system).</s><s>Positive for utilization of glycerol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, glycogen and potassium 2-ketogluconate, but negative for utilization of erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50CH system).</s><s>Resistant to flumequine, kanamycin, metronidazole, nitrofurantoin, oxolinic acid and sulfamethizole, but sensitive to amoxicillin, apramycin, augmentin, cefoperazone, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, colistin, doxycycline, erythromycin, gentamicin, lincomycin, oxacillin, penicillin, pristinamycin, rifampicin, streptomycin, spectinomycin, tetracycline and tylosin (API VET system).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7, the cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, and the major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SU1<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 102646<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 13244<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the gut of a Japanese horned beetle larva (<em>Trypoxylus dichotomus septentrionalis</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>