<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.253_nm.9110" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9110" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9110" rank="species">Methanothrix soehngenii</organism><reference id="rid.253"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huser</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wuhrmann</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zehnder</surname><given-names>A.J.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanothrix soehngenii gen. nov., sp. nov., a new acetophilic, non-hydrogen oxidizing methane bacterium</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>132</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00690808</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> (soehn'gen.i.i., M.L.gen.n. <i>soehngenii</i> of Söhngen; named in honor of N.L. Söhngen who in 1906 first described a similar organism converting acetate to methane)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A combined generic and specific description follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology</s></p><p class="description"><s>The non-sporeforming cells are rod-shaped with flat ends occurring as long filaments in unshaken cultures.</s><s>The Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>The outer layer of the cell wall is composed of proteins (O.</s><s>Kandler and H.</s><s>König, personal communication).</s><s>It has a sheath-like structure which shows a regular striation.</s><s>Cells are non-motile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell Wall</s></p><p class="description"><s>The unstable cell wall is devoid of muramic acid (O.</s><s>Kandler, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipids</s></p><p class="description"><s>Di-o-phytanyl glycerol ether (C<sub>20</sub>) was found as the only polar lipid.</s><s>Tetraether (C<sub>40</sub>) and phosphoglycolipids are absent (T.</s><s>Langworthy, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutrition</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Grows chemoorganotrophicatly in a defined mineral salt medium that contains vitamins, trace metals and acetate as the only organic component.</s><s>Other organic supplements are not required.</s><s>Methane is exclusively formed from the methyl group of acetate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, formate, methanol and methylamines cannot be used for growth or methane formation.</s><s>Formate is split into hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Acetate and carbon dioxide are assimilated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth Characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism grows at temperatures between 3° and 45°C with an optimum at 37°C, and at pH values between 6.8 and 8.2, with optimum growth between pH 7.4-7.8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oxygen Tolerance</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exposure to oxygen has no lethal effect.</s><s>Growth and methane formation occurs, however, only under strictly anaerobic and highly reducing conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical Features</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coenzyme M (0.35 nmol/mg dry cells) and F<sub>420</sub> (0.55 μg/mg protein) were determined in cell extracts.</s><s>Two different types of membrane-bound cytochromes were found (W.</s><s>Kühn, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA Base Composition</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 51.9 moles %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetic Relationship</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comparative analysis of the 16S rRNA revealed only a distant relationship to other methanogens.</s><s>The highest degree of relatedness was found to <i>Methanosarcina barkeri</i> (SAB = 0.44).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> was isolated from digested sewage sludge.</s><s>Enrichments were obtained from all of nine examined sewage digesters for domestic wastes, from biogas fermenters for animal wastes, from a sanitary landfill and from mechanically pretreated raw sewage.</s><s>It was not found in enrichments from anoxic freshwater sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type Strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> is strain Opfikon.</s><s>The description of the type strain is identical to that of the species.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms (DSM) under the number 2139.</s></p></content></protolog>