<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2955_nm.5263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5263" rank="species">Staphylococcus nepalensis</organism><reference id="rid.2955"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spergser</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wieser</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Täubel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosengarten</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus nepalensis sp. nov., isolated from goats of the Himalayan region.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2007</fpage><lpage>2011</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02646-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657137</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Staphylococcus nepalensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Staphylococcus nepalensis</em> (ne.pa.len′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nepalensis</em> pertaining to the kingdom of Nepal, where clinical samples for bacteriological examination were collected from local goats).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci, 1·1–1·6 μm in diameter, that occur singly, in pairs and in irregular clusters.</s><s>Motility is not observed.</s><s>Colonies after 2 days on P agar are circular, low-convex, smooth, glossy, opaque white and 2–6 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs aerobically and anaerobically in the presence of 0–7·5 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>The type strain grows well in the presence of 10 % NaCl (w/v), but growth is variable for other strains.</s><s>No growth is observed in the presence of 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 40 °C, best growth at 30 °C.</s><s>No growth at 15 or 45 °C.</s><s>Oxidase-negative.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Produces urease, alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and Tween 80.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Positive for aerobic production of acid from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, mannitol, sucrose, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, galactose, glycerol, erythritol, d-xylose, arbutin and salicin.</s><s>Negative for oxidase activity, clumping factor, coagulase, hyaluronidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, acetoin, arginine arylamidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-haemolysins, heat-stable and heat-labile nucleases, indole, hydrogen sulphide and lecithinase.</s><s>Acid is not formed aerobically from d-raffinose, ribose, d-cellobiose, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, rhamnose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, starch, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, melibiose, melezitose, gentiobiose, glycogen, inulin, d-tagatose, d-lyxose, cellobiose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from d-arabitol, sorbitol, turanose and xylitol is variable; the type strain is positive.</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin, bacitracin, vibriostatic agent O/129, lysozyme, metronidazole and optochin.</s><s>Susceptible to lysostaphin, furazolidone, ampicillin, amoxicillin, amoxicillin/clavulanic acid, ceftiofur, cephalexin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, clindamycin, colistin sulphate, enrofloxacin, erythromycin, florfenicol, fosfomycin, fusidic acid, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, nitrofurantoin, oxacillin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>The quinone system consists of the major menaquinone MK-7 and minor amounts of MK-6 and MK-8.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, whilst i-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>20 : 0</sub> and i-C<sub>19 : 0</sub> are present in moderate amounts.</s><s>Polar lipid profile consists of the major lipids diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid (assumed to be <em>β</em>-gentiobiosyl diacylglycerol).</s><s>Additionally, minor amounts of two unknown aminophospholipids and three unknown glycolipids are detected.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 33 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CW1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15150<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7045<sup>T</sup>) and the most dissimilar strain is PM34 (=DSM 15151=CCM 7046).</s></p></content></protolog>