<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.279_nm.1894" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1894" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1894" rank="species">Thiobacillus thyasiris</organism><reference id="rid.279"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and physiological characterisation of Thiobacillus thyasiris sp. nov., a novel marine facultative autotroph and the putative symbiont of Thyasira flexuosa.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>152</volume><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>166</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00456095</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus thyasiris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus thyasiris</i> (thy.a.si'ris; M. L. adj. from <i>Thyasira</i>, a genus of the bivalve mollusc family of the <i>Thyasiridae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>T. thyasiris</i>  given here is based on the type strain (referred to as strain TG2 in this paper), deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Microorganismen, Braunschweig, FRG (DSM 5322).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-sporeforming, short rods 0.3 x 0.8-1.2 μm, and contain volutin and polyhydroxybutyrate inclusions.</s><s>There is no capsule but extracellular slime is variably produced during growth.</s><s>The organism is facultatively heterotrophic, able to grow on complex substrates such as yeast extract and on single carbon substrates including acetate and cellobiose.</s><s>It is autotrophic and chemolithotrophic, using the aerobic oxidation of sulphur, thiosulphate or tetrathionate for growth, during which the medium is lowered to a pH value of about pH 6.2.</s><s>Oxidizes sulphur, sulphide, thiosulphate, trithionate, tetrathionate and hexathionate, but not thiocyanate or dimethyl sulphide.</s><s>Cannot grow on formate or methylamine.</s><s>Grows anaerobically, with reduction of nitrate to nitrite and gas, on heterotrophic substrates but not thiosulphate.</s><s>Initiates growth over the range 10-45°C and pH 7.0-8.4.</s><s>Optimum pH 7.5; optimum temperature 35-40°C Moderately halophilic on thiosulphate medium and tolerating at least 3 M NaCl on acetate medium.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed by means of ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>Colonies on thiosulphate agar are small (1 - 2 mm), circular, convex and smooth, becoming white with precipitated sulphur.</s><s>The DNA contains 52 mol % G + C.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-10 as major quinone.</s></p></content></protolog>