<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3422_nm.1765" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1765" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1765" rank="species">Pelistega europaea</organism><reference id="rid.3422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryll</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Baere</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van de Peer</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Wachter</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pelistega europaea gen. nov., sp. nov., a bacterium associated with respiratory disease in pigeons: taxonomic structure and phylogenetic allocation.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>431</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-431</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731281</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pelistega europaea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pelistega europaea</i> (eu.ro.pae'a. L. adj. of Europe, because this first collection of strains was isolated in European countries)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, capsulated and rod-shaped with variable morphological forms.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>In 16-24-h-old cultures on blood agar, the mean cell size is 0.2-0.4 μm in width and 1-2 μm in length.</s><s>Strains produce convex, circular and greyish-white to yellowish colonies with entire edge and smooth surface on blood agar.</s><s>The strains do not require special growth factors and grow on conventional media.</s><s>In standard I1 nutrient broth, growth appears as moderate turbidity and pellicle near the surface of the broth after 24-48 h incubation.</s><s>In most cases, a small button-like sediment can be seen.</s><s>No growth on litmus lactose agar at the primary isolation from the infected tissues.</s><s>However, after some passages on artificial media some strains show a poor growth.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Microaerobic growth at 37 and 42°C , not at 24°C.</s><s>Strains grew aerobically (although most strains less abundant), but not anaerobically.</s><s>All strains produce catalase and oxidase activity ; urease and arginine dihydrolase activity is strain-dependent.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate, no denitrification, no production of acetylmethylcarbinol, indole or methyl red, no aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase (except strain LMG 11609), β-galactosidase, DNase, chondroitinsulfatase, hyaluronidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, lecithinase or phenylalanine deaminase activity.</s><s>Glucose is oxidized with the production of alkali using the medium described by Pickett (19) and Hugh &#x0026; Leifson (9); no fermentation of, or acid production from, glucose.</s><s>Malonate is not used as a carbon source.</s><s>Strain-dependent utilization of citrate on Simmons citrate agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains produce acid from D-glucose, D-fructose, sucrose, lactose, maltose, D-galactose, galacturonate, D-mannose, rhamnose, cellobiose, palatinose, dextrin, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, lactulose, L-sorbose, adonitol, D-mannitol, L-arabinose, D- and L-arabitol, salicin, D-sorbitol, trehalose, D-xylose, dulcitol, inositol or <i>myo</i>-inositol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There is no assimilation of D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-mannitol, L-arabinose, D-gluconate, caprate, adipate or phenyl acetate; most strains (18 out of 19 examined) assimilated L-malate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8 and leucine, arginine, alanine, glycine and L-aspartic acid arylamidase activities are present.</s><s>Activities of naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase and lipase (as present in the API ID 32E system) are strain-dependent.</s><s>Lipase C14, valine, leucyl glycine, phenylalanine, histidine, glutamyl glutamic acid, serine and cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, α-maltosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Proline, pyroglutamic acid and tyrosine arylamidase activities are strain-dependent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two major clusters of strains are delineated by means of cellular fatty acid analysis.</s><s>The major fatty acid components of all strains examined are 12:0, 14:0, 16:0, 16:1ω7c, 16:1ω5c, 16:0(3-OH) and summed features 3 and 7.</s><s>However, the percentages of these fatty acids vary strongly among the clusters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have been isolated on common non-selective blood agar media under microaerobic (candle jar) conditions mainly from samples of lungs, air sac exudate and trachea mucosa and less frequently from other organs such as liver and spleen.</s><s>They can also be isolated from swabs taken from the palatine cleft or trachea of living acutely diseased pigeons.</s><s>At present the knowledge with regard to pathogenicity is incomplete.</s><s>The present clinical observations suggest that they are pathogenic and involved especially in pathogenesis of respiratory diseases in pigeons.</s><s>However, the role of co-factors and the interaction with other agents are uncertain.</s><s>Bacteria associated with similar clinical signs in pigeons were described by Andreasen &#x0026; Sandhu (1).</s><s>All morphological and biochemical characteristics reported by the latter authors corresponded with our findings.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 42-43 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 10982, which was isolated from a pigeon in Belgium.</s><s>Its G+C content is 43 mol %.</s><s>Strain LMG 10982<sup>T</sup> belongs to fatty acid cluster I and protein electrophoretic sub-group 1, which comprise 13 and 5 isolates, respectively.</s><s>It is not unlikely that the name <i>P. europaea</i> will be restricted in the future to organisms belonging to fatty acid cluster I, or even to protein electrophoretic sub-group 1, upon discovery of differential diagnostic features.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>P. europaea</i> strains have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Culture Collection.</s></p></content></protolog>