<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2209_nm.6263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6263" rank="species">Corynebacterium seminale</organism><reference id="rid.2209"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bimet</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium seminale sp. nov., a new species associated with genital infections in male patients.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>2244</fpage><lpage>2249</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7494009</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium seminale</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium seminale</i> (se.mi.na'le. L. neut. adj. <i>seminale</i>, pertaining to the semen, sperma)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data for the 12 strains included in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacteria are gram-positive, pleomorphic, clubbed, nonmotile rods occurring in pairs or V-shaped forms.</s><s>They are non-spore forming.</s><s>They are catalase positive, oxidase negative, and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies on 1% (vol/vol) sheep blood agar are white-grey-beige, slightly convex, and from 1 to 2 mm in size after 48 h at 37°C.</s><s>They are non-betahemolytic, but the CAMP test is strongly positive with the use of a β-hemolysin-producing S. aureus strain.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate occurs variably, and hydrolyses of urea and esculin are variable.</s><s>Tyrosine and gelatin are not degraded, but starch, arginine, and hippurate are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, ribose, and sucrose but not from D-mannitol, lactose, trehalose, or glycogen.</s><s>Fermentation of maltose and xylose occurs variably.</s><s>Cells produce pyrazinamidase and β-glucuronidase, but alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are not produced.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, and galactose.</s><s>Mycolic acids with short chain lengths (C<sub>26</sub> to C<sub>36</sub>) are present.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 60 mol% G+C (by the capillary electrophoresis procedure). <i>C. seminale</i> strains were isolated from human specimens, mainly from semen cultures.</s><s>The type strain is IBS B12915 (CIP 104297).</s><s>It was isolated in Strasbourg, France, from the semen of a patient with prostatitis.</s><s>This strain has all of the above-described properties for the species.</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose and xylose, urea is hydrolyzed, nitrate is not reduced, and esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s></p></content></protolog>