<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12456_nm.21284" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21284" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21284" rank="species">Olsenella umbonata</organism><reference id="rid.12456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kraatz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svensson</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Olsenella umbonata sp. nov., a microaerotolerant anaerobic lactic acid bacterium from the sheep rumen and pig jejunum, and emended descriptions of Olsenella, Olsenella uli and Olsenella profusa</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>795</fpage><lpage>803</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022954-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20435744</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Olsenella umbonata</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Olsenella umbonata</em> [um.bo.na′ta. N.L. fem. adj. <em>umbonata</em> bossed, umbonate (from L. masc. n. <em>umbo</em>, <em>umbonis</em> a shield boss), referring to the umbonate elevations of outgrown colonies on solid culture media].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown on FAA and PYG agar plates for 48 h under anaerobic conditions at 37 °C form colonies that are circular, up to 1.5 mm in diameter, have entire margins and smooth surfaces and are raised to slightly umbonate, semi-translucent, greyish-white and butyrous.</s><s>Outgrown colonies on FAA and PYG agar display opaque, greyish-white umbonate elevations (Table 1).</s><s>No haemolysis occurs on FAA or blood agar.</s><s>After anaerobic incubation on PGM, PGMM and PJMM agar plates at 37 °C for 14 days, colonies are circular, punctiform (PGMM) to 1 mm (PJMM) or 2 mm (PGM) in diameter, have entire margins and smooth surfaces and are flat (PGMM, PJMM) to slightly umbonate (PGM), translucent and butyrous.</s><s>Cells grown under anaerobic conditions on PYG agar for 48 h and on PGM agar for 14 days are small [0.3–0.6 µm wide (mean, approx. 0.4 µm; <em>n</em> = 78 for PYG agar and <em>n</em> = 46 for PGM agar) by 0.6–2.2 µm long (mean, approx. 1.1 µm; <em>n</em> = 62 for PYG agar and <em>n</em> = 209 for PGM agar)], irregular (centrally or terminally swollen) and occasionally curved rods (Supplementary Figs S2 and S3).</s><s>Cells grown on PJMM agar are slightly shorter (0.5–2.0 µm; mean, approx. 1.0 µm; <em>n</em> = 40) and thus more often appear coccoid (Supplementary Fig. S4).</s><s>Cells are variously arranged (Table 1).</s><s>Very long, serpentine chains occur with cells grown for long periods on PGM agar (Supplementary Fig. S3).</s><s>Cells are less (after 48 h) or more (after 7 days) variably Gram-stain-positive (Table 1).</s><s>Cells are non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase activity is not detected.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Cells are microaerotolerantly (moderately obligately) anaerobic (less than approx. 5 % O<sub>2</sub>, v/v).</s><s>They grow routinely in microaerobic URAS PYG broth (Table 1).</s><s>During growth, the resazurin in URAS PYG broth is reduced (colour change of the medium from red to orange).</s><s>Cells are mesophilic; growth is absent at 21 °C, moderately good at 30 °C, very good at 37 °C and good at 45 °C.</s><s>Cells are neutrophilic and acidotolerant; the pH range for growth is 4.5–8.0, occasionally pH 8.5 (optimum, pH 6.0–7.0).</s><s>Growth is positive in 20 % bile and is absent in 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth is stimulated markedly by 0.1 % Tween 80 and is not stimulated by 0.5 % l-arginine.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced from meat peptone or l-cysteine.</s><s>No gas is detected in agar deeps.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide is not accumulated.</s><s>Catalase activity is negative.</s><s>Biochemical and enzyme characteristics using API kits are listed in Table 2.</s><s>In API 20 A, acidification of trehalose is variable (negative for strain A2).</s><s>Growth on and fermentation of d-fructose is positive.</s><s>Growth on and fermentation of melibiose (Table 2), inulin, raffinose, α-l-rhamnose and d-xylose is negative.</s><s>Cells are able to grow on mucin from porcine stomach (Table 1).</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, glucose is metabolized predominantly to d-lactic acid (mean, approx. 39 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>) and to minor amounts of formic acid (mean, approx. 4.5 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>) and acetic acid (mean, approx. 3.3 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>) (<em>n</em> = 12).</s><s>Under unreduced microaerobic conditions, metabolism of glucose is not decreased in terms of production of d-lactic acid (mean, approx. 39 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>; <em>n</em> = 10) and is decreased slightly in terms of production of formic and acetic acids [means, approx. 2.5 and 2.2 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>, respectively (<em>n</em> = 12)].</s><s>Glucose is not metabolized to l-lactic acid, propionic acid, butyric acid, isobutyric acid, valeric acid, isovaleric acid, caproic acid or succinic acid.</s><s>Cells are presumably obligately homofermentative and produce formic and acetic acids via the anaerobic pyruvate-formate lyase system (Axelsson, 2004).</s><s>Lactic and formic acids are reducing agents and contribute to the oxygen tolerance of cells (Brioukhanov &#x0026; Netrusov, 2007).</s><s>Ammonium is produced from peptone under anaerobic and unreduced microaerobic conditions [means, approx. 12 and 9 mmol l<sup>−1</sup>, respectively (<em>n</em> = 12)].</s><s>Cellular fatty acids consist predominantly of saturated unbranched fatty acids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids of cells grown in M2 liquid medium are the saturated acids 14 : 0 (tetradecanoic acid) and 18 : 0 (octadecanoic acid) in varying proportions (Supplementary Table S2 and Table 1).</s><s>Well-adapted and presumably indigenous to the gastrointestinal tract of homoeothermic vertebrates, as suggested by the phenotypic characteristics of mesophily, obligate anaerobiosis and microaerotolerance [appropriate to the micro-oxic conditions at the absorptive mucosae (Isolauri <em>et al.</em>, 2004; Wilson, 2005)], neutrophily and acidotolerance, bile resistance and mucin utilization.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, lac31<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 58604<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22620<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16156<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the mucosal jejunum of a pig in Berlin, Germany.</s><s>Strain A2 ( = CCUG 58212  = DSM 22619  = JCM 16157) was isolated from the ruminal fluid of a sheep in Aberdeen, UK.</s><s>Strain A2 can be readily differentiated from the type strain by a negative result for acidification of trehalose in the API 20 A strip.</s><s>Strains lac15 and lac16, isolated together with the type strain, are also included in the species.</s></p></content></protolog>