<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.637_nm.8755" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8755" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8755" rank="species">Paenibacillus antarcticus</organism><reference id="rid.637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mercadé</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinea</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus antarcticus sp. nov., a novel psychrotolerant organism from the Antarctic environment.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1521</fpage><lpage>1526</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63078-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus antarcticus</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus antarcticus</em> (ant.arc′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>antarcticus</em> of the Antarctic environment, where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0·7×2·5 μm) and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Subterminal or terminal ellipsoidal spores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA are non-pigmented, circular, slightly convex, bright and cream coloured.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic and stain Gram-variable.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by the presence of 4 % NaCl or 0·001 % lysozyme.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 31 °C, but not at 0 or 32 °C; optimal growth occurs at 10–15 °C.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, urease and methyl red reactions are positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, Voges–Proskauer reaction, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, dihydroxyacetone production, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production, phenylalanine deamination and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, lecithin, gelatin, DNA or tyrosine.</s><s>With API systems, acid is produced from l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-raffinose, starch, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose and d-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, arbutin, inulin, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (55·32 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 20CM<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22078<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5836<sup>T</sup>); its G+C content is 40·7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>