<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5702_nm.9972" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9972" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9972" rank="species">Millisia brevis</organism><reference id="rid.5702"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Soddell</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stainsby</surname><given-names>F.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eales</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Millisia brevis gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from activated sludge foam.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>739</fpage><lpage>744</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63855-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Millisia brevis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Millisia brevis</em> (bre′vis. L. fem. adj. <em>brevis</em> short, denoting the formation of short, branched rods).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from Soddell <em>et al.</em> (1998).</s><s>In addition to having the properties given in the genus description, the organism degrades Tweens 20, 40 and 60, but not adenine, casein, elastin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Hydrolyses allantoin (weakly) and urea (strongly) but does not reduce nitrate or produce <em>m</em>- or <em>p</em>-nitrophenol oxidases.</s><s>Grows between 15 and 35 °C, but not at 10 or 37 °C, and at pH 5·5–9·5.</s><s>Cellobiose, ethanol, fructose, glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, mannose, sucrose and trehalose are used as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth, but arabinose, galactose, inulin, lactose, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol and xylose (all at 0·1 %, w/v) are not.</s><s>Similarly, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoic acid, sebacic acid, sodium butyrate, sodium gluconate, sodium lactate, sodium octanoate and sodium pyruvate are used as sole carbon sources, but acetamide, benzamide, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoic acid, pimelic acid, sodium benzoate, sodium succinate, sodium tartrate, testosterone and tyrosine (0·01 %, w/v) are not; variable results are obtained with <em>p</em>-cresol, sodium acetate, sodium adipate, sodium citrate, sodium fumarate, sodium malate and sodium propionate (all at 0·01 %, w/v).</s><s>Coconut oil, glycerol trioleate, kerosene, hexadexane, olive oil, paraffin oil, safflower oil and xylene (weakly) are used as sole carbon sources in shake-flask liquid culture (all at 1 %, v/v).</s><s>Variable results are obtained with acetamide and serine as sole carbon and nitrogen sources, but trimethyldiamine does not support growth.</s><s>Grows in the presence of crystal violet (0·0001 %, w/v), phenol (0·01 %, w/v) and phenyl ethanol (0·02 and 0·03 %, v/v), but is sensitive to crystal violet (0·001 %, w/v), phenol (0·1 %, w/v), sodium azide (0·01 and 0·02 %, w/v), sodium chloride (5 and 7 %, w/v) and penicillin G (10 IU).</s><s>Produces acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase (weakly), esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase (weakly), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase, but not chymotrypsin, lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase or trypsin; variable results are obtained for cystine arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain J81<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44463<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24424<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge foam from Tamworth Sewage Treatment Plant, New South Wales, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>