<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9589_nm.14780" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14780" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14780" rank="species">Pedobacter oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.9589"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.-N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter oryzae sp. nov., isolated from rice paddy soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2491</fpage><lpage>2495</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005710-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622659</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. fem. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, referring to the rice paddy fields where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming, straight rods, 0.5–0.7 μm in diameter and 2.0–3.0 μm long when grown at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are slightly raised, circular with regular edges and pink in colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30 °C on R2A agar, LB, TSA and NA.</s><s>Grows optimally on R2A agar without the addition of NaCl; growth is severely inhibited on R2A agar containing more than 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth on R2A agar occurs at 15–35 °C (optimum of 25–30 °C) and at pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum of pH 6.5–7.5).</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed after 15 days at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed by colonies and flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, tyrosine, Tweens 80 and 20, urea, starch and CM-cellulose are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-mannose, but not from d-fructose, d-galactose, raffinose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, melibiose, d-mannitol, l-arabinose, arbutin or salicin.</s><s>In the API ZYM kit, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Trisodium citrate is assimilated, but d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid and phenylacetic acid are not assimilated (API 20NE).</s><s>Resistant to polymyxin B, gentamicin, kanamycin, oleandomycin, neomycin, ampicillin, streptomycin, penicillin G, lincomycin, chloramphenicol, carbenicillin and novobiocin, but sensitive to tetracycline.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;9 % of the total fatty acids) are summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is N7<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12821<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19973<sup>T</sup>), isolated from rice paddy soil in South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.7 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>