<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1058_nm.6236" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6236" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6236" rank="species">Corynebacterium lipophiloflavum</organism><reference id="rid.1058"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hilleringmann</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heizmann</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium lipophiloflavum sp. nov. isolated from a patient with bacterial vaginosis</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>150</volume><fpage>219</fpage><lpage>224</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0378-1097(97)00118-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9170265</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium lipophiloflavum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium lipophiloflavum</i> (li'po.phi.lo.fla.vum. Gr. n. <i>lipos</i>, fat; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; L. adj. <i>flavus</i>, yellow; M.L. adj. lipophilojlavum, fat loving and yellow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, asporogenous, club-shaped, 1 to 3 μm in length, and nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, circular, convex, slightly dry, and less than 0.2 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation on SBA but colonies are up to 1 mm in diameter when cells are grown on SBA supplemented with 1% Tween 80.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, maltose, sucrose, mannitol, xylose, lactose, and glycogen.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea is slowly hydrolyzed but esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, and phosphoamidase activities are detected but pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <i>n</i>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, amannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 65 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolated from a patient with bacterial vaginosis.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg, Sweden, as CCUG 37336, and in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as DSM 44291.</s></p></content></protolog>