<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12850_nm.22656" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22656" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22656" rank="species">Kaistia geumhonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12850"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kaistia geumhonensis sp. nov. and Kaistia dalseonensis sp. nov., two members of the class Alphaproteobacteria</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2577</fpage><lpage>2581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028894-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21131499</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kaistia geumhonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kaistia geumhonensis</em> (geum.ho.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>geumhonensis</em> pertaining to the Geumho River, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, non-motile short rods and cocci, varying in size between 0.6 and 1.0 µm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are round with a greasy surface and cream in colour.</s><s>Good growth is observed on R2A agar at 28–32 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 18–37 °C but not at 10 or 42 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is pH 7–8; growth occurs at pH 6–9 but not at pH 5 or 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, chitin, DNA, starch, HE-cellulose or xylan.</s><s>Positive for urease, aesculin hydrolysis and β-galactosidase activities but negative for nitrate and nitrite reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase activity and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20 NE test strip).</s><s>Assimilates <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, inositol, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, malic acid, d-melibiose, potassium 2-ketogluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sucrose and d-sorbitol but does not assimilate potassium adipic acid, l-alanine, capric acid, gluconate, glycogen, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, lactic acid, phenylacetic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, l-proline, propionic acid, l-serine, sodium acetate, sodium malonate, suberic acid, trisodium citrate or valeric acid (API 20 NE and API ID 32GN test strips).</s><s>Positive for (API ZYM test strip): <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), β-galactosidase and α- and β-glucosidase activities but negative for alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin, d- and l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fucose, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl β-d-xylose, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, d-turanose, xylitol and l-xylose and is produced weakly from adonitol, dulcitol, fructose, l-fucose, galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, mannose, melibiose, methyl α-d-mannoside, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, d-tagatose and d-xylose, but is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, d- or l-arabitol, erythritol, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate or starch.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> cyclo.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B1-1<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 12849<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 18799<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the Geumho River in Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.6 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>