<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3267_nm.1369" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1369" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1369" rank="species">Bartonella koehlerae</organism><reference id="rid.3267"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Droz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chi</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horn</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitney</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bartonella koehlerae sp. nov., isolated from cats.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>1117</fpage><lpage>1122</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10074535</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bartonella koehlerae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bartonella koehlerae</i> (koeh' ler. ae. N. L. fem. adj. <i>koehlerae</i>, in honor of Jane</s></p><p class="description"><s>E.</s><s>Koehler, who was the first to isolate <i>Bartonella</i> species from bacillary angiomatosis lesions and whose studies of <i>B. quintana</i> and <i>B. henselae</i> isolates from human immunodeficiency virus-infected patients have contributed to an improved understanding of the molecular epidemiology, reservoirs, and vectors of <i>Bartonella</i>-associated disease in humans.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is optimal on chocolate agar, and primary colonies are observed after 14 days of incubation at 35°C in a CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched environment.</s><s>The code for preformed enzymes obtained with a MicroScan Rapid Anaerobe Panel is 10073240.</s><s>The new species shows patterns for citrate synthase PCR-RFLP and for genomic RFLP which are not previously described and differ from those of <i>B. henselae</i>.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of C-29 is distinguished from that of the <i>B. henselae</i> type strain by six base pair changes.</s><s>The two strains thus far isolated were from healthy cats; to date, no feline or human pathogenicity has been attributed to this species.</s><s>The type strain, C-29 (ATCC 700693), was recovered from the blood of a healthy kitten during a prevalence study of <i>B. henselae</i> in domestic cats in the greater San Francisco Bay area of northern California.</s></p></content></protolog>