<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3444_nm.5063" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5063" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4958" rank="species">Virgibacillus pantothenticus</organism><reference id="rid.3444"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Wachter</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Virgibacillus proomii sp. nov. and emended description of Virgibacillus pantothenticus (Proom and Knight 1950) Heyndrickx et al. 1998.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1083</fpage><lpage>1090</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1083</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425765</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Virgibacillus pantothenticus</i> (Proom and Knight 1950, 539<sup>AL</sup>) Heyndrickx et al. 1998</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Virgibacillus pantothenticus</i> (pan.to.then'tic.us. M.L. <i>acidum pantothenticum</i> pantothenic acid ; M.L. adj. <i>pantothenticus</i> relating to pantothenic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive, usually long, rods (0.5-0.7 by 2-8 μm) which sometimes, especially in older cultures, form chains and/or filaments.</s><s>They bear spherical to ellipsoidal endospores which lie in terminal, sometimes subterminal, positions in swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 2 d on TSA colonies are 1-4 mm in diameter, low convex, circular and slightly irregular, butyrous (sometimes slightly tenacious when cells form filaments), creamy-grey and almost opaque with an eggshell or glossy appearance ; the appearance under x 10 magnification is reminiscent of white soapflakes in a greyish matrix.</s><s>After 4 d colonies smell of ammonia and are 5-10 mm in diameter with lobed and/or fimbriate margins.</s><s>Organisms are facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>They have a nutritional requirement for pantothenic acid, thiamin, biotin and amino acids.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is usually not produced, but a few strains give weak positive reactions in the API 20E strip; a few strains also give positive reactions for arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, and <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactoside in the API 20E strip.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate reduction to nitrite is variable.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and of casein positive ; hydrolysis of gelatin usually positive.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by 4% NaCl and not inhibited by 10% NaCl.</s><s>Growth may occur between 15 and 50°C, with an optimum of about 37°C.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates : N-acetylglucosamine, D-arabinose, arbutin, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, maltose, D-mannose, methyl α-D-glucoside, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, D-tagatose, trehalose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid production from the following carbohydrates is variable: amygdalin, cellobiose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, lactose, methyl α-D-mannoside and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, L-arabinose, D- or L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D- fucose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, D-lyxose, mannitol, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, methylxyloside, D-raffinose, L-sorbose, xylitol or D- or L-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> in a ratio of 1:3; iso-C<sub>13:0</sub> is present at a level of less than 0.5% of the total fatty acid content.</s><s>The major quinone is menaquinone 7 (Watanuki &#x0026; Aida, 1972).</s><s>Murein of the type strain has been reported as rneso-DAP direct type (Claus &#x0026; Berkeley, 1986).</s><s>The G + C content is 36.9 mol% for the type strain, LMG 7129<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>In the variable characters listed above, its reactions are positive for H<sub>2</sub>S production (weak), citrate utilization, gelatin hydrolysis, and production of acid without gas from amygdalin, cellobiose and methyl α-D-mannoside ; its reactions are negative for arginine dihydrolase, nitrate reduction, ONPG, and production of acid without gas from L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, lactose and sorbitol.</s></p></content></protolog>