<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6715_nm.4036" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4036" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4036" rank="species">Clostridium thermobutyricum</organism><reference id="rid.6715"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuk</surname><given-names>S.U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kohring</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thermobutyricum sp. nov., a moderate thermophile isolated from a cellulolytic culture, that produces butyrate as the major product.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>199</fpage><lpage>204</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium thermobutyricum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium thermobutyricum</i> (ther. mo. bu. ty'ri. cum. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. n. <i>boutyron</i>, butter; N. L. neut. adj. <i>thermobutyricum</i>, referring to the production of butyrate under thermophilic conditions)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells from liquid cultures containing 0.3% (wt/vol) yeast extract and 0.5% (wt/vol) glucose are straight to slightly curved rods which are 0.9 to 1.1 μm in diameter and 2.0 to 4.5 μm long.</s><s>Cells appear mainly as single cells, but pairs and longer chains with up to 15 cells are frequently observed (Fig. 1A).</s><s>In the late logarithmic and stationary growth phases many larger cells (1.6 to 2.1 μm in diameter and up to 8 μm long) are observed.</s><s>These large cells are formed regardless of whether the cells sporulate (Fig. 1B).</s><s>Usually sporulated cells are like the large stationary cells (Fig. 1C).</s><s>When sporulation occurs in mid-logarithmic phase, the spore-containing cells are only slightly larger than the other cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sporulation.</s><s>Sporulation apparently is initiated at pH values below 6.2.</s><s>The spores are central to subterminal.</s><s>More pronounced swelling is observed during early enrichment when the spores are found more in the central parts of the cells.</s><s>After 3 years of subculturing on medium containing glucose plus yeast extract, the predominant spore position is subterminal, with little or no distension of the cells.</s><s>In micrographs of ultra-thin sections of sporulated cells, the spores usually are surrounded by inclusion bodies, which are assumed to be β-hydroxybutyrate granules (Fig. 2A).</s><s>These granules also are seen in stationary-phase cells that do not sporulate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Flagella.</s><s>Although the cells are peritrichous (Fig. 2B), they do not exhibit pronounced motility.</s><s>However, a tumbling motion beyond Brownian movement is observed during the early logarithmic growth phase.</s><s>Cells have 5 to 12 flagella of the 25.0-nm (250-Å) type with a wavelength of 2 to 3 μm (Fig. 2).</s><s>Pili or fimbriae are not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A regular pattern of an outer protein layer is not observed on whole cells, cell envelope fragments, or ultra-thin sections.</s><s>However, in micrographs of ultra-thin sections (Fig. 3) protein-like structures are seen on fragments of the cell envelope and fractions of an additional layer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram stain reaction and Gram type.</s><s>The Gram stain reaction usually is negative.</s><s>Cells staining gram positive occasionally are found during the very early logarithmic growth phase, between 1 and 2 h after inoculation.</s><s>Micrographs of ultra-thin sections show a slightly atypical gram-positive type of cell wall.</s><s>The polymyxin B-lipopolysaccharide test (19) gives no indication of the presence of lipopolysaccharides.</s><s>Such behavior also is known for some other clostridia (19).</s><s>Thus, <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> is classified as Gram type positive as defined by Wiegel (18) and Wiegel and Quandt (19).</s><s>The organism has an m-Dpm-direct cell wall type (A1<sub>τ</sub> peptidoglycan type) (N.</s><s>Weiss, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Colonies in agar shake roll tubes are white to creamish and irregularly circular with lobate margins.</s><s>Colonies on agar surfaces are irregularly circular with matte surfaces.</s><s>Colonies that are 3 weeks old turn brown, but do not produce water-soluble pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth requirements.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>No growth is observed when rezasurin in the medium is slightly pink.</s><s>The exposure of vegetative cells to air for more than 10 min during transfer frequently causes prolonged lag phases or even no growth.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth and cannot be replaced with peptone, tryptone, casein, or a mixture of vitamins (Wolfe vitamin solution).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.8 to 9.0, with an optimum between pH 6.8 and 7.1. (Fig. 4).</s><s>The doubling time at the optimal pH and temperature is 45 to 50 min.</s><s>At pH 8.5, a value encountered in fresh horse manure piles, the doubling time is about 90 min, which is faster than the doubling times of the thermophilic cellulose degraders.</s><s>The marginal temperature data are as follows: maximum temperature, 61.5°C; optimal temperature, around 55°C; and minimum temperature, 26°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrates.</s><s>The organism grows with 0.3% (wt/vol) yeast extract alone but not with peptone, tryptone, or casein alone.</s><s>Moreover, in the presence of 0.3% yeast extract, these additives do not stimulate growth.</s><s>In the presence of 0.3% yeast extract, the following substrates lead to an increase in growth (increase in optical density at 600 nm of 0.4 to 0.8 u above background growth on medium containing yeast extract; see above) and acidification of the medium (decrease in pH of 0.8 to 1.6 u): monomeric sugars (D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose, D-xylose and D-ribose but not D-arabinose, D-galactose, and D-mannose); dimeric, oligomeric, or polymeric sugars (cellobiose, but not sucrose, D-raffinose, starch, or beech or birch hemicellulose); sugar derivatives (D-gluconic acid and D-galacturonic acid, but not xylitol, pectin, or polygalacturonic acid); and organic acids (pyruvate, but not succinate, fumarate with or without formate, and malate).</s><s>Growth is not stimulated by H<sub>2</sub> plus CO<sub>2</sub>, H<sub>2</sub> plus So with or without CO<sub>2</sub>, 0.3% (wt/vol) methanol, gelatin, or ethanol.</s><s>The addition of 25 mM threonine, 25 mM valine, 25 mM phenylalanine, 25 mM leucine, or 25 mM isoleucine does not support, stimulate, or inhibit growth on medium containing 0.3% yeast extract and 0.25% (wt/vol) glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The doubling times are between 45 and 55 min during growth on all carbohydrates except cellobiose, which yields a doubling time of 70 min.</s><s>With pyruvate the doubling time is 35 to 40 min at pH 7.0 and 55°C.</s><s>The addition of up to 250 kPa of H<sub>2</sub> to the head gas does not inhibit growth with sugars.</s><s>As with <i>C. thermocellum</i> (7), a shift to more oxidized products and an increase in acetate production occur when H<sub>2</sub> is continuously removed by flushing the headspace with argon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Meat is not digested.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>When the An-Ident System (API Analytab Products, Plainview, N.Y .) is used for characterization, positive results are obtained at 30 and 45°C for L-glucosidase and arginine aminopeptidase.</s><s>At both temperatures, the phosphatase reaction and gelatin hydrolysis give weak positive reactions.</s><s>All of the following reactions are negative: ammonia production from arginine; casein hydrolysis; nitrate reduction; denitrification; indole production; N-acetylglucosaminidase; L-arabinosidase; beta-glucosidase; L-fucosidase; L-galactosidase; beta-galactosidase; pyroglutamic acid arylamidase; indoxyl acetate reaction; leucine, proline, tyrosine, alanine, histidine, phenylalanine, and glycine aminopeptidases; and formate-plus-fumarate utilization.</s><s>Volatile fatty acids are not formed from valine, leucine, isoleucine, and phenylalanine (0.1 to 0.3%, wt/vol; tested separately).</s><s>However, 10 μmol of propionate per ml of culture is formed from 0.3% (wt/vol) threonine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation balance.</s><s>The fermentation during growth on glucose in the presence of yeast extract can be represented by the following equation: glucose → 0.85 butyrate + 1.8 CO<sub>2</sub> + 1.9 H<sub>2</sub> + 0.2 lactate + 0.1 acetate.</s><s>Variations occur, especially with respect to the amount of acetate formed.</s><s>When no acetate is produced, the molar yield of butyrate increases to 0.9 mol of butyrate per mol of glucose.</s><s>In some experiments, up to 0.2 mol of acetate per mol of glucose is produced, and the butyrate yield deceases to 0.7 mol of butyrate per mol of glucose.</s><s>Yeast extract has some influence on the fermentation balance (Table 1).</s><s>In the absence of glucose but in the presence of 0.3% (wt/vol) yeast extract, 1.7 μmol of butyrate, 5.6 μmol of H<sub>2</sub>, and 5.0 μmol of CO<sub>2</sub> are formed per ml of culture, along with traces of α-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, and propionate.</s><s>These trace products also are found when cells are grown with carbohydrates or pyruvate.</s><s>In the presence of 2% yeast extract, traces of pyruvate also are frequently observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on pyruvate in the presence of 0.3% yeast extract can be represented by the following equation (Table 1): 3 pyruvate → 1.0 butyrate + 3.0 CO<sub>2</sub> + 1.0 H<sub>2</sub> + 1.0 acetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptibility to antibiotics. <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> is not susceptible to cycloheximide, amphotericin B, actinomycin D, and novobiocin at concentrations of 100 μg/ml of culture, but is susceptible to a variety of other antibiotics at concentrations of 5 μg/ml of culture (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Maintenance.</s><s>Viable stock cultures are prepared by mixing 1 volume of a logarithmically grown culture with 1 volume of anaerobic glycerol and storing the mixture in 5-ml serum vials closed with black butyl rubber stoppers at -18 or -75°C.</s><s>After more than 2 years of storage, the inoculation of 0.2 ml of stock culture into 10 ml of fresh medium yields a turbid, actively growing culture in less than 8 h.</s><s>Sporulated cultures can be kept at 4°C.</s><s>They can be easily reactivated after 25 months by subjecting them to heat shock for 1 min at 100°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Type strain JW171K (= DSM 4928) was isolated from horse manure compost containing straw and wood shavings.</s><s>Similar strains, (strains JW172 and JW173) were isolated at 55°C and pH 8.4 from other horse manure piles near Athens, Ga.</s><s>However, these strains have not been characterized in detail.</s><s>They grow at 60°C but not at 65°C and produce butyrate as the major fermentation product from glucose.</s><s>No other morphologically similar strains have been detected in enrichment cultures, under the same conditions, from various soil samples from near Athens, Ga., and from salt marshes near Sapolo Island, Ga.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Type strain JW171K has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen as strain under DSM 4928.</s><s>Its description is identical to the description given above for the species, and its G+C content is 37.0 2 0.1 mol% (as determined by a chemical method [17]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Key differential tests. <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> is a thermophile and is differentiated from mesophilic clostridia by growth at temperatures above 55°C.</s><s>Although several of the thermophilic species have G+C contents in the range of the G+C content of this species (37 mol%), none of them produces butyric acid (<i>C. thermocellum</i>, 38 to 40 mol%; <i>Clostridium thermohydrosulfuricum</i>, 35 to 37 mol%; <i>Clostridium thermosulfurigenes</i>, 33 mol%; <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i>, 39 mol%).</s><s>Among the validly published thermophilic clostridia, <i>Clostridium thermosaccharolyticum</i> (G+C content, 29 to 32 mol%) is the only species that produces butyrate as a major product.</s><s>However, this organism can shift totally to ethanol formation, as reported by Landhuyt et al. (10), and also produces butanol (D.</s><s>Freier, G.</s><s>Gottschalk, and J.</s><s>Wiegel unpublished data), properties which we have not observed for <i>C. thermobutyricum</i>.</s><s>Thus, ethanol formation can be used as a differential test.</s><s>Furthermore, the spore morphology differs markedly. <i>C. thermosaccharolyticum</i> forms a drumstick type of sporangium with distinct elongated thin cells, and the vegatative cells have a rectangular protein surface pattern, whereas <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> exhibits no regular surface pattern and forms subterminal spores that cause only a slight swelling. <i>C. thermosaccharolytricum</i> also differs with respect to pectin fermentation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The combination of formation of butyrate as the major fermentation product from glucose and a G+C content of 37 mol% further distinguish <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> from other mesophilic species.</s><s>Among clostridia, the formation of butyrate is widespread.</s><s>Of more than 90 previously described species of Clostridium, nearly one-half produce butyrate as a major fermentation product in peptone-yeast extract-glucose medium, but only 20 form butyrate as the main product.</s><s>However, in addition to butyrate, most species also produce significant amounts of other products, such as acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, isocaproate, lactate, ethanol, and butanol. <i>C. thermobutyricum</i> does not form ethanol, propanol, or butanol.</s><s>Among the mesophilic and thermotolerant clostridia, there are only a few species that have G+C contents of 37 mol%, the value for <i>C. thermobutyricum</i>.</s><s>However, these species either do not produce butyrate as a major product or differ markedly in their morphology. <i>Clostridium aceticum</i> and <i>Clostridium formicoaceticum</i> have G+C contents of 33 and 34 mol%, respectively, are mesophiles, have different morphologies, and produce no butyrate since they are homoacetogens. <i>Clostridium aminovalerium</i> has a G+C content of 33 mol%, is a mesophile, and has a different morphology, and its main product is acetic acid. <i>Clostridium innocuum</i> has a G+C content of 43 mol%, is a mesophile, has a different morphology, and does not convert threonine. <i>Clostridium nexile</i> has a G+C content of 40 mol%, is a mesophile, and does not form butyrate. <i>Clostridium polysaccharolyticum</i> has a G+ C content of 42 mol%, is a mesophile, utilizes cellulose, xylan, and starch, and forms formate as its main product.</s><s>Furthermore, we found no indication that our strain is a thermophilic variant of any of the other mesophilic butyrate-forming clostridia (3).</s><s>Therefore, we conclude that we are justified in placing our strains in the new species <i>C. thermobutyricum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>