<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6992_nm.2930" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2930" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2930" rank="species">Shewanella olleyana</organism><reference id="rid.6992"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Skerratt</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella olleyana sp. nov., a marine species isolated from a temperate estuary which produces high levels of polyunsaturated fatty acids.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2101</fpage><lpage>2106</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02351-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508875</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Shewanella olleyana</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Shewanella olleyana</i> (ol.ley'a.na. N.L. fem. adj. <i>olleyana</i> named for June Olley for her contributions to food microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are roD-shaped, Gram-negative, 1-2 μm in length, 0.4-0.5 μm in diameter and have a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 2-30 °C.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth was 20-22 °C.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth (minimum 0.35 M, optimal 0.4-0.6 M, maximum 1.1 M).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalasepositive.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Can grow anaerobically by respiration using Fe(III), Mn(IV), nitrate, thiosulfate, trimethylamine N-oxide and AQDS as electron acceptors and lactate as an electron donor.</s><s>Carbohydates are not fermented.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite in the presence of oxygen.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and lysine decarboxylase are not produced.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80, gelatin, starch, alginate and aesculin but not carboxymethylcellulose, chitin, dextran, casein, elastin, DNA or uric acid.</s><s>Weakly agarolytic.</s><s>Production of H<sub>2</sub>S from L-cysteine is negative (from API 20E test strip results) but H<sub>2</sub>S was formed from thiosulfate anaerobically.</s><s>Negative for tryptophan deaminase and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Indole is not formed from L-tryptophan.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>In addition to the carbon source utilization data shown in Table 1, D-fructose, D-galactose, <i>m</i>-erythritol, glycerol, DL-malate, L-glutamate, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine and tannic acid were used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The utilization of D-melibiose, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, fumarate and succinate was variable between strains while L-arabinose, lactose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, caproate, citrate and phenylacetate were not utilized.</s><s>Forms tan-coloured, butyrous, regular, convex, undulate, opaque colonies 2-4 mm in diameter following 24 h incubation at 20 °C.</s><s>Major fatty acids are i13:0, i15:0, 16:0, 16: 1(n-7), 18:1(n-7) and 20:5(n-3) (Table 2).</s><s>Based on 16S rDNA nucleotide sequence analysis, the species belongs to the family <i>Alteromonadaceae</i>, order `<i>Alteromonadales</i>' and class `<i>Gammaproteobacteria</i>'.</s><s>The type strain is ACEM 9<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 644<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21437<sup>T</sup>) isolated from saline waters of the Huon River estuary, Tasmania, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>