<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5740_nm.5993" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5993" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5993" rank="species">Dermatophilus chelonae</organism><reference id="rid.5740"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Masters</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ellis</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carson</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutherland</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gregory</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dermatophilus chelonae sp. nov., isolated from chelonids in Australia.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>50</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857807</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dematophilus chelonae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dematophilus chelonae</i> (ke. lo'nae. L. gen. n. <i>chelonae</i>, of a turtle or tortoise, the source of the first isolates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccoid zoospores that are 0.7 by 0.8 μm (minimum diameter by maximum diameter) to 1.2 by 1.6 μm produce germ tubes (diameter, -1 μm) which elongate into filaments, eventually producing branching mycelia.</s><s>Initially, septa form transversely, and there is a slight bulging of the filament on one side of the septum.</s><s>Longitudinal septa are produced later, creating mature filaments with transverse and longitudinal divisions at regular intervals; the filaments are up to five cuboidal segments (-4 μm) in diameter and are surrounded by a thin capsule (thickness, 0.13 to 1.3 μm).</s><s>The segments separate, becoming zoospores with zero to six flagella; a flagellate zoospores are the most common zoospores.</s><s>All forms (zoospores, germ tubes, filaments, and segments) are gram positive.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>Negative for fluorescent-antibody staining with monoclonal antibody 2F<sub>4</sub> (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on bovine blood agar after 3 days of growth are initially dry and adherent; the colonies are small, very slightly raised, and grey-white and have two hemolysis zones (beta and alpha) at 37°C, and they are white, raised, and larger and have a beta-hemolysis zone at 27°C.</s><s>After transfer to room temperature, growth continues, and colonies are adherent, white, raised, and umbonate or annelliform; the colonies become sticky after several days and caseous after prolonged storage.</s><s>On ovine blood agar, colonies are beta-hemolytic; on equine blood agar, colonies are nonhemolytic at 37°C and weakly beta-hemolytic at 27°C.</s><s>Good growth occurs on 1% tryptone- 1.75% casein hydrolysate-0.5% NaCl agar, continuing for several weeks at room temperature.</s><s>Cultures in tryptosephosphate-10% ovine serum broth produce a flocculent deposit and a clear supernatant, and no growth is suspended or occurs at the surface.</s><s>Cultures produce a distinctive putrid odor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from glucose and is often produced from fructose and galactose (variable), as well as maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from lactose, sucrose, xylose, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, salicin, or trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin and casein are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Urease is not always produced.</s><s>Weak reduction of nitrate to nitrite occurs.</s><s>Indole is not formed; methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Chondroitinase activity occurs with chondroitin 4-sulfate but not with chondroitin 6-sulfate.</s><s>Collagenase activity occurs with in vitro-assembled collagen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to polymyxin B (1,000 IU/ml), streptomycin (10 μg), and neomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Susceptible to penicillin G (10 U), tetracycline (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), and sulfafurazole (100 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differs from <i>D. congolensis</i> by electrophoretic detection of alleles for the following enzymes (34): phosphoglucose mutase, 6-phosphoglucose dehydrogenase, arginophosphokinase, catalase, superoxide dismutase, phosphoglucose isomerase, malate dehydrogenase, malic enzyme, nucleoside phosphorylase, leucine amino peptidase, and lactate dehydrogenase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from chelonids with skin lesions or abscesses.</s><s>Low levels of infectivity on sheep, rabbits, and guinea pigs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain W16(= ATCC 51576).</s></p></content></protolog>