<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3321_nm.10077" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10077" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10077" rank="species">Porphyromonas somerae</organism><reference id="rid.3321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Summanen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Durmaz</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Väisänen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Molitoris</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eerola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Helander</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Porphyromonas somerae sp. nov., a pathogen isolated from humans and distinct from porphyromonas levii.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>4455</fpage><lpage>4459</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.43.9.4455-4459.2005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16145091</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas somerae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas somerae</i> (so'mer.ae, N.L. gen. n. <i>somerae</i>, of Somer, in honor of the late Finnish microbiologist Hannele Jousimies-Somer, who has contributed significantly to our knowledge of pigmented anaerobic gram-negative rods and to the identification of clinically important anaerobic bacteria in general)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Porphyromonas somerae</i> is a gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile rod.</s><s>Colonies incubated on blood agar for 2 days often exhibit a "patchy" growth pattern, with larger colonies surrounded by smaller colonies; they are circular, entire, and convex.</s><s>The colonies on laked rabbit blood agar are white-yellow to tan; after 4 days of incubation, the colonies are pigmented (light brown to dark brown) and show no or occasionally weak red fluorescence under long-wave UV light.</s><s>The organisms are indole, nitrate, lipase, and catalase negative.</s><s>They are weakly saccharolytic, and the pH of glucose, lactose, and maltose cultures is 5.3 to 5.4 after 5 days of incubation.</s><s>Major fermentation products from PYG metabolism are acetic, propionic, isobutyric, butyric, and isovaleric acids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>Organisms are negative for lipase, cystine arylaminidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, β-xylosidase, esculin, and trypsin; positive for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphohydrolase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-galactosidase, and chymotrypsin; and variable for esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase; valine arylamidase, and α-glucosidase activities by the API ZYM system.</s><s>They are negative for α-fucosidase, β-xylosidase, trypsin, and esculin and positive for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and ONPG (o-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside) in the Rosco diagnostic tablets system.</s><s>β-Lactamase is produced by 21% of the strains.</s><s>Some strains are resistant to amoxicillin and to clindamycin.</s><s>They are isolated in mixed culture from various clinical specimens of nonoral origin, mainly from chronic foot infections of diabetics or other patients with vascular insufficiency.</s><s>The type strain (WAL 6690) has been submitted to CCUG.</s></p></content></protolog>