<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6609_nm.6357" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6357" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6357" rank="species">Mycobacterium hassiacum</organism><reference id="rid.6609"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schröder</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naumann</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reischl</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium hassiacum sp. nov., a new rapidly growing thermophilic mycobacterium</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>86</fpage><lpage>91</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-86</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995808</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium hassiacum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium hassiacum</i> (has.si'a.cum. M. L. adj. <i>hassiacum</i>, referring to the German province of Hesse, where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The rod-shaped cells show partial acid-alcohol fastness.</s><s>Colonies grown on LJ medium are scotochromogenic, 2 to 5 mm in diameter, smooth, and (in dense growth) slimy.</s><s>When colonies are grown at 40 to 65°C, they are distinct and drier.</s><s>The strain grows at temperatures between 30 and 65°C, tolerates 5% NaC1, does not utilize sugars, and is unable to take up iron and citrate. <i>M. hassiacum</i> is susceptible to streptomycin, ethambutol, cycloserine, ciprofloxacin, and clarithromycin but resistant to isoniazid, rifampin, and prothionamide.</s><s>Positive for benzamidase, urease, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, and a heat-stable catalase.</s><s>The acid phosphatase activity is only weak.</s><s>Negative for niacin, nitrate reductase, and hydrolysis of Tween 80, as well as acetamidase, succinamidase, and allantoinamidase.</s><s>The 16s rRNA sequence demonstrates that this taxon is a novel species.</s><s>Although its sequence has molecular signatures of thermotolerant and rapidly growing bacteria, the rapidly growing organism <i>M. hassiacum</i> seems to be phylogenetically near the slowly growing organism <i>M. xenopi</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 3849 is the type strain and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 44199.</s></p></content></protolog>