<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1612_nm.10919" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10919" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10919" rank="species">Paenibacillus panacisoli</organism><reference id="rid.1612"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus panacisoli sp. nov., a xylanolytic bacterium isolated from soil in a ginseng field in South Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2677</fpage><lpage>2681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64405-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082410</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus panacisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus panacisoli</em> (pa.na.ci.so′li. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name of ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panacisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic, motile, spore-forming and rod-shaped with a length of approximately 2.0–5.0 μm and a width of 0.4–0.6 μm.</s><s>Spores are oval, subterminal and occur in swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 1 day on R2A, colonies are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, convex, irregular, undulate, non-glossy and slightly yellowish.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C, the maximum growth temperature is between 42 and 45 °C, and the minimum growth temperature is between 15 and 20 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth is between 4.5 and 5.0, the optimum pH is 6.5 and the maximum pH is between 8.5 and 9.0.</s><s>Tolerates 5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 7 %.</s><s>No growth occurs on TSA, MacConkey or nutrient agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses xylan and casein (weakly), but not chitin, starch, cellulose, DNA or aesculin.</s><s>Utilizes d-mannose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-lactose, d-raffinose, gluconate (weakly), glycerol and inulin for growth, but not d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-fucose, sucrose, d-trehalose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-lyxose, formate, propionate, caprate, maleate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, pyruvate, acetate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, fumarate, salicin, citrate, lactate, malate, succinate, tartrate, glutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, xylitol, inositol, amygdalin, methanol, glycogen, dextran, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-cysteine, glycine, l-iso-leucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, l-valine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-proline or l-threonine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease, indole and hydrogen sulfide production, citrate utilization and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-mannitol and weakly from l-arabinose, d-melibiose and amygdalin, but not from inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-glucose.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 53.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 1411<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13020<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23405<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field of Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>