<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2476_nm.11409" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11409" rank="species">Burkholderia megapolitana</organism><reference id="rid.2476"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Opelt</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Knöchel</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schönmann</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Brandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eberl</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia bryophila sp. nov. and Burkholderia megapolitana sp. nov., moss-associated species with antifungal and plant-growth-promoting properties</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2228</fpage><lpage>2235</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65142-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911288</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia megapolitana</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia megapolitana</em> (me.ga.po.li.ta′na. L. fem. adj. <em>megapolitana</em> pertaining to Megapolis, the Latin name of Mecklenburg, the region from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-sporulating, straight rods.</s><s>Growth is observed at 28 °C.</s><s>No acid production is observed in O/F medium with d-glucose, maltose, adonitol, d-fructose or d-xylose as carbon source.</s><s>No production of fluorescent pigment.</s><s>No catalase or oxidase activity.</s><s>No growth on cetrimide agar (except for strain A3<sup>T</sup>, which is weakly positive), on 10 % lactose medium, in the presence of acetamide or in the presence of 0.5, 1.5, 3.0, 4.5 or 6.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows on blood agar at 30 °C, but not on Drigalski agar, on blood agar at 37 °C or on nutrient agar at 42 °C.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate or nitrite or denitrification.</s><s>No liquefaction of gelatin or hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed.</s><s>Haemolysis of horse blood is not observed.</s><s>No production of acid or H<sub>2</sub>S in triple-sugar-iron agar and no indole or pigment production.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to penicillin (10 μg per disc); the other known strains are resistant.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase (ONPG test), DNase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase and urease (except for strain A10, which is weakly positive) activities are not detected.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, trehalose, l-arginine, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-gluconate (weak for strain A1), caprate (weak for strain A1), l-malate, phenylacetate, sucrose, dl-lactate and dl-lactate with methionine, but not adipate or citrate.</s><s>Assimilation of dl-norleucine is weak except in strain A3<sup>T</sup>, which is clearly positive.</s><s>Strong (strain A3<sup>T</sup>) or weak (all other strains) assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase activities are present.</s><s>Activity of esterase C4, ester lipase C8 and chymotrypsin is weak.</s><s>Amylase, lipase C14, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is about 61.5 mol%.</s><s>So far strains have been only isolated from moss gametophytes in northern Germany.</s><s>Plant-growth-promoting experiments demonstrate a clear effect on overall plant length (+31 %) and root length (+36 %) and primary leaf length (+57 %) (means of all strains in lettuce seedling assay in comparison with untreated controls).</s><s>However, indole-3-acetic acid production determined according to Sarwar &#x0026; Kremer (1995) is not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain A3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23650<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 53006<sup>T</sup>), isolated from <em>Aulacomnium palustre</em> at Graal-Müritz, Ribnitzer Großes Moor, in March 2002.</s><s>Strains A1 (=LMG 23652 =CCUG 53008) and A10 (=LMG 23651 =CCUG 53007) are reference strains of this species and were isolated from the same source.</s></p></content></protolog>