<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7155_nm.6010" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6010" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6010" rank="species">Janibacter limosus</organism><reference id="rid.7155"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Janibacter limosus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new actinomycete with meso-diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>534</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-529</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103644</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Janibacter limosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Janibacter limosus</i> (li.mo'sus. L. adj. <i>limosus</i>, muddy, pertaining to sludge, the natural habitat of the species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive and nonmotile and occur singly, in pairs, or occasionally in irregular clumps.</s><s>In liquid cultures cells are coccoid (diameter, 0.3 to 1.2 μm).</s><s>On solid medium strains vary in cell morphology.</s><s>The cells of some strains are short rods (0.4 by 1.4 μm), which change shape and become coccoid in older cultures.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are white or yellow, opaque, and convex; the colony surfaces are glistening or matt; and the colony margins are entire. <i>J. limosus</i> grows aerobically and tolerates 4% (wt/vol) NaCl in the medium.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C; growth occurs at 37°C on BHI medium but not on R medium.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Catalase, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S are produced; urease and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, Tween 80, and casein are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate, formate, malate, and tyrosine are decomposed; aconitate, benzoate, succinate, tartrate, hippurate, esculin, adenine, xanthine, and hypoxanthine not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer and methyl red reactions are negative.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, <i>m</i>-inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, potato starch, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Has the chemotaxonomic characteristics of the genus.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 70 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is strain HKI 83 (= DSM 11 140).</s></p></content></protolog>