<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12465_nm.21295" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21295" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21295" rank="species">Arthrobacter cryotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.12465"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ganzert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bajerski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mangelsdorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter livingstonensis sp. nov. and Arthrobacter cryotolerans sp. nov., salt-tolerant and psychrotolerant species from Antarctic soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>979</fpage><lpage>984</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021022-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511467</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter cryotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter cryotolerans</em> (cry.o.to′ler.ans. N.L. <em>cryo</em> from Gr. adj. <em>krýos</em> cold; L. pres. part. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating, enduring; N.L. part. adj. <em>cryotolerans</em> cold-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are yellow, opaque, round, convex and glossy with a slimy consistency and entire margins.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, psychrotolerant, Gram-stain-positive, motile, non-spore-forming and exhibit a rod–coccus cycle.</s><s>Growth occurs from −6 to 24 °C, at pH 4.0–9.5 and in the presence of 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth at 16 °C, pH 6.5 and 0.5–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase and H<sub>2</sub>S production, and negative for oxidase, urease, indole production and the methyl red test.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch or casein.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from d-fructose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, l-fucose, d-glucose, d-galactose, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Can utilize cellobiose (weakly), dulcitol (weakly), d-fructose (weakly), d-glucose, maltose (weakly), d-mannose (weakly), melezitose (weakly), raffinose, d-salicin (weakly), trehalose, glycine and glycogen as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, l-arabitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, l-fucose, inulin, lactose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, d-xylose, glycerol, l-asparagine, lactic acid, acetate, formate, pyruvate or succinate.</s><s>Sensitive to (10 µg per disc) penicillin, ampicillin, kanamycin, neomycin, streptomycin, erythromycin, oxytetracycline, novobiocin and rifampicin.</s><s>Shows weak sensitivity to lysozyme (10 µg per disc).</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;20 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 64.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LI3<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22826<sup>T</sup>  = NCCB 100315<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a moss-covered soil from Livingston Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>