<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12546_nm.21407" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21407" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21407" rank="species">Hansschlegelia zhihuaiae</organism><reference id="rid.12546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hansschlegelia zhihuaiae sp. nov., isolated from a polluted farmland soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1114</fpage><lpage>1117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021543-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543155</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hansschlegelia zhihuaiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hansschlegelia zhihuaiae</em> [zhi.hua.i′ae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>zhihuaiae</em> named after Zhihua Wu (1935–2001), a Chinese pedologist who devoted herself to the study of soil biology].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, aerobic coccoids (0.6–0.9×1.0–1.3 µm) (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>Colonies are circular and white on YTC agar, 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 3 days of cultivation at 30 °C.</s><s>Moderately sensitive to NaCl (&#x003C;0.5 %).</s><s>Shows good growth in liquid mineral medium K with 0.5 % (v/v) methanol but not with formaldehyde or methylamine.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 25–30 °C and at pH 6.5–7.5, but not above pH 9.0 or below pH 6.0.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed; casein, cellulose, DNA, gelatin and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, melezitose and sucrose, but not from d-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>d-Arabinose, glucosamine, pyruvate and starch are utilized.</s><s><em>N</em>-Acetylglucosamine, acetate, aesculin, cellobiose, dulcitol, dextrin, d-erythrose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gelatin, d-glucose, inulin, inositol, lactose, d-mannose, maltose, melibiose, d-mannitol, mucic acid, malonate, raffinose, d-ribose, ribulose, d-sorbitol, d-sorbose, salicin, trehalose, Tween 80, turanose, tartrate, xylitol and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Weak oxidase and urease activities are present.</s><s>Arginine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, catalase, DNase, β-galactosidase, lysine decarboxylase, methyl α-d-glucosidase, ornithine decarboxylase and phenylalanine decarboxylase activities are absent.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced (triple sugar-iron reaction).</s><s>Reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>KCN (0.0075 %) is not tolerated.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disc unless indicated) chloramphenicol (30), doxycycline (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), polymixin B (100 U), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30); resistant to ampicillin (10), erythromycin (15), lincomycin (15), penicillin G (10 U) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The dominant phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.7 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, S 113<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 18984<sup>T</sup>  = CCTCC AB 206143<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 12880<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface layer of a polluted farmland soil from Jiangsu province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>