<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3400_nm.6453" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6453" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6453" rank="species">Nocardia pinensis</organism><reference id="rid.3400"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Parlett</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greenfield</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harbers</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia pinensis sp.nov., an actinomycete found in activated sludge foams in Australia</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>1547</fpage><lpage>1558</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia pinensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia pinensis</i> (M.L. n. <i>Pinus</i> genus of pine trees; M.L adj. <i>pinensis</i> pertaining to pines and specifically pine tree like in microscopic morphology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UQM3063 deposited in the University of Queensland, Department of Microbiology Culture Collection.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In an activated sludge plant where the organism may proliferate as an extensive surface scum or foam, the microscopic appearance of the filaments resembles a pine tree.</s><s>The filaments are Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-motile, non-sheathed and about 0.5-1.0 μm in width.</s><s>In a Gram stained preparation using acetone as decolourizer, the filaments appear blue as compared to <i>N. amarae</i>, which is dark blue or black.</s><s>Cells from the activated sludge plant or from artificial culture media contain intracellular sudanophilic and polyphosphate inclusions.</s><s>On TYG solid medium the strains may take 10-21 d to produce colonies that are about 1-2 mm in diameter, with the growth rate being variable.</s><s>The colonies are orange, opaque, macroscopically dry and friable, microscopically moist and shiny, with a pasty texture, not adherent to the agar, difficult to emulsify or subculture, circular with an entire edge.</s><s>When picked from the agar surface, the whole colony can be removed intact.</s><s>The majority of the colonies are about 1 mm in diameter; however, some colonies that are 3-4 mm in diameter occur.</s><s>Good growth occurs on a defined medium containing glycerol as a carbon source and asparagine as a nitrogen source.</s><s>In TYG liquid medium the organisms grow as macroscopically visible colonies in a slightly turbid liquid.</s><s>The strains are positive for catalase, oxidase and urease, and their metabolism is oxidative.</s><s>Maximum and minimum growth temperatures are 31°C and 15°C, respectively, whilst the optimum lies between 18 and 25°C.</s><s>Strains do not degrade hypoxanthine, xanthine, tyrosine, casein, gelatin or aesculin, reduce nitrate or hydrolyse the Tweens 20,40,60 or 80 when the basal medium is TYG.</s><s>Strains do not grow in the presence of rifampicin (20 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), mitomycin-C (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), 5-fluorouracil(20 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) or isoniazid (200 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) with TYG as basal medium; or in the presence of lysozyme (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) using glycerol broth as basal medium.</s><s>No growth occurs anaerobically, microaerophilically or in a candle jar; and growth is not enhanced in an atmosphere of 5% C0<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Based upon chemotaxonomy, the strains contain peptidoglycan type Aly, cell wall type IV, whole cell sugar pattern type A, phospholipid type PII, menaquinones o-cyclo-MK-8(H4), fatty acids comprising straight chain saturated and unsaturated acids and tuberculostearic acid, and mycolic acids with 58-64 carbons containing substantial amounts of unsaturated chains in the 2-position.</s><s>Using the API ZYM testing protocol the strains contain esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, phosphatase acid, phosphoamidase, α-glucosidase and α-mannosidase.</s></p></content></protolog>