<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7430_nm.1837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1837" rank="genus">Aquabacterium</organism><reference id="rid.7430"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kalmbach</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wecke</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Szewzyk</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquabacterium gen. nov., with description of Aquabacterium citratiphilum sp. nov., Aquabacterium parvum sp. nov. and Aquabacterium commune sp. nov., three in situ dominant bacterial species from the Berlin drinking water system.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>769</fpage><lpage>777</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-769</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319501</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aquabacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aquabacterium</i> (A.qua.bac'te.ri.um. L. n. <i>aqua</i> water; Gr. n. <i>bakterion</i> rod; <i>Aquabacterium</i> a rod-shaped bacterium, isolated from drinking water biofilms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three proposed new species, <i>A. citratiphilum</i>, <i>A. parvum</i> and <i>A. commune</i>, were isolated from a drinking water biofilm in a house installation system at the Technische Universitat Berlin.</s><s>All members of the genus are Gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria and are motile by means of monotrichous flagella.</s><s>They contain polyalkanoate and polyphosphate inclusion bodies and produce fibrillar matrix material.</s><s>They are oxidase-positive, catalase-negative, display a microaerophilic growth behaviour and cannot grow by fermentation.</s><s>Nitrate serves as an alternative electron acceptor, but not nitrite, chlorate, sulfate or iron(III).</s><s>Manganese is not oxidized.</s><s>All three species utilize Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, acetate, butyrate, valerate, capronate, caprylate, succinate, adipate, pimelate, azelate, sebacate, fumarate, β-hydroxybutyrate, malate and butanol.</s><s>None of them utilizes any of the carbohydrates tested, nor is starch, aesculin, gelatin or DNA hydrolysed.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA ranges from 65 to 66 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Aquabacterium commune</i>, since it is the most widespread species in drinking water system biofilms.</s></p></content></protolog>