<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9254_nm.14531" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14531" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14531" rank="species">Georgenia thermotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.9254"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.-i.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Georgenia thermotolerans sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from forest soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1875</fpage><lpage>1879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005140-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567573</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Georgenia thermotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Georgenia thermotolerans</em> (ther.mo.to′le.rans. Gr. n. <em>therme</em> heat; L. pres. part. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>thermotolerans</em> able to tolerate high temperatures).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular, rod-shaped, 0.5–0.7×1.0–2.0 μm, Gram-positive, motile, and non-sporulating.</s><s>The sizes of the colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, whitish-yellow, circular, opaque and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0–7 % (w/v) but not at 10  or 15 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–45 °C, with an optimum growth temperature of 28 °C.</s><s>Very similar growth rates occur between 25 and 45 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is pH 6.0–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth occurs under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-ribose, d-xylose, d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, maltose and sucrose.</s><s>No acid production occurs from l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, melibiose, trehalose, d-raffinose, starch or glycogen.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine aminopeptidase, phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, pyrazinamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase are present; alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine aminopeptidase, cysteine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the A4<em>α</em> type with aspartic acid.</s><s>The cell-wall sugar is galactose.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides, and the only menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, followed by iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Mycolic acid is not present and the acyl type of muramic acid is <em>N</em>-acetyl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TT02-04<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 104148<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21501<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a forest soil sample in Iriomote Island, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>