<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2434_nm.11308" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11308" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11308" rank="species">Pseudoxanthomonas spadix</organism><reference id="rid.2434"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoxanthomonas spadix sp. nov., isolated from oil-contaminated soil</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1823</fpage><lpage>1827</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65053-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684265</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoxanthomonas spadix</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoxanthomonas spadix</em> [spa′dix. L. fem. adj. <em>spadix</em> (date-brown) date-coloured, referring to the brown pigment produced by the organism].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, curved rods that are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase-positive and oxidase-positive.</s><s>On TSA and BHI agar, colonies are smooth and yellow with entire margins.</s><s>Produces a diffusible, date-brown pigment that becomes more marked in older cultures.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 22 and 37 °C.</s><s>Has the chemotaxonomic characteristics of members of the genus <em>Pseudoxanthomonas</em>.</s><s>Possesses a ubiquinone with eight isoprene units (Q-8) as the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The fatty acid profile mainly consists of saturated and unsaturated acids with straight-chain and branched-chain fatty acids of the iso/anteiso type.</s><s>The predominant non-hydroxylated fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>/n-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, whereas the major 3-OH fatty acids are iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, amygdalin, d-glucose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin, but not hippurate or starch.</s><s>Possesses alkaline phosphatase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities but is negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine aminopeptidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, nitrate reductase and urease.</s><s>Positive for acetoin production, but negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, but not l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.5±0.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB AFH-5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18855<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53828<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from an oil-contaminated site located in Chyai County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>