<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.833_nm.4341" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4341" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4341" rank="species">Desulfotomaculum kuznetsovii</organism><reference id="rid.833"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nazina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanchaveli</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rozanova</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfotomaculum kuznetsovii sp. nov., a new spore-forming thermophilic sulfate-reducing bacterium.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>823</fpage><lpage>827</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfotomaculum kuznetsovii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfotomaculum kuznetsovii</i> (named in honor of the leading Soviet microbiologist, S. I. Kuznetsov, who has made a significant contribution to the study of the geochemical activity of microorganisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 1.0-1.4 x 3.5-5 μm in dimensions, with rounded ends.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Spindle- or lemon-shaped cells are encountered.</s><s>Spores spherical, 1.3 μm in diameter, situated centrally and causing swelling of the cells.</s><s>Gas vacuoles are absent.</s><s>Gram-negative, although the cell wall has a Gram-positive structure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophs and chemolithoautotrophs, exhibiting a respiratory or fermentative metabolism.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, methanol, ethanol, propanol butanol, lactate, and pyruvate are utilized as carbon and energy sources, and these compounds are oxidized to CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>In addition salts of valeric, caproic, caprylic, palmitic and malate, succinate, and fumarate are utilized, and the organism can grow for more than three-four successive subcultures on H<sub>2</sub> + CO<sub>2</sub> in the absence of organic carbon.</s><s>No growth in media containing citrate, oxalate, benzoate, para-aminobenzoate, phenol, acetone, methyl ethyl ketone, isopropanol, glucose fructose maltose, sucrose, alanine, valinine, threonine, or glutamic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sulfate, sulfite, and thiosulfate serve as electron acceptors and are reduced to sufide.</s><s>Elemental sulfur, oxygen, and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pyruvate and fumarate are fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Molecular nitrogen is not fixed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobes.</s><s>Grow when reducing agents (sulfide, dithionite) are present in the medium.</s><s>No requirement for vitamins, sodium chloride, or growth factors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism grows in the temperature range of 50 to 85°C with a temperature optimum of 60-65°C.</s><s>Highest quantities of H<sub>2</sub>S are formed in media containing no NaCl, and growth is found in the presence of no more than 2-3% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells contain cytochrome b and sulfite reductase P582.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The GC base content in the DNA is 49 mol%.</s><s>Source of isolation: underground thermal mineral waters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain No. 17 has been deposited in the All-Union Culture Collection of Microorganisms, Moscow.</s></p></content></protolog>