<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7446_nm.4444" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4444" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4444" rank="species">Succinispira mobilis</organism><reference id="rid.7446"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Farrell</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Succinispira mobilis gen. nov., sp. nov., a succinate-decarboxylating anaerobic bacterium.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1009</fpage><lpage>1013</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425757</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Succinispira mobilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Succinispira mobilis</i> (mo'bi.lis. L. adj. <i>mobilis</i> movable, motile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are curved rods, 0.5 μm in diameter and 2-10 μm long.</s><s>Longer cells can be spirals of up to 3 or 4 turns with an amplitude of 1.5-2.0 μm and a wavelength of 3-4 μm.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>The cells are highly motile with laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Cytochromes are not formed.</s><s>Gram-staining gives a negative result.</s><s>Aminopeptidase activity is absent and the cell wall structure appears to be of a Gram-negative type with an outer membrane.</s><s>Colonies in agar-deep cultures are white and lens-shaped.</s><s>Liquid cultures grow with a uniform turbidity.</s><s>The genomic DNA has a G+C ratio of 36 mol YO, determined by thermal denaturation.</s><s>Comparative analysis of the 16s rRNA gene suggests a close phylogenetic relationship with the genera <i>Succiniclasticum</i>, <i>Phascolarctobacterium</i> and <i>Acidaminococcus</i> within the <i>Sporomusa</i> sub-branch of the 'low G + C' Gram-positive bacteria.</s><s>The species displays a chemo-organotrophic fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Pyruvate, citrate, oxaloacetate, maleate, succinate, fumarate, glutamate and aspartate are fermented, whereas carbohydrates and alcohols are not utilized.</s><s>Formate, acetate, propionate, malate, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> are the fermentation end-products, depending on the substrate.</s><s>Hydrogenase activity is present.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate, nitrate and fumarate are not used as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis, urea hydrolysis, indole formation from L-tryptophan and sulfide formation from L-cysteine are all negative.</s><s>The organism is a strict anaerobe.</s><s>Media containing a suitable reductant are required for growth.</s><s>Growth factors are required and can be supplied by the addition of yeast extract.</s><s>The range of pH for growth is 6.7-8.5, with an optimum of 7.4-7.7.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 37°C.</s><s>No growth is possible at 40°C.</s><s>NaCl at 0.2 gl<sup>-1</sup> is sufficient for growth.</s><s>Growth is possible at NaCl concentration of 19 gl<sup>-1</sup>, but not at 24 gl<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The type strain, 19gly1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 6222<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a mixed culture growing on glycolate, originally obtained from a pond receiving effluent from an anaerobic solids digester.</s></p></content></protolog>