<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1154_nm.1219" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1219" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1219" rank="species">Novosphingobium hassiacum</organism><reference id="rid.1154"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Witzenberger</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neef</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novosphingobium hassiacum sp. nov., a new species isolated from an aerated sewage pond.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>37</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00083</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12086187</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Novosphingobium hassiacum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>[has.sí.a.cum, M.L. adj. <i>hassiacum</i>, “of Hesse”, referring to the German state of Hesse, where the organism was first isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0.8 to 1.2 μm by 1 to 2 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly, they are motile, Gram-negative, oxidase positive, catalase positive; with an oxidative, chemoheterotrophic metabolism.</s><s>Cells may also occur in chains and in liquid media a tendency of agglomeration is observed.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the major quinone type, beside low amounts of ubiquinone Q-9; spermidine is the major polyamine.</s><s>The polar lipid profile is characterized by the presence of a sphingoglycolipid, in addition to phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, and phosphatidylcholine and minor amounts of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine.</s><s>The fatty acids 17:1 ω6c, 18:1 ω7c and summed feature 4 (16:1 ω7c and iso 15:0 2OH), in addition to the three hydroxylated fatty acids (13:0 2OH, 14:0 2OH, and 15:0 2OH) are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On nutrient agar, colonies are circular, opaque slightly raised, and yellow with entire margins.</s><s>The type strain W-51<sup>T</sup> grew well at 15 to 30 °C on different complex media, like R2A-agar, PTYG agar, no growth was found at 4, 37 and 42 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurred on MacConkey agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate reduction is positive.</s><s>N<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Indole production, growth on Simmons citrate, urease, arginine dihydrolase, hydrolysis of starch are all negative.</s><s>DNA is hydrolyzed.</s><s>No acid production from the following sugars could be detected: glucose, lactose, sucrose, D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, D-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl-D-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, D-arabitol and D-mannose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilization of D-glucose (weak), D-cellobiose, sucrose, acetate, propionate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, suberate (weak), L-proline, and 4-hydroxybenzoate was positive.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: N-acetylgalactosamine, N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabinose, L-arbutine, D-galactose, gluconate, D-maltose, D-mannose, α-D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, salicine, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, glycerol, D-fructose, D-mannitol, maltitol, putrescine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, mesaconate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, itaconate, DL-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-aspartate, L-alanine, b-alanine, L-ornithine, Lphenylalanine, L-serine, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-tryptophan,</s></p><p class="description"><s>3-hydroxybenzoate, and phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The chromogenic substrates <i>p</i>NP-α-D-glucopyranoside, bis-<i>p</i>NP-phosphate, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, L-alanine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, and L-glutamate-γ-3-carboxy-<i>p</i>NA were hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolyzed: <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside (<i>p</i>NPG), ONPG, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucuronide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, p-nitrophenyl-β-D-xylopyranoside, L-proline-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to amoxycillin/clavulanic acid, ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, colistin sulphate, furazolidone, fusidic acid, gentamycin, kanamycin, nitrofurantoin, polymyxin B, and tetracycline.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin G and streptomycin.</s><s>The type strain is strain W-51<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14552<sup>T</sup> = CIP 107176<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain W-51<sup>T</sup> has been isolated from a sewage pond on 10-fold diluted PTYG agar.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence is deposited at the EMBL data bank under the accession number AJ416411.</s></p></content></protolog>