<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12095_nm.20084" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20084" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20084" rank="species">Arthrobacter alpinus</organism><reference id="rid.12095"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter alpinus sp. nov., a psychrophilic
bacterium isolated from alpine soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2149</fpage><lpage>2153</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017178-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19880631</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter alpinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter alpinus</em> (al.pi′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>alpinus</em> alpine, referring to the isolation of the type strain from an alpine environment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular rods showing a rod–coccus cycle, 0.8–1.0×1.3–1.9 μm after 3 days at 20 °C on R2A agar plates, often occurring in pairs as typical V-forms.</s><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive, aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar and on nutrient agar are creamy yellow after 3 days and yellow after 6 days, round, convex, shiny and with an entire margin; colony diameter is 1–1.5 mm after 3 days at 20 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in liquid R2A medium and on agar plates at 1–25 °C, with fastest growth at 20–25 °C; growth is absent at 30 °C.</s><s>On R2A agar plates, growth occurs at pH 6–9 and in the presence of 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces catalase; cytochrome oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production and citrate utilization.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, urea and starch, but not casein or Tween 80.</s><s>Negative for activities of arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase, ornithine dihydrolase, lipase (C14), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase.</s><s>Positive for activities of alkaline phosphatase, acidic phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, lactose, l-arabinose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine as sole carbon source, utilizes Tween 40 weakly and does not utilize citrate, capric acid, adipic acid or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose, glycogen, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, penicillin G, streptomycin, tetracycline and chloramphenicol (each at 30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but resistant to cyclosporin A (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids of the type strain are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Contains MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) as the major menaquinone, with minor amounts of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is of type A3<em>α</em> l-Lys–l-Thr–Ala<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>The predominant cell-wall sugars are galactose and rhamnose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, S6-3<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22274<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.8950<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an alpine soil in Fuschertörl, Hohe Tauern, Austria.</s></p></content></protolog>