<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7036_nm.1579" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1579" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1579" rank="species">Xanthobacter viscosus</organism><reference id="rid.7036"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of 'Blastobacter viscosus' 7d and 'Blastobacter aminooxidans' 14a as Xanthobacter viscosus sp. nov. and Xanthobacter aminoxidans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>179</fpage><lpage>182</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02231-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656170</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Xanthobacter viscosus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Xanthobacter viscosus</em> (vis.co′sus. L. masc. adj. <em>viscosus</em> sticky).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative pleomorphic, often bent and occasionally branched rods, 0·5–0·9×1·0–3·2 μm.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Reproduction occurs by asymmetric division (budding) of the mother cell to produce a shorter daughter cell.</s><s>A capsule is formed, but not rosettes.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, round, convex and of slimy consistency.</s><s>In liquid medium with methanol or glucose, growth occurs as turbidity, finally with a slimy sediment.</s><s>An exopolysaccharide consisting of galactose, glucose, rhamnose, xylose and glucuronic acid is formed.</s><s>The temperature range is 5–34 °C, optimum 28–30 °C, and the pH range is 6·5–8·5, optimum pH 6·8–7·2.</s><s>Obligately aerobic but potentially, microaerophilic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin, starch and cellulose.</s><s>Urease, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Indole is formed from l-tryptophan.</s><s>Reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>Acid but not gas is produced from glucose and fructose.</s><s>Utilizable carbon sources are methanol, ethanol, propanol, butanol, glycerol, ribose, xylose, glucose, fructose, mannitol, sorbitol, formate, formamide, glyoxylate, pyruvate, butyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, α-ketobutyrate, fumarate, succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate.</s><s>Utilizable nitrogen sources are ammonium salts, peptone and amino acids.</s><s>Fixes N<sub>2</sub> when grown in nitrogen-deficient media.</s><s>Grows autotrophically in an atmosphere of H<sub>2</sub>+O<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub> and on methanol by the key Calvin-cycle enzymes phosphoribulokinase and ribulosebisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>The main ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid of peptone-yeast-glucose agar-grown cells is C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (76·0 %).</s><s>The major phospholipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66·3 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of strain 7d<sup>T</sup> is AF399970. <em>X. viscosus</em> strain 7d<sup>T</sup> was isolated from activated sludge of a sewage purification system of the Baikal paper mill (Russia).</s><s>The type strain, 7d<sup>T</sup>, is deposited in the All-Russian Collection of Microorganisms as VKM B-2253<sup>T</sup> and the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC BAA-298<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>