<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7367_nm.5380" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5380" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5380" rank="species">Lactobacillus iners</organism><reference id="rid.7367"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and phylogenetic characterization of a novel Lactobacillus species from human sources: description of Lactobacillus iners sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>217</fpage><lpage>221</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028266</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus iners</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus iners</i> (L. adj. <i>iners</i> inert, lazy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>After 24 h incubation on blood agar, under anaerobic conditions, colonies are small (&#x003C;1 mm diameter), smooth, circular, translucent and non-pigmented.</s><s>Old cultures display a 'fried egg' appearance.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are nonspore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows on blood agar, but not MRS agar or Rogosa agar.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 1.5% NaCl, but not 3% NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow at 15°C but grows at 30 and at 42°C.</s><s>L(+)-Lactic acid is produced from glucose without gas.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-β-glucosamine, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, ribose, rhamnose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Positive for alanine-phenylalanine- proline arylamidase, esterase C4, α-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C14, trypsin and urease.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, ester lipase C8 and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase activity is detected in some strains.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed, but not aesculin or gelatin.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer-negative.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is L-Lys-D-Asp (A4α).</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens (urine, vagina) and medical care products.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 28746<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The G + C content of CCUG 28746<sup>T</sup> is 34.4 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics of the species but is negative for acid phosphatase, ester lipase C8 and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase.</s></p></content></protolog>