<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3817_nm.4896" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4896" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4896" rank="species">Bacillus decolorationis</organism><reference id="rid.3817"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Diaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus decolorationis sp. nov., isolated from biodeteriorated parts of the mural paintings at the Servilia tomb (Roman necropolis of Carmona, Spain) and the Saint-Catherine chapel (Castle Herberstein, Austria).</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>459</fpage><lpage>463</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02452-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710613</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus decolorationis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus decolorationis</em> (de.co.lo.ra.ti.on′is. L. gen. n. <em>decolorationis</em> of discoloration).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, coccoid rods, 0·5–0·8 μm wide and 1·0–4·0 μm long, that occur singly, in pairs or short chains (Fig. 2) and show a variable Gram-stain reaction.</s><s>Spores are produced slowly and in small numbers in culture; they are ellipsoidal, sometimes nearly spherical, central to subterminal and swell the sporangia slightly.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are cream-coloured to beige, circular with a smooth to slightly irregular margin, low-convex with a glistening and rough surface.</s><s>No growth in an anaerobic chamber.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5–40 °C with optimal growth at 25–37 °C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration for growth is 0–10 % (w/v), with an optimum of 4–7 % (w/v).</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is positive within 4 days incubation.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, conversion of nitrates to nitrite and dinitrogen is positive and gelatin hydrolysis occurs with or without added salt, but only with generous inocula.</s><s>Reactions are negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and Voges–Proskauer.</s><s>The ONPG reaction is negative without added NaCl and variable when supplemented with 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly and without gas from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium supplemented with 7 % NaCl: cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, 5-keto-d-gluconate, maltose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, ribose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is positive with or without added NaCl.</s><s>Results are variable amongst strains for acid production from arbutin, galactose, glycerol, lactose and d-mannitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gluconate, glycogen, <em>meso-</em>inositol, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, d-raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d- or l-xylose, d-melezitose, starch, d-tagatose, d-turanose or xylitol.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, present at about 68 %; anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> accounts for about 11 % of the total.</s><s>Other fatty acids present at at least 1 % are listed above.</s><s>Isolated from mural paintings, discoloured by microbial growths.</s><s>The G+C content is 39·8 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG 19507<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14890<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>In the variable characters listed above, the type strain is positive for ONPG, arbutin, glycerol and d-mannitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photomicrograph of sporangia and vegetative cells of <em>B. decolorationis</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 19507<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Sporangia are slightly swollen by central to subterminal, ellipsoidal and sometimes nearly spherical spores.</s><s>Bar, 2 µm.</s></p></content></protolog>