<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8586_nm.13571" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13571" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13571" rank="species">Rhodobacter maris</organism><reference id="rid.8586"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Venkata Ramana</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>Ch.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>Ch.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter maris sp. nov., a phototrophic alphaproteobacterium isolated from a marine habitat of India.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1719</fpage><lpage>1722</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65638-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599723</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodobacter maris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodobacter maris</em> (ma′ris. L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea, pertaining to the habitat from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid to rod-shaped, 0.6–1.0 μm wide and 1.0–1.5 μm long, non-motile, divide by binary fission and can from chains of four to six cells.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photoorganoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemoorganoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of phototrophic cultures is yellowish brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 476, 509, 590, 803, 860 nm, confirming the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em>.</s><s>Carotenoids include spheroidene and spheroidenone.</s><s>Substrates utilized by the type strain as carbon sources and electron donors under photoorganoheterotrophic conditions include acetate, fumarate, pyruvate, malate, glycerol, valerate, lactate, caproate, propionate and butyrate.</s><s>The type strain cannot utilize formate, caprylate, gluconate, succinate, thiosulfate, aspartate, ascorbate, benzoate, glutamate, sulfur, propanol, glucose, fructose, mannitol, peptone, sucrose, Casamino acids, sorbitol, ethanol, tartrate, sulfite, citrate, oxaloacetate, 2-ketoglutarate, lactose, maltose, starch, sulfide, bicarbonate, pelargonate, arginine, yeast extract or oleic acid.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, glutamate, glutamine and molecular nitrogen are utilized as nitrogen sources, but urea, aspartate, nitrate and nitrite do not support growth.</s><s>Magnesium sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, thioglycolate and sulfide are utilized as sulfur sources, but elemental sulfur, methionine and cysteine do not support growth.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth of the type strain; NaCl concentrations up to 3 % (w/v) are tolerated.</s><s>Strain JA276<sup>T</sup> grows at pH 6.0–8.0 (optimally at pH 6.5–7.0) and at 25–35 °C (optimally at 30 °C).</s><s>Thiamine is required as a growth factor.</s><s>Autotrophic and fermentative growth is not possible.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 62.85 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA276<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14794<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1549<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 55129<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from samples of a sediment collected from the seashore of Cochin, Kerala State, India.</s></p></content></protolog>