<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9670_nm.14807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14807" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14807" rank="species">Nocardiopsis litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.9670"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis litoralis sp. nov., a halophilic marine actinomycete isolated from a sea anemone</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2708</fpage><lpage>2713</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009704-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625431</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardiopsis litoralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardiopsis litoralis</em> (li.to.ra′lis. L. adj. <em>litoralis</em> of the shore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, moderately halophilic, alkalitolerant, non-motile, filamentous, aerobic actinomycete that forms white aerial mycelium and white to yellow–white substrate mycelium and straight to flexuous hyphae.</s><s>Good growth occurs on most of the media tested.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Substrate hyphae are well developed and fragment with age.</s><s>Long, straight to flexuous spore chains are borne on aerial hyphae, which fragment into elongated non-motile spores (0.5–0.7×1.5–1.8 μm in size) with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Grows optimally at 25 °C and pH 8.5 and in the presence of 5–7 % (w/v) total salts.</s><s>Growth is not observed in the absence of salts.</s><s>Positive for catalase but negative for oxidase.</s><s>Unable to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and melanin are not produced.</s><s>Degrades adenine, gelatin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine, but not aesculin, casein, cellulose, chitin, DNA, starch, Tweens (20, 40, 60, 80) or urea.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole source of carbon and energy or sole source of carbon, nitrogen and energy: d-glucose, sucrose, d-xylose and l-alanine.</s><s>The following substances are not utilized: l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, trehalose, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, citrate, gluconate, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and l-valine.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and no diagnostic sugars.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 073097<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45168<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19473<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from homogenates of a sea anemone collected from a tidal flat on Naozhou Island in the South China Sea, near Zhanjiang City, southern China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.4 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p></content></protolog>