<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2450_nm.11357" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11357" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11357" rank="species">Glycomyces sambucus</organism><reference id="rid.2450"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glycomyces sambucus sp. nov., an endophytic actinomycete isolated from the stem of Sambucus adnata Wall.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1995</fpage><lpage>1998</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65064-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766861</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glycomyces sambucus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glycomyces sambucus</em> (sam′bu.cus. N.L. gen. n. <em>sambucus</em> of the plant genus <em>Sambucus</em>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic actinomycete that forms yellowish-white to tan substrate mycelium, depending on the growth medium.</s><s>White aerial mycelia are produced and fragment into square-ended conidia.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-lactulose or l-sorbose.</s><s>d-Cellobiose, l-fucose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, sucrose, glycerol, glycogen, l-arginine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-tyrosine, l-valine, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and salicin are utilized as sole carbon source, but d-fructose, d-inulin, d-lactulose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, d-xylose, erythritol, inositol, l-alanine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, malonate, d-glutamic acid, d-sorbose and l-cysteine are not.</s><s>d-Melezitose and d-raffinose are weakly utilized as sole carbon source.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C.</s><s>Additional physiological properties are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern consists of galactose, glucose, xylose and ribose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-11 (69 %) and MK-11 (H<sub>4</sub>) (26 %).</s><s>The fatty acid profile comprises major amounts of 16 : 0 iso (28.8 %), 15 : 0 anteiso (26.2 %) and 17 : 0 anteiso (18.0 %), and minor amounts of 15 : 0 iso (8.2 %), 14 : 0 iso (7.2 %), 16 : 0 iso G (5.4 %), 17 : 1 anteiso A (2.8 %) and 17 : 0 iso (1.4 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 70 mol%.</s><s>Other chemotaxonomic characteristics are typical of the genus <em>Glycomyces</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, E71<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.3147<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45047<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface-sterilized stem of <em>Sambucus adnata</em> Wall collected in the rainforest of Jinghong Natural Reserve, Yunnan Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>