<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.123_nm.3371" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3371" rank="genus">Pasteurella</organism><reference id="rid.123"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ihm</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pohl</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frederiksen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mannheim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of the genus Pasteurella Trevisan 1887 on the basis of deoxyribonucleic acid homology, with proposals for the new species Pasteurella dagmatis, Pasteurella canis, Pasteurella stomatis, Pasteurella anatis, and Pasteurella langaa.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>309</fpage><lpage>322</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Pasteurella</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(Pas.teu.rel'la. M .L.dim.fem.n. <i>Pasteurella</i> named after Louis Pasteur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are nonmotile, small, and coccoid to rod shaped, and, depending on the growth stage, they occur singly, in pairs, or short chains.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on chocolate agar are round, grayish or yellowish, and nearly 2 mm in diameter after 48 h.</s><s>Colonies of some species have a rough character and may reach 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>No hemolysis on sheep blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mesophilic; chemoorganotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Ubiquinones and demethylmenaquinones are produced; molecular oxygen is used as a terminal electron acceptor but can be replaced bynitrate and fumarate.</s><s>Oxidase positive, alkaline phosphatase positive, almost always catalase positive.</s><s>Most species are V-factor (β-nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide) and X-factor (protohemin or protoporphyrin IX) independent, although V-factor-requiring species and strains do occur.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus are always promptly positive for fermentation of D-glucose, D-galactose, D-fructose, Dmannose, and sucrose; acid is not produced from L-sorbose, L-rhamnose, <i>m</i>-inositol, or adonitol.</s><s>No hydrolysis of starch, salicin, or esculin occurs.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, and liquefaction of gelatin are negative, except for a delayed gelatinase reaction that is observed after more than 14 days of incubation with strains of <i>P. dagmatis</i>.</s><s>Fermentation of maltose is mostly combined with fermentation of trehalose.</s><s>Members of the genus are parasitic in vertebrates, particularly mammals and birds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genome DNAs of members of the genus <i>Pasteurella</i> contain 37.7 to 45.9 mol% G+C (T, method).</s><s>The genome molecular weights range from 1.4 x 10<sup>9</sup> to 1.9 x 10<sup>9</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: Pasteurella multocida (Lehmann and Neumann, 1899) Rosenbusch and Merchant 1939.</s></p></content></protolog>