<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3901_nm.11289" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11289" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11289" rank="species">Hymenobacter xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.3901"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hymenobacter xinjiangensis sp. nov., a radiation-resistant bacterium isolated from the desert of Xinjiang, China.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1752</fpage><lpage>1756</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65033-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684250</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hymenobacter xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hymenobacter xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, an autonomous region in north-west China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Motility is not observed.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.7×2–5 μm in size.</s><s>Cells grow best on nutrient-reduced media such as 0.1× TSA and PYES agar.</s><s>Colonies on 0.1× TSA and PYES agar are translucent, pink, circular, entire, of low convexity and rough; colony diameter is up to 1.5 cm after 5 days at 28 °C.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C (optimum 28 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is positive.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of glucose, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, citrate utilization, indole production and urease.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase activity are detectable.</s><s>Lipase C14, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activity are not detectable.</s><s>Positive in the Biolog system for dextrin, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, acetic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, glucuronamide, l-alanine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, dl-carnitine, thymidine and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Negative in the Biolog system for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol and glycerol.</s><s>Sensitive to chloramphenicol, colistin sulfate, erythromycin, gentamicin, penicillin G, polymyxin B sulfate, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>Tolerates high doses of gamma radiation, with a D<sub>10</sub> (dose required to reduce the bacterial population by 10-fold) of 4.8 kGy.</s><s>Quinone system is menaquinone MK-7.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (19.5 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (20.2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (10.6 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (6.2 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B/iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I (8.5 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (6.5 %); complete fatty acid data are given in Table 2.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 54 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, X2-1g<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 206080<sup>T</sup> =IAM 15452<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from gamma-irradiated soil of the Xinjiang desert, China.</s></p></content></protolog>