<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4538_nm.12213" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12213" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6437" rank="species">Nocardia cyriacigeorgici</organism><reference id="rid.4538"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia cyriacigeorgici sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1419</fpage><lpage>1423</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491341</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia cyriacigeorgici</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia cyriacigeorgici</i> (cy.ri.a.ci.ge.or'gi.ci. Gr. neut. n. <i>kyriako'n</i> house of the lord, church; M.L. neut. n. <i>cyriacum</i>, <i>cyriaci</i> church; Gr. adj. <i>georgikos</i> related to agriculture, related to St George; M.L. adj. <i>georgicus</i> of St George; M.L. adj. <i>cyriacigeorgici</i> of St George's church, referring to the origin of the name of the German town Gelsenkirchen where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hyphae are Gram-positive and slightly acid-alcohol-fast.</s><s>The vegetative hyphae are well-developed with irregular branches penetrating the agar and bear white aerial hyphae.</s><s>At a late stage of growth, the hyphae fragment into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>The organism contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e. cell wall chemotype IV).</s><s>It has mycolic acids with 46-54 carbon atoms and 0-3 double bonds (C<sub>46:0</sub>, C<sub>46:3</sub>, C<sub>48:0</sub>, C<sub>48:3</sub>, C<sub>50:0</sub>, C<sub>50:1</sub>, C<sub>50:3</sub>, C<sub>52:0</sub>, C<sub>52:1</sub> and C<sub>54:1</sub>) that are cleaved on pyrolysis to release fatty acids with C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>18:1</sub> and C<sub>18:0</sub> carbon atoms with C<sub>16:0</sub> as the major cleavage product; thus <i>Nocardia cyriacigeorgici</i> has a cellular fatty acid profile that comprises saturated, unsaturated and 10-methyl branched fatty acids.</s><s>Possesses type PII phospholipids with significant amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The menaquinone system consists of partially saturated menaquinones with eight isoprene units, in which the two terminal isoprene moieties are cyclized ; MK-8(H<sub>6</sub>) is the major menaquinone and minor amounts of 2,3-epoxy-MK-8(H<sub>6</sub>) are also present.</s><s>It hydrolyses aesculin, testosterone and urea but not adenine, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, keratin, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, gluconate, sucrose and paraffin as carbon sources but not adipate, benzoate, citrate, lactate, arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, trehalose, xylose, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butanediol, 1,2-propanediol, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate or phydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Utilizes acetamide, but not alanine, gelatin, proline or serine, as simultaneous carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 68.1 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is IMMIB D-1627<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44484<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the bronchial secretion of a patient suffering from chronic bronchitis.</s></p></content></protolog>