<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5798_nm.4225" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4225" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4225" rank="species">Tissierella creatinini</organism><reference id="rid.5798"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gauglitz</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic evidence that the gram-negative nonsporulating bacterium Tissierella (Bacteroides) praeacuta is a member of the Clostridium subphylum of the gram-positive bacteria and description of Tissierella creatinini sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>436</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-436</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tissierella creatinini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tissierella creatinini</i> (cre.a.ti.ni' ni. N. L. gen. n. <i>creatinini</i>, of creatinine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (1.0 by 3.5 μm) and occur mostly singly or in pairs and rarely in chains of four to six cells (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells are nonmotile, and spores are not observed.</s><s>Cells are gram positive and are surrounded by a slime capsule that is easily detectable in India ink preparations.</s><s>Grows anaerobically in AMO.1 medium containing 0.05% yeast extract, 0.05% Trypticase, and creatinine or N-methylhydantoin.</s><s>Growth is stimulated fivefold by the addition of formate (40 mM), twofold by the addition of serine (2 g/liter) or threonine (2 dliter), and threefold by the addition of arginine (2 g/liter) and serine (2 g/liter), but not by the addition of arginine alone.</s><s>In the absence of creatinine or N-methylhydantoin, formate and amino acids do not support growth.</s><s>No stimulation of growth is produced by lactate, malate, succinate, glycerol, or H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Yeast extract (optimal concentration, 0.5 to 1.0%) is required for growth and cannot be replaced by Casamino Acids or peptones.</s><s>Utilizes a limited range of mainly nitrogen-containing compounds, such as creatinine and structurally related substances, for growth.</s><s>Not able to utilize creatine, carbohydrates, or various other substances (Table 2).</s><s>Very weak growth occurs in peptone-yeast extract media (10), and biochemical tests for gelatin hydrolysis, production of lipase, lecithinase, indole, and urease, digestion of meat and milk, reduction of nitrate, and hemolysis are negative.</s><s>Grows at 20 and 39°C, and optimum growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.7 to 9.1, and the optimum pH is pH 8.3 (determined with N-methylhydantoin as the substrate).</s><s>Sodium bicarbonate and sodium chloride are required for good growth; the optimum concentrations of these compounds are 27 and 60 mM, respectively, in AMO.1 medium containing 0.5% yeast extract and 50 mM N-methylhydantoin as the substrate.</s><s>Creatinine is metabolized via N-methylhydantoin, N-carbamoylsarcosine, and sarcosine to acetate, ammonia, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>In a typical growth experiment performed with AMO.1 medium containing 0.5% yeast extract, 2 g of serine per liter, 2 g of threonine per liter, and 46 mM creatinine, the fermentation products formed after 60 h are 22 mmol of acetate per liter, 78 mmol of ammonia per liter, 24 mmol of sarcosine per liter, and 7 mmol of N-carbamoylsarcosine per liter.</s><s>Respiratory menaquinones are not produced.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 32 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall murein is based on L-ornithine with D-glutamic acid as the interpeptide bridge (type A4β).</s><s>Contains predominantly unsaturated fatty acids; C<sub>18:1 c11/12</sub> (61%) is the major component.</s><s>Minor amounts of straight-chain saturated, methylbranched, and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are also produced.</s><s>Isolated from a sugar refinery wastewater pond.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 9508 (= BN11).</s></p></content></protolog>