<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6711_nm.5240" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5240" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5240" rank="species">Staphylococcus caseolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6711"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faller</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Endl</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of "Micrococcus candidus" ATCC 14852 as a strain of Staphylococcus epidermidis and of "Micrococcus caseolyticus" ATCC 13548 and Micrococcus varians ATCC 29750 as members of a new species, Staphylococcus caseolyticus.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus caseolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus caseolyticus</i> (ca.se.o.ly'ti-cus. L. noun <i>caseus</i> cheese; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i> able to loose; M.L. adj. <i>caseolyticus</i> casein-dissolving.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cocci, 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in pairs and clusters, occasionally singly.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Colonies are slightly convex, circular, usually entire, 2 to 5 mm in diameter, smooth, glistening, and opaque.</s><s>Pigment occurs as a yellow ring around the edge of the colonies.</s><s>Growth is predominantly aerobic; under anaerobic conditions, growth is rather weak.</s><s>A small amount of L-(+)-lactic acid is produced from glucose under anaerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains failed to produce coagulase.</s><s>They were catalase positive and also reacted positively in the modified oxidase and benzidine tests.</s><s>Both strains produced acid aerobically from glucose, maltose, fructose, ribose, galactose, and lactose; strain 29750 also produced acid from sucrose.</s><s>No acid was produced from mannose, mannitol, xylose, xylitol, or turnanose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains were resistant to lysozyme and were susceptible only to a high concentration (500 μg/ml) of lysostaphin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is L-Lys-Gly<sub>4</sub>, L-Ser.</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acids are atypical, since they contain only small amounts of glycerol.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38 to 39 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. caseolyticus</i> can be distinguished from all other known staphylococci primarily on the basis of carbohydrate reaction pattern, novobiocin susceptibility, cell wall composition, positive oxidase reaction, weak lysostaphin susceptibility, low acid production under anaerobic conditions, and the presence of class II FDP aldolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 13548.</s><s>A description of this strain is presented below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells: Spheres, 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in pairs and clusters.</s><s>Nonmotile and nonsporeforming.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies: Circular entire, 3 to 5 mm in diameter, low convex, smooth with glistening surface, sticky consistency.</s><s>Opaque pale cream with yellow edge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, benzidine, and oxidase tests are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic; metabolism is respiratory.</s><s>Cytochromes of type c are present in the electron transport system.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, there is almost no growth.</s><s>A class II FDP aldolase is produced.</s><s>Coagulase is not produced.</s><s>Sheep blood is not hemolyzed.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Casein is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Susceptible to novobiocin (4.6 μg/ml).</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically from glucose, fructose, ribose, maltose, lactose, galactose, and trehalose.</s><s>No acid from mannose, mannitol, xylose, xylitol, turanose, or sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan: L-Lys-Gly<sub>4</sub>, L-Ser.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall teichoic acid composition: glucose and N-acetylgalactosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only small amounts of N-acetylglucosamine and glycerol are present.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA: 38 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>