<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12623_nm.22152" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22152" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22152" rank="species">Massilia consociata</organism><reference id="rid.12623"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revision of the genus Massilia La Scola et al. 2000, with an emended description of the genus and inclusion of all species of the genus Naxibacter as new combinations, and proposal of Massilia consociata sp. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1528</fpage><lpage>1533</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025585-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656816</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Massilia consociata</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Massilia consociata</em> (con.so.ci′a.ta. L. part. fem. adj. <em>consociata</em> associated; intended to mean that the organism was associated with a human clinical case).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are weakly motile, non-spore-forming rods (approx. 2 µm in length and 1 µm in width).</s><s>Gram-stain-negative, oxidase-positive, showing an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar, TSA, PYE agar, nutrient agar and MacConkey agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Grows on TSA at temperatures ranging from 15 to 37 °C.</s><s>No growth at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Grows in TS broth at pH 5.5–10.5.</s><s>Beige, translucent and shiny colonies with entire edges are formed within 24 h, with a diameter of approximately 2 mm.</s><s>Quinone system consists of ubiquinone Q-8.</s><s>The major compounds in the polar lipid profile are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Moderate amounts of three unknown phospholipids and of one unknown aminolipid are present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is largely composed of summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> as well as moderate amounts of C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Carbon source utilization and hydrolysis of chromogenic substrates (including differentiating characters for all species of the genus <em>Naxibacter</em>) are indicated in Table 2.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, trisodium citrate, glycogen, propionic acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline, but not potassium gluconate, l-rhamnose, suberic acid, lactic acid, l-alanine, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine or l-histidine.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, urease and oxidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 58010<sup>T</sup> ( = CCM 7792<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in Göteborg, Sweden, from blood of a 48-year-old man.</s></p></content></protolog>