<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12906_nm.22727" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22727" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22727" rank="species">Bisgaardia hudsonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12906"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclair</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korczak</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikaelian</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patterson</surname><given-names>I.A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuhnert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Bisgaardia hudsonensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and an additional genomospecies, isolated from seals, as new members of the family Pasteurellaceae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3016</fpage><lpage>3022</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028027-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21296928</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bisgaardia hudsonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bisgaardia hudsonensis</em> (hud.so.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>hudsonensis</em> from Hudson Bay, the area of Canada where the strains originated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on CSBA are circular, entire, low convex, smooth, grey and attain a diameter of 0.5 mm after 48 h of aerobic incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>Growth occurs on media without blood or serum.</s><s>Growth occurs at 22 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>In addition to characteristics for the genus, acid is produced from <em>myo</em>-inositol and maltose, but not from adonitol, dulcitol, lactose, melibiose, raffinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase are produced in large amounts and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase is produced in lesser amounts.</s><s>Valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphoamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and lipase (C14) are not produced.</s><s>Using the Vitek 2 system, positive reactions are obtained for arginine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, phosphorylcholine, d-galactose, d-mannose, phosphatase and phenylphosphonate.</s><s>Negative reactions using Vitek 2 are obtained for adonitol, l-arabitol, Ala-Phe-Pro-arylamidase, maltotriose, β-galactopyranosidase, β-galactosidase, d-malate, l-pyrrolydonyl arylamidase, β-<em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase, γ-glutamyltransferase, glutamylarylamidase, β-glucosidase, β-xylosidase, β-alanine arylamidase, l-proline arylamidase, lipase, palatinose, citrate, l-malate, urease, H<sub>2</sub>S, d-tagatose, malonate, l-lactate alkalinization, succinate alkalinization, β-<em>N</em>-acetylgalactosaminidase, glycine arylamidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, l-histidine, β-glucuronidase, Glu-Gly-Arg-arylamidase, pyruvate, l-glutamine, cellobiose, 5-keto-d-gluconate, α-galactosidase and coumarate.</s><s>Variable reactions were observed with α-arabinosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-ribose, tyrosine arylamidase, starch (glycogen), l-lysine arylamidase and Ellman’s reagent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M327/99/2<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 43067<sup>T</sup> = NCTC 13475<sup>T</sup> = 98-D-690B<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from ringed seals.</s><s>Pathological significance is unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>