<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9688_nm.14831" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14831" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14831" rank="species">Streptomyces atriruber</organism><reference id="rid.9688"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Price</surname><given-names>N.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Donahue</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sells</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces atriruber sp. nov. and Streptomyces silaceus sp. nov., two novel species of equine origin</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2899</fpage><lpage>2903</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008862-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces atriruber</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces atriruber</em> (a.tri.ru′ber. L. adj. <em>ater</em> -<em>tra</em> -<em>trum</em> black, dark; L. adj. <em>ruber</em> -<em>bra</em> -<em>brum</em> red; N.L. masc. adj. <em>atriruber</em> blackish-red, referring to the colour of the substrate mycelium and soluble pigments).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium is very dark red in colour.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white to pinkish white and the spore mass, where produced, is light grey.</s><s>Dark red to reddish purple soluble pigments are produced on most media.</s><s>Spores are borne on flexuous aerial hyphae (<em>Rectiflexibiles</em>) and are ovoid to cylindrical (0.6–0.7×0.6–1.1 μm) and have a smooth surface.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced.</s><s>Adenine, casein, aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are hydrolysed, but allantoin is not.</s><s>Nitrate reductase is produced; phosphatase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced on adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin and trehalose, but not on dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, d-lactose, maltose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, sorbitol or xylose.</s><s>Weak acid production on mannitol and methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside.</s><s>Grows on adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, galactose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, trehalose and xylose as sole carbon sources and weak growth on sucrose, but no growth on inulin, d-lactose, maltose or melezitose.</s><s>dl-Malate, oxalate and l-tartrate are assimilated and acetate, citrate and propionate are weakly assimilated, but benzoate, dl-lactate, mucate and succinate are not assimilated.</s><s>Grows on l-asparagine, l-arginine, potassium nitrate, l-serine, l-threonine and l-valine, but not on l-cysteine, l-methionine or l-phenylalanine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRRL B-24165<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41860<sup>T</sup>=LDDC 6330-99<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an equine placenta.</s></p></content></protolog>