<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10367_nm.16888" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16888" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16888" rank="species">Bryobacter aggregatus</organism><reference id="rid.10367"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kulichevskaya</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzina</surname><given-names>N.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bryobacter aggregatus gen. nov., sp. nov., a peat-inhabiting, aerobic chemo-organotroph from subdivision 3 of the Acidobacteria</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>301</fpage><lpage>306</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013250-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651730</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bryobacter aggregatus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bryobacter aggregatus</em> (ag.gre.ga′tus. L. masc. adj. <em>aggregatus</em> joined together, referring to the frequent formation of cell aggregates).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus with the following additional information.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.8 μm wide by 0.8–1.3 μm long and form irregularly shaped cell aggregates.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized (0.05 %, w/v) include glucose, fructose, galactose, lactose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, rhamnose, ribose, trehalose, sucrose, xylose, raffinose, lactulose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, arbutin, alginate, galacturonic acid and glucuronic acid.</s><s>The ability to utilize arabinose, sorbose, dulcitol, sorbitol, fucose, lactate and pyruvate is variable across strains.</s><s>Unable to utilize acetate, benzoate, caproate, citrate, ethanol, formate, formaldehyde, fumarate, glycerol, malate, mannitol, methanol, oxalate, propionate, succinate or tartrate.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing aesculin, casein, chondroitin sulphate, gelatin, pectin, peptone, protein hydrolysate and starch.</s><s>Unable to hydrolyse laminarin, fucoidan, pullulan, xylan, cellulose, CM-cellulose, chitin or chitosan.</s><s>Cells show the following enzyme activities (API ZYM test): <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterases (C4 and C8), leucyl and valyl arylamidases, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Able to utilize the following nitrogen sources: ammonia, nitrate, Bacto peptone, Bacto yeast extract, alanine, valine, asparagine, isoleucine, lysine, ornithine and methionine.</s><s>Nitrite, urea, arginine, glycine and serine are not utilized.</s><s>Growth factors are required.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, lincomycin, kanamycin and neomycin, but sensitive to streptomycin, novobiocin and gentamicin.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 4.5–7.2 and between 4 and 33 °C (optimum growth at pH 5.5–6.5 and 22–28 °C).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 1.5 % (w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MPL3<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1390<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18758<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar, Tomsk region, West Siberia.</s><s>Reference strains MPL1011 and MOB76 were also isolated from <em>Sphagnum</em>-dominated acidic wetlands.</s></p></content></protolog>