<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8519_nm.13760" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13760" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13760" rank="species">Proteiniborus ethanoligenes</organism><reference id="rid.8519"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proteiniborus ethanoligenes gen. nov., sp. nov., an anaerobic protein-utilizing bacterium.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>12</fpage><lpage>16</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65108-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175674</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Proteiniborus ethanoligenes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Proteiniborus ethanoligenes</em> (e.tha.no.li′ge.nes. N.L. n. <em>ethanol-is</em> ethanol; Gr. v. <em>gennao</em> produce; N.L. part. adj. <em>ethanoligenes</em> ethanol-producing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and general characteristics are as described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.6 μm wide and 1.4–3.8 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on PY agar are white, smooth, circular and entire and slightly convex and reach 0.5 mm after cultivation at 37 °C for 72 h.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 48 °C (optimum 37 °C) and at pH 6.4–10.0 (optimum 8.5–8.8).</s><s>Besides yeast extract and peptone, weak growth is also observed on tryptone and Casamino acids.</s><s>Ethanol, acetic acid and hydrogen are the main products from yeast extract and peptone, and a trace amount of propionic acid is also produced.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: l-serine, l-threonine, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine, l-glutamine, l-arginine, l-tyrosine, tryptophan, l-isoleucine, l-proline, aspartate, l-cysteine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, salicin, sorbose, starch, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribitol, methanol, ethanol, l-propanol, citrate, fumarate, malate, succinate, malonate, hippurate, sodium gluconate, butane diacid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid, cellulose and xylan.</s><s>Milk is not curdled.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>No NH<sub>3</sub> is produced from yeast extract or peptone.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Casein is degraded and nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Gelatin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GW<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.5055<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14574<sup>T</sup>), isolated from granular sludge from a laboratory-scale UASB hydrogen-producing reactor used to treat food industry wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>