<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.179_nm.7287" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7287" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7287" rank="species">Streptomyces sulfonofaciens</organism><reference id="rid.179"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miyadoh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itö</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niida</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces sulfonofaciens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>321</fpage><lpage>324</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces sulfonofaciens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces sulfonofaciens</i> (sul.fon.o.fa’ ci.ens. N. L. n. <i>acidum sulfonicum</i> sulfonic acid; L. part. adj. <i>faciens</i> producing; M.L. part. adj. <i>sulfonofaciens</i> producing sulfonic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>The aerial mycelium of strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> branches monopodially and forms spore chains, as shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>Spores are 0.7 to 0.8 by 1 .O to 1.5 μm and oval to cylindrical and have smooth surfaces (Fig. 2 and 3).</s><s>The spore chains are nearly straight and moderately short, bearing 10 to 30 spores, Fragmentation of mycelium is not observed on agar or in liquid cultures.</s><s>Neither sclerotia nor sporangia are formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>The cultural characteristics of strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> are summarized in Table 3.</s><s>The colors of the mature aerial masses produced on inorganic salts-starch agar, oatmeal agar, and yeast extract-malt extract agar belong to the red color series (5cb, grayish yellowish pink [15]).</s><s>The undersides of colonies are colorless to pale yellowish brown.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are formed, except for a light rose beige pigment formed on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Frequent subculturing of strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> onto fresh agar media results in the loss of the ability to produce aerial mycelium, and small aerial mycelium tends to be formed and then lysed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth of strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> is 15 to 42°C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs between 27 and 33°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics.</s><s>Positive physiological properties for strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> include gelatin liquefaction, starch hydrolysis, and milk peptonization.</s><s>Negative properties include production of melanoid pigment on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar and tryptone-yeast extract broth, milk coagulation, and nitrate reduction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbohydrate utilization.</s><s>On ISP medium 9, good or moderate growth is obtained with D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, and D-fructose, and poor growth is obtained with D-mannitol and sucrose.</s><s>No growth is observed with i-inositol or raffinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall analysis.</s><s>Analysis of the cell wall hydrolysates by paper chromatography demonstrates the presence of LL-diaminopimelic acid in addition to glycine.</s><s>Thus, strain SF-2103<sup>T</sup> can be considered to have cell wall type I of Becker et al. (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antagonistic properties.</s><s>Produces a new plactam antibiotic, SF-2103A.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain SF-2103 (= ATCC 31892).</s></p></content></protolog>