<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6944_nm.1209" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1209" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1209" rank="species">Erythrobacter citreus</organism><reference id="rid.6944"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vybiral</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koblížek</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velimirov</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erythrobacter citreus sp. nov., a yellow-pigmented bacterium that lacks bacteriochlorophyll a, isolated from the western Mediterranean Sea.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1655</fpage><lpage>1661</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01885-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361270</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erythrobacter citreus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erythrobacter citreus</i> (cit.re.us. M.L. adj. <i>citreus</i> describing the lemon-yellow pigmentation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data compiled from Vybiral et al. (1999) and data generated in the present study.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, rod-shaped (0.3-0.7x1.0-1.5 μm), non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Catalase-and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Yellow intracellular pigments (carotenoids) are produced.</s><s>The acetone-extracted pigment shows two peaks at 453 and 481 nm, as well as a slight inflexion at 427 nm.</s><s>Cells do not contain BChl a.</s><s>Colonies on complex media such as SWPY-2000 agar or Bacto marine agar 2216 are opaque, intensely yellow, circular, entire, low-convex and smooth.</s><s>Colonies on sea water agar are translucent, yellow, circular, entire, low-convex and smooth.</s><s>Na+ ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated: acetate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, glutarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, suberate, L-aspartate and L-proline.</s><s>The type strain RE35F/1<sup>T</sup> also utilizes propionate, cis-aconitate, adipate and azelate.</s><s>The following compounds are hydrolysed: 2-deoxythymidine-5'-<i>para</i>-nitrophenyl (pNP) phosphate, L-alanine-paranitroanilide (pNA), L-glutamate-c-3-carboxy-pNA and L-proline-pNA.</s><s>The compounds which are not assimilated or hydrolysed are listed in Table 1.</s><s>Susceptible to bacitracin, 30 μg chloramphenicol, 15 μg oleandomycin and 10 μg vancomycin.</s><s>Resistant to 30 μg ampicillin, 10 μg gentamicin, 15 μg lincomycin, 30 μg neomycin, 30 μg kanamycin, 10 IU penicillin G, 300 IU polymyxin B, 10 μg streptomycin, 30 μg tetracycline and 10 μg vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Strain RE10F/45 is, in contrast to strain RE35F/1<sup>T</sup>, sensitive to streptomycin and penicillin G, but resistant to 150 μg vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the respiratory lipoquinone system.</s><s>The main component in the polyamine pattern is spermidine.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol are the major polar lipids; phosphatidylcholine and a sphingoglycolipid are present in minor concentrations.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 16:0, 17:1<i>ω</i>6<i>c</i> and 16:1<i>ω</i>7 and/or 15:0 iso 2-OH; hydroxylated fatty acids are 14:0 2-OH, 16:0 2-OH, 18:1 2-OH and 16:0 iso 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G­C content is 62.0-62.4 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>The type strain is RE35/F1<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107092<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14432<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the western Mediterranean Sea (Bay of Calvi, Corsica, France) by 0.2 μm membrane filtration.</s></p></content></protolog>