<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12094_nm.20083" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20083" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20083" rank="species">Marmoricola scoriae</organism><reference id="rid.12094"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marmoricola scoriae sp. nov., isolated from volcanic
ash</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2139</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018242-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19880634</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marmoricola scoriae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marmoricola scoriae</em> [sco.ri′ae. L. gen. n. <em>scoriae</em> of scoria (volcanic ash), referring to the site from which the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-stain-positive, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, non-motile cocci (0.6–1.0 μm in diameter) that are present singly, in pairs or in clusters.</s><s>Colonies are vivid yellow, circular, convex with entire margins and 0.1–0.2 mm in diameter after incubation on ISP 2 for 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 6.1–12.1 (optimum at pH 8.1–11.1), at 10–37 °C (optimum at 30 °C) and in the presence of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum at 0 % NaCl).</s><s>CM-cellulose, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production is not observed.</s><s>Positive for enzyme activities of naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase, but negative for activity of <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM).</s><s>Acetate, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, dl-malate, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, l-ribose, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but benzoate, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol and melibiose are not.</s><s>Data for other physiological and biochemical properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>ll-DAP is the diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Polar lipids comprise phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Sco-D01<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19597<sup>T</sup>=DSM 22127<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from volcanic ash of Oreum (a parasitic volcanic cone) in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>