<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4692_nm.2810" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2810" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2810" rank="species">Alteromonas carrageenovora</organism><reference id="rid.4692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akagawa-Matsushita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alteromonas atlantica sp. nov. and Alteromonas carrageenovora sp. nov., bacteria that decompose algal polysaccharides.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>621</fpage><lpage>627</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-621</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas carrageenovora</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas carrageenovora</i> (car. ra.gee. no'. vo. ra. M.L.n. <i>carrageenum</i>, carrageen, another name for carrageenan; L.v. <i>voro</i>, to devour; M.L.fem.adj. <i>carrageenovora</i>, carrageenan decomposing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, polarly flagellated bacterium isolated from seaweeds.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped, with rounded ends, and are 0.7 to 0.8 μm in diameter and 1.9 to 2.5 μm long when the organism is grown on marine agar 2216 medium (catalog no. 0979; Difco); the cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Peritrichous flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solidified media.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 medium are beige to pale yellow orange, circular, and smooth and convex with entire edge and grow to a diameter of 6.0 to 8.0 mm in 5 days at 25°C.</s><s>Sodium ion is essential for growth.</s><s>Are mesophilic and neutrophilic chemoorganotrophs which grow at temperatures between 5 and 35°C and at pHs between 5.5 and 9.0.</s><s>No growth occurs at 40°C and pH 5.0.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose and mannitol.</s><s>Are positive for hydrolyses of esculin, Tween 80, gelatin, casein, DNA, alginate, and carrageenan.</s><s>Chitin, starch, and agar are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Are positive for oxidase and catalase; in the ONPG test; and for tyrosine decomposition, phosphatase, urease, arginine hydrolysis, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, litmus milk coagulation, and methylene blue reduction.</s><s>Are negative for nitrate reduction, denitrification, cell pigmentation, amidase production, xanthine decomposition, indole production, 2-ketogluconate production from gluconate, 3-ketolactose production from lactose, 0/129 sensitivity, growth on medium containing 0.4% phenethyl alcohol, and deaminases for tryptophan and phenylalanine; are negative in the methyl red test; and are negative for curdlan-like polysaccharide production.</s><s>Melanin-like diffusible dark pigment was produced on tyrosine-containing medium.</s><s>Luminescence was never observed.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, <i>n</i>-valerate, caprylate, pelargonate, caprate, oxalate, succinate, fumarate, L-malate, 2-ketoglutarate, citrate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-glutamate, glycerol, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannitol, amygdalin, esculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, starch, and gentiobiose are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: butyrate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, <i>n</i>-caproate, heptanoate, malonate, maleate, glutarate, adipate, pimerate, suberate, azerate, sebacate, glycolate, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate, DL-3- hydroxybutyrate, D-malate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, levulinate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, aconitate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, <i>tert</i>-phthalate, glycine, D-α-alanine, L-α-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-norleucine, L-valine, DL-norvaline, DL-2-aminobutyrate, L-serine, L-threonine, L-cysteine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, L-histidine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, trigonelline, L-aspartate, L-ornithine, L-lysine, L-citrulline, L-arginine, DL-kynurenine, L-proline, betaine, creatine, 9-alanine, DL-3-aminobutyate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovarelate, 2-aminobenzoate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, urea, acetoamide, sarcosine, ethylamine, butylamine, amylamine , ethanolamine, benzylamine, 1,4-diaminobutane , spermine, histamine, tryptamine, D-glucosamine, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-D-xyloside, D-mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, amethyl- D-glumside, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, arbutin, salicine, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fumse, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39.5 mol%.</s><s>Isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The type strain is IAM 12662 (=IFO 12985, =NCIMB 302, =ATCC 43555).</s></p></content></protolog>