<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6065_nm.10167" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10167" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10167" rank="species">Ochrobactrum oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.6065"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tripathi</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chowdhury</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebuhn</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gattinger</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schloter</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum oryzae sp. nov., an endophytic bacterial species isolated from deep-water rice in India</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1677</fpage><lpage>1680</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63934-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825649</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ochrobactrum oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ochrobactrum oryzae</em> (L. fem. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, pertaining to the habitat from which the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic (oxidase- and catalase-positive), non-spore-forming rods (0.8×1.4 μm), producing non-pigmented, translucent to milky white, circular, convex, smooth colonies on nutrient agar; typical growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and between pH 4 and 9 (optimum, pH 6–7).</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Utilization of various carbon sources was determined using the Biolog test system.</s><s>Positive test results were obtained for the following: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, d-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine and uridine.</s><s>Negative Biolog reactions were obtained for dextrin, gentiobiose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucosamide, d-raffinose, xylitol, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, d-saccharic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (65.2 %) and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo (16.5 %).</s><s>In addition, significant amounts of C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (5.1 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> cyclo 2-OH (1.8 %) are detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MTCC 4195<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17471<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface-sterilized seeds and plant tissue from deep-water rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em>) cultivated in Suraha Tal Lake in northern India.</s></p></content></protolog>