<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2660_nm.3211" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3211" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3211" rank="species">Klebsiella planticola</organism><reference id="rid.2660"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bagley</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidler</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Klebsiella planticola sp. nov.: a new species of Enterobacteriaceae found primarily in nonclinical environments.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>109</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01569013</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Klebsiella planticola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Klebsiella planticola</i> (plan.tid.o.la. M. L. fem.n. <i>planta</i>-a plant; L. suff. <i>cola</i>-dweller; M. L. fem.n. <i>planticola</i>-plant dweller)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Numerical taxonomy, mol% G+C, and DNA hybridization tests all indicate that <i>Klebsiella planticola</i> belongs as a new species within the genus <i>Klebsiella</i>. <i>K. planticola</i> mol% G+C base composition values are within the range reported for the genus: 52-59 mol% [4,9].</s><s>Both intragroup (79%) and intergroup (64-75%) phenetic similarities with other species of <i>Klebsiella</i> indicate the position of <i>K. planticola</i> as a separate species [7].</s><s>The numerical taxonomy data is confirmed by the fact that <i>K. planticola</i> strains had less than 50% RR to <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>K. oxytoca</i>.</s><s>However, the average 79% RR of <i>K. planticola</i> strains when tested at the stringent temperature (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>-10°C reveals genetic variation among the strains.</s><s>This is evidenced by the somewhat variable biochemical test results.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypically, <i>K. planticola</i> is most closely related to <i>K. pneumoniae</i>.</s><s>However, <i>K. planticola</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>can be distinguished from both <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>K. oxytoca</i> by a combination of biochemical tests (Table 3) [7,8].</s><s>Differentation between <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>K. planticola</i> can be made on the basis of the fecal coliform test and growth at 10°C Previous studies have revealed both the ecological and sanitary significance of the fecal coliform reaction in the genus <i>Klebsiella</i> [2]; the present report illustrates that growth-temperature responses also have taxonomic significance.</s><s>For example, only 5 of 202 <i>Klebsiella</i> isolates from many sources did not conform to group placement based on reactions in the fecal coliform test, growth at 10~ indole production, and pectate degradation [8].</s><s>Only 1 <i>K. pneumoniae</i> strain did not produce gas from lactose fermentation at 44.5°C This culture is the neotype strain of <i>K. pneumoniae</i>, ATCC 13883.</s><s>In all other characteristics, including DNA reassociation, this strain conforms with other strains in the <i>K. pneumoniae</i> linkage group [7].</s><s>Although this strain is aberrant in the fecal coliform test, its lack of growth at 10°C provided a reassurance of the significance of the growth-temperature response for <i>Klebsiella</i> [8].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Indole-positive <i>K. planticola</i> can be distinguished from <i>K. oxytoca</i> by pectate degradation and utilization of gentisate and <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate. <i>K. ozaenae</i> and <i>K. rhinoscleromatis</i> can be distinguished from <i>K. planticola</i>,<i> K. oxytoca</i>, and <i>K. pneumoniae</i> because both of the former are positive on methyl red and negative on Voges-Proskauer tests [4,5].</s><s>In addition, <i>K. rhinoscleromatis</i> is anaerogenic on glucose and negative on Simmons' citrate and lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Strains of <i>K. ozaenae</i> are generally negative on malonate and lysine decarboxylase and are often anaerogenic on glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In an earlier numerical taxonomy study involving strains of <i>Klebsiella</i>, Gavini et al. [6] found a group of strains with biochemical characteristics similar to <i>K. planticola</i> (as described in this paper).</s><s>This group was designated as Class K or as strains having characteristics of both <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>K. oxytoca</i>.</s><s>Strains in Class K were also largely of environmental origin (primarily aquatic), and only 3 of 25 strains were of direct human association (from feces).</s><s>As in the present studies, Gavini et al. found that the Class K <i>Klebsiella</i> did not ferment melezitose or dulcitol and did not use m-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>The Class K isolates did not grow at 44.5°C about 50% grew at 4°C <i>K. planticola</i> did not ferment lactose at 44.5°C but grew at 10°C Indole was produced by 54% of the Class K isolates, whereas only 15% of the <i>K. planticola</i> were indole positive and only some of the biogroup 1 strains exhibited this trait.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>K. planticola</i> can also be differentiated from <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>K. oxytoca</i> based on habitat of origin, as most <i>K. planticola</i> (about 95%) have been isolated from plant-associated and aquatic environments [3,7,8,9].</s><s>The general lack of antibiotic resistance (other than to ampicillin) is characteristic of organisms of this environmental origin [11]. <i>K. planticola</i> strains have been found in wastewater, although few isolates were associated with cases of human and animal disease [7,8], and the two multiply-antibiotic-resistant strains in this study were of human and animal origin.</s><s>Clinical bacteriologists would, however, identify most of these strains as <i>K. pneumoniae</i> owing to the fact that fecal coliform and growth at 10°C tests are not performed routinely [4].</s><s>If indole positive, strains might be identified as <i>K. oxytoca</i> owing to the lack of pectate degradation tests.</s><s>Further studies should therefore be conducted to determine the environmental, human, and animal distribution and importance of <i>K. planticola</i>.</s><s>The name <i>Klebsiella planticola</i> is proposed for this organism.</s><s>This species name was chosen to indicate the typical plant-associated habitat of origin for the majority of the strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain V-236 (ATCC 33531, CDC 4245-72) is designated as the type strain of this species.</s><s>As planta can be loosely translated as "an edible vegetable" [10], <i>planticola</i> also signifies the vegetable (i.e., radish) origin of the type strain [3].</s><s>The biochemical characteristics for this strain are given in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>