<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6809_nm.5619" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5619" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5619" rank="subspecies">Streptococcus constellatus pharyngis</organism><reference id="rid.6809"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>L.M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A study of small-colony, beta-haemolytic, Lancefield group C streptococci within the anginosus group: description of Streptococcus constellatus subsp. pharyngis subsp. nov., associated with the human throat and pharyngitis.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1443</fpage><lpage>1449</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1443</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555325</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>pharyngis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>pharyngis</i> (pha.ryn’gis. Gr. n. pharynx throat; Gr. gen. n. pharygnis of the throat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics of the six strains included in this study.</s><s>Small (0.5-1.0 μm in diameter), Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, nonmotile cocci in short chains.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are 0.5-2.0 mm in diameter, white or translucent, and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Growth is reduced under aerobic conditions and is enhanced by the addition of CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Arginine and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Urea and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Strains produce β-N-acetylgalactosaminidase, β-D-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>The majority of strains produce β-N-acetylglucosaminidase.</s><s>Strains do not produce α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase or sialidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, lactose, glucose or β-D-N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inulin, mannitol, melibiose, raffinose or sorbitol.</s><s>The majority of strains produce hyaluronidase.</s><s>Strains are β-haemolytic and belong to Lancefield group C.</s><s>Strains were isolated from infections of the human throat (pharyngitis) and clinical specimens (strains M5823 was from an abdominal mass).</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 35-37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>pharyngis</i> is MM9889a<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 13122<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the human throat in a subject with pharyngitis.</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics described above and produces β-N-acetylglucosaminidase and hyaluronidase.</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 35 mol %.</s></p></content></protolog>