<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7475_nm.1343" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1343" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1343" rank="species">Sinorhizobium kostiense</organism><reference id="rid.7475"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nick</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eardly</surname><given-names>B.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suomalainen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paulin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lindström</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sinorhizobium arboris sp. nov. and Sinorhizobium kostiense sp. nov., isolated from leguminous trees in Sudan and Kenya.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1359</fpage><lpage>1368</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1359</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sinorhizobium kostiense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sinorhizobium kostiense</i> (kos.ti.en'se. L. neut. adj. <i>kostiense</i> pertaining to Kosti, the region in Sudan from which the majority of the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.5-0.7 μm wide by 1.5-2.0 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of one or two polar or subpolar flagella.</s><s>The maximum growth temperature of the majority of the strains on YEM medium is 38-40°C.</s><s>Colonies of most strains on YEM are circular, creamcoloured, semi-translucent and mucilaginous and often spread over an entire plate within 2-4 d.</s><s>A narrow range of carbohydrates and amino acids are utilized as sole carbon sources for growth.</s><s>Physiological and biochemical features typical for this species include tolerance of only 1% (w/v) NaCl and sensitivity to heavy metals (except copper and lead) and to a wide range of antibiotics.</s><s>Produces melanin but does not grow at pH 5.5 or 8.5.</s><s>However, this species cannot be identified by biochemical and physiological characters alone.</s><s>Strains can nodulate <i>Acacia senegal</i> and <i>Prosopis chilensis</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level, this species can be differentiated by SDS-PAGE whole-cell protein pattern, MLEE, rep-PCR genomic fingerprinting (Nick et al., 1999), RFLP analysis of amplified 16s rDNA (Nick, 1998), total DNA-DNA hybridization (Nick et al., 1999) and sequencing of the whole 16s rRNA gene. <i>S. kostiense</i> can be assigned to the genus <i>Sinorhizobium</i> by cellular fatty acid analysis (S.</s><s>W.</s><s>Tighe &#x0026; B.</s><s>D.</s><s>W.</s><s>Jarvis, unpublished results).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57.9-61.6 mol% (Nick et al., 1999).</s><s>Strain HAMBI 1489<sup>T</sup> (= LMG 15613<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain.</s><s>All the <i>Sinorhizobium kostiense</i> strains identified in this paper have been deposited in the Culture Collections of the Department of Applied Chemistry and Microbiology, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland, and the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Ghent, Ghent, Belgium.</s></p></content></protolog>