<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6613_nm.7294" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7294" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7294" rank="species">Streptomyces thermoalcalitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.6613"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sahin</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zakrzewska-Czerwinska</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mordarski</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of thermophilic streptomycetes, including the description of Streptomyces thermoalcalitolerans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>7</fpage><lpage>17</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028242</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces thermoalcalitolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces thermoalcalitolerans</i> (ther.mo.al.ca.li.to'le.rans. Gr. n. <i>therme</i> heat; N.L. n. alcali from arabic <i>al</i> end; <i>galiy</i> soda ash; L. pres. part. <i>tolerans</i> tolerating, enduring; M.L. part. adj. <i>thermoalcalitolerans</i> thermophilic alkali-tolerating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and an earlier study (Sahin, 1995).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, thermophilic actinomycete with extensively branched substrate and aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spiral chains of warty surfaced spores are borne on aerial hyphae.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is grey; neither distinctive substrate mycelium colours nor diffusible pigments are formed.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on peptone iron agar.</s><s>Casein, DNA, gelatin, starch, testosterone, L-tyrosine and xylan are degraded, but not adenine, arbutin, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine or xanthine.</s><s>Adonitol, L-arabinose, arabitol, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, α-lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose hydrate, melibiose, α-L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-turanose, xylitol and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but Draffinose is not.</s><s>Growth occurs between 25 and 55°C, from pH 6.0 to 11.5, and in the presence of ampicillin (8 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), bacitracin (16 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), oleandomycin phosphate (16 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), penicillin G (1 5 international units), rifampicin (1 6 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (4 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), tetracycline hydrochloride (1 6 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and tunicamycin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>In contrast, growth is inhibited in the presence of gentamicin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), lincomycin hydrochloride (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), neomycin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), novobiocin (4 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), oleandomycin phosphate (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), polymyxin B phosphate (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), rifampicin (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (1 6 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), tetracycline hydrochloride (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), tobramycin sulphate (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and vancomycin hydrochloride (1 6 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>The DNA base composition of the organism is 73 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolated from tropical garden soil collected by M.</s><s>Goodfellow in 1991 from Yogyakarta, Central Java, Indonesia.</s><s>The type strain, TA56 (= DSM 41741) is deposited in the DSMZ, Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>