<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1674_nm.2935" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2935" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2935" rank="species">Shewanella violacea</organism><reference id="rid.1674"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies of deep-sea barophilic Shewanella strains and description of Shewanella violacea sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>170</volume><fpage>331</fpage><lpage>338</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050650</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9818352</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Shewanella violacea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Shewanella violacea</i> (vi.o.lace.a. L.gen.n. <i>violacea</i>, of violet.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped; cell width ranges from 0.8 to 1.0 μm, and cell length ranges from 2 to 4 μm.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative and motile by means of a single, unsheathed polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Marine Agar 2216 are entire, smooth, semitranslucent, and nonpigmented, 2–4 mm in diameter following 2–3 days of incubation at 8°C at atmospheric pressure.</s><s>After 7 days of incubation at 8°C at atmospheric pressure, the colonies display a violet pigment.</s><s>This bacterium is halophilic, psychrophilic, and moderately barophilic.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of ca. 3%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>The optimal temperature and pressure for growth are 8°C and 30 MPa, respectively.</s><s>No growth occurs at over 20°C.</s><s>It is a facultatively anaerobic chemoorganotroph having both respiratory and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-glucose with gas.</s><s>The organism does not produce H<sub>2 </sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from cellobiose, D-galactose, and D-glucose.</s><s>No acid is produced from arabinose, D-fructose, glycerol, inositol, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is approximately 47 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are iso-15:0, 16:0, 16:1, and 20:5(ω3).</s><s>The type strain is <i>S. violacea</i> strain DSS12, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (Wako-shi, Saitama, Japan) as strain JCM 10179.</s></p></content></protolog>