<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12742_nm.22522" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22522" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22522" rank="species">Chryseobacterium piperi</organism><reference id="rid.12742"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Strahan</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Failor</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Batties</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayes</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cicconi</surname><given-names>K.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>C.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Newman</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium piperi sp. nov., isolated from a freshwater creek</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2162</fpage><lpage>2166</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027805-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20889766</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium piperi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium piperi</em> (pi′per.i. N.L. gen. masc. <em>piperi</em> of Piper, in honour of John F. Piper Jr, recently retired Academic Dean of Lycoming College).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile Gram-reaction-negative rods, 0.5×3 µm.</s><s>Grows on R2A, tryptic soy, Endo and cetrimide agars, but not on MacConkey, EMB, phenylethanol or mannitol-salt agars.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are translucent and shiny with entire edges.</s><s>Yellow–orange non-diffusible flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Grows well at 20–30 °C and weakly at 37 °C, but not at 5 °C or 42 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 6–10 (optimum pH 6.5–8.0).</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells produce indole on SIM medium and exhibit oxidase, catalase, amylase, caseinase, DNase, gelatinase, Tween 80 hydrolase and β-haemolytic activities.</s><s>Negative for phenylalanine deaminase and lipase activities, nitrate reduction, utilization of citrate, production of hydrogen sulfide and acetoin and production of acid from fermentation of glucose, lactose, sucrose, mannitol, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>In the API 20 NE system; positive for indole production and hydrolysis of urea, aesculin, gelatin and PNPG but negative for nitrate reduction, production of acid from d-glucose, arginine dihydrolase activity and the utilization of l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconic acid, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Weakly utilizes α-d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, and maltose.</s><s>In the API ZYM system; positive for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase (weakly), C8 esterase lipase, leucine-, valine-, and cystine (weakly) arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities; negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>On the GenIII plate; positive for utilization of dextrin, maltose, trehalose, gentiobiose, sucrose, α-d-glucose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, glycerol, d-glucose-6-phosphate, d-fructose-6-phosphate, d-aspartic acid, gelatin, glycyl-l-proline, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, pectin, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, citric acid, Tween-40, acetoacetic acid, acetic acid and formic acid; weakly positive for utilization of d-galactose, 3-methyl glucose, d- and l-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-alanine, mucic acid, quinic acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester and α-keto-glutaric acid; negative for the remaining utilization tests.</s><s>Also on the GenIII plate; resistant to pH 6, 1 % NaCl, 1 % Na-lactate, rifamycin SV and aztreonam; weakly resistant to d-serine, lincomycin, guanidine HCl, and K-tellurite; sensitive to the remaining inhibitory conditions.</s><s>Tetrazolium blue and tetrazolium violet are reduced.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>Menaquinone MK-6 is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CTM<sup>T</sup> ( = ATCC BAA-1782<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 57707<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 15960<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22249<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 23267<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a freshwater creek in North-central Pennsylvania, USA.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>