<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5978_nm.5941" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5941" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5941" rank="species">Brevibacterium mcbrellneri</organism><reference id="rid.5978"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McBride</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ellner</surname><given-names>K.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Black</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clarridge</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolf</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new Brevibacterium sp. isolated from infected genital hair of patients with white piedra</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>255</fpage><lpage>261</lpage><source id="290">Journal of Medical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Med Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-2615</issn><essn>1473-5644</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8411085</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brevibacterium mcbrellneri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Aerobic, non-sporeforming, gram-positive bacilli of environmental origin frequently evade a taxonomic position. In some studies of clinical isolates, in which classical methods alone were used, over half of the coryneforms were unnamed. The more analytical methods added information, but left many groups taxonomically unassigned. With the advent of whole-cell fatty-acid analysis and the API Coryne system, many of the clinically relevant species, such as <i>C. diphtheriae</i>, <i>C. jeikeium</i> and <i>C. cystitiditis</i> (D2) can be identified reliably.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There are several morphologically similar genera from which medically significant coryneform isolates must be distinguished.</s><s>We have shown that these white piedra isolates are in the genus <i>Brevibacterium</i> by: rod-to-coccus cycle conversion; fatty-acid profile; the presence of DAP and absence of mycolic acids and arabinose in the cell wall; strict aerobic growth; NaCl tolerance; G + C mol% content; production of methanethiol; strong proteolysis; and lack of saccharolytic activity in conventional tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty-acid profiles of <i>Corynebacterium</i> spp. are predominantly straight chain saturated and monounsaturated, whereas the major component of the new organism is iso 15:0 with anteiso 17:0 as the second component.</s><s>The DNA G + C mol% composition of strain E2cr was 63.05% which is similar to that of other species of <i>Brevibacterium</i>: <i>B. epidermidis</i>, 63.3%; <i>B. linens</i>, 63.4% ; and <i>B. iodinum</i>, 62.5 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Many environmental, poorly defined species were originally included in the genus <i>Brevibacterium</i>.</s><s>With more exacting studies, many of these have now been re-assigned, such as <i>B. divaricatum</i>, which has mycolic acid and arabinose in the cell wall and was found to resemble <i>C. glutamicum</i>.</s><s>Similarly, the fatty-acid components of <i>B. acetylicum</i> are incompatible with <i>Brevibacterium</i> spp.</s><s>On the other hand, the unassigned CDC Gp.B resembles the genus <i>Brevibacterium</i> in its whole cell fatty-acid composition.</s><s>Currently, in contrast with previous classifications, there are only four recognised species: <i>B. linens</i>, <i>B. iodinum</i>, <i>B. casei</i> and <i>B. epidermidis</i>.</s><s>The latter is the only species isolated from skin; the others have been associated with dairy products, have lower optimum temperature for growth, and are pigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The white piedra isolate described here resembles <i>B. epidermidis</i> in habitat but differs from it in several significant ways (table III).</s><s>The colonial and microscopic morphology are distinctive and the cultural conditions necessary to initiate the rod-to-coccus cycle are different.</s><s>Biochemically, the new species can reduce tellurite and utilise ribose.</s><s>We propose a new species, <i>B. mcbrellneri</i>, and the type strain, E2cr, has been deposited with the ATCC (49030).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The potential pathogenicity of the strains in this report is of particular interest, as, so far, no pathogenic species of <i>Brevibacterium</i> has been described.</s><s>Salt tolerance, thought to be a factor in skin colonisation by <i>Brevibacterium</i> spp., is lower for the new strains than for other skin isolates, but the proteolytic properties may be significant in the attachment and invasion of keratin structures such as hair.</s><s>The relationship of the white piedra strains to coryneform bacteria previously cultured from infected hair of cases of trichomycosis axillaris needs to be clarified.</s><s>Ellner postulated two separate diseases-white piedra, caused by the synergic activity between <i>Trichosporon beigelii</i> and <i>B. mcbrellneri</i> (proposed name), and trichomycosis axillaris, caused by a variety of undefined coryneform bacteria.</s><s>However, since for these latter isolates, neither cell-wall analysis nor DNA G + C mol% content has been studied to establish a distinct taxonomic identity, it is possible that some could be <i>Brevibacterium</i> spp.</s><s>Further studies are necessary to elucidate the taxonomic position of isolates from trichomycosis axillaris to evaluate the pathogenic potential of <i>Brevibacterium</i> spp. for skin and hair.</s></p></content></protolog>