<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6708_nm.10861" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10861" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10861" rank="species">Methylobacterium oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.6708"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sa</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium oryzae sp. nov., an aerobic, pink-pigmented, facultatively methylotrophic, 1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate deaminase-producing bacterium isolated from rice.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>326</fpage><lpage>331</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64603-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267973</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, motile rods (0.60–0.80×2.10–2.75 μm), occurring singly, in pairs or in rosettes.</s><s>Colonies are pink to red, convex and translucent with regular edges, slow-growing and 0.2–1.2 mm in diameter after 96 h at 28 °C on AMS.</s><s>Growth occurs on NA and Luria–Bertani, R2A, PYG, succinate, glycerol-peptone and plate count agars.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C (optimal temperature 28 °C), but not at 4 or 40 °C, and at pH 5.0–10.0 (optimal pH 6.8).</s><s>No growth in the presence of 2.0 % NaCl or higher.</s><s>The pink pigment is water-insoluble and has absorption maxima at 233, 358, 505 and 534 nm in chloroform/methanol (1 : 1).</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, esterase and leucine arylamidase activities.</s><s>Weak activity for esterase lipase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>No activity for pectinase, cellulase, protease or lipase.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, lipid, casein and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Methanol, ethanol, d-arabinose, d-xylose and fumarate are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not use sucrose, 2-propanol, 1-butanol, dulcitol, l-lysine, betaine, oxalate, tartrate, salicylate, formaldehyde, methylamine, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, dichloromethane or methane.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, potassium nitrate, sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride, l-alanine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, urea, ACC and potassium thiocyanate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Does not utilize l-aspartate, glycine, l-tryptophan, methylamine or potassium cyanate.</s><s>Carbon assimilation tests are positive for l-arabinose, potassium gluconate, adipic acid and malic acid.</s><s>The intrinsic antibiotic-resistance pattern of the type strain shows high resistance to ampicillin, carbenicillin, nalidixic acid, chloramphenicol and streptomycin and sensitivity to kanamycin, gentamicin, spectinomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): l-arabinose, d-galactose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, lactone, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are hexadecanoate (palmitic acid; C<sub>16 : 0</sub>), 3.01 %; <em>cis</em>-7-octadecenoate (<em>cis</em>-vaccenic acid; C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), 88.18 %; octadecanoate (stearic acid; C<sub>18 : 0</sub>), 4.61 %; and 3-hydroxyoctadecanoate (C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH), 0.77 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CBMB20<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18207<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23582<sup>T</sup>=KACC 11585<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from stem tissues of rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L.</s><s>‘Nam-Pyeoung’) obtained from Chungbuk Provincial Agricultural Research and Extension Services, Cheongwon (36° 58′ N 127° 57′ E), Chungbuk, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain CBMB20<sup>T</sup> is 70.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>