<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12755_nm.22541" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22541" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22541" rank="species">Salarchaeum japonicum</organism><reference id="rid.12755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shimane</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minegishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Echigo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagaoka</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohta</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Usami</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salarchaeum japonicum gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, extremely halophilic member of the Archaea isolated from commercial salt</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2266</fpage><lpage>2270</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025064-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952548</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salarchaeum japonicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salarchaeum japonicum</em> (ja.po′ni.cum. N.L. neut. adj. <em>japonicum</em> Japanese, pertaining to Japan, referring to the place of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Salarchaeum japonicum</em> is as that given above for the genus, with the following additions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, short rods, 0.5–1.0×0.5–2.0 µm in liquid media.</s><s>On agar plates, under optimal conditions clear red microcolonies are formed (0.1 mm in diameter after 1 week growth at 37 °C).</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1.5–5.3 M (saturated), optimum 2.5–3.0 M; at pH 5.0–8.8, optimum pH 5.2–6.3; and at 20–55 °C, optimum 40 °C.</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> is required for growth, with maximum growth occurring at 200–300 mM.</s><s>Cells lyse in distilled water.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or nitrite under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Anaerobic growth with nitrate, arginine and DMSO does not occur.</s><s>Indole production from tryptophan is negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulfate or cysteine is negative.</s><s>Susceptible to novobiocin; resistant to ampicillin, anisomycin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>Utilizes sodium fumarate, sodium malate, sodium succinate, sodium glutamate, yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone (Oxoid) and neopeptone (BD Difco) as single or complex carbon sources for growth.</s><s>Does not utilize arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, ribitol, ribose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium pyruvate, sodium lactate, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, glycine, l-alanine, l-arginine chloride, l-lysine chloride, sodium l-aspartate or Bacto peptone.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin or casein.</s><s>The following enzymic activities are positive: esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14, weak), alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and α-chymotrypsin.</s><s>Ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, valine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YSM-79<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16327<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7563<sup>T</sup>), isolated from commercial salt made from seawater in Yonaguni island, Okinawa, Japan.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 64 mol% as determined by HPLC.</s></p></content></protolog>