<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1330_nm.8020" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8020" rank="genus">Porphyromonas</organism><reference id="rid.1330"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for reclassification of Bacteroides asaccharolyticus, Bacteroides gingivalis, and Bacteroides endodontalis in a new genus, Porphyromonas.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>128</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas</i> (Por. phy. ro. mo'nas. Gr. adj. <i>porphyreos</i> purple; Gr. n. <i>monas</i> unit; N. L. fem.n. <i>Porphyromonas</i> porphyrin cell)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on our own observations and previous descriptions of the asaccharolytic, pigmented <i>Bacteroides</i> species (2,-11, 16, 20, 22, 23, 26-33, 35-38, 42, 43, 45).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative , obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Most cells in broth are small (0.5 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 3.5 μm), but occasionally longer cells (4 to 6 μm) may be formed.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar plates are smooth (rarely rough), shiny, convex, and 1 to 3 mm in diameter and darken progressively from the edge toward the center after 6 to 10 days.</s><s>Eventually the whole colony becomes black due to protoheme production.</s><s>Growth is not significantly affected by carbohydrates.</s><s>Nitrogenous substrates such as Proteose Peptone, Trypticase, and yeast extract markedly enhance growth.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>Major fermentation products from BM or PYG medium are n-butyric and acetic acids; lower levels of propionic, isobutyric, and isovaleric acids are also produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>MDH and glutamate dehydrogenase are present; glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase are absent.</s><s>Proteolytic activity is variable.</s><s>Limited ability to ferment amino acids such as aspartate and asparagine.</s><s>Indole produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Starch and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine as the diamino acids; 2-keto-3-deoxyoctulosonica cid is absent.</s><s>The principal respiratory quinones are unsaturated menaquinones with 9 or 10 isoprene units.</s><s>Both nonhydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present.</s><s>The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are composed of predominantly isomethyl branched types (iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> acid) and lower levels of straight-chain saturated acids.</s><s>The 3-hydroxylated fatty acids are the straight-chain saturated types.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base compositions range between 46 to 54 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type species is <i>Porphyromonas asaccharolytica</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>