<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1373_nm.6168" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6168" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6168" rank="species">Georgenia muralis</organism><reference id="rid.1373"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Altenburger</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vybiral</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lubitz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Georgenia muralis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from a medieval wall painting</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>875</fpage><lpage>881</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01984-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054252</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Georgenia muralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Georgenia muralis</i> (mu.ra´lis. L. adj. <i>muralis</i>, <i>-le</i> pertaining or belonging to walls)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics are as described for the genus.</s><s>An unidentified compound is present in the fatty acid profile in significant amounts.</s><s>Colonies reach a maximum diameter of 2 mm.</s><s>They are yellow-pigmented, transparent, circular and convex. <i>N</i>-Acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, <i>p</i>-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, D-maltose, α-D-melibiose, sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose, D-xylose and D-mannitol are assimilated.</s><s>L-Rhamnose, D-ribose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, maltitol, D-sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, DL-lactate, L-malate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, L-alanine, β-alanine, L-aspartate, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate are not assimilated.</s><s>Assimilation of D-mannose is variable.</s><s><i>p</i>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) β-D-galactopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucuronide, pNP α-D-glucopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate, L-alanine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide (pNA) and L-proline pNA are hydrolysed. pNP Phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5´-pNP phosphate and L-glutamate γ-3-carboxy-pNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, cellulose azur and potato starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>α-Cellulose, casein and Tween 80 are not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production and urease activity.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 28 and 37 °C, weak growth at 4 °C and no growth at 44 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs at NaCl concentrations up to 5% (w/v), with weak growth at 7% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth is observed between pH 6 and 9.</s><s>The genomic DNA G­C content of strain 1A-C<sup>T</sup> is 70 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a medieval wall painting in the church of St Georgen in Styria, Austria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 1A-C<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14418<sup>T</sup>=CCM 4963<sup>T</sup>) ; a second strain of this species is 3A-1 (=DSM 14419=CCM 4964).</s></p></content></protolog>