<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10_nm.6805" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6805" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6805" rank="species">Saccharothrix espanaensis</organism><reference id="rid.10"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amendment of the genus Saccharothrix Labeda et al. 1984 and descriptions of Saccharothrix espanaesis sp. nov., Saccharothrix cryophilis sp. nov, and Saccharothrix mutabilis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>420</fpage><lpage>423</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-420</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Saccharothrix espanaensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix espanaensis</i> (es. pan. a. en' sis. L. adj. <i>espanaensis</i>, referring to the source of the soil sample, Puerto Llano, Spain, from which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium grayish yellow to yellowish brown.</s><s>Sparse white aerial mycelium is produced on some media, particularly on inorganic salts-starch agar and glycerol-asparagine agar.</s><s>A yellow soluble pigment is produced on glycerol-asparagine agar and inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Brown to reddish brown soluble pigments are produced on yeast extract-malt extract agar and on ATCC medium 172.</s><s>Casein, esculin, hippurate, and hypoxanthine are hydrolyzed or decomposed; adenine, allantoin, cellulose, gelatin, guanine, starch, tyrosine, urea, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is weakly reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, DL-lactate, DL-malate, and succinate are assimilated; benzoate, mucate, oxalate, and DL-tartrate are not assimilated; and assimilation of citrate and propionate is variable.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-mannose, sucrose, and trehalose; no acid is produced from adonitol, L-arabinose, dextrin, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, and D-sorbitol; and acid production from maltose and D-xylose is variable.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 4% NaCl but not in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15 to 42°C.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 72.2 mol% (thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Produces the antibiotic LLC19004.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. espanaensis</i> is strain NRRL 15764 (= LL-C19004-NS29)</s></p></content></protolog>