<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7515_nm.2282" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2282" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2282" rank="species">Thiothrix eikelboomii</organism><reference id="rid.7515"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Howarth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Unz</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pickup</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yaguchi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Head</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic relationships of filamentous sulfur bacteria (Thiothrix spp. and Eikelboom type 021N bacteria) isolated from wastewater-treatment plants and description of Thiothrix eikelboomii sp. nov., Thiothrix unzii sp. nov., Thiothrix fructosivorans sp. nov. and Thiothrix defluvii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1817</fpage><lpage>1827</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1817</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555365</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiothrix eikelboomii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiothrix eikelboomii</i> (ei.kel.boom'i.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>eikelboomii</i> of Eikelboom; named for D. H. Eikelboom, who pioneered morphological identification keys for filamentous bacteria in wastewater)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods and form multicellular filaments.</s><s>Baseto-tip differentiation in filaments is observed.</s><s>Cell morphology in filaments is highly variable, and cuboidal, barrel-shaped, cylindrical, discoid and beadlike cells are often observed.</s><s>Discoid cells at the base of filaments can range from 1.0 to 3.0 μm in diameter and 0.4 to 0.7 μm in length.</s><s>Apical cells are 0.6-0.8 μm in diameter and 1.0-5-0 μm in length and form bead-like strings.</s><s>Knots may be observed in filaments.</s><s>Gramnegative or Gram-variable.</s><s>A sheath is absent.</s><s>Rosettes and a holdfast are formed in some but not all strains.</s><s>Gliding gonidia are produced from the end of the filaments only in rosette-forming strains.</s><s>No flagella are present but a tuft of fimbriae is present at the end of the gonidium.</s><s>Volutin inclusions, sudanophilic granules and poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are observed within cells.</s><s>Growth occurs in the temperature range 10-33°C and pH range 6.5-8.5, but there is no growth at 37°C.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>No requirement for reduced inorganic sulfur for growth and is heterotrophic.</s><s>Sulfur globules are deposited within invaginations of the cytoplasmic membrane when cells are grown in the presence of a reduced inorganic sulfur compound.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch, casein, Tween 80 and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, mannitol, pyruvate, succinate, malate, acetate, lactate and propionate are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>No growth occurs with mannoheptulose, galactose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, fucose, ribose, xylose, arabinose, glyceraldehyde phosphate, lactose, melibiose, gentiobiose, cellobiose, raffinose, starch, inulin, salicin, aesculin, amygdalin, inositol, glycerol, erythritol, sorbitol, gluconate, glucuronate, galacturonate, Tween 80 or tributyrin.</s><s>Ammonia, arginine, tryptophan, proline, cysteine, phenylalanine, methionine, valine, asparagine, glutamine, aspartate, glutamate, isoleucine, tyrosine, histidine, leucine and alanine are used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Some isolates may also use nitrate, nitrite or urea as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Tyrosine, histidine and glutamate are used as carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from activated-sludge plants.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Thiothrix eikelboomii</i> is AP3<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 49788<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>