<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12553_nm.21417" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21417" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21417" rank="species">Ohtaekwangia kribbensis</organism><reference id="rid.12553"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ohtaekwangia koreensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Ohtaekwangia kribbensis sp. nov., isolated from marine sand, deep-branching members of the phylum Bacteroidetes</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1066</fpage><lpage>1072</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025874-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ohtaekwangia kribbensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ohtaekwangia kribbensis</em> (kri.bben′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>kribbensis</em> pertaining to KRIBB, an arbitrary adjective formed from the acronym of the Korea Research Institute of Bioscience and Biotechnology, KRIBB, where taxonomic studies on this species were performed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.2–0.5 µm in diameter and 1.5–7.5 µm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are irregular and yellow.</s><s>Optimal growth at 30 °C; grows at 10 and 39 °C, but not at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth at pH 6.5–7.5; grows at pH 5.0 and 8.5, but not at pH 4.5 or 9.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of NaCl, but growth occurs in the presence of up to 0.2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions on R2A agar or on R2A agar supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, casein, gelatin, Tween 80 and l-tyrosine, but not hypoxanthine, xanthine, starch or urea.</s><s>Assimilation data of substrates in the GN2 microplate system are given in Table 1.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, novobiocin, streptomycin and tetracycline, and weakly susceptible to polymycin B, but resistant to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, oleandomycin and penicillin G.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, positive for activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and β-fucosidase, but negative for activities of lipase (C14), trypsin, β-glucuronidase and α-mannosidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 44.6 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 10AO<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23019<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 58938<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sand sample collected from the coast at Saemankum, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>