<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12550_nm.21411" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21411" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21411" rank="species">Halomonas vilamensis</organism><reference id="rid.12550"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Menes</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Viera</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farías</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seufferheld</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas vilamensis sp. nov., isolated from high-altitude Andean lakes</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1211</fpage><lpage>1217</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023150-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20584819</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas vilamensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas vilamensis</em> (vi.la.men′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>vilamensis</em> pertaining to Laguna Vilama, Jujuy, Argentina).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, rod-shaped (2.0–4.0×1.0–1.6 µm) and occur singly and in pairs.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of polar and laterally inserted flagella, non-spore-forming and aerobic.</s><s>Does not produce exopolysaccharides or diffusible pigments and stains positively for intracellular polyphosphate granules but not for poly-β-hydroxyalkanoates.</s><s>Colonies are cream to pale pink, circular, smooth, convex and 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation on MGM 10 agar or MH medium with 7.5 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Grows at temperatures ranging from 5 to 40 °C (optimum growth around 30 °C) and at pH 5.0–10.0 (optimum growth at pH 7.0–8.0) (Supplementary Fig. S3).</s><s>Moderately halophilic, capable of growing at NaCl concentrations from 1 to 25 % (w/v) with optimum growth at 5–10 % (w/v) in media with 2.4 % (w/v) magnesium and potassium salts.</s><s>Requires NaCl, potassium salts and magnesium salts for growth.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar supplemented with 7.5 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>No oxidation or fermentation of glucose in OF Hugh and Leifson medium (after 15 days).</s><s>Does not produce acids from carbohydrates and alcohols.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase-positive.</s><s>Blood is haemolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed but not aesculin, casein, DNA, Tween 20, Tween 80, tributyrin, tyrosine, starch or urea.</s><s>Nitrate but not nitrite is reduced aerobically.</s><s>Selenite is reduced.</s><s>The following tests are negative: anaerobic growth, gluconate oxidation, respiration on nitrite and fumarate, H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine, pigment from tyrosine, phosphatase, ONPG, lecitovitellin, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer.</s><s>Respiration on nitrate is positive.</s><s>Arsenate, fumarate, molybdate, nitrite, selenate, selenite and tungstate are not reduced with tryptone, malate or acetate as electron donors.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, caproate, fumarate, dl-β-hydroxybutyrate, malate, maleate, malonate and succinate.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, glycine, l-lysine, l-proline and l-valine are utilized as sole carbon, energy and nitrogen sources but not l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine or l-threonine.</s><s>No growth is observed on the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: aesculin, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, sorbose, trehalose, d-xylose, sucrose, benzoate, butyrate, caprylate, citrate, formate, gluconate, lactate, propionate, pyruvate, tartrate, adonitol, ethanol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, propanol, d-sorbitol or creatine.</s><s>In API 20 NE, malic acid is utilized, gelatinase is produced and nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but tests for d-glucose, l-arabinose, gluconate, adipic acid, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, aesculin, arginine dihydrolase and indole are negative.</s><s>Does not produce acid or utilize any of the carbohydrates in API 50 CH: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, α-methyl d-glucoside, α-methyl d-mannoside, β-methyl d-xyloside, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, l-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 µg), azithromycin (15 µg), bacitracin (10 µg), cefotaxime (30 µg), cefoxitin (30 µg), ceftazidime (30 µg), ceftriaxone (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), clindamycin (2 µg), doxycycline (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), levofloxacin (5 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), neomycin (30 µg), nitrofurantoin (300 µg), norfloxacin (10 µg), oxacillin (1 µg), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (5 µg), trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1.25/23.75 µg) and vancomycin (30 µg).</s><s>Resistant to amikacin (30 µg), penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10 µg), sulfisoxazole (0.25 mg) and tobramycin (10 µg).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.0 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>The predominant quinones are Q-9 and Q-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (up to 90 %) are C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SV325<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 21020<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24332<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the sediment of a hypersaline lake located 4600 m above sea level (Laguna Vilama, Argentina).</s></p></content></protolog>