<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5759_nm.2955" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2955" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2955" rank="species">Vibrio calviensis</organism><reference id="rid.5759"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vybiral</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>U.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velimirov</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio calviensis sp. nov., a halophilic, facultatively oligotrophic 0.2 microm-fiIterabIe marine bacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>549</fpage><lpage>553</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01859-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931167</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio calviensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio calviensis</i> (cal.vi.en'sis. N.L. gen. n. <i>calviensis</i> of or pertaining to the Bay of Calvi, Corsica, from where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data compiled from Vybiral et al. (1999) and data generated in this study.</s><s>The cells are straight to slightly curved and rod-shaped (0.25-1.0x0.75-2.5 μm), Gram-negative and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Bacto marine agar 2216 (Difco) as well as on sea-water agar are brownish, translucent, circular, smooth and convex with an entire edge.</s><s>Bioluminescence was not observed.</s><s>Growth occurs at room temperature, at 30 °C and within 10 d at 4 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows on TCBS agar, producing green colonies.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs between 1.5 and 12% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 2.5-3.5% (w/v) ; there is no growth at 1.0% NaCl or when NaCl is absent.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, colistin sulphate, fusidic acid, kanamycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, streptomycin, tetracycline and vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin, oxacillin and spectinomycin.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase tests give positive results.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not further to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative and the methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed but casein, starch and agar are not.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: β-gentiobiose, cellobiose, citrate, ribose, galactose, gluconate, mannitol, melibiose, maltose, D-mannose, D-turanose and saccharose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adipate, amidon, arbutine, L-arabinose, caprate, D-fructose, D-glucose, glycogen, inulin, methyl α-D-mannoside, N-acetylglucosamine, trehalose, D- and L-xylose.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acidic phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase (C<sub>14</sub>), β-galactosidase, lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, amannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 16:1 cis, 16:0 and 18:1<i>trans</i>9, <i>cis</i>11; in addition, hydroxylated fatty acids 12:0 3-OH and 14:0 3-OH are present in minor amounts.</s><s>The cellular polyamine content is characterized by the presence of putrescine, spermidine, cadaverine, 1,3-diaminopropane and symnorspermidine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is RE35F/12<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107077<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14347<sup>T</sup>); it was isolated from sea water by 0.2 μm membrane filtration.</s></p></content></protolog>