<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2388_nm.11252" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11252" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11252" rank="species">Sphingobacterium composti</organism><reference id="rid.2388"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium composti sp. nov., isolated from cotton-waste composts</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1590</fpage><lpage>1593</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64948-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobacterium composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobacterium composti</em> (com.pos′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile rods, 0.5–0.6 μm long by 1.0–2.0 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA are yellow, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>The temperature, pH and NaCl ranges for growth are 10–45 °C, pH 6–9 and 0–5 % NaCl, respectively.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present.</s><s>Negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tweens 20 and 80.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin, casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tween 40, tyrosine or urea.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, d-sucrose, salicin and d-melibiose.</s><s>Does not assimilate d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-proline.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-sucrose, d-raffinose and l-fucose.</s><s>Acids are produced weakly from d-xylose, d-melibiose, d-trehalose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acids are not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inulin, d-melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), benzylpenicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (15 μg), neomycin (30 μg), oleandomycin, polymyxin (300 U) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Sensitive to carbenicillin (100 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 42.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4M24<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11313<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18850<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from cotton-waste composts in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>