<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2557_nm.11510" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11510" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11510" rank="species">Arenibacter echinorum</organism><reference id="rid.2557"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenibacter echinorum sp. nov., isolated from the sea urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2655</fpage><lpage>2659</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65251-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978235</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenibacter echinorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenibacter echinorum</em> (e.chi.no′rum. L. gen. pl. n. <em>echinorum</em> of sea urchins; N.L. gen. n. <em>echinorum</em> bacterium isolated from sea urchins).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells range from 0.4 to 0.5 μm in width and from 1.5 to 2.7 μm in length and move by means of gliding.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are 2–4 mm in diameter, circular, convex with entire edges and dark-orange in colour.</s><s>Growth is observed at 4–35 °C and with 0–8 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 24–26 °C and with 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Tween 40 is hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 20 is strain-dependent.</s><s>Agar, casein, gelatin, alginate, starch, Tween 80, DNA, urea, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) and chitin are not decomposed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, dl-xylose and amygdalin, but not from l-arabinose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, citrate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Acid production from d-raffinose is strain-dependent.</s><s>l-Arabinose, glucose, lactose, d-mannose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, citrate, malate and mannitol are utilized, but inositol and sorbitol are not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) is produced, but indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine- and ornithine-decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>In API ZYM strips, esterase lipase (C8), leucine-, valine-, cystine-arylamidases, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14) and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activities are absent.</s><s>Esterase (C4) activity is strain-dependent.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 Microplates, dextrin, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-raffinose, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate and dl-lactic acid are utilized.</s><s>Utilization of <em>α</em>-d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside and <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid is strain-dependent.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, Tween 80, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, <em>i</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-psicose, xylitol, mono-methylsuccinate, acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-proline, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-threonine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, uronic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, lincomycin and oleandomycin.</s><s>In addition, the type strain is susceptible to doxycycline, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, carbenicillin, neomycin and polymyxin B.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids of strain KMM 6032<sup>T</sup> are the straight-chain saturated, and unsaturated and branched-chain unsaturated fatty acids C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (22.0 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (13.1 %), summed feature 3 (10.7 %; comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (10.5 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (6.4 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (4.2 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (3.9 %) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.5 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 39–40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 6032<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22013<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22574<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sea urchin <em>Strongylocentrotus intermedius</em> collected in Troitsa Bay, East Sea.</s><s>Another reference strain is KMM 6047 (=KCTC 22014=LMG 22582).</s></p></content></protolog>