<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6907_nm.1303" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1303" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1303" rank="species">Rhizobium sullae</organism><reference id="rid.6907"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Squartini</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Struffi</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Döring</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Selenska-Pobell</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giacomini</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vendramin</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dazzo</surname><given-names>F.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casella</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nuti</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium sullae sp. nov. (formerly 'Rhizobium hedysari'), the root-nodule microsymbiont of Hedysarum coronarium L.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1267</fpage><lpage>1276</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01821-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148639</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium sullae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium sullae</i> (sul'la.e. N.L. gen. n. <i>sullae</i> of sulla, the common Italian name of <i>Hedysarum coronarium</i>, the host plant)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods, motile by multiple polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on YMA are circular and opaque, reaching a diameter of 3-5 mm within 3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth rate (10 strains measured) is between 0.28 and 0.32 h<sup>-1</sup> (Cabrera &#x0026; Ruiz-Argüeso, 1979).</s><s>The G+C content is 61.6 mol% (Struffi et al., 1998).</s><s>Growth on YEM is inhibited between 0.5 and 1% (w/v) NaCl and below pH 5.5.</s><s>Most strains are resistant to carbenicillin and nalidixic acid, all strains tested utilize D-(+­)-galactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose and lactose as carbon sources and glutamate, valine, proline, isoleucine, arginine and asparagine as nitrogen sources.</s><s>The strains considered for the inclusion in this taxon are listed in Table 1.</s><s>A complete table of the metabolic reactions of each strain, including those of the type strain, has been presented previously (Struffi et al., 1998).</s><s>The characteristics considered essential for membership in the taxon, and that distinguish <i>R. sullae</i> from related species, are (i) specific nitrogen-fixing endosymbiosis with <i>H. coronarium</i> and (ii) DNA-DNA hybridization values among taxon members above 70%.</s><s>Other characteristics considered nonessential but indicative of possible membership in the taxon are: (i) presence of insertion element ISRH1 (Meneghetti et al., 1996), (ii) double-layered infection thread (Squartini et al., 1993), (iii) Latin cross-shaped bacteroids (Squartini et al., 1993) and (iv) sensitivity to one or more of the following bacteriophages: f835a, f123c, fHA5, fHC, f100c, f19a, f19c, f44a and f44c1 (Struffi et al., 1998).</s><s>Characteristics that qualify the species for inclusion in the genus <i>Rhizobium</i> are the results of (i) 16S sequencing, (ii) rrn ARDRA, (iii) LMM RNA electrophoresis and (iv) DNA-DNA hybridization, which consistently cluster all isolates within the genus <i>Rhizobium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IS123<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the USDA National Rhizobium Germplasm Culture Collection (Beltsville, MD, USA) as USDA 4950<sup>T</sup> and in the DSMZ as DSM 14623<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>