<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1516_nm.945" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.945" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.945" rank="species">Stella vacuolata</organism><reference id="rid.1516"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vasilyeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stella, a new genus of soil prosthecobacteria, with proposals  for Stella humosa sp.nov. and Stella vacuolata sp.nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>518</fpage><lpage>521</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-518</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stella vacuolata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stella vacuolata</i> (va.cu.o.la’ta. L. adj. <i>vaccus</i> empty, void; L. adj. <i>latus</i> broad, wide; M.L. adj. <i>vacuolata</i> referring to large areas in the cytoplasm which appear empty due to gas vesicle formation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are flat, six-pronged stars ranging from 1.9 to 2.5 μm in diameter and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Clusters or aggregates are not formed.</s><s>Gram negative; nonmotile.</s><s>Multiplication by symmetrical division into two three-pronged daughter cells.</s><s>The distinctive morphological feature is the presence of gas vesicles throughout the cytoplasm.</s><s>Cells exhibit considerable buoyancy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on agar prepared with dilute (1:5) media are milky white, circular, and viscous and may reach 2.5 mm in</s></p><p class="description"><s>diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In liquid broth a pellicle is formed, and sediment occurs in the bottom of the tube.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by shaking cultures and by 1% NaCl.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 28°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is near neutral or slightly alkaline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic , microaerophilic .</s><s>Selected amino acids and organic acids of the tricarboxylic acid cycle are utilized as energy sources.</s><s>There is a growth requirement for yeast extract, although Casamino Acids or L-glutamic acid and a B vitamin mixture can substitute for yeast extract.</s><s>Sugars are not utilized but do not inhibit growth.</s><s>Complex polysaccharides (cellulose, starch) and protein (gelatin) are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: isolated from horse manure and sewage sludge of a piggery.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 70.0 to 73.5 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Plasmids not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 229, which has been deposited in the culture collection of the Institute of Microbiology, Academy of Sciences, Moscow, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>