<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2758_nm.2854" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2854" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2854" rank="species">Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus</organism><reference id="rid.2758"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gauthier</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lafay</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Acquaviva</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonin</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bertrand</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new, extremely halotolerant, hydrocarbon-degrading marine bacterium.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>568</fpage><lpage>576</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-568</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1382536</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus</i> (hy'dro.car.bo.no.clas'ti.cus M. L. part. adj. <i>hydrocarbonoclastic</i>, hydrocarbon dismantling)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of the type strain of <i>Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclastic</i> are rod shaped (2 to 3 μm long and 0.3 to 0.6 μm wide in logarithmic growth phase) and harbor numerous surface blebs when grown on eicosane in mineral medium.</s><s>Cells are gram negative, nonsporeforming, and motile by means of a single unsheathed polar flagellum in media containing 0.2 to 1 M NaCl.</s><s>They are unflagellated in media with a lower or higher NaCl concentration.</s><s>Colonies on agar media are white when young and pinky beige after 48 h of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are able to grow at temperatures ranging from 10 to 45°C (mesotrophic), with optimal growth at 32°C.</s><s>They exhibit extreme halotolerance and can grow in NaCl concentrations ranging from 0.08 to 3.5 M.</s><s>They have an absolute requirement for sodium ion.</s><s>Aerobic, with a nonfermentative metabolism, they can grow anaerobically with nitrate or on succinate, citrate, or acetate but not on glucose.</s><s>They are able to denitrify, with N2 production.</s><s>They exhibit oxidase, cytochrome oxidase, catalase, tweenase, and lecithinase activities.</s><s>They grow on acetate, butyrate, caproate, succinate, fumarate, adipate, DL-lactate, and citrate as sole carbon sources but not on carbohydrates and amino acids (except L-proline and L-glutamate).</s><s>They degrade a large variety of aliphatic or aromatic hydrocarbons and produce a nondialyzable bioemulsifier when grown on hydrocarbons.</s></p><p class="description"><s>SP.17 cells are resistant to novobiocin, tetracycline, oleandomycin, staphylomycin, and vibriostatic agent 0/129 and are susceptible to penicillin G, kanamycin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, cephaloridine, gentamicin, and nalidixic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA, determined from measurements of thermal denaturation temperatures, is 52.7 mol%.</s><s>According to the 16s rRNA sequence, the bacterium belongs to the gamma-type <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is part of a distinct monophyletic group including <i>O. linum</i>, <i>M. vaga</i>, <i>H. elongata</i>,<i> P. aeruginosa</i>, and <i>A. calcoaceticus</i>.</s><s>Strain SP.17 was isolated from Mediterranean seawater (Gulf of Fos) near a petroleum refinery outlet.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49840.</s></p></content></protolog>