<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1163_nm.2584" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2584" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2584" rank="species">Pseudomonas cepacia</organism><reference id="rid.1163"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palleroni</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas cepacia sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>479</fpage><lpage>481</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-479</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas cepacia</i> (ex Burkholder, 1950) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(<i>P. multivorans</i> Stanier et al., 1966; “P. kingii” Jonsson, 1970) (ce pa'ci a.L. fem.n. <i>caepa</i> or <i>cepa</i> onion; M.L. fem. adj. <i>Cepacius</i> of or like onion.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods 0.8 to 1 by 1.6 to 3.2 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and are motile by means of a tuft of polar flagella.</s><s>Cells accumulate poly-betahydroxybutyrate as a carbon reserve material, especially in nitrogen-deficient media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pigments which do not fluoresce under low wavelength ultraviolet light (254 nm) are produced by most strains.</s><s>On ordinary complex media, the pigmentation is yellow or greenish, but on chemically defined media the pigments may show a great variety of colors, depending on the carbon source used for growth.</s><s>In some cases the pigments are associated with the cells, and in other cases they diffuse into the medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Denitrification is negative; nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipolytic.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyze gelatin, and some give a positive lecithinase (egg yolk) reaction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No organic growth factors are required.</s><s>Nutritionally, the most versatile of the <i>Pseudomonas</i> species known to date.</s><s>Out of about 150 organic compounds, one-third or more can be used as sole carbon and energy sources for growth; these compounds include a large variety of carbohydrates, mono- and dicarboxylic acids, mono- and polyalcohols, aromatic compounds, amino acids, and amines.</s><s>Substrates which are of diagnostic value and are used by</s></p><p class="description"><s>the great majority of the strains but which are used only infrequently by strains of other <i>Pseudomonas</i> species include D-arabinose, D-fucose, cellobiose, saccharate, mucate, 2,3-butylene glycol, sebacate, <i>mess</i>-tartrate, citraconate, α-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-threonine, DL-ornithine, and tryptamine.</s><s>D-(-)-Tartrate, mesaconate, and erythritol are among the compounds not utilized for growth.</s><s>Only three strains originally labeled <i>P. multiuorans</i> can use maltose for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature, 30 to 35°C.</s><s>No growth at 4°C.</s><s>Most strains grow at 41°C, and almost all grow at 40°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have been isolated from rotten onions, soils, and various clinical specimens, including benzalkonium chloride solutions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The average guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 67.4 mol%, as determined by buoyant density centrifugation.</s><s>Deoxyribonucleic acid-deoxyribonucleic acid hybridization experiments have indicated that this species is related to <i>Pseudomonas gladioli</i> (“<i>Pseudomonas marginata</i>,” “<i>Pseudomonas alliicola</i>”), <i>Pseudomonas caryophylli</i>, <i>Pseudomonas mallei</i>, and <i>Pseudomonas pseudomallei</i> (1; M.</s><s>Rogul, J.</s><s>Brendle, D.</s><s>K.</s><s>Haapala, and A.D.</s><s>Alexander, Bacteriol.</s><s>Proc., p. 19, 1968).</s><s>In addition, ribosomal ribonucleic acid-deoxyribonucleic acid hybridization studies have shown a relationship to <i>Pseudomonas solanacearum</i> and <i>Pseudomonas pickettii</i>.</s><s>At present this species is included in <i>Pseudomonas</i> Group II.</s><s>Table 1 lists characters of diagnostic value for the differentiation of <i>P. cepacia</i> from other species of this group.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Burkholder (=717-ICPB 25, =ATCC 25416, =NCTC 10743).</s><s>This strain has given the following results for the tests that are not universally positive or negative for the 37 strains of <i>P. cepacia</i> that have been characterized fully: it liquefies gelatin and gives a positive egg yolk reaction; it is able to grow on trehalose, butanol, glycolate, L-mandelate, benzoylformate, benzoate, testosterone, L-valine, L-leucine, delta-aminovalerate, butylamine, benzylamine, and acetamide; and it does not grow on L-rhamnose, maltose, starch, isobutanol or nicotinate.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 67.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>