<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11569_nm.18604" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18604" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18604" rank="species">Haladaptatus cibarius</organism><reference id="rid.11569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haladaptatus cibarius sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from seafood, and emended description of the genus Haladaptatus</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1187</fpage><lpage>1190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013037-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667394</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haladaptatus cibarius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haladaptatus cibarius</em> (ci.ba′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>cibarius</em> pertaining to or suitable for food).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative-staining cocci or coccobacilli with a diameter of 1.0 μm, motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>The colonies are pink, circular with entire margins and 1.0 mm in diameter after 3 weeks of incubation on a complex agar medium (DSM medium 954) at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–50 °C (optimum 37 °C), in the presence of 10–30 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 15 %) and at pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> is required for growth.</s><s>The minimal Mg<sup>2+</sup> concentration for growth and the Mg<sup>2+</sup> concentration for optimal growth are 5 and 20 mM, respectively.</s><s>Cell lysis does not occur in distilled water.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase and indole formation.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but starch, casein and urea are not.</s><s>Sucrose, d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, formate and acetate are utilized as carbon and energy sources, but citrate and d-mannitol are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from sucrose and d-glucose, but not from d-fructose, citrate, lactose, formate, acetate or d-mannitol.</s><s>Anaerobic growth with nitrate, sulfate, thiosulfate or DMSO does not occur.</s><s>Sensitive to anisomycin, aphidicolin, chloramphenicol and rifampicin, and resistant to ampicillin, erythromycin, kanamycin, streptomycin and polymycin B.</s><s>The polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me and two unidentified glycolipids.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 56.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is D43<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19505<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15962<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from Korean salt-fermented seafood made from shellfish.</s></p></content></protolog>