<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8247_nm.14184" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14184" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14184" rank="species">Aquabacterium fontiphilum</organism><reference id="rid.8247"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquabacterium fontiphilum sp. nov., isolated from spring water.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>681</fpage><lpage>685</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000745-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329587</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquabacterium fontiphilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquabacterium fontiphilum</em> [fon.ti.phi′lum. L. n. <em>fons</em>, <em>fontis</em> a spring, fountain; N.L. neut. adj. <em>philum</em> (from Gr. neut. adj. <em>philon</em>) loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>fontiphilum</em> loving spring-water environment].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods (0.5–0.8 μm wide and 1.0–2.0 μm long) that are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are round, elevated with a knob-like protuberance, semi-transparent and have irregular edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1.3–1.5 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 48 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15, 25, 30, 37 and 42 °C, in 0–2 % NaCl and at pH 5–9.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25–30 °C, 1.0 % NaCl and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Positive for cytochrome oxidase and weakly positive for catalase.</s><s>Growth is observed under aerobic and microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of urea, gelatin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for DNase, lipase (corn oil) and for hydrolysis of skimmed milk, starch and aesculin.</s><s>Nitrate serves as an alternative electron acceptor, but nitrite, chlorate, sulfate or iron(III) do not.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN2 test system: Tween 40, Tween 80, i-erythritol, d-mannitol, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, turanose, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, dl-lactic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-glutamic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Does not oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, inosine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim, and sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, rifampicin, penicillin G and tetracycline.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-15 : 0 2-OH), 16 : 0 and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CS-6<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24215<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17729<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected from a spring located inside Nature Valley, Hsinchu County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>