<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12539_nm.21398" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21398" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21398" rank="species">Thalassobacillus pellis</organism><reference id="rid.12539"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yilmaz</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de la Haba</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birbir</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassobacillus pellis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, Gram-positive bacterium isolated from salted hides</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1206</fpage><lpage>1210</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024778-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20562240</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassobacillus pellis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassobacillus pellis</em> (pel′lis. L. n. <em>pellis –is</em> hide, tanned hide, leather; L. gen. n. <em>pellis</em> of/from hide, tanned hide, leather, isolated from salted hides that are used in the leather industry).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, motile, endospore-forming rods, 1.0×1.5–6.0 µm in size, and occur as single cells, pairs or short chains (see Supplementary Fig. S3).</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores are produced at a terminal position in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, smooth, convex, cream and 1–2 mm in diameter on 10 % HM agar medium after 48 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing at 0.5–25 % (w/v) NaCl; with optimal growth at 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 15–45 °C, showing optimal growth at 37 °C, and at pH values between 5.0 and 9.0, with optimal growth at pH 7.5.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, DNA, pullulan and aesculin are hydrolysed, but starch, Tween 80 and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, glycerol, trehalose, sucrose and d-xylose, but not from d-arabinose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose or d-mannitol.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Phosphatase activity is positive.</s><s>Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, Simmons’ citrate, urease, β-galactosidase arginine, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and phenylalanine deaminase tests are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy: cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, dulcitol, ethanol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, acetate, benzoate, citrate, fumarate, propionate and hippurate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy: starch, d-arabinose, fructose, d-fucose, aesculin, melezitose, butanol, glycerol, propanol, methanol, formate, succinate, valerate, malate and tartrate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: l-alanine, l-arginine, phenylalanine, glutamine, l-serine, tryptophan, valine, l-lysine, isoleucine and l-threonine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: aspartate, l-cysteine, l-methionine and l-ornithine.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin (30 µg), penicillin G (10 U), nalidixic acid (30 µg) and neomycin (10 µg).</s><s>Sensitive to cephalothin (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), novobiocin (30 µg) and sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25 µg).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The respiratory isoprenoid quinones are MK-7 (98.5 %) and MK-6 (1.5 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 18OM<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7566<sup>T</sup> = DSM 22784<sup>T</sup> = JCM 16412<sup>T</sup>), isolated from salted animal hides.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>