<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6380_nm.10089" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10089" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10089" rank="species">Kineococcus marinus</organism><reference id="rid.6380"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineococcus marinus sp. nov., isolated from marine sediment of the coast of Jeju, Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1279</fpage><lpage>1283</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64128-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738104</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kineococcus marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kineococcus marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, the origin of the sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, Gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or in clusters.</s><s>Forms capsular polysaccharide-like substances on most solid media.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex and deep orange in colour.</s><s>Glucose fermentation, H<sub>2</sub>S production and nitrate reduction are not observed.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C with an optimum at 30 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at or above 40 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.1–10.1, with an optimum at pH 7.1.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase is present, but urease activity is not detected.</s><s>DNA, aesculin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but casein and elastin are not.</s><s>Salt is required for growth; good growth occurs at 1–4 % NaCl, moderate growth at 5–8 % NaCl and poor growth at 9 % NaCl.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, l-lactic acid, d- and l-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources for growth.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: inulin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, maltotriose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-sorbitol, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, methyl pyruvate, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, thymidine, uridine and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid of the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain arabinose and galactose as characteristic sugars.</s><s>The glycan moiety of the murein structure is acetylated.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Polar lipid contains phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol (phospholipid-type PI pattern <em>sensu</em> Lechevalier <em>et al.</em>, 1981).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is 12-methyltetradecanoic acid (anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 76.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KST3-3<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42250<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24439<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sediment sample of the coast of Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>