<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9580_nm.14768" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14768" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14768" rank="species">Fodinicurvata fenggangensis</organism><reference id="rid.9580"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fodinicurvata sediminis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Fodinicurvata fenggangensis sp. nov., poly-β-hydroxybutyrate-producing bacteria in the family Rhodospirillaceae</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2575</fpage><lpage>2581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009340-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622654</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fodinicurvata fenggangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fodinicurvata fenggangensis</em> (feng.gang.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>fenggangensis</em> the locality of the salt mine from which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are cream–white, smooth, circular, convex and opaque with slightly irregular margins.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.2–0.5 μm wide and 0.5–1.3 μm long.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–42 °C (optimum, 28 °C).</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.5–8.5 (optimum, 7.5).</s><s>Grows at NaCl concentrations of 1.5–20 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive for urease, arginine dihydrolase and nitrate reduction, and negative for hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin, indole production, glucose acidification, l-phenylalanine deaminase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, citrate, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycerol and l-proline as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, amylum, l-arabinose, d-cellulose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, l-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, ethanol, d-mannitol, methanol, acetate, glycine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine or d-serine.</s><s>With the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, weakly positive for esterase (C4) and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, and negative for acid phosphatase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): carbenicillin (100), chloramphenicol (30) and penicillin (10 U), but resistant to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), nalidixic acid (30), norfloxacin (10) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>Polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol and three unknown phospholipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM D812<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208037<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21160<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt mine of Fenggang in Yunnan, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>