<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12162_nm.20153" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20153" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20153" rank="species">Oceanobacillus neutriphilus</organism><reference id="rid.12162"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huo</surname><given-names>Y.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meng</surname><given-names>F.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oceanobacillus neutriphilus sp. nov., isolated from
activated sludge in a bioreactor</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2409</fpage><lpage>2414</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016295-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19946056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Oceanobacillus neutriphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Oceanobacillus neutriphilus</em> (neu.tri.phi′lus. L. adj. <em>neuter</em> -<em>tra</em> -<em>trum</em> neither, used to refer to neutral pH; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>neutriphilus</em> preferring neutral pH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, aerobic rods, 0.7–1.2 μm wide and 1.5–2.5 μm long with rounded ends, that are motile by means of polar flagella and produce ellipsoidal spores in a central position.</s><s>Colonies on MA are 1–2 mm in diameter, of low convexity, smooth, circular with regular borders and cream-coloured after 48 h.</s><s>Growth occurs in PY medium at NaCl concentrations of 0–17.0 % (w/v) with optimum growth at 3.0–5.0 %.</s><s>The pH and temperature ranges for growth are 6.0–9.0 and 10–45 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0 and 37 °C).</s><s>No growth is detected below pH 5.5 or above pH 9.5.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, Tween 40 and Tween 60, but not casein, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 or tyrosine.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Positive for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, indole production, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose and sucrose as sole carbon and energy sources, but not acetate, l-alanine, l-arabinose, citrate, l-cysteine, ethanol, formate, fumarate, glutamate, l-glutamine, glycine, l-histidine, isoleucine, lactate, lactose, malate, malonate, l-methionine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-ornithine, propionate, pyruvate, raffinose, l-serine, l-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, succinate or l-valine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose and sucrose, but not from l-arabinose, ethanol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, raffinose, l-sorbitol or l-sorbose.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc unless indicated otherwise) amoxicillin (10), ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), novobiocin (30) and rifampicin (5), but not to cefoxitin (30), nystatin (100), penicillin (10), polymyxin B (300 IU), streptomycin (10) or tetracycline (30).</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities are not observed.</s><s>Oxidative acid production in API 50 CH tests is positive for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, aesculin, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, salicin, sucrose, d-tagatose and trehalose and weakly positive for cellobiose and glycerol.</s><s>Principal fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, A1g<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7693<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15776<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge of a bioreactor treating salt-containing wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>