<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.746_nm.6591" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6591" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6591" rank="species">Dactylosporangium roseum</organism><reference id="rid.746"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amano</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tohyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niida</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dactylosporangium roseum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>4</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dactylosporangium roseum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dactylosporangium roseum</i> (ro'se.um. L. neut. adj. <i>roseum</i> rose colored, referring to the color of the vegetative mycelium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The formation of finger-shaped sporangia containing motile spores, the absence of true alerial mycelia, and type II cell walls place strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> in the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> Thiemann et al. (14).</s><s>Four species, <i>D. aurantiacum</i> (14), <i>D. thailandense</i> (13, 14), <i>D. matsuzakiense</i> (11), and <i>D. vinaceum</i> (12), have been described previously as species of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i>.</s><s>We compared strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> directly with the type strains of these four previously described species.</s><s>No outstanding differences in morphology were apparent among these four type strains and strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup>, regardless of whether sporangia or spores were compared.</s><s>However, strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> differs clearly from the other four type strains in its cultural and physiological characteristics, as described below. <i>D. vinaceum</i> produces a wine to deep red diffusible pigment on almost all media used, whereas no obvious diffusible pigment was observed in strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> on the same media.</s><s>As shown in Table 2, the reverse colors of <i>D. aurantiacum</i>, <i>D. thailandense</i>, and <i>D. matsuzakiense</i> are apricot to orange on oatmeal agar, whereas the reverse of strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> is colorless.</s><s>On the other hand, strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> shows a distinctive rose reverse color on yeast extract-malt extract agar, on inorganic salts-starch agar, and especially on sucrose-yeast extract agar, whereas the other three species do not show such color on these media.</s><s>In addition, strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> and the other four species differ in some physiological properties, such as starch hydrolysis and utilization of D-mannitol and L-rhamnose (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In view of the characteristics described above, strain SF-2186<sup>T</sup> can be considered a new species of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i>, for which we propose the name <i>Dactylosporangium roseum</i> sp. nov.</s><s>Strain SF-2186 is the type strain of <i>D. roseum</i>; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, Japan, as strain IFO 14352</s></p></content></protolog>