<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12289_nm.20308" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20308" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20308" rank="species">Granulicella pectinivorans</organism><reference id="rid.12289"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Granulicella paludicola gen. nov., sp. nov., Granulicella pectinivorans sp. nov., Granulicella aggregans  sp. nov. and Granulicella rosea sp. nov., acidophilic, polymer-degrading acidobacteria from Sphagnum  peat bogs</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2951</fpage><lpage>2959</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021824-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118293</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Granulicella pectinivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Granulicella pectinivorans</em> (pec.ti.ni.vor′ans. N.L. n. <em>pectinum</em> pectin; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>pectinivorans</em> pectin-devouring, referring to the ability to use pectin as a growth substrate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus but with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.8–1.0×1.5–15 μm.</s><s>Colony colour varies from pale pink to red.</s><s>Produces copious amounts of EPS.</s><s>Able to utilize the following carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v): d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-xylose, cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, acetate, gluconate, lactate, sodium d-galacturonate, succinate, mannitol, inulin and <em>myo</em>-inositol.</s><s>Unable to utilize d-arabinose, lactose, lactulose, leucrose, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbose, d-fucose, salicin, arbutin, adonitol, sorbitol, dulcitol, glucuronate, malate, pyruvate, butyrate, oxalate, propionate, formiate, fumarate, capronate, citrate, valerate, ethanol or methanol.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, laminarin, pectin, lichenan, starch and xylan but not sodium alginate, CM-cellulose, cellulose, chitin, chitosan, fucoidan or pullulan.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are present: valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, esterase, urease and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM test).</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Capable of growth at pH 3.0–7.5 (optimum pH 3.8–4.5) and at 2–33 °C (optimum 18–22 °C).</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, streptomycin and neomycin but susceptible to lincomycin, novobiocin and kanamycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain TPB6011<sup>T</sup> (=VKM B-2509<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21001<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar, Tomsk region, West Siberia.</s></p></content></protolog>