<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8716_nm.13595" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13595" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13595" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora cebuensis</organism><reference id="rid.8716"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pimentel-Elardo</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiro</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grozdanov</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hentschel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora cebuensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from a Philippine sponge (Porifera).</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>628</fpage><lpage>632</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64971-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharopolyspora cebuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharopolyspora cebuensis</em> (ce.bu′en.sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>cebuensis</em> pertaining to the province of Cebu in the Philippines where the type strain was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic and form extensively branched white mycelium fragmenting into rod-shaped elements and aerial hyphae bearing short chains of spores.</s><s>Brown diffusible pigment is observed.</s><s>Growth is possible at 15–37 °C and in ISP2 or M1 media containing 2.5–12.5 % NaCl or 25–100 % ASW.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically.</s><s>Utilizes a variety of organic compounds such as glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-fucose, d-arabitol and potassium gluconate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Able to degrade tyrosine, but not adenine, casein, chitin or hypoxanthine.</s><s>Negative for oxidase and nitrate reduction, but positive for catalase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Whole cell hydrolysate contains galactose and arabinose.</s><s>Major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Lacks mycolic acids.</s><s>Fatty acid pattern consists of iso, anteiso and 10-methyl-branched fatty acids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SPE 10-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45019<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109355<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the Philippine sponge <em>Haliclona</em> sp.</s></p></content></protolog>