<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8423_nm.13389" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13389" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13389" rank="species">Leifsonia pindariensis</organism><reference id="rid.8423"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabagaran</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia pindariensis sp. nov., isolated from the Pindari glacier of the Indian Himalayas, and emended description of the genus Leifsonia.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2229</fpage><lpage>2234</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65715-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768634</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leifsonia pindariensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leifsonia pindariensis</em> (pin.da.ri.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>pindariensis</em> pertaining to the Pindari glacier of the Himalayan region of India, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.</s><s>Colonies are convex, yellow-pigmented and opaque.</s><s>Cells are motile, short rods.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease but negative for oxidase, phosphatase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, nitrate reduction, phenylalanine deamination, indole production and the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not gelatin or starch.</s><s>Produces acid from maltose and d-mannose but not from d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, melibiose, salicin, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes dulcitol, erythritol, d-glucose, d-glucuronic acid, glucosamine, glycerol, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-methionine and l-valine, but not <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, aesculin, d- or l-arabinose, cellobiose, citrate, dextran, d-fructose, galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, malonate, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, rhamnose, sodium gluconate, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, d- or l-xylose, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine or l-tyrosine.</s><s>Cells are resistant to (μg per disc unless indicated) colistin (10), nalidixic acid (30), norfloxacin (10), polymyxin B (50 U) and tobramycin (10) but sensitive to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), bacitracin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefazolin (30), cefoperazone (75), cefotaxime (30), cefuroxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), co-trimoxazole (25), doxycycline (10), erythromycin (15), gentamicin G (30), kanamycin (30), leucomycin (30), lomefloxacin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), novobiocin (30), oleandomycin (15), penicillin G (10), rifampicin (30), roxithromycin (30), spectinomycin (100), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The cell-wall sugars consist of a predominant amount of d-rhamnose and trace amounts of glucose, galactose and mannose.</s><s>The isoprenoid quinones present are MK-9 (minor), MK-10 and MK-11 (major).</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol; an unknown lipid is present in a minor amount.</s><s>The fatty acid profile (&#x003E;0.5 %) includes anteiso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> (0.9 %)<sub>,</sub> anteiso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (0.6 %), anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0.6 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.7 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.9 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (5.6 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G (0.5 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (54.3 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (6.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.9 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (2.0 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (19.1 %).</s><s>The methanolic spectrum of the yellow pigment shows absorption peaks at 350, 390, 440, 470 and 500 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PON10<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24222<sup>T</sup> =MTCC9128<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected at an altitude of approximately 3500 m near the Pindari glacier of the Indian Himalayas.</s></p></content></protolog>