<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8637_nm.13535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13535" rank="species">Polaromonas jejuensis</organism><reference id="rid.8637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polaromonas jejuensis sp. nov., isolated from soil in Korea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1525</fpage><lpage>1528</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65529-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599688</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Polaromonas jejuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Polaromonas jejuensis</em> (je.ju.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>jejuensis</em> referring to Jeju, Korea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, 0.6 μm wide and 1–3 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are pale yellow, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–30 °C (optimum, 28–30 °C), pH 5–9 (optimum, pH 6–7) and 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine, but not casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, DNA, pectin, starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Assimilates potassium gluconate, malic acid, trisodium citrate, itaconic acid, suberic acid, lactic acid, l-alanine, propionic acid, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, valeric acid, potassium 2-ketogluconate or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid (API 20NE and API ID 32GN test strips).</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase (API 20NE and API ZYM).</s><s>Negative for the following characteristics: nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API 20NE and API ZYM).</s><s>Naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activity is weak (API ZYM).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are summed feature 3, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JS12-13<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12508<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19351<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from Halla Mountain on Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>