<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1949_nm.8470" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8470" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8470" rank="species">Aquiflexum balticum</organism><reference id="rid.1949"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brettar</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Höfle</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquiflexum balticum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium of the Cytophaga-Flavobacterium-Bacteroides group isolated from surface water of the central Baltic Sea.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2335</fpage><lpage>2341</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63255-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquiflexum balticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquiflexum balticum</em> (bal′ti.cum. N.L. neut. adj. <em>balticum</em> from the Baltic Sea, referring to the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex and entire.</s><s>Red and transparent when young, but turn opaque with ongoing incubation (&#x003E;1 week, 30 °C, on half-strength marine agar).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped (width, 0·3–0·6 μm; length, 1·1–4·8 μm), and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–40 °C, with an optimum around 30 °C.</s><s>NaCl is not needed for growth, but growth occurs in the presence of 0 to 6 % NaCl, with an optimum around 1·5 %.</s><s>Grows from pH 7 to 9, with an optimum around neutral pH.</s><s>Does not grow on 0·5 % yeast extract.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, starch and gelatin.</s><s>Produces acid from galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentobiose, d-turanose, l-fucose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Shows <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, acid and alkaline phosphatase, leucine, valine and cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, naphthol-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminase activities.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, arabinose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose and gluconate.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, cellobiose, l-fructose, d-galactose, gentobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactic acid and propionic acid as substrates.</s><s>No use of amino acids is detected, but aminopeptidase is produced.</s><s>Of marine or estuarine origin.</s><s>The G+C content is 38·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BA160<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16537<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22565<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108445<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>