<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12119_nm.20113" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20113" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20113" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas lipolytica</organism><reference id="rid.12119"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>X.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas lipolytica sp. nov., isolated
from the Yangtze River estuary</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2176</fpage><lpage>2181</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017673-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897616</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoalteromonas lipolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoalteromonas lipolytica</em> (li.po.ly′ti.ca. Gr. n. <em>lipos</em> fat; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lytica</em> from Gr. fem. adj. <em>lutikê</em> able to dissolve; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lipolytica</em> fat-dissolving, referring to the property of being able to hydrolyse lipids).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative and motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved and rod-shaped (0.5–0.8 μm in width and 1.0–2.0 μm in length) with rounded ends.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Colonies on MA are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, circular and non-pigmented after 48 h.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> or seawater for growth.</s><s>Growth is observed in the presence of 0.5–15.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 3.0 %.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–9.5 and 15–37 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0–8.0 and 25 °C).</s><s>No growth is detected at 4 °C or above 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar (red colonies), but not on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin, Tweens 20 and 80 and tyrosine are hydrolysed.</s><s>Agar is not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from l-cysteine or thiosulfate.</s><s>Glucose fermentation, indole production and ONPG hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, tryptophan deaminase and urease.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and trypsin.</s><s>The following activities are not observed: <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adipate, l-arabinose, caprate, glucosamine, d-glucose, malate and maltose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: citrate, gluconate, d-mannitol, d-mannose and phenylacetate.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, maltose, d-mannose, salicin and sucrose, but not from d-galactose, glucose, lactose, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, rhamnose, raffinose, d-ribose, l-sorbitol, sorbose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg unless otherwise stated) ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), neomycin (30), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifamycin (5), tetracycline (30) and tobramycin (10), but not to bacitracin (0.04 IU), cefotaxime (30), kanamycin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), novobiocin (30) or nystatin (100).</s><s>Principal fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Ubiquinone-8 is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>The polar lipid profiles include phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol as the major compounds and minor to trace amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, two unidentified phospholipids and two unidentified glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMEB 39<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.8499<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15903<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the Yangtze River estuary near the East China Sea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.3 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>