<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1299_nm.5658" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5658" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5658" rank="species">Streptococcus macacae</organism><reference id="rid.1299"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayday</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>R.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus macacae sp. nov. from dental plaques of monkeys (Macaca fascicularis.)</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>332</fpage><lpage>335</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-332</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus macacae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus macacae</i> (ma.cacae.M.L.fem.n. <i>Macaca</i> genus name of macaque; M.L. gen.n.<i>macacae</i> of macaque)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and growth characteristics of <i>S. macacae</i>. <i>S. macaque</i> cells are gram-positive cocci which grow in chains in Todd-Hewitt broth and on sucrose-containing solid medium.</s><s>The strains grow poorly in air, but growth is stimulated by the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>; hence, growth occurs in candle jars and in anaerobe jars fitted with cold Deoxy catalyst (Oxoid) in an atmosphere initially consisting of 90% (vol/vol) H<sub>2</sub> and 10% (vol/vol) CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On sucrose-containing medium the colonies are easily removed but coherent.</s><s>They are transparent and 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation.</s><s>As with other muttons streptococci, a less frequent colony form is produced, which is vivid white, less than 1 mm in diameter, erose, crumbly, and easily removed from the medium with a loop.</s><s>The transparent forms always give rise to the two colony types, but the vivid white forms retain their original colonial morphology despite repeated streaking onto fresh medium.</s><s>Strains produce greening of horse blood agar plates whether they are grown anaerobically or in candle jars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics.</s><s>The strains examined all give similar results in the tests which we performed.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetyl glucosamine, amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, galactose, maltose, sucrose, and trehalose; sorbitol is fermented slowly.</s><s>The terminal pH in sucrose broth varies from 4.6 to 4.9.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, arabinose, glycerol, inositol, melezitose, melibiose, ribose, sorbose, xylitol, or xylose.</s><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Dextran is produced from sucrose, and catalase is not produced; H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> is not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing 10 and 40% (wt/vol) bile but not in the presence of 6.5% (wt/vol) NaCl, at 45°C, or at pH 9.6.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed; starch and blue dextran are weakly hydrolyzed, and arginine is not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serotype c antigen.</s><s>The strains of <i>S. mutans</i>, <i>S . macancae</i>, and <i>S. ferus</i> all contain an antigen which forms a precipitin line of identity when a bacterial pellet one of the strains is tested in an immunodiffusion assay with typing sera raised against <i>S. mutans</i> (three different sera) or strain 25-1<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>No other precipitin lines are observed with a wide range of antiserum concentrations and varying amounts of bacterial pellet.</s><s>This antigen can be extracted from the bacteria by the Lancefield, Rantz-Randall, and hot phenolwater procedures and has been purified by ion-exchange chromatography on diethylaminoethyl-Trisacryl.</s><s>The serotype c antigen elutes at approximately 0.1 M NaCl.</s><s>Glucose and rhamnose are the major sugars detected after hydrolysis of the antigen, as previously found for <i>S . mutans</i>, although a trace of galactose also is found.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA composition.</s><s>The G+C contents of three of the new isolates (strains H1569, H1762, and 25-1<sup>T</sup>) are 35 and 36 mol%, respectively.</s><s>The values found for <i>S. muttons</i> NCTC 10449<sup>T</sup> and <i>S. rattus</i> Fitzgerald FAIT are 37 and 42 mol%. respectively; these values are almost identical to the values found by other workers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intraoral distribution.</s><s>The strains of <i>S. macaque</i> were isolated primarily from dental plaque samples, indicating that tooth surfaces are the preferred habitat of these organisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>SDS-PAGE of cell extracts.</s><s>The SDS-PAGE profiles of the 11 strains of <i>S. macacae</i> were identical and were distinct from the profiles of the other Streptococcus species examined.</s><s>Figure 2 shows only the difference between the three streptococcal species bearing the serotype c polysaccharide antigen, as these species may be confused if serotyping is used to identify isolates. <i>S. macacae</i>, <i>S . mutans</i>, and <i>S. ferus</i> each has a characteristic protein profile that is distinctly different from the profiles of all other mutans streptococci.</s></p></content></protolog>