<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2227" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2227" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2227" rank="species">Xanthomonas pisi</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas pisi</i> (ex Goto and Okabe 1958) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. pisi</i> is the same as that of the genus. Isolated from diseased <i>Pisum sativum</i> (Fabaceae).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. pisi</i> has a distinct SDS-PAGE protein profile (48).</s><s>It can be distinguished from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, N-acetyh-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, cellobiose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-psicose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, monomethylsuccinate, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, DL-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, D-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glycerol, DL-α-glycerolphosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, and glucose 6-phosphate and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates acetic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, and α-ketovaleric acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 64.6 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 847 (= NCPPB 762 = ICMP 570).</s></p></content></protolog>