<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9521_nm.14672" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14672" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14672" rank="species">Blochmannia herculeanus</organism><reference id="rid.9521"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sauer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gadau</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hölldobler</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Systematic relationships and cospeciation of bacterial endosymbionts and their carpenter ant host species: proposal of the new taxon Candidatus Blochmannia gen. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1877</fpage><lpage>1886</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Candidatus</i> Blochmannia herculeanus sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Candidatus</i> Blochmannia herculeanus (Bloch.man'ni.a' N.L. fem. n. referring to F. Blochmann, a German zoologist who provided the first description of the endosymbiotic bacteria in ants as early as 1887; her'cu.lea.nus. N.L. masc. adj.)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Candidatus</i> Blochmannia comprises Gram-negative rod-shaped bacteria which are found in the cytoplasm of specialized cells, so-called mycetocytes, intercalated between midgut epithelial cells or in oocytes of ants of the subfamily <i>Formicinae</i>.</s><s>Bacterial cells are non-sporulating and divide by septation.</s><s>They are 0.5–1.5 μm in width and have a quite variable length between 12 and 30 μm.</s><s>On the basis of the 16S rDNA sequences, these bacteria belong to the γ-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The 16S RNA encoding rrs genes are not located upstream of the 23S RNA genes.</s><s>Cospeciation with their host animals indicates that transmission of the bacteria generally occurs vertically.</s><s>For the symbionts of the ant species <i>C. floridanus</i>, <i>C. rufipes</i> and <i>C. ligniperdus</i> the identification of unique regions within the 16S rDNA allowed their unequivocal identification by <i>in situ</i> hybridization in their respective host organisms.</s><s>On the basis of these unique sequences we propose the symbionts of these three species to be designated as follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>[(<i>Proteobacteria</i>) NC; NAS (GenBank no. X92550), oligonucleotide sequence complementary to a unique region of the 16S rRNA gene 5'-GTGGGCTATTACCCCG-3'; S (<i>Camponotus herculeanus</i>, mycetocytes)] (Schröder <i>et al</i>., 1996).</s></p></content></protolog>