<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3544_nm.3905" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3905" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3905" rank="species">Clostridium caminithermale</organism><reference id="rid.3544"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brisbarre</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cueff</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cilia</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ravot</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium caminithermale sp. nov., a slightly halophilic and moderately thermophilic bacterium isolated from an Atlantic deep-sea hydrothermal chimney.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1043</fpage><lpage>1049</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02471-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892124</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium caminithermale</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium caminithermale</em> (ca.mi.ni.ther.ma′le. L. n. <em>caminus</em> chimney; L. pl. n. <em>thermae</em> hot springs; N.L. neut. adj. <em>caminithermale</em> of a thermal chimney, describing the site of sampling).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic rods, 0·4–0·5×5–9 μm, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by a few laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Electron microscopy of sections of cells exhibits a thick, layered, Gram-positive-type cell wall composed of three dense layers (two thick layers and a middle thinner layer) separated by two less dense spaces.</s><s>Grows at 20–58 °C (optimum 45 °C).</s><s>Grows in the presence of sea salt at 12–55 g l<sup>−1</sup> (optimum 30 g l<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 6·6, but growth occurs between pH 5·8 and 8·2.</s><s>Heterotrophic.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth on sugars.</s><s>Ferments yeast extract, peptone, Bio-trypticase and Casamino acids into a mixture of volatile fatty acids.</s><s>Fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, maltose, mannose and ribose are fermented primarily into acetate, butyrate, propionate and H<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Succinate, fumarate and pyruvate are also fermented.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, starch, sucrose, xylose, dulcitol, sorbitol, lactate, formate, acetate, propionate and H<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The following amino acids are used as energy sources in the presence of yeast extract and peptone (0·5 g l<sup>−1</sup>): arginine, cysteine, glycine, proline and tyrosine (oxidized to acetate); glutamic acid (to propionate); histidine (to propionate and formate); isoleucine (to methyl 2-butyrate); leucine (to isovalerate); lysine (to acetate and butyrate); and methionine (to propionate and acetate).</s><s>The following amino acids are not used: alanine, asparagine, aspartic acid, glutamine, phenylalanine, serine, threonine, tryptophan and valine.</s><s>Performs the Stickland reaction, using isoleucine as electron donor and methionine or betaine as electron acceptors.</s><s>Does not use elemental sulfur, sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, nitrate or nitrite as an electron acceptors.</s><s>The following tests were negative: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, Simmons' citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole and acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer reaction).</s><s>Adverse effects on animals and humans are not known.</s><s>Because of the ability to degrade amino acids and peptides, the possibility of harmful effects cannot be excluded.</s><s>Cautious handling and autoclaving of cultures before disposal is recommended.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 33·1 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain DVird3<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15212<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107654<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an Atlantic Ocean hydrothermal chimney.</s></p></content></protolog>