<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5626_nm.3883" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3883" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3883" rank="species">Clostridium acetobutylicum</organism><reference id="rid.5626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Keis</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shaheen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Clostridium acetobutylicum and Clostridium beijerinckii, and descriptions of Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum sp. nov. and Clostridium saccharobutylicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760952</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Clostridium acetobutylicum</i> McCoy et al. 1926</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>Clostridium acetobutylicum</i> in Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology (Cato et al., 1986) is based on the description by Smith &#x0026; Hobbs (1974) and Holdeman et al. (1977). Smith &#x0026; Hobbs (1974) group this species within Group II of the genus <i>Clostridium</i>, on the basis of its ability to hydrolyse gelatin. However, Holdeman et al. (1977) describe this species as being unable to hydrolyse gelatin, as in Bergey's Manual.We found that all seven representative strains of <i>C. acetobutylicum</i> tested positive for gelatin liquefaction. This is in agreement not only with the formal description of <i>C. acetobutylicum</i> by McCoy et al. (1926), but also with the description given in the patent, issued to Weizmann (1919), describing the original acetone-butanol fermentation process. The description of <i>C. acetobutylicum</i> should therefore be emended accordingly. Furthermore, we found that amygdalin and raffinose were fermented by <i>C. acetobutylicum</i>. This is contrary to the description given in Bergey's Manual but is in agreement with the formal description given by McCoy et al. (1926). In addition, we found that <i>C. acetobutylicum</i> was able to ferment saccharose and pectin but was able to ferment turanose only weakly.</s></p></content></protolog>