<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6529_nm.4570" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4570" rank="order">Halanaerobiales</organism><reference id="rid.6529"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhilina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boulygina</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zavarzin</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The taxonomic status of the fermentative halophilic anaerobic bacteria: description of Haloanaerobiales ord. nov., Halobacteroidaceae fam. nov., Orenia gen. nov. and further taxonomic rearrangements at the genus and species level.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>185</fpage><lpage>199</lpage><source id="225">Anaerobe</source><issn>1075-9964</issn><essn>1095-8274</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/anae.1995.1018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16887527</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloanaerobiales</i> ord. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloanaerobiales</i> (Ha. lo.an.ae.ro'.bi.รก.les. <i>Haloanaerobiaceae</i> type family of the order: -<i>ales</i> ending to denote an order: <i>Haloanaerobiales</i> the <i>Haloanaerobiaceae</i> order)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods with Gram-negative cell wall type.</s><s>Halophilic.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>A member of the phylogenetically defined <i>Clostridium/Bacillus</i> subphylum of Gram-postive <i>Bacteria</i>.</s><s>The order can be differentiated from other major clusters of this subphylum by a set of 16s rDNA signature nucleotides.</s><s>G+C content of DNA ranges from 27-40 mol%.</s><s>The obvious bifurcation of the branching pattern of members of the order <i>Haloanaerobiales</i>, with two major clusters of similar phylogenetic depth, can be interpreted in two ways.</s><s>Firstly, if one maintains a single family, the two major clusters could be elevated to two families.</s><s>Based on the distinct differences in 16S rDNA percent similarity and the presence of a high number of signature nucleotides, we feel that the separation of the family into two families <i>Haloanaerobiaceae</i> and <i>Halobacteroidaceae</i> is justified.</s><s>Although we are aware of the lack of multiple phenotypic characters which would be helpful in supporting this conclusion, the lack of spore formation is observed in all members of <i>Haloanaerobiaceae</i>, while the majority of members of <i>Halobacteroidaceae</i> are spore formers (Table 1).</s><s>The present lack of comprehensive comparative studies of physiological and chemotaxonomic properties involving all species in parallel leaves an incomplete data set.</s><s>Considering the phylogenetic distinctness of these lineages one can expect greater phenotypic differences to exist.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type family of the order is <i>Haloanaerobiaceae</i>.</s><s>The original description of this family, based on the analysis of two species of two genera, still holds except for an extension of the range of G+C content.</s><s>Gram-negative rods, non-motile or motile by means of peritrichous flagella, non spore-forming, chemoorganotrophs, obligate anaerobes, halophilic, growing optimally at NaCl concentrations of ~10-15%.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 27-40%.</s><s>Distinct genomic properties are present in the 16S rDNA primary and secondary structure, defined by a set of signature nucleotides.</s><s>The type genus of the family <i>Haloanaerbium</i> (Zeikus et al. [13]).</s><s>Additional genera are <i>Halocella</i> and <i>Halothermothrix</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>