<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4407_nm.5584" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5584" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5584" rank="species">Leuconostoc kimchii</organism><reference id="rid.4407"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>H.U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leuconostoc kimchii sp. nov., a new species from kimchi.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1915</fpage><lpage>1919</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034505</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leuconostoc kimchii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leuconostoc kimchii</i> (kim'chi.i. M.L. gen. <i>kimchii</i> of kimchi, a traditional Korean food made by fermentation of Chinese cabbage)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical but similar to coccobacilli and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-motile and nonspore-forming cells are catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows at 15 and 37 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 7% NaCl but not 10% NaCl.</s><s>Produces dextran from sucrose and gas from glucose.</s><s>More than 95% of the lactate produced is as the d-(-) isomer.</s><s>Arginine is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, gluconate, lactose, mannitol, ribose, salicin, trehalose, turanose, fructose, maltose, mannose and sucrose, but not from melezitose, sorbitol, starch, rhamnose, inulin, melibiose, raffinose or xylose.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated and cyclopropane-ring acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+­C content of the DNA of the type strain is 37 mol%.</s><s>The type and only strain, IH25<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the Korean Collection for Type Cultures as KCTC 2386<sup>T</sup> and the culture collection of the Institute of Microbiology, Seoul National University as IMSNU 11154<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>