<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2229_nm.9469" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9469" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9469" rank="species">Bacteroides massiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.2229"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fenner</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides massiliensis sp. nov., isolated from blood culture of a newborn.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1335</fpage><lpage>1337</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63350-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879278</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacteroides massiliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacteroides massiliensis</em> (mas.si.li.en′sis. L. adj. <em>massiliensis</em> of Massilia, the ancient Greek and Roman name for Marseille, France, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative, straight rods that are 0·8–1·4 μm wide and 2·1–3·9 μm long, and which usually occur singly.</s><s>Surface colonies on sheep blood agar plates after 2 days are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, white–greyish, translucent, raised and convex.</s><s>No haemolysis on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 37 °C, but growth is observed at 25–42 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of bile and is resistant to 5 μg vancomycin ml<sup>−1</sup>, 1000 μg kanamycin ml<sup>−1</sup> and 10 μg colistin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Indole-negative and catalase-negative.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Using API ID 32A (bioMérieux), activities of <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase or serine arylamidase.</s><s>The following sugars are fermented: starch, aesculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, saccharose and sucrose.</s><s>Fermentation of sorbitol is variable.</s><s>The following sugars are not fermented: amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, trehalose, xylitol and xylose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 49 mol%.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-branched C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from human blood culture, is B84634<sup>T</sup>; it has been deposited in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur, Paris, France, as CIP 107942<sup>T</sup> and in the Collection of the University of Göteborg, Sweden, as CCUG 48901<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>