<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10790_nm.17897" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17897" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17897" rank="species">Kaistia terrae</organism><reference id="rid.10790"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anandham</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kaistia terrae sp. nov., isolated from a wetland in Korea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>949</fpage><lpage>952</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011924-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661503</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kaistia terrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kaistia terrae</em> (ter′rae. L. gen. n. <em>terrae</em> of the soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, aerobic, non-motile, short rods, 0.8–0.9 μm in width and 1.2–1.4 μm in length.</s><s>Cells grow on R2A, NA, TSA and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies on R2A at 30 °C are ivory-coloured, convex and round with clear margins.</s><s>Grows at 5–35 °C (optimum, 30 °C), but not at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–8.0 (optimum, 7.0).</s><s>Able to grow without NaCl added to the medium and does not tolerate salt levels above 1 %.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically on R2A.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase tests.</s><s>Xanthine is hydrolysed, but casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, DNA, hypoxanthine, pectin, starch, Tween 80 and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for urease, aesculin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20NE test strip).</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, glycogen, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose and d-sorbitol, weakly assimilates l-alanine, lactic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate, and does not assimilate potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-proline (API 20NE and API ID 32GN test strips).</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM test strip): alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities: esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (51.2 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (25.0 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (12.9 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (10.8 %) (&#x003E;10 % of the total fatty acids).</s><s>Ubiquinone-10 is the predominant quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5YN7-3<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12910<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21341<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wetland soil of Yongneup, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>