<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1065_nm.5532" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5532" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5532" rank="species">Enterococcus columbae</organism><reference id="rid.1065"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ceyssens</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodrigues</surname><given-names>U.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus columbae, a species from pigeon intestines.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>247</fpage><lpage>252</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2272492</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus columbae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(co.lumb'ae. L. n. <i>columba</i> pigeon; gen. s. n. <i>columbae</i> of pigeons)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains grew to fairly large, non-haemolytie, enterococcal-like colonies on blood agar: 2-3 mm in diameter, regular, somewhat mucoid, unpigmented and semi-opaque.</s><s>In broth they formed deposits with a turbid supernatant and they appeared as short chains composed of 2 to 4 Gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Growth on agar plates was better when incubation at 35-37°C was performed in 3-10% CO<sub>2</sub> than in air.</s><s>Their requirement for CO<sub>2</sub> was not absolute.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains were catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>They failed to grow on Slanetz-Bartley Medium.</s><s>They appeared to be resistant to 40% bile and were able to grow on Bile Aesculin agar when incubated in 3 to 10% CO<sub>2</sub> but not in air, and they all failed to grow in broth with 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>They grew on Edward's Medium and hydrolysed aesculin on this medium.</s><s>On Mitis-Salivarius agar they formed small colonies or showed</s></p><p class="description"><s>partly inhibited growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The 9 strains were all positive in the Voges Proskauer reaction and produced α-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase and leucine-arylamidase.</s><s>They did not hydrolyse arginine and hippurate and also their β-ghicuronidase and pyrrohdonylarylamidase reactions were negative.</s><s>Acid productionfrom carbohydrates was positive with α-arabinose, mannitol, ribose, D-xylose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, sorbitol, amethyl-D-glucoside, N-acetyi glucosamine, arbutine, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, saccharose, trehalose, inulin, D-raffinose,</s></p><p class="description"><s>amidon and β-gentiobiose.</s><s>Negative carbohydrate reactions were noted with erythritol, D-arabinose, L-Iyxose, adonitol, glycerol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, glycogen, gluconate and 5-ketoghicohate.</s><s>Variable results were obtained with β-galactosidase (strains P100, P52, d23 and STR 487: positive), rhamnose (only d23 and P107 positive), amygdaline (strains 100, P52, d23 and P8: positive), lactose (only P26 and P1 negative), melezirose (only STR 345 positive), D-tagatose (only STR345, P8 and d23 positive), D-turanose (only STR345 weakly positive), xylitol (only strain P52 positive), D-arabitol (only STR 345, P100 and P107 negative) and 2-ketogluconate (only STR 487 positive).</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains reacted with the <i>Streptococcus</i> group A, B, C, D, G and F antisera in coagglutination tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 38.2 mol% G + C (as determined by melting temperature).</s><s>Habitat: intestines of pigeons.</s><s>The type strain is STR 345 (NCIMB 13013) and has been deposited at The National Collections of Industrial and Marine Bacteria, Torry Research Station,</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aberdeen, Scotland.</s></p></content></protolog>