<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.49_nm.9156" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9156" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6677" rank="species">Amycolata alni</organism><reference id="rid.49"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobritsa</surname><given-names>S.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taptykova</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of Actinomycete, Amycolata alni</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>72</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-1-72</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolata alni</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolata alni</i> (al'ni. L.adj. <i>alni</i>, of Alnus, alder, referring to the isolation of the type strain and some other strains from alder associations)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate and aerial mycelia are formed; both fragment into rod-shaped and oval elements.</s><s>The aerial mycelium (0.7 to 1.0 μm wide) is white to cream colored, and the vegetative mycelium is orange to brown.</s><s>Chains of spores (up to 1.5 μm in diameter) are abundantly formed on the aerial hyphae.</s><s>The vegetative hyphae are characterized by pronounced pleomorphisms, forming thickenings up to 2 μm in diameter, as well as cells of a polygonal shape and their conglomerates.</s><s>Formation of swollen hyphal segments (up to 2.5 μm in diameter and up to 10 μm long) with transverse and longitudinal septa is a characteristic trait.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate reductase, phosphatase, and urease are produced by most strains.</s><s>Adenine, esculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, tyrosine, and xanthine are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Allantoin, casein, and cellulose are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, formate, fumarate, α-ketoglutarate, lactate, malate, maleate, propionate, pyruvate, sebacate , succinate, and trans-aconitate are utilized.</s><s>Produces acid from and grows on adonitol, L-arabinose , meso-erythritol, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, D-maltose, D-mannitol, L-ribose, D-salicin, D-sorbitol, DL-sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-arabinose, but growth is variable.</s><s>No acid is formed from n-cellobiose, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-lactose, D-mannose, melibiose, L-rhamnose, and D-sorbose.</s><s>Grows on D-gluconate but not on D-glucuronate as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Assimilates as nitrogen sources asparagine , glutamine, ornithine, arginine, leucine , proline , and histidine.</s><s>Very weak growth on media containing other amino acids as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Moderate growth on water agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tolerates 7% NaCl, 0.001% phenol, and 0.01% thymol.</s><s>Susceptible to the following antibiotics: monomycin (8 μg/ml), roseofungin (10 μg/ml), neomycin (4 μg/ml), fucidin (10 μg/ml), streptomycin (4 μg/ml), chloramphenicol(32 μg/ml), gentamicin (4 μg/ml), rifampin (0.125 μg/ml), kanamycin (16 μg/ml), and vancomycin (0.5 μg/ml).</s><s>In contrast to <i>Amycolata autotrophica</i>, susceptible to nalidixic acid (64 kg/ml), novobiocin (0.25 μg/ml), and tetracycline (1 μglml) but resistant to ampicillin (1 to 16 μg/ml), benzylpenicillin (0.5 to 10 μg/ml), carbenicillin (1 to 10 μg/ml), ristomycin (0.05 μg/ml), tobramycin (5 μg/ml), and vancomycin (0.25 μg/ml).</s><s>No growth in lysozyme broth (50 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fatty acids are the following saturated branched-chain acids of the iso and anteiso types: iso-16:O acid (up to 40%) and anteiso-17:O acid (up to 20%). 10- methyl-17:O and 10-methyl-18:O acids, as well as tuberculostearic acid (traces), are also present.</s><s>The principal menaquinone component is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72 to 74 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from root nodules and rhizospheres of alders (<i>Alnus glutinosa</i> [L.] Gaertn. and <i>Alnus incana</i> [L.] Moench.), as well as from other sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 3LS (= VKM Ac-901).</s></p></content></protolog>