<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8798_nm.13725" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13725" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13725" rank="species">Halosarcina pallida</organism><reference id="rid.8798"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Savage</surname><given-names>K.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elshahed</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halosarcina pallida gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon from a low-salt, sulfide-rich spring.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>856</fpage><lpage>860</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65398-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398182</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halosarcina pallida</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halosarcina pallida</em> (pal′li.da. L. fem. adj. <em>pallida</em> pale).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are small (0.2 mm), pink, translucent, round and convex with an entire margin.</s><s>Grows at 1.7–4.3 M NaCl, with optimal growth at 3.1 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 25–45 °C, with optimal growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Requires a minimum of 1 mM Mg<sup>2+</sup> for growth.</s><s>Grows at pH values ranging from 5 to at least 8.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.5.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically with nitrate, sulfate, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, DMSO or trimethylamine oxide.</s><s>Does not ferment arginine.</s><s>Capable of using single-carbon substrates.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, lactate, malic acid, fumaric acid, sucrose, l-glutamic acid, glucose, fructose, succinate, lactose, dl-aspartic acid, pyruvate, glycine, galactose, sorbitol, glycerol, starch, l-histidine, trehalose, dl-norleucine, d-glucuronic acid, dl-phenylalanine, aesculin and salicin, but not l-arginine, l-alanine, sodium citrate, xylose, mannitol, l-threonine, dulcitol, dextrin, l-methionine, 3,3-dimethylglutaric acid or l-tyrosine.</s><s>Produces acid when grown on sucrose, glucose, starch, fructose, lactose, galactose, sorbitol and glycerol, but not l-arginine, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, dl-aspartic acid, glycine, acetate, lactate, malic acid, fumaric acid, citrate, succinate or pyruvate.</s><s>Able to utilize complex carbon sources such as yeast extract and Casamino acids.</s><s>Indole is produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, casein, gelatin or Tween 80.</s><s>Sensitive to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin, rifampacin and aphidicolin.</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, nalidixic acid, kanamycin, gentamicin and trimethoprim.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BZ256<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 4017<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14848<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Zodletone Spring in south-western Oklahoma, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>