<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7030_nm.1480" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1480" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1480" rank="species">Bosea eneae</organism><reference id="rid.7030"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>La Scola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bosea eneae sp. nov., Bosea massiliensis sp. nov. and Bosea vestrisii sp. nov., isolated from hospital water supplies, and emendation of the genus Bosea (Das et al. 1996).</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02127-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656146</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bosea eneae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bosea eneae</em> (e.ne′ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>eneae</em> of Enea, to honour Maryse Enea, a technician in the Unité des Rickettsies, for her many contributions to the isolation of obligate intracellular bacteria, especially <em>Rickettsiaceae</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits all of the characteristics of the genus, growing on MacConkey's agar and Columbia agar with 5 % sheep blood, in co-cultivation with <em>Acanthamoeba polyphaga</em> in Page's amoebal saline, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or oxidize thiosulphate, and gives variable reactions for the assimilation of gluconate and adipate.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics of use in differentiating this species from other species of <em>Bosea</em> are given in Table 2.</s><s>The whole-cell fatty acids profile of the species is given in Table I (supplementary data).</s><s>The antimicrobial susceptibility profile of the species is given in Table II (supplementary data) and is characterized only by the low MIC value for doxycycline.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 67·9–69 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the water supply of the La Timone Hospital Centre (Marseilles, France).</s><s>The type strain of <em>Bosea eneae</em> is 34614<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106338<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 43111<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>