<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6132_nm.10259" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10259" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10259" rank="species">Pedobacter roseus</organism><reference id="rid.6132"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter roseus sp. nov., isolated from a hypertrophic pond, and emended description of the genus Pedobacter</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1831</fpage><lpage>1836</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64045-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902016</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter roseus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter roseus</em> (ro.se′us. L. masc. adj. <em>roseus</em> rose-coloured, pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, obligately aerobic, short rods, approximately 0.5–0.7 μm wide and 0.8–1.1 μm long.</s><s>Cells are non-motile with no flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar after 2 days are pink and round (1–4.5 mm in diameter), convex and smooth and with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs between 5 and 33 °C and pH 6 and 8; optimal temperature and pH for growth are 25–30 °C and pH 7, respectively.</s><s>Grows well without NaCl, and growth occurs in the presence of up to 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows on R2A medium, nutrient medium, TSA medium and MacConkey's medium.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, gelatinase and amylase activities; negative for heparinase and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; negative for indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from dl-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, aesculin, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, sucrose, inulin, d-raffinose, starch, gentiobiose and d-turanose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, d-melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes l-rhamnose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glycogen, inulin, d-raffinose, l-xylose, l-glutamic acid, pyruvate, sodium succinate, l-arabinose, trehalose, d-glucose, d-lactose, salicin, sucrose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose as sole carbon sources, but not l-arginine, ribose, sorbitol, mannitol, gluconate, l-aspartic acid, l-proline, inositol, l-lysine, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citric acid or phenylacetate.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5) and tetracycline (30), but resistant to penicillin (10), ampicillin (10), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41.3 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid is MK-7 and sphingolipids are present.</s><s>Fatty acids comprising &#x003E;1 % of the total are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (37.0 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (24.5 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (11.3 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (7.6 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2.7 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.9 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1.6 %), unknown ECL (equivalent chain length) 13.565 (1.6 %), unknown ECL 16.582 (1.5 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (1.3 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B (1.1 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-GP80<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42272<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13399<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hypertrophic pond in Seoul, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>