<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1505_nm.4178" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4178" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4178" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus hydrogenalis</organism><reference id="rid.1505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hashimoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Peptostreptococcus hydrogenalis sp. nov. from human fecal and vaginal flora.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>305</fpage><lpage>306</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-305</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus hydrogenalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus hydrogenalis</i> (hy.dro.ge.na'lis. chemical term hydrogen; L. suff. <i>-alis</i>, pertaining to; N. L. masc. adj. <i>hydrogenalis</i>, pertaining to hydrogen, because this organism produces hydrogen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, grampositive cocci (diameter, 0.7 to 1.8 μm) and occur in short chains or in masses.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar range from 0.5 to 2 mm in diameter and are not hemolytic.</s><s>The three strains which we studied do not produce coagulase or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Abundant hydrogen gas and weak acid (pH range, 5.6 to 6.0) are produced from PYG.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-(+)-rhamnose, D-(+)-xylose, maltose, D- (+)-mannose, D-(-)-mannitol, sucrose, D-(-)-fructose, D-(+)-cellobiose, or D-( +)-trehalose.</s><s>Indole and alkaline phosphatase are produced.</s><s>Catalase activity is weak or negative.</s><s>Pyrrolidone arylamidase (AMD) activity is positive.</s><s>The major metabolic products from prereduced PYG are butyrate and acetate. <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> has been isolated from human feces and vaginal discharge.</s><s>The pathogenicity of this organism is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNAs of the type strain and two other strains is 31 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain GIFU 7662 (= JCM 7635), which was isolated from human feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics useful for differentiating <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> from other species of peptostreptococci are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Positive alkaline phosphatase and pyrrolidone AMD activities and acid production from glucose are useful characteristics for differentiating this species from <i>P. asaccharolyticus</i>. <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> has week α-glucosidase, β-glucronidase, β-glucosidase, and β-galactosidase activities; the other two indole-positive species do not have these enzyme activities.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The oligopeptidase activities of <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> as determined by using a commercial API-ZYM kit (kindly supplied by Aska Pure Chemical Co., Tokyo, Japan) were distinct from those of <i>P. asaccharolyticus</i>. <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> and <i>P. asaccharolyticus</i> have the same aspartate-alanine AMD, serine-tryptophan AMD, lysine-lysine AMD, benzyl-cysteine AMD, and lysine-alanine AMD activities, but the aspartate-arginine AMD activity of <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> is positive and that of <i>P. asaccharolyticus</i> is negative or very weak (2).</s><s>Of the 20 amino acid AMD activities tested, <i>P. hydrogenalis</i> showed only pyrrolidone AMD activity, whereas <i>P. asaccharolyticus</i> was active on most of the substrates tested (2) but did not show pyrrolidone AMD activity.</s></p></content></protolog>