<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2331_nm.5228" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5228" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5228" rank="species">Marinococcus hispanicus</organism><reference id="rid.2331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Marquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruiz-Berraquera</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinococcus hispanicus, a new species of moderately halophilic Gram-positive cocci</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>165</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-165</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Marinococcus hispanicus</i> Marquez, Ventosa, and Ruiz-Berraquero sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Marinococcus hispanicus</i> (his. pa’ni.cus. L. adj . <i>hispanicus</i>, Spanish)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, spherical cells (diameter, 1.0 to 2.0 μm) occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads, or in clumps.</s><s>Nonmotile and nonsporing.</s><s>Colonies are round and smooth and form a reddish orange, nondiffusible pigment.</s><s>Broth cultures are uniformly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal salt concentration for growth is 10% (wt/vol) at 37°C; the organism grows at salt concentrations between 0.5 and 25% (wt/vol).</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 15 to 37°C and pH 5 to 9; optimal growth occurs at 37°C and pH 7.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, galactose, glycerol, D-glucose, and D-mannitol; acid is not produced from arabinose, lactose, D-trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolyzed; casein, Tween 80, and tyrosine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Voges-Proskauer, indole, Simmons citrate, phenylalanine deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, arginine, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-mannose, L-raffinose, L-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: amygdalin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-galactosamine, lactose, maltose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, ethanol, propanol, D-sorbitol, N-acetylglucosamine, DL-α-aminobutyrate, δ-aminovalerate, benzoate, butyrate, caprylate, lactate, DL-malate, oxalate, propionate, quinate, D-saccharate, succinate, and D-tartrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-Glutamine is used as a sole source of carbon, nitrogen, and energy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources: L-allantoin, DL-arginine, L-asparagine, aspartic acid, betaine, creatine, ethionine, phenylalanine, glycine, glutamic acid, L-histidine, L-leucine, DL-lysine, L-ornithine, putrescine, sarcosine, L-serine, L-threonine, and L-valine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other phenotypic features of this species are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition ranges from 45.6 to 49.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the meso-diaminopimelic acid type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major quinones are MK-8 and MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat is solar saltern and saline soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 5-82 (= ATCC 49259 = DSM 5352 = CCM 4148).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>The base composition of its DNA is 45.7 mol% G+C, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>