<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3581_nm.9931" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9931" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9931" rank="species">Gracilibacillus orientalis</organism><reference id="rid.3581"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carrasco</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yanfen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cowan</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus orientalis sp. nov., a novel moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake in Inner Mongolia, China</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>599</fpage><lpage>604</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63971-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilibacillus orientalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gracilibacillus orientalis</em> (o.ri.en.ta′lis. L. adj. <em>orientalis</em> eastern, bacterium inhabiting the East).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive rods, 0·7–0·9×2·0–10·0 μm.</s><s>Motile, spherical endospores are produced at a terminal position in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are 0·3–0·6 mm in diameter, cream, circular, opaque and entire on MH-10 medium after 2 days of cultivation.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing in a wide range (1–20 %, w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimal growth at 10 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 4–45 °C (optimal at 37 °C) and pH 5·0–9·0 (optimal at pH 7·5).</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, galactose, glycerol, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-xylose, maltose, d-trehalose and sucrose.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed; casein, Tween 80 and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, phenylalanine deaminase, Simmons citrate, arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Phosphatase test is positive.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, d-fucose, lactose, propanol, d-sorbitol and valerate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: d-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-melizitose, l-raffinose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, butanol, ethanol, methanol, benzoate, propionate and succinate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-arginine, aspartic acid, l-cysteine, phenylalanine, glutamic acid, dl-lysine, l-methionine, l-ornithine, l-threonine, tryptophan and l-serine.</s><s>Susceptible to bacitracin (10 U), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg) and rifampicin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), neomycin (10 μg), novobiocin (30 μg) and penicillin (10 U).</s><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid type.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, and a phospholipid and two amino phospholipids of unknown structure.</s><s>Additional characteristics of the strains are listed in Table 1.</s><s>Cellular fatty acid composition is given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is XH-63<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7326<sup>T</sup>=AS 1.4250<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7097<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt lake near Xilin Hot in Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p></content></protolog>