<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3448_nm.6312" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6312" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6312" rank="subspecies">Mycobacterium tuberculosis caprae</organism><reference id="rid.3448"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aranaz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liébana</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gómez-Mampaso</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Galán</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cousins</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ortega</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blázquez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baquero</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Súarez</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium tuberculosis subsp. caprae subsp. nov.: a taxonomic study of a new member of the Mycobacterium tuberculosis complex isolated from goats in Spain.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1263</fpage><lpage>1273</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1263</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425790</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</i> subsp. <i>caprae</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</i> subsp. <i>caprae</i> (ca'p.rae. L. fem. gen. n. <i>caprae</i> referring to <i>capra</i>, the L. fem. n. for goat, the host animal from which the bacteria are isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains can be isolated from the lymph nodes and lungs of tuberculous goats.</s><s>These organisms are acid-alcohol-fast, non-spore forming, non-motile bacilli with weak cording formation.</s><s>Growth is enhanced with pyruvate and usually occurs after 4-6 weeks incubation at 36 °C.</s><s>Colonies are smooth and nonchromogenic.</s><s>Strains are negative for niacin accumulation and nitrate reduction, sensitive to PZA (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), resistant to 1 and 2 μg TCH ml<sup>-1</sup>, but sensitive to 5 and 10 μg TCH ml<sup>-1</sup> They weakly hydrolyse Tween 80 (10 d) and do not hydrolyse arylsulphatase (3 and 14 d).</s><s>Other enzymic activities include acid and alkaline phosphatases and β-glucosidase.</s><s>Catalase test is positive at room temperature and negative at 68 °C.</s><s>The key biochemical features that separate this subspecies from the previously established taxa within the <i>M. tuberculosis</i> complex are as follows: niacin accumulation, nitrate reduction and TCH susceptibility differentiate the new taxon from <i>M. tuberculosis</i>; PZA susceptibility differentiates it from <i>M. bovis</i> and <i>M. bovis</i> BCG; resistance to 1 μg TCH ml<sup>-1</sup> differentiates it from <i>M. africanum</i>; and niacin accumulation differentiates it from <i>M. microti</i>.</s><s>The sequence of the 16s rRNA and the GLC profile are characteristic of all members of the <i>M. tuberculosis</i> complex.</s><s>All isolates contain the sequences IS6110, IS1081 and MPB70 and lack the <i>mtp40</i> element.</s><s>The strains present a special combination of gene polymorphisms: the <i>pncA</i> gene contains CAC (His) at codon 57; codon 463 of the <i>katG</i> gene, CTG, gives a Leu; nucleotide 285 of the <i>oxyR</i> pseudogene is an adenine; and codon 95 of the <i>gyrA</i> gene displays an ACC (Thr).</s><s>The DVR-spoligotyping and RFLP patterns are unique.</s><s>The type strain is gM-1<sup>T</sup> (= CIP 105776<sup>T</sup>), which has the characteristics described for the taxon.</s></p></content></protolog>