<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1007_nm.8382" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8382" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8382" rank="species">Leptotrichia trevisanii</organism><reference id="rid.1007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tee</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Midolo</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kerr</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteremia due to Leptotrichia trevisanii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>765</fpage><lpage>769</lpage><source id="159">European Journal of Clinical Microbiology &#x0026; Infectious Diseases : Official Publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis</abbrev><issn>0934-9723</issn><essn>1435-4373</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11783691</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leptotrichia trevisanii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leptotrichia trevisanii</i> (tre.vi.san.i.i, L. gen. n. trevisanii) is derived from V. Trevisan, who proposed the name for this genus in 1879.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is characterised by long, fusiform, nonmotile, Gram stain negative bacilli that are 0.8–0.9 µm wide and 6–13 µm long with tapered ends.</s><s>Many cells are slightly curved.</s><s>Cells are arranged in pairs and chains and, where they join, the ends are flattened.</s><s>Isolates are non-spore forming, catalase positive, indole negative and oxidase negative.</s><s>They are negative for urease, negative for hydrolysis of the pNP-sugars α-D-arabinoside, α-D-galactoside and α-L-fucoside and are unable to hydrolyse oNP-beta-D-galactoside.</s><s>They are positive for hydrolysis of pNP derivatives of α-D-glucoside, β-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosamine and pNP-phosphate.</s><s>The organism is unable to hydrolyse the napthylamide derivatives of leucyl-glycine, glycine, proline, serine and pyrrollidone, but is able to hydrolyse arginine and phenylalanine derivatives (RapID ANA II test kit results).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Leptotrichia trevisanii</i> grows both anaerobically and under 5% CO<sub>2</sub> (in air) on subsequent culture on solid media.</s><s>It ferments glucose to produce lactic acid as the major organic end-product.</s><s>Mol% G+C of DNA is 29.7%.</s><s>On horse blood agar plates, colonies appeared smooth, grayish in color, low convex and erose edged; they showed a dark central spot with transillumination and grew to about 2 mm diameter after 5 days of incubation.</s><s>Older colonies showed a slightly convoluted surface.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Leptotrichia trevisanii</i> strain “Wee Tee” 1999 and has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700907.</s></p></content></protolog>