<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7633_nm.14057" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14057" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14057" rank="species">Phaeobacter arcticus</organism><reference id="rid.7633"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chi</surname><given-names>Z.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phaeobacter arcticus sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from the Arctic</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1384</fpage><lpage>1387</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65708-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523182</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phaeobacter arcticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phaeobacter arcticus</em> (arc′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>arcticus</em> northern, arctic, referring to the site from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, psychrophilic, motile rods, 0.3–0.5 μm×1.0–2.6 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, smooth, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Grows aerobically and produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–25 °C and pH 5.0–10.0, with optimum growth at 19–20 °C and approximately pH 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2–9 % (w/v) NaCl and no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Neither reduction of nitrate nor production of hydrogen sulfide occurs.</s><s>Negative for indole production and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Negative for utilization of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, urease, gelatinase, trypsin, caseinase, agarase, chitinase, amylase, lecithinase and citrate, and negative for acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Tests for alkaline phosphatase and esterase lipase (C8) are positive.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: maltose, glucose, glycerol, fructose, melezitose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, mannitol, gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and malate.</s><s>Produces acid only from glucose and glycerol.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: sucrose, lactose, galactose, trehalose, cellobiose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, inositol, succinate, capric acid, adipic acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>The main polar lipids present include phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and an unidentified aminolipid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (44.63 %), 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (18.10 %), an unknown fatty acid (ECL 11.799; 10.88 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (9.69 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6.75 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH (3.95 %), and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (2.30 %).</s><s>Ubiquinone-10 (Q10) is the principal isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 59.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 20188<sup>T</sup>(=CGMCC 1.6500<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14644<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediment of the Arctic Ocean (7 ° 00′ 24″ N 16 ° 59′ 37″ W) at a depth of 167 m.</s></p></content></protolog>