<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8628_nm.13764" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13764" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13764" rank="species">Pseudoxanthobacter soli</organism><reference id="rid.8628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>H.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hung</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoxanthobacter soli gen. nov., sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing alphaproteobacterium isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1571</fpage><lpage>1575</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65206-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599697</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoxanthobacter soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoxanthobacter soli</em> (so′li. L. neut. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive for oxidase, acetoin and catalase; shows aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Reproduction occurs by asymmetric division (budding) of the mother cell to produce a shorter daughter cell.</s><s>Growth is visible after 48 h incubation on NA at 30 °C.</s><s>Cells are 0.2×2.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard media at 37 °C are whitish, circular, smooth and convex with entire edges.</s><s>In glucose medium, acid and gas are not produced.</s><s>Grows at 10–37 °C but not at 42 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–10.0 (optimally at pH 7.0).</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain comprises C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (34.8 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo (28.2 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (25.4 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2.3 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2.3 %), C<sub>20 : 0</sub> (1.9 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (1.1 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.7 %), 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (0.5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.5 %), C<sub>20 : 2</sub><em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em> (0.3 %) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (0.2 %).</s><s>Shares the quinone system and polar lipids listed in the genus description.</s><s>Fixes nitrogen when grown in nitrogen-deficient media.</s><s>In addition, methanol, methylamine and thiosulphate are not utilized.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Non-fluorescent.</s><s>On the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991), the type strain utilizes d-ribose, d-xylose, 4-aminobutyrate, fumarate and l-malate but not l-arbutin, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, maltitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, suberate, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate or phenylacetate.</s><s>On the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991), l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) is hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, bis-pNP phenylphosphonate, bis-pNP phosphorylcholine, l-aniline pNA, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA and l-proline pNA.</s><s>No acids are produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (positive with the Biolog GN2 system): adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline and glycerol.</s><s>Weakly positive reactions are observed for d-alanine, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-aspartic acid and l-ornithine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon sources: dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis-</em>aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate and d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities: alkaline and acid phosphatases, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), myristate lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities: valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to cotrimoxazole, gentamicin, tetracycline, minocycline, rifampicin, norfloxacin, levofloxacin and nitrofurantoin but is resistant to penicillin, clindamycin, erythromycin, fusidic acid, plindamycin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, quinupristin-dalfopristin, coag(−) oxacillin and oxacillin.</s><s>Additional physiological features are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19599<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109513<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected at a regional agricultural research field station located in Kaohsiung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>