<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2222" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2222" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2222" rank="species">Xanthomonas hyacinthi</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas hyacinthi</i> (ex Wakker 1883) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. hyacinthi</i> is the same as that of the genus. Strains of this species cause wilting disease in <i>Hyacinthus orientalis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. hyacinthi</i> strains have very distinct SDS-PAGE protein and FAME profiles (48, 60).</s><s>This species can be distinguished from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, maltose, D-psicose, sucrose, D-trehalose, monomethylsuccinate, β-hydroxybutyric acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, glycerol, glucose 1-phosphate, and glucose 6-phosphate and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, L-fucose, α-D-lactose, lactulose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, acetic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, and thymidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 69.2 to 69.3 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 739 (= NCPPB 599 = ICMP 189 = ATCC 19314 =</s></p><p class="description"><s>CFBP 1156).</s></p></content></protolog>