<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8731_nm.13661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13661" rank="species">Thalassospira tepidiphila</organism><reference id="rid.8731"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kodama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stiknowati</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassospira tepidiphila sp. nov., a polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-degrading bacterium isolated from seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>711</fpage><lpage>715</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65476-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassospira tepidiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassospira tepidiphila</em> (te.pi.di.phi′la. L. adj. <em>tepidus</em> lukewarm; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>tepidiphila</em> lukewarm-loving, mesophilic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, vibrioid to spiral, 0.17–0.33 μm wide and 0.9–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on MB Gelrite are smooth, convex, opaque and slightly yellow.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>In the API 20NE test, negative for glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and gelatinase activity.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth; optimum growth occurs with 3 % NaCl and the range is 2–14 %.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 43 °C (range, 8–45 °C) and the optimum pH is 7.0 (range, pH 5.0–10.0).</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic; nitrate is reduced to nitrite under anaerobic conditions, but nitrite is not reduced to nitrogen (nitrite is the final product of nitrate reduction).</s><s>In Biolog GN2 plates, the following are utilized as carbon sources: Tween 40, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid and glycerol.</s><s>The following are utilized weakly: glycogen, Tween 80, d-psicose, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid and l-alanyl glycine.</s><s>Degrades naphthalene, phenanthrene, dibenzothiophene and fluorene (mixed into crude oil).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω7c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.1±0.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1-1B<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14578<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18888<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from petroleum-contaminated seawater in a beach-simulation tank during a bioremediation experiment.</s></p></content></protolog>