<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11690_nm.19296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19296" rank="species">Paenibacillus hunanensis</organism><reference id="rid.11690"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus hunanensis sp. nov., isolated from rice seeds</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1266</fpage><lpage>1270</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012179-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667385</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus hunanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus hunanensis</em> (hu.nan.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>hunanensis</em> of Hunan, a province of China, from where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, motile, endospore-forming, rod-shaped bacteria (2.1–3.0×0.7–1.0 μm).</s><s>Capsules are observed by light microscopy and electron microscopy.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in sporangia and in a subterminal position in cells.</s><s>After 24–48 h growth on LB agar, colonies are up to 3–7 mm in diameter, circular and raised with entire edges and off-white to yellow.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C and the maximum growth temperature is 44 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth at pH 5.0–10.0.</s><s>Reactions for catalase, nitrate reduction and hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween 80, starch and casein are positive.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole production and Voges–Proskauer tests are positive.</s><s>Oxidase test is negative.</s><s>Grows at 0–5 % NaCl.</s><s>The culture medium becomes more alkaline during growth.</s><s>Dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, thymidine, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, pyruvic acid, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-psicose, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, glycerol, adenosine, inosine and uridine are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, when API CHB suspension medium is used, acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose; acid is produced weakly from glycerol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, inulin, turanose and gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FeL05<sup>T</sup> (=ACCC 10718<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.8907<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22170<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seeds of hybrid rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L.) sampled from Hunan Province, China.</s><s>Strains FeL11, Fek19 and Fek21 are additional strains of the species, isolated from the same source.</s></p></content></protolog>