<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4520_nm.9847" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9847" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9847" rank="species">Shewanella halifaxensis</organism><reference id="rid.4520"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manno</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leggiadro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Neil</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hawari</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella halifaxensis sp. nov., a novel obligately respiratory and denitrifying psychrophile.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>205</fpage><lpage>212</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63829-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403888</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella halifaxensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella halifaxensis</em> (ha.li.fax.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>halifaxensis</em> from Halifax, Nova Scotia, a harbour city near the sediment sampling site, Emerald Basin, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, straight or slightly curved rods generally 2–3 μm long and 0·55–0·65 μm in diameter.</s><s>Cells 6 μm long also occur.</s><s>Motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Biomass is slightly dark yellow and non-bioluminescent.</s><s>Psychrophilic growth at temperatures of 4–25 °C (optimum at 10 °C).</s><s>No growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup>-requiring and slightly halophilic (0·5–4 % NaCl; optimum at 2 %).</s><s>Growth at 4 % but not at 6 % NaCl.</s><s>MnO<sub>2</sub>, nitrate, nitrite, TMAO, thiosulfate and RDX are reduced.</s><s>No reduction of Fe<sup>3+</sup> (iron oxide or ferric citrate) or elemental sulfur.</s><s>Strong production of H<sub>2</sub>S from thiosulfate.</s><s>Anaerobic growth by reducing nitrate (to N<sub>2</sub>O), nitrite or TMAO, but not by fermentation.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitroreductase, chitinase, DNase, gelatinase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase; weakly positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40 and 80, proline arylamidase and arginine arylamidase; negative for caseinase, alginase, amylase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, histidine arylamidase, serine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycylarylamidase, leucine glycine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>On GN2 microplate (10 °C, 7 days), positive for metabolism of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, methylpyruvate, dl-lactic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, inosine, uridine and thymidine; weakly positive for Tweens 40 and 80, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, l-leucine and l-threonine; negative for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Weak aerobic acid formation from <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and glucose.</s><s>No anaerobic acid formation from <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, fructose, sucrose, galactose, lactose, mannose or glucose.</s><s>Peptone, yeast extract, Casamino acid, Tweens (20, 40 and 80), propionate, pyruvate, serine and proline are sole carbon and energy sources for growth. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, ribose, lactate, acetate, valerate, glutamate, formate and glycine are weak growth substrates.</s><s>Alanine, threonine, leucine, butyrate and glucose are poorly utilized.</s><s>Succinate, citrate, malate and fumarate are not utilized.</s><s>Choline and yeast extract are not required but improve growth on certain substrates.</s><s>Fatty acids iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (3 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (6 %), C<sub>14 : 1</sub> (1 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (12 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (20 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 (37 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9 (1 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 (7 %), C<sub>20 : 5</sub><em>ω</em>3 (7 %) and C<sub>20 : 4</sub><em>ω</em>3 (1 %) are produced.</s><s>Quinone composition is Q7 (28·1 %), Q8 (4·0 %), MK-7 (60·9 %) and MMK-7 (6·9 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HAW-EB4<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14093<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17350<sup>T</sup>), isolated from marine sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>