<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9713_nm.14864" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14864" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14864" rank="species">Parabacteroides gordonii</organism><reference id="rid.9713"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsunaga</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koshihara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komiya</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parabacteroides gordonii sp. nov., isolated from human blood cultures</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2843</fpage><lpage>2856</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010611-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628614</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parabacteroides gordonii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parabacteroides gordonii</em> (gor.do′ni.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>gordonii</em> of Gordon, named after the American biologist Jeffrey I. Gordon, in recognition of his many contributions to intestinal microbiology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods (0.8×1.7–2.5 μm).</s><s>Colonies on EG agar after 48 h of incubation at 37 °C under anaerobic conditions are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey to off-white–grey, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth.</s><s>Indole and urease are not produced.</s><s>Catalase is variable (activity is not detected in the API 20A test but is detected on EG agar).</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is not digested.</s><s>Growth occurs on medium containing 20 % bile.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose and d-xylose, but not from cellobiose, glycerol, d-mannitol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol or trehalose.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase.</s><s>Mannose and raffinose are fermented.</s><s>All of the other tests that were performed in this study (urease, arginine dihydrolase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase) gave negative results.</s><s>The major end product in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth (1 %, w/v, of each) is acetic acid; a small amount of succinic acid is also produced.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-15 : 0.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is menaquinone MK-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MS-1<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15724<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 57478<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human blood cultures.</s><s>Two additional strains from the same source, MS-2 (=JCM 15725) and MS-3 (=JCM 15726), are included in this species.</s></p></content></protolog>