<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1941_nm.8578" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8578" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8578" rank="species">Erwinia toletana</organism><reference id="rid.1941"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rojas</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García de Los Rios</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer-Le Saux</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jimenez</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reche</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonneau</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutra</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mathieu-Daudé</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McClelland</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia toletana sp. nov., associated with Pseudomonas savastanoi-induced tree knots</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2217</fpage><lpage>2222</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02924-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545461</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Erwinia toletana</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Erwinia toletana</em> (to.le.ta′na. L. fem. adj. <em>toletana</em> from <em>Toletum</em>, the Roman name for Toledo, the location from which the organisms were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains show the general characteristics of the <em>Enterobacteriaceae</em> and the specific characteristics of the genus <em>Erwinia</em>, as described by Hauben <em>et al.</em> (1998).</s><s>Cultures are Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, motile and ferment glucose without gas formation.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 36 °C but not at 39 °C.</s><s>Colonies grown on nutrient agar are circular, slightly convex with entire margins, translucent and non-pigmented.</s><s>In KB medium, colonies are circular, convex, highly mucoid, translucent and non-pigmented.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied; indole, acetoin and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>The methyl red reaction is positive and nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Strains exhibit <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activity, but no urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, phenylalanine deaminase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-maltosidase, lipase or l-aspartic acid arylamidase activities.</s><s>Acid is produced when growth medium contains mannitol, glucose, trehalose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, galacturonate, maltose, d-arabitol or cellobiose.</s><s>Strains grow on the following substrates as sole carbon sources: d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, mannitol, salicin, melibiose, citrate, acetate, propionate, 2-ketogluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, malonate, l-alanine, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>Strains possess signature nucleotides identical to the signatures described by Hauben <em>et al.</em> (1998) for the genus <em>Erwinia</em>: A408, A594, C598, G639, G646, C839, G847, G987, G988, C989, G1216, C1217, C1218, C1308 and G1329, using the <em>Escherichia coli</em> 16S rRNA gene sequence numbering (Brosius <em>et al.</em>, 1981).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strains CFBP 6631<sup>T</sup> and CFBP 6630 is 52±0·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain A37<sup>T</sup> (=CFBP 6631<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 700880<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5263<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Several other isolates from this species have been deposited in the CFBP (see Fig. 1) and CECT.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from olive knots in association with <em>Pseudomonas savastanoi</em> pv. <em>savastanoi</em> as secondary invaders on diseased plants.</s></p></content></protolog>