<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1231_nm.4189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4189" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus tetradius</organism><reference id="rid.1231"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ninomiya</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Peptococcus indolicus, Peptococcus asaccharolyticus, Peptococcus prevotii and Peptococcus magnus to the genus Peptostreptococcus and proposal of Peptostreptococcus tetradius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>683</fpage><lpage>698</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-683</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus tetradius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus tetradius</i> sp. nov. (te.tra'di.us. Gr. adj. <i>tetradios</i> by fours; N. L. masc. adj. <i>tetradius</i> occurring in groups of four)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.8 to 1.8 μm in diameter and occur mostly in pairs or tetrads. occasionally in short chains or masses.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar range from pinpoint to 1.2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Strains are nonhemolytic and make no black colonies on either rabbit or sheep blood agar after 7 days of anaerobic incubation.</s><s>The major metabolic end products in PYG broth cultures are butyrate and lactate.</s><s>No strain produces coagulase or indole or reduces nitrate.</s><s>Catalase production is variable among strains.</s><s>All strains produce urease and ferment fructose, glucose, maltose, mannose, and sucrose.</s><s>They do not make acid from arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, or sorbitol.</s><s>They produce ammonia from threonine and serine, but not from glycine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pathogenicity is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human vaginal discharge and various purulent secretions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 30 to 32 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain GIFU 7672 (= ATCC 35098 = JCM 1964 = CCM 3634).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tetrad formation is not always observed and cannot be used as a distinctive trait to separate this species from other anaerobic cocci.</s><s>Urease and β-glucuronidase activities and fermentation of fructose, glucose, maltose, mannose, and sucrose are useful characters for separating <i>Peptostreptococcus tetrudius</i> from <i>Peptostreptococcus prevotii</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>