<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2622_nm.11579" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11579" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11579" rank="species">Sejongia marina</organism><reference id="rid.2622"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>T.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sejongia marina sp. nov., isolated from Antarctic seawater.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2917</fpage><lpage>2921</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65279-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048749</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sejongia marina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sejongia marina</em> (ma.ri′na. L. fem. adj. <em>marina</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-gliding, non-motile, aerobic, psychrotolerant and chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved rods with rounded ends and are 0.6–1.2 μm long and 0.5–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies grown on MA for 7 days are 0.2–1.0 mm in diameter, circular, convex, shiny with entire margins, butyrous and yellow in colour.</s><s>Old colonies (grown for 3 weeks) become dark yellowish and viscous.</s><s>Growth occurs at 3–25 °C (optimum, 15 °C), pH 6–10 (optimum, pH 7) and with 0–3.5 % NaCl (optimum, 0.5 %).</s><s>Oxidizes the following carbon substrates (Biolog GN2 microplates): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine.</s><s>Does not oxidize the following carbon substrates: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-phenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin but resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin and kanamycin.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid constituents (&#x003E;1 %) are given in Table 2.</s><s>Traces (&#x003C;1 %) of the following fatty acids are also present: anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>19 : 0</sub>, C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 1</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.09 %).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 35.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC3228<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42689<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 103143<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of surface seawater from Maxwell Bay, King George Island, West Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>