<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12676_nm.5028" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5028" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4992" rank="species">Geobacillus thermocatenulatus</organism><reference id="rid.12676"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dinsdale</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halket</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coorevits</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Landschoot</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Geobacillus thermoleovorans and Geobacillus thermocatenulatus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1802</fpage><lpage>1810</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025445-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20817844</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Geobacillus thermocatenulatus</em> (Golovacheva <em>et al.</em> 1991) Nazina <em>et al.</em> 2001</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Geobacillus thermocatenulatus</em> (ther.mo.ca.te′nu.la.tus. Gr. n. <em>therme</em> heat; N.L. adj. <em>catenulatus</em> chain-like; N.L. masc. adj. <em>thermocatenulatus</em> thermophilic and chain-like, referring to two of the organism’s features).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Bacillus thermocatenulatus</em> Golovacheva <em>et al.</em> 1991.</s><s>Effective publication: Golovacheva <em>et al.</em> (1975).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, peritrichously motile rods, 0.9–1.5×6–12 µm.</s><s>The description is based on two strains.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, but growth is weak in the absence of oxygen.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in long chains.</s><s>Ellipsoidal or cylindrical spores are located terminally, occasionally subterminally and paracentrally, and do not swell the sporangia.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are butyrous, cream or yellowish in colour, round and raised with entire margins; may become partially heaped-up and viscid.</s><s>Growth can occur at 37 and 80 °C, with optimum growth at 60 °C.</s><s>Tolerates 5 % but not 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at pH 5 and 9, and optimally at pH 7.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed; casein and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, gelatin is hydrolysed and the Voges–Proskauer test is positive; citrate utilization (Simmons’) and nitrate reduction are variable and arginine dihydrolase, hydrogen sulfide, indole, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, ONPG, tryptophan deaminase and urease production are negative.</s><s>In the API 50CHB gallery, acid without gas is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid production is variable from methyl d-glucoside and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Acid production is negative from adonitol, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inulin, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol and d- and l-xylose.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain produces acid from methyl d-glucoside and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and does not utilize citrate or reduce nitrate.</s><s>A number of hydrocarbons (C<sub>10</sub>–C<sub>16</sub>) may be utilized as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, making up more than 60 % of the total fatty acids (Nazina <em>et al.</em>, 2001).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.17 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>The EMBL/GenBank/DDBJ accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain (BGSC 93<sup>T</sup>) is AY608935.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 178<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 19007<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 730<sup>T</sup>  = VKM B-1259<sup>T</sup>  = BGSC 93<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a slime layer inside a hot-gas borehole pipe; another strain (Ga  = DSM 15378  = VKM B-2300) was isolated from the Garga hot spring in the Transbaikal region, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>