<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12733_nm.22504" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22504" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22504" rank="species">Achromobacter marplatensis</organism><reference id="rid.12733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomila</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tvrzová</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Teshim</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>González-Escalona</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zdráhal</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Šedo</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>González</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bennasar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lalucat</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Murialdo</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Achromobacter marplatensis sp. nov., isolated from a pentachlorophenol-contaminated soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2231</fpage><lpage>2237</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025304-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952547</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Achromobacter marplatensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Achromobacter marplatensis</em> (mar.pla.ten′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>marplatensis</em> pertaining to Mar del Plata, the Argentinian city where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile, small rod-shaped, Gram-negative bacterium, 0.5–1 µm long, able to grow at 15–40 °C.</s><s>Unable to grow at 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Asaccharolytic.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin and sensitive to amoxicillin, ampicillin and carbenicillin (at 30 µg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, leucine arylamidase, alkaline and acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase and catalase activities and tyrosine hydrolysis.</s><s>Negative for activities of amylase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Able to assimilate malate, citrate and phenylacetate and to assimilate gluconate weakly.</s><s>Capable of nitrate and nitrite reduction.</s><s>Tests for the Voges–Proskauer reaction and indole production are negative.</s><s>Unable to grow on inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin, glucose, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl β-d-galactopyranoside, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, caprate, arginine, King’s media A and B, α-(+)-d-glucose, β-(+)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, (+)-trehalose, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-l-sorbose, (+)-melibiose, (+)-raffinose, maltotriose, lactose, lactulose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl α-galactopyranoside, (+)-cellobiose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Does not utilize 1-<em>O</em>-methyl β-d-glucopyranoside, (−)-d-ribose, (+)-l-arabinose, (+)-d-xylose, palatinose, α-l-rhamnose, α-(−)-l-fucose, (+)-melezitose, (+)-d-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, d-tagatose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, maltitol, (+)-turanose, d-sorbitol, adonitol, hydroxyquinoline β-glucuronide, d-lyxose, i-erythritol, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl d-glucopyranose, d-saccharate, mucate, (+)-l-, (−)-d- and <em>meso</em>-tartrate, (+)-d- and (−)-l-malate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, tricarballylate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, l-tryptophan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-gluconate, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, gentisate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, <em>m</em>-coumarate, trigonelline, betaine, putrescine, dl-α-amino-n-butyrate, histamine, dl-lactate, caprylate, l-histidine, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, dl-α-amino-n-valerate, ethanolamine, tryptamine, d-glucosamine, itaconate, dl-β-hydroxybutyrate, l-aspartate, l-proline, d- and l-alanine, l-serine, malonate, propionate, l-tyrosine or α-ketoglutarate.</s><s>No hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween 80, gelatin, starch, casein, lecithin, elastin or DNA or production of acid or H<sub>2</sub>S from triple-sugar-iron agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B2<sup>T</sup> ( = CCM 7608<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7342<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 56371<sup>T</sup>), isolated in 2001 from soil in Mar del Plata, Argentina, by selective enrichment with PCP.</s></p></content></protolog>