<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7250_nm.8177" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8177" rank="genus">Polaribacter</organism><reference id="rid.7250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gosink</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polaribacter gen. nov., with three new species, P. irgensii sp. nov., P. franzmannii sp. nov. and P. filamentus sp. nov., gas vacuolate polar marine bacteria of the Cytophaga-Flavobacterium-Bacteroides group and reclassification of 'Flectobacillus glomeratus' as Polaribacter glomeratus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>223</fpage><lpage>235</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-223</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542092</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Polaribacter</i> gen nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Polaribacter</i> (Po.lar.i.bac'ter. <i>Polaro</i> M.L. adj. polaris pertaining to the geographic poles; <i>bacter</i> from the Gr. n. <i>baktron</i> for rod or staff; <i>Polaribacter</i> rod-shaped bacterium from a polar region)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Psychrophilic or psychrotrophic Gram-negative nonmotile rods.</s><s>Cell size varies between 2 and 48 μm in length and 0.25-1.6 μm in diameter depending on growth medium, temperature, and age of the culture.</s><s>Coccoid bodies are often seen in ageing cultures.</s><s>May form coils.</s><s>Cells produce orange-, salmon- or pink-coloured pigments which are not flexirubins.</s><s>Gas vesicles are produced in some strains.</s><s>Some strains may be flagellated, but motility has never been observed in wet mounts.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Cells grow well in media which contain NaCl.</s><s>Cells produce acid from a number of carbohydrates.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed by these bacteria.</s><s>Cells can grow on yeast extract and Casamino acids.</s><s>G + C content range is 31-33 mol%.</s><s>All strains have been isolated from polar marine environments and grow well at low temperatures. 16s rRNA sequence analysis clearly indicates that this genus of bacteria forms a distinct clade of the <i>Cytophaga-Flavobacterium-Bacteroides</i> phylum. <i>Polaribacter filamentus</i> is the type species of the genus.</s></p></content></protolog>