<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4207_nm.3683" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3683" rank="genus">Bacteriovorax</organism><reference id="rid.4207"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baer</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ravel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>R.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A proposal for the reclassification of Bdellovibrio stolpii and Bdellovibrio starrii into a new genus, Bacteriovorax gen. nov. as Bacteriovorax stolpii comb. nov. and Bacteriovorax starrii comb. nov., respectively.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>219</fpage><lpage>224</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826807</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteriovorax</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteriovorax</i> (Bac.te.ri.o.vo'rax. Gr. dim. n. <i>baktron</i> small rod; L. n. <i>vorax</i> devourer; <i>bacteriovorax</i> devourer of bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of this genus exhibit a biphasic life cycle, with the potential of displaying an actively predacious form as well as a PI, saprophytic form capable of growing on nutrient medium.</s><s>Prey-dependent (wild-type) strains are comma-shaped rods, 0.5-1.4 μm in length which demonstrate a predatory lifestyle in the presence of susceptible prey bacteria.</s><s>The wild-type strains are motile by a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>PI cells (mutants) are pleomorphic, demonstrating a range of cell shapes from simple rods to long, tightly spiral shaped cells.</s><s>The mutants are motile upon initial isolation, but lose their motility after repeated transfer on solid media.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Some PI mutants may demonstrate variable catalase activity as some strains have been shown to lose this ability upon repeated transfer.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>The G+C content for members of this genus is 41.0-43.5 mol%.</s><s>This genus demonstrates little to no DNA-DNA hybridization (&#x003C;4%) with the <i>Bdellovibrio</i> genus, although they were previously considered to belong with the bdellovibrios.</s><s>Comparisons of total genomic restriction digest patterns (PFGE) generated for <i>B. stolpii</i> Uki2<sup>T</sup> and <i>B. starrii</i> A3.12<sup>T</sup> demonstrate little similarity to the patterns produced by members of the <i>Bdellovibrio</i> genus (Baer et al., 1998).</s><s>Similar results have been observed when comparing arbitrarily primed amplification profiles (AP-PCR) (Baer et al., 1998). rDNA sequence analysis demonstrates that the two species placed within this genus are more closely related to each other (&#x003E;90% rDNA sequence similarity) than to the other members of the delta division of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> (<i>Desulfovibrio</i>, <i>Myxococcus</i>, <i>Bdellovibrio</i>, <i>Desulfomonile</i>, <i>Desulfuromusa</i>, <i>Desulfuromonas</i> and <i>Geobacter</i>). <i>Bacteriovorax stolpii</i> comb. nov. has been designated the type species for this genus.</s></p></content></protolog>