<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1767_nm.2987" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2987" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2987" rank="species">Vibrio navarrensis</organism><reference id="rid.1767"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urdaci</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marchand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ageron</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arcos</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sesma</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio navarrensis sp. nov., a species from sewage.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>294</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-290</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854642</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio navarrensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio navarrensis</i> (na.var.ren'sis. L. gen. n. <i>navarrensis</i>, of Navarra, the Spanish province where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods that are 1 to 2 by 0.8 to 1 μm and are motile by means of a single polar flagellum (when grown on solid media or in liquid media) (Fig. 1).</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>No growth or weak growth when NaCl is absent from the culture medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on nutrient agar supplemented with 2% (wt/vol) NaCl are 2 to 3 mm in diameter after overnight incubation at 30”C, round, opaque, and nonpigmented and do not swarm.</s><s>They are not luminescent.</s><s>Colonies on thiosulfate-citratebile salts-sucrose agar are yellow (sucrose positive).</s><s>All strains grow in media containing 7% NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 30 to 37°C but also occurs at 40°C.</s><s>Most strains grow at 10°C (7 of 11 strains) and 42°C (9 of 11 strains).</s><s>Does not fix nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Indole is produced, gelatin and starch are hydrolyzed, and acid (but no gas) is produced from D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, maltose, and sucrose.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (vibrios tatic agent O/129).</s></p><p class="description"><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from glucose-lactose-iron or triple sugar iron agar; urease, tryptophanase , arginine dihydrolase (Thornley-Moeller media), and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are not produced.</s><s>Negative Voges-Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, and lactose.</s><s>Esculin is blackened by six of nine strains tested (in API assimilation strips).</s><s>Hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide is not hydrolyzed (in API assimilation strips).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The nine strains subjected to assimilation tests utilize 24 substrates and do not utilize 63 other substrates.</s><s>Variable results are obtained with the following substrates (the number of strains positive is given in parentheses): D-cellobiose (eight), citrate (eight), D-malate (eight), 2-ketoglutarate (seven), <i>cis</i>-aconitate (seven), L-tyrosine (seven), D-turanose (five), palatinose (four), and D-galactose (three).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>V. navarrensis</i> strains utilize the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: N-acetylglucosamine , D-alanine, L-alanine , L-aspartate, D-fructose, fumarate, gluconate, glucosamine, D-glucose, L-glutamate, m-glycerate, glycerol, DL-lactate, L-malate, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, β-methyl-D-glucoside, L-proline, D-ribose, L-serine, succinate, sucrose, and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains utilize the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adonitol, DL-5-aminovalerate, DL-4-aminobutyratLe-α rabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, benzoate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, <i>meso</i>-coumarate , dulcitol, meso-erythritol, ethanolamine, L-fucose , galacturonate, β-gentiobiose, gentisate, glucuronate, glutarate, histamine, L-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, lactulose, D-lyxose, malonate, maltitol, D-melezitose, melibiose, methyl-α-D-galactoside, methyl-β-D-galactoside, 3-methyl-α-glucose, methyl-α-D-glucoside, mucate, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, propionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, raffinose, rhamnose, D-saccharate, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, tryptophan, D-xylitol, and D-Xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sewage and surface water.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs from two strains are 45 to 47 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 1397-6 (= CIP 103381).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain 1397-6<sup>T</sup> has all of the properties given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, it is Simmons citrate positive, hydrolyzes <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside and esculin, produces acid from galactose, mannose, and glycerol, utilizes cellobiose, L-tyrosine, and 2-ketoglutarate, and grows at 10°C but not at 42°C.</s><s>It grows weakly in peptone water without NaCl.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 45 mol%.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from sewage in Villafranca, Navarra, Spain, in July 1982.</s></p></content></protolog>