<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2765_nm.5211" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5211" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5211" rank="species">Sporosarcina aquimarina</organism><reference id="rid.2765"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kho</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sporosarcina aquimarina sp. nov., a bacterium isolated from seawater in Korea, and transfer of Bacillus globisporus (Larkin and Stokes 1967), Bacillus psychrophilus (Nakamura 1984) and Bacillus pasteurii (Chester 1898) to the genus Sporosarcina as Sporosarcina globispora comb. nov., Sporosarcina psychrophila comb. nov. and Sporosarcina pasteurii comb. nov., and emended description of th.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1079</fpage><lpage>1086</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411676</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sporosarcina aquimarina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sporosarcina aquimarina</i> (a.qui.ma.ri'na. L. n. <i>aqua</i> water; L. adj. <i>marinus</i> of the sea;M.L. adj. <i>aquimarina</i> pertaining to seawater)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, endospore-forming rods that are approximately 0.9-1.2 μm wide and 2.0-3.5 μm long in 3 d cultures on TSA.</s><s>Round terminal spores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Gram-variable.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are light-orange-coloured, smooth, circular to irregular and raised on TSA.</s><s>Catalase-, oxidase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Aesculin, arbutin, casein, hypoxanthine, starch, Tween 80 and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed and tyrosine is weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Arginine is not deaminated and indole is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, fructose, glycerol, 5-ketogluconate, ribose and D-tagatose.</s><s>No acid is produced from erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-D-xyloside, galactose, glucose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 13% NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of more than 14% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 37 °C, but not at 40 °C.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 25 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 6.5-7.0.</s><s>Growth is inhibited below pH 5.0.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A4α (L-Lys-L-Ala-D-Asp).</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acid is ante-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>The G+­C content is 40 mol%(determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from seawater in Korea.</s><s>The type strain is strain SW28<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Korean Culture Center of Microorganisms as KCCM 41039T and in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as JCM 10887<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>