<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.610_nm.8459" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8459" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8459" rank="species">Alteromonas stellipolaris</organism><reference id="rid.610"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alteromonas stellipolaris sp. nov., a novel, budding, prosthecate bacterium from Antarctic seas, and emended description of the genus Alteromonas.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1157</fpage><lpage>1163</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02862-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280285</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alteromonas stellipolaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alteromonas stellipolaris</em> [stel.li.po.la′ris. L. fem. n. <em>stella</em> star; L. adj. <em>polaris</em> polar; N.L. gen. n. <em>stellipolaris</em> referring to the <em>Polarstern</em> (AWI, Bremerhaven), the name of the vessel that was used to collect the samples from which the organisms were isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0·4×2·0–7·0 μm) with a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>Prosthecae are produced peritrichously and can be branched.</s><s>Buds can be formed on mother and daughter cells and also at the end of the prostheca.</s><s>Forms creamy-white, circular, flat to low convex, shiny, opaque and slimy colonies that are slightly adherent to agar, with entire margins and a diameter of 2–5 mm on marine agar plates after 3 days incubation at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on marine agar and PYG agar; slight growth is observed on nutrient agar, but no growth is seen on trypticase soy agar or R2A agar.</s><s>Strain LMG 21856 releases a brown, diffusible pigment into the medium.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 5–37 °C; no growth occurs at 40 °C or higher.</s><s>Growth is supported on R2A agar that contains 1–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Moderately halophilic and psychrotolerant.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–9; optimum pH for growth is 7·0–8·5.</s><s>No evidence is found for growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Polyhydroxybutyrate is not accumulated and spores are not formed.</s><s>Egg-yolk precipitation is positive for some strains (LMG 21861<sup>T</sup>, LMG 21856, LMG 21860, LMG 21862 and LMG 21863).</s><s>Negative for indole and acetoin production, Voges–Proskauer test, citrate utilization, hydrolysis of urea, nitrate reduction and production of hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Degradation of starch, aesculin, gelatin and DNA is positive for all strains and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity is detected.</s><s>All strains are able to utilize Tween 40, Tween 80, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-trehalose, furanose, acetic acid, propionic acid, alaninamide, l-alanyl-glycine, l-glutamic acid and glycyl-l-glutamic acid; all strains except LMG 21862 are able to utilize dextrin, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-galacturonic acid and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid; all strains except LMG 21864 are able to utilize glycogen; all strains except LMG 21863 are able to utilize cellobiose; all strains except LMG 21860 are able to utilize d-mannose; all strains except LMG 21859 are able to utilize d-psicose.</s><s>Variable results are obtained for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, succinic acid, l-alanine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine and glycerol.</s><s>No metabolic activity is observed on adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, iso-erythritol, l-fucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerolphosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Acids are produced from amygdalin in a clear positive reaction, whereas an intermediate positive reaction is detected for mannitol, sucrose and melibiose for all strains.</s><s>No acids are produced from glucose, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose or arabinose.</s><s>Degradation of alginate and chitin is negative.</s><s>No arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are observed.</s><s>For all strains, low activity (score 1) or no activity is obtained for lipase (C14), medium activity (score 2 or 3) is obtained for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), valine arylamidase, trypsin and <em>α</em>-galactosidase, and high activity (score 4 or 5) is obtained for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Cells contain the fatty acids C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> as the main constituents.</s><s>DNA G+C content of the strains is 43–45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21861<sup>T</sup> (=ANT 69a<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15691<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>