<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3728_nm.10681" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10681" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10681" rank="species">Cyclobacterium lianum</organism><reference id="rid.3728"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ying</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cyclobacterium lianum sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from sediment of an oilfield in the South China Sea, and emended description of the genus Cyclobacterium.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2927</fpage><lpage>2930</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64510-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17159000</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cyclobacterium lianum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cyclobacterium lianum</em> (N.L. neut. adj. <em>lianum</em> pertaining to Li, named in honour of Professor Ji-Lun Li, who devotes himself to microbiological research and education in China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic and heterotrophic, non-motile, curved, ring-like or horseshoe-shaped, 0.4–0.5 μm wide, and the outer diameter of rings is 1.5–1.8 μm.</s><s>Colonies grown for 3 days on MA are circular (2–3 mm in diameter), light rose in colour and shiny.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–42 °C (optimum 33 °C), at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum pH 7.5–8.0) and with 0.1–12 % NaCl (optimum 1–4 %).</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase activities, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, urease and lecithinase activities.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin and Tween 20 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80 are hydrolysed weakly; agar, casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and carboxymethyl-cellulose are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Glucose, sucrose, d-melibiose, ribose, lactose, galactose, maltose, melezitose, inulin, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, d-raffinose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and gluconate are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Glycerol, mannitol, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-xylose, lactic acid, succinate, malate, pyruvate and l-glutamic acid are weakly utilized.</s><s>l-Fucose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, citrate, malonate, l-lysine, l-alanine, formic acid, butyric acid and caprate are not utilized.</s><s>Forms acid from glucose, ribose (weakly), sucrose, d-melibiose, lactose, galactose, maltose, melezitose, inulin, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, d-raffinose, trehalose, cellobiose, d-xylose, glycerol (weakly) and methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside.</s><s>Shows strong activity in the API ZYM system for alkaline and acid phosphatases, leucine and valine arylamidases, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Shows weak activity for esterases C4 and C8, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>No activity is shown for trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase or lipase (C14).</s><s>In GN2 MicroPlates, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-galacturonic acid, dl-lactic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, dl-carnitine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and glucose 1-phosphate are oxidized.</s><s>Weak or variable results are detected with glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, i-erythritol, d-mannitol, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, monomethyl succinate, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, succinic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, dl-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, uridine, 2-aminoethanol and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg): gentamicin (10), neomycin (30), polymyxin B (300), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg): ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), vancomycin (30), ciprofloxacin (5), rifampicin (5), norfloxacin (10), chloramphenicol (30), benzyl penicillin (10), kanamycin (30) and erythromycin (15).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (28.3 %), summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>; 16.6 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (10.3 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (8.0 %) and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (6.4 %).</s><s>The molar G+C content of the DNA is 45.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HY9<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6102<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14011<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment from the Xijiang oilfield in the South China Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>