<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3131_nm.7952" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7952" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7952" rank="species">Bacteroides galacturonicus</organism><reference id="rid.3131"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides pectinophilus sp. nov. and Bacteroides galacturonicus sp. nov.: two pectinolytic bacteria from the human intestinal tract</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>880</fpage><lpage>887</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3777933</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides galacturonicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides galacturonicus</i> (ga.lac.tu.ro'ni.cus M.L. adj. <i>galacturonicus</i> pertaining to <i>galacturonate</i>, with reference to the ability to fermerit this compound or polygalacturonate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown in broth containing polygalacturonate as the fermentable substrate (PF broth) are rod shaped, 0.6 by 3.5-6 μm, arranged singly or in pairs, and rarely in short chains.</s><s>Cells up to 12 μm in length are present in cultures.</s><s>Nonsporeforming, gram-negative.</s><s>Six to eight peritrichous flagella per cell are present.</s><s>However, motility has not been observed under the cultural conditions used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on PF agar medium are white with a tan tinge, irregularly shaped with uneven margins, flat, opaque, and rough and measure 4 to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Final growth yield in PF broth approximates 2.3 x 10<sup>9</sup> cells per ml, and the cell population doubling time is 1 h.</s><s>Final pH of PF broth cultures ranges from 5.0 to 5.5.</s><s>Optimum growth is between 35 and 40°C, with no growth at 20 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobes.</s><s>Pectin, polygalacturonate, D-galacturonate, and D-glucuronate are fermented.</s><s>L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, Dmannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, L-rhamnose, D-gluconate, pyruvate, glycerol, methanol, amino acids, alginate, amylose, arabinogalactan, carboxymethyl cellulose, cellulose, chondroitin sulfate, dextran, hyaluronic acid, inulin, starch, and xylan are not fermented.</s><s>Folic acid, pantothenic acid, and biotin are required as growth factors.</s><s>Neither hemin nor vitamin K is required for growth.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Gelatin and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Excellent growth in PF broth containing 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate, formate, and a small amount of lactate are end products of polygalacturonate or pectin fermentation.</s><s>In addition, pectin fermentation yields methanol.</s><s>Pectin is depolymerized extracellularly by the cumulative action of pectinesterase (EC 3.1.1.11) and of an exopolygalacturonate lyase activity that releases unsaturated trigalacturonate molecules from polygalacturonate and that has a pH optimum of 8.2 to 8.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G + C of the DNA is 36 as determined by thermal denaturation.</s><s>The type strain is N6; this strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 43244.</s></p></content></protolog>