<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2644_nm.11845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11845" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11453" rank="species">Krasilnikovia cinnamonea</organism><reference id="rid.2644"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Krasilnikovia gen. nov., a new member of the family Micromonosporaceae and description of Krasilnikovia cinnamonea sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><source id="668">Nihon Hōsenkin Gakkai shi = Actinomycetologica</source><abbrev>Actinomycetol</abbrev><issn>0914-5818</issn><essn>1881-6371</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3209/saj.SAJ210101</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Krasilnikovia cinnamonea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Krasilnikovia cinnamonea</i> (cin.na.mo'nea L. n. <i>cinnamum</i> cinnamon; N.L. adj. <i>cinnamonea</i> cinnamon-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics are as given above for the genus description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism shows moderate growth on 1/5 yeast-starch agar, glycerol-asparagine agar, tyrosine agar, sucrose-beef extract agar, ISP medium 6, ISP medium 1, 1/20 V8 juice agar, HV agar, and 1/10 yeast-malt extract agar, and poor growth on nutrient agar and tap water agar.</s><s>Melanin pigment production on ISP medium 7 is negative.</s><s>Abundant sporulation occurs on glucose-asparagine agar, sucrose-nitrate agar and HV agar media, moderate sporulation on glycerol asparagine agar, tyrosine agar, nutrient agar, Hickey-Tresner agar, yeast extract-starch agar, 1/5 yeast extract-starch agar, ISP medium 1 agar, 1/20 V8 juice agar and 1/10 yeast extract-malt extract agar, and no sporulation on inorganic salts-starch agar, yeast extract-malt extract agar, oatmeal agar, Bennett agar, glucose-yeast extract agar, oatmeal-nitrate agar, sucrose-beef extract agar and ISP medium 6 agar media.</s><s>In general, the vegetative mycelia are light melon yellow to cinnamon yellow in colour and aerial mycelia are not present.</s><s>Adonitol, L-rhamnose, D-mannitol, α-D(+)melibiose, D-raffinose and trehalose are poorly utilized, and erythritol, L-arabinose, D-ribose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, α-methyl-D-glucoside and lactose are not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 71%.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The type strain is 3-54(41)<sup>T</sup> (= JCM 13252<sup>T</sup> = MTCC 8094<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>