<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4502_nm.10606" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10606" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10606" rank="species">Azospirillum canadense</organism><reference id="rid.4502"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mehnaz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weselowski</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lazarovits</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azospirillum canadense sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium isolated from corn rhizosphere.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>620</fpage><lpage>624</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64804-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329796</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Azospirillum canadense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Azospirillum canadense</em> (can.ad.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>canadense</em> pertaining to Canada, the region of isolation, referring to its isolation from Canadian soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short rods, 0.9×1.8–2.5 μm in size, Gram-negative, motile via a single polar flagellum.</s><s>White to light-pink, rounded, wet colonies form after 48–72 h.</s><s>Growth occurs on M medium at 20–37 °C, pH 5–7 and 0.5–1 % NaCl concentration.</s><s>Optimum temperature is 25–30 °C and optimum pH is 5–7.</s><s>Positive for nitrogen fixation and indole acetic acid production; negative for phosphate solubilization.</s><s>Malic acid, potassium gluconate, acetic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em> and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-asparagine and l-aspartic acid can be use as single carbon source.</s><s>Sucrose, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, l-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, xylitol, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, trisodium acetate, capric acid, adipic acid and phenylacetic acid are not utilized.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and acetoin production and negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Biotin is not required for growth.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 16 : 0.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67.9 mol%.</s><s>The predominant quinone system is ubiquinone Q-10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DS2<sup>T</sup> (=NCCB 100108<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23617<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere of corn (<em>Zea mays</em>) from Delhi, Ontario, Canada.</s></p></content></protolog>