<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5933_nm.8485" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8485" rank="genus">Avibacterium</organism><reference id="rid.5933"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beckenham</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Pasteurella gallinarum, [Haemophilus] paragallinarum, Pasteurella avium and Pasteurella volantium as Avibacterium gallinarum gen. nov., comb. nov., Avibacterium paragallinarum comb. nov., Avibacterium avium comb. nov. and Avibacterium volantium comb. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>362</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63357-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653900</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Avibacterium</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Avibacterium</em> (Av′i.bac.te′ri.um. L. pl. n. <em>aves</em> birds; N.L. neut. n. <em>bacterium</em> rod; N.L. neut. n. <em>Avibacterium</em> bacterium of birds).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A member of the family <em>Pasteurellaceae</em> as defined by Olsen <em>et al.</em> (2004).</s><s>Gram-negative, non-motile, rod-shaped or pleomorphic with cells occurring singly and in pairs or short chains depending upon the growth stage.</s><s>Colonies on sheep-blood agar are non-haemolytic, greyish, non-transparent, but eventually translucent at the periphery, with a butyrous consistency, smooth and shiny, circular and raised with an entire margin.</s><s>Some isolates show symbiotic growth.</s><s>Major differences are consequently observed in the size of colonies after 24 h incubation (pinpoint up to almost 2 mm in diameter).</s><s>Pigment production is variable.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is mesophilic and facultatively anaerobic or microaerophilic.</s><s>The oxidase reaction is positive and nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The reaction in Hugh–Leifson medium with d-glucose is fermentative without gas production.</s><s>Porphyrin and alanine aminopeptidase tests are positive.</s><s>Negative reactions occur for Simmons' citrate, mucate-acid, malonate-base, H<sub>2</sub>S/tri-sugar iron (TSI), growth in the presence of KCN, Voges–Proskauer, methyl red and urease tests.</s><s>Negative tests are further observed with arginine dehydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, indole, gelatinase and Tween 20 and 80 hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is formed from d-fructose, d-mannose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from <em>meso</em>-erythritol, adonitol, l-xylose, dulcitol, d-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, cellobiose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-glycogen, inulin, aesculin, amygdalin, arbutin, gentiobiose, salicin, d-turanose or <em>β</em>-<em>N</em>-CH<sub>3</sub>-glucosamid.</s><s>Reactions for <em>β</em>-glucosidase (NPG), <em>α</em>-fucosidase (ONPF), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (PGUA), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-xylosidase (ONPX) are also negative.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Variable reactions occur for catalase, phosphatase, ornithine decarboxylase and ONPG and PNPG tests and the production of acid from glycerol, d-arabitol, xylitol, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-fucose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, trehalose, raffinose and dextrin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 44·2 to 47 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Avibacterium gallinarum</em>, originally described as <em>Pasteurella gallinarum</em> by Hall <em>et al.</em> (1955).</s></p></content></protolog>