<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12774_nm.22555" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22555" rank="species">Vibrio atlanticus</organism><reference id="rid.12774"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Diéguez</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaz-Hidalgo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balboa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romalde</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio atlanticus sp. nov. and Vibrio artabrorum sp. nov., isolated from the clams Ruditapes philippinarum and Ruditapes decussatus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2406</fpage><lpage>2411</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025320-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075909</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio atlanticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio atlanticus</em> (at.lan′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>atlanticus</em> Atlantic, from the Atlantic Ocean).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, motile, flagellated rods (0.7–0.8×1.1–1.4 µm in size).</s><s>Colonies are beige in colour, round and smooth on MA.</s><s>Swarming is not observed.</s><s>Colonies are 2–6 mm in diameter on MA plates after 24 h of incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive and indole test is usually positive.</s><s>All strains hydrolyse starch and Tween 80.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed by all isolates except the type strain, Vb 11.11<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 °C and with 3–6 % NaCl (w/v), but not at 3 or 44 °C and salinities greater than 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Most strains are susceptible to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 µg per disc).</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and potassium gluconate.</s><s>None of the strains produce acid from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In addition, the type strain, Vb 11.11<sup>T</sup>, produced acid from l-arabinose, d-xylose, sucrose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, gentiobiose and l-fucose.</s><s>All strains can use as sole carbon source d-ribose, d-fructose, trehalose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, gluconic acid, d-mannitol, glycerol, succinic acid, l-threonine, l-glutamic acid, d-alanine, l-arginine and l-tyrosine, but not d-xylose, l-rhamnose, lactose, d-salicin, d-amygdalin, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, butyric acid, l-ornithine, amino-<em>N</em>-butyric acid, l-lysine, putrescine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid or l-fucose.</s><s>In addition, the type strain, Vb 11.11<sup>T</sup>, can use as sole carbon source d-glucose, sodium acetate, propionic acid, citric acid, l-serine, l-citrulline, aspartic acid and l-histidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Vb 11.11<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7223<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24300<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from clam, <em>Ruditapes philippinarum</em>, in Galicia, north-west Spain, in January 2005.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain Vb 11.11<sup>T</sup> is 44.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>