<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6692_nm.10772" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10772" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10772" rank="species">Halomonas janggokensis</organism><reference id="rid.6692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas gomseomensis sp. nov., Halomonas janggokensis sp. nov., Halomonas salaria sp. nov. and Halomonas denitrificans sp. nov., moderately halophilic bacteria isolated from saline water.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>675</fpage><lpage>681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64767-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392185</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas janggokensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas janggokensis</em> (jang.gok.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>janggokensis</em> referring to Janggok in Anmyeondo, from where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods (0.5–0.7×1.6–2.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies are white, smooth, translucent and circular with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–45 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH 6–10 (optimum pH 7–8).</s><s>Growth occurs at salinities of 1–20 % NaCl (optimum 10–15 % NaCl).</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>DNA is hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, adonitol, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannitol, sorbitol, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-fucose, d-arabitol and l-arabitol, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: mannitol, d-glucose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, gluconate, propionate, malate, malonate, valerate, acetate, adipate, citrate, dl-lactate, l-alanine, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate and l-proline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, d-ribose, d-melibiose, l-fucose, mannose, itaconate, suberate, caprate, histidine, phenylacetate, 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate and l-serine.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are available as Supplementary Table S2.</s><s>The predominant quinone is ubiquinone Q-9; a small amount of Q-8 is also present.</s><s>The fatty acids C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH are predominant.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 60.2–61.0 mol% (61.0 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M24<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12663<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18043<sup>T</sup>), isolated from saline water of Janggok solar saltern in Anmyeondo, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>