<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2732_nm.10022" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10022" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10022" rank="species">Actinocorallia cavernae</organism><reference id="rid.2732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinocorallia cavernae sp. nov., isolated from a natural cave in Jeju, Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1085</fpage><lpage>1088</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63895-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627659</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinocorallia cavernae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinocorallia cavernae</em> (ca′ver.nae. L. gen. n. <em>cavernae</em>, of a cavern, the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Forms a well-developed, branched, non-fragmenting vegetative mycelium.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is sparse on ISP 2 and ISP 4 media but abundant and greyish white in colour on ISP 3 medium.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is olive black in colour on ISP 2 medium, dark yellowish brown on ISP 3 medium and cream on ISP 4 medium.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Smooth spores are formed in the aerial mycelium and form straight to flexuous chains.</s><s>The optimum temperature range for growth is 25–30 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 or 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.1–10.1.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH 4.1.</s><s>Degradation of hypoxanthine and dl-tyrosine is observed but not that of elastin and xanthine.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, starch and urea are hydrolysed, but DNA is not.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction is observed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl but not on 1–7 % NaCl.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose are utilized as sole carbon sources, but inulin, melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, methyl d-mannoside, d-raffinose, l-sorbose, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, 1,2-propanediol, d-sorbitol and d-xylitol are not.</s><s>The cell wall is of type III/C (<em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and no diagnostic sugar in the cell wall).</s><s>The <em>N</em>-acyl type of the muramic acid is acetyl.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is of type PII (phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (25.9 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (19.2 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (11.7 %), 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (tuberculostearic acid, 9.4 %), ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (7.4 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (6.7 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 70.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain N3-7<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13278<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24429<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil inside a natural cave on Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>