<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7394_nm.851" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.851" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.851" rank="species">Skermanella parooensis</organism><reference id="rid.7394"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Skermanella parooensis gen. nov., sp. nov. to accommodate Conglomeromonas largomobilis subsp. parooensis following the transfer of Conglomeromonas largomobilis subsp. largomobilis to the genus Azospirillum.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>541</fpage><lpage>544</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-541</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Skermanella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Skermanella</i> (Sker.ma.nel'la. M.L. dim. ending -<i>ella</i>; M.L. fem. dim. n. <i>Skermanella</i> named after V. B. D. Skerman who first isolated this bacterium, and in honour of his contribution to bacterial systematics)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-sporing bacterium, which exhibits unicellular and multicellular phases of growth.</s><s>Unicellar-phase cells are rod-shaped, with rounded or tapered ends and a straight or slightly curved axis, arranged singularly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile cells have mixed flagellation, with a single polar flagellum and one or more distinct lateral flagella of different wavelength.</s><s>Multicellular conglomerates arise from single cells which lose motility, become optically refractile and reproduce by multi-planar septation.</s><s>Under suitable conditions conglomerates dissociate into single motile cells which produce water-clear colonies in which the sparse number of cells move in a sluggish manner.</s><s>No filamentous structures are formed and no buds are produced.</s><s>The bacterium is an obligate chemo-organotroph and a facultative anaerobe.</s><s>Carbohydrate metabolism is fermentative.</s><s>Unable to fix dinitrogen under microaerophilic conditions, acetylene reduction in malate-N<sub>2</sub>-free medium is negative.</s><s>This taxon belongs to an isolated subline of descent in the <i>Azospirillum</i> branch of the α-Proteobacteria.</s><s>Its nearest phylogenetic relative is <i>Azospirillurn largirnobile</i> (93% rRNA sequence similarity).</s><s>Characteristics that differentiate <i>Skermanella</i> from <i>Azospirillum</i> species are given in Table 1.</s><s>The type species is <i>Skermanella parooensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>