<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6134_nm.10263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10263" rank="species">Myroides pelagicus</organism><reference id="rid.6134"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maneerat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Myroides pelagicus sp. nov., isolated from seawater in Thailand.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1917</fpage><lpage>1920</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64336-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902031</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Myroides pelagicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Myroides pelagicus</em> (pe.la′gi.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>pelagicus</em> belonging to the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, straight, short and single rods (0.5–1×0.2–0.3 μm).</s><s>Cells lack flagella.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth are observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on LB agar medium are circular, convex and yellow-to-orange.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C; no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.0–9.0.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth, but is able to tolerate up to 9.0 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Catalase reaction is weakly positive, whereas oxidase reaction is positive.</s><s>Gelatin hydrolysis, Voges–Proskauer test and citrate utilization results are positive, but activities of ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease, production of hydrogen sulfide and indole and reduction of nitrate and nitrite are negative.</s><s>Positive results for activities of alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative results for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Glycogen, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine and thymidine are utilized, but cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, furanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are not utilized.</s><s>The major quinone system is menaquinone MK-6.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> iso and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 33.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SM1<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15337<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12661<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater, off the coast of Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>