<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.155_nm.6381" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6381" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6381" rank="species">Mycobacterium mucogenicum</organism><reference id="rid.155"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Böttger</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirschner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny of the Mycobacterium chelonae-like organism based on partial sequencing of the 16S rRNA gene and proposal of Mycobacterium mucogenicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>262</fpage><lpage>267</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-262</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537060</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium mucogenicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium mucogenicum</i> (mu.co.gen'i.cum. M.L. adj. <i>mucogenicum</i>, producing mucus, referring to the highly mucoid character of most strains on solid agar)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Mycobacterium mucogenicum</i> is a gram-positive, acid- and alcohol-fast, curved bacillus that grows aerobically or microaerophilically (2).</s><s>It does not form spores or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Visible growth occurs in 2 to 4 days.</s><s>Colonies on Middlebrook 7H10 agar or Trypticase soy agar arc usually smooth, mucoid, and off-white.</s><s>No pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 28 to 37°C but not at 42°C.</s><s>Susceptible in vitro to amikacin, imipenem, cefoxitin, clarithromycin, and ciprofloxacin.</s><s>Variable susceptibility is observed with doxycycline.</s><s>Resistant to isoniazid and rifampin.</s><s>Iron uptake negative (often the colonies are tan, and there is a rust-colored ring at the margin of the slant).</s><s>Typically positive for arylsulfatase activity at 3 and 14 days, acetamidase activity, and Tween hydrolysis.</s><s>Grows (poorly at times) on MacConkey agar and utilizes mannitol and citrate but not glucitol (sorbitol) or inositol as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is variable.</s><s>Strains produce catalase that is inactivated at 68°C and pH 7; the level of catalase activity is low.</s><s>Reduces tellurite.</s><s>Urease positive (2).</s><s>Susceptible to cephalothin as determined by the disk method.</s><s>Two widely separated sets of mycolic acid ester peaks occur on HPLC gels.</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 49650, which was recovered from a human neck abscess</s></p></content></protolog>