<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1974_nm.10960" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10960" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10960" rank="species">Prevotella timonensis</organism><reference id="rid.1974"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Glazunova</surname><given-names>O.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Launay</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella timonensis sp. nov., isolated from a human breast abscess.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>883</fpage><lpage>886</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64609-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392225</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella timonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella timonensis</em> (ti.mo.n.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>timonensis</em> from the name Hôpital de la Timone, the hospital in Marseille, France, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-pigmented, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative straight rods.</s><s>Growth occurs on sheep blood agar and in TSB liquid medium.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 20 % (w/v) bile.</s><s>After 72 h growth on blood sheep agar, surface colonies are circular, white–greyish, smooth, shiny and up to 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 25–37 °C, with an optimum at 37 °C.</s><s>After 48 h growth in TSB medium, rods are 0.8–1.4 μm in length, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and occur singly (as observed by TEM).</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Ferments glucose, lactose and maltose.</s><s>Tests positive for gelatin hydrolysis using an API 20A strip.</s><s>With an API 20A strip, tests negative for indole formation, urease activity, aesculin hydrolysis and fermentation of mannitol, sucrose, salicin, xylose, arabinose, glycerol, cellobiose, mannose, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, rhamnose and trehalose.</s><s>Using API ID 32A tests, positive for activities of alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase.</s><s>Activities of <em>β</em>-galactosidase 6-phosphate and <em>α</em>-galactosidase are weakly positive.</s><s>Negative reaction for indole production, reduction of nitrates and fermentation of mannose and raffinose.</s><s>No activity is detected for glutamic acid decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase or serine arylamidase.</s><s>Using an API 50CH strip, only reactions for d-ribose, d-tagatose, potassium 5-ketogluconate and aesculin (iron citrate) are positive after 1 week of cultivation.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by the predominance of C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (19.5 %), followed by C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (15.3 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (14 %) and a mixture of C<sub>18 : 2</sub><em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (16 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4401737<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108522<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 50105<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human breast abscess.</s></p></content></protolog>