<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.14473_nm.4882" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4882" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4882" rank="species">Bacillus brevis</organism><reference id="rid.14473"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Laubach</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rice</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>W.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Studies on aerobic spore-bearing non-pathogenic bacteria: Part II.</article-title><year>1916</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>493</fpage><lpage>533</lpage><source id="177">Journal of Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-9193</issn><essn>1098-5530</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Laubach, C.A., Rice, J.L. and Ford, W.W. 1916. Studies on aerobic spore-bearing non-pathogenic bacteria: Part II. J. Bacteriology. 1(5):493-533.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Bacillus brevis Migula 1900</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism was first described by Flugge (1894) as Bacillus No. I.</s><s>According to Neide (1904) who has given an accurate account of its morphology and cultural reactions under the name Bacills lactis Fliigge, it is probably identical with Bacillus cylindrosporus Burchard (1898).</s><s>The correct name is that of Migula.</s><s>Three different strains have been isolated from milk, from soil, and from dust.</s><s>They agree in their cultural reactions with the description given by one of us (W.</s><s>W.</s><s>F.) of a culture isolated in Montreal.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Bacilli with pointed ends and slightly granular protoplasm, sometimes fusiformin shape.</s><s>In 24 hour cultures on plain agar they measure 0.375 to 0.5 by 2 to 3 microns.</s><s>On glucose agar they are more uniform and slightly thicker and longer, measuring usually 0.5 by 3 to 4 microns. (Figures 78, 79 and 80.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motility.</s><s>Active progressive motility in 24 hour agar cultures.</s><s>Staining properties.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore formation.</s><s>Spores are formed early appearing often within 24 hours on plain and glucose agar.</s><s>They are cylindrical, usually subterminal in position, thicker than the organisms from which they spring, and present a characteristic appearance.</s><s>They may retain spurs of protoplasm at each end or may be entirely naked.</s><s>They measure usually 0.75 by 1.125 to 1.5 microns.</s><s>Rarely they may be distinctly terminal in position.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar slant.</s><s>Thick moist spreading growth with a silvery sheen abundant in 24 hours and becoming thick white and glistening in older cultures.</s><s>Easily scraped from medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar stab.</s><s>Filifonn growth along line of inoculation with an abundant surface growth spreading to the tube wall.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies.</s><s>Surface colonies in 24 hours are round and regular or thin spreading translucent, under low power slightly granular with entire edges.</s><s>Deep colonies small fine, under low power irregular and pale yellow.</s><s>As the superficial colonies get older they become thicker and heaped up slightly.</s><s>The deep colonies may show irregular fuzzy margins under the low power.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose agar.</s><s>Heaped up white moist non-spreading growth in 24 hours, becoming thick and raised in old cultures.</s><s>Reaction alkaline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose agar colonies.</s><s>Superficial colonies are slightly thicker than plain agar colonies in 24 hours and show a greater tendency to spread.</s><s>Under the low power they are granular with entire edges.</s><s>Deep colonies small and fine, under low power irregular and pale yellow.</s><s>Older superficial colonies are thick, irregular and heaped up.</s><s>Reaction of agar alkaline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin stab.</s><s>Faint growth along line of inoculation and at the point of puncture in 3 to 4 days, with beginning liquefaction.</s><s>Distinct cup-shaped or funnel liquefaction in two weeks.</s><s>Occasionally a fragile scum appears on the liquid gelatin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin colonies.</s><s>Colonies begin to appear in 48 hours and show dark central areas with hazy peripheries.</s><s>Under the low power they show dark opaque centers with wavy branching peripheries.</s><s>Deep colonies frequently show peculiar prickly margins.</s><s>Gelatin completely liquefied at the end of about two weeks and may show a thick scum on the surface.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth.</s><s>Turbidity and a flocculent sediment in 24 to 48 hours with a gradual production of a heavy scum which appears often only after 4 days.</s><s>In old cultures the precipitate is quite heavy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptone.</s><s>Turbidity and heavy flocculent sediment.</s><s>Scum may be thick and heavy or entirely lacking.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Potato.</s><s>Usually a rather scanty moist yellow or yellow-brown growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Milk.</s><s>No change in reaction.</s><s>Litmus begins to decolorize in 48 hours and by the end of two weeks is completely decolorized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At the same time the proteins are digested and the resulting fluid is a pale rather thin colorless solution.</s><s>No coagulation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Blood serum.</s><s>Thin cream-white non-spreading growth becoming yellowish-brown in old cultures.</s><s>No liquefaction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation tubes.</s><s>Glucose: thick scum, turbidity in bowl, arm clear.</s><s>Reaction alkaline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Saccharose: reactions the same.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lactose: reactions the same.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thermal death point.</s><s>The spores survive steaming 30 minutes but are destroyed by 45 minutes exposure.</s><s>They may survive a pressure of 16 pounds in the autoclave but are destroyed by 18 pounds pressure.</s></p></content></protolog>