<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1438_nm.2602" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2602" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2602" rank="species">Pseudomonas ficuserectae</organism><reference id="rid.1438"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas ficuserectae sp. nov., the causal agent of bacterial leaf spot of Ficus erecta Thunb.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>546</fpage><lpage>550</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-546</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> (fi.cus.e.rećtae. <i>Ficus erecta</i> name of host species; L. n. <i>ficuserectae</i> of <i>Ficus erecta</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, non-encapsulated, nonsporeforming rods with an average size of 2.0 by 0.5 μm and are motile by means of one to five polar flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules accumulate.</s><s>Colonies on yeast extract-peptone agar plates at 28°C are white, transparent, circular, convex, and 0.1 to 0.3 mm in diameter after 2 days and 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 6 days.</s><s>Growth on yeast extractpeptone agar slants becomes very viscid after several days.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> was identical to the other four species studied in being positive for the following tests: motility, aerobic growth, catalase reaction, oxidative metabolism of fructose, alkaline reaction of litmus milk, growth in 3% NaCl, utilization of L-galactose, fructose, malate, fumarate, succinate, and citrate, and tobacco hypersensitive reaction.</s><s>Negative reactions were obtained in the following tests: Gram stain, growth factor requirement, denitrification, utilization of arginine and betaine as carbon sources, arginine dihydrolase, starch hydrolysis, decarboxylase reaction with lysine and ornithine, phenylalanine deaminase, growth in 5% NaCl and 0.0075% KCN, indole production, methyl red test, acetoin production, potato rot, and utilization of D-galactose, maltose, trehalose, erythritol, dulcitol, xylan, inulin, glycogen, starch, carboxymethyl cellulose, salicin, α-methyl-D-glucoside, esculin, oxalate, glycolate, butyrate, sebacate, hippurate, arginine, betaine, valine, and ethylene glycol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics of <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> that differentiate this species from <i>Pseudomonas amygdali</i>, <i>Pseudomonas pseudoalcaligenes</i> subsp. <i>citrulli</i>, <i>Pseudomonas andropogonis</i>, and <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>phaseolicola</i> are shown in Table 2. <i>Pseudomonus ficuserectae</i> is clearly distinguished from <i>Pseudomonas andropogonis</i> and <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>phaseolicola</i> by its limited ability to utilize sugars and sugar alcohols and from <i>Pseudomonas pseudoalcaligenes</i> subsp. <i>citrulli</i> in the limited number of organic acids utilized, as well as by its negative reactions in some physiological and biochemical tests.</s><s>In contrast, <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> is similar to <i>Pseudomonas amygdali</i> in phenotypic characteristics (8).</s><s>The differences between these two species are shown in Table 3.</s><s>In addition to differences in seven biochemical properties and G+C content, the strains of <i>Pseudomonas amygdali</i> are quite distinctive in that their growth on yeast extract-peptone agar plates is retarded; colonies are only 0.3 to 1 .O mm in diameter after 7 days at 28°C in contrast to <i>P. ficuserectae</i> colonies, which are 3 to 4 mm in diameter.</s><s>The delayed growth of <i>Pseudomonas amygdali</i> on agar plates is consistent even after repeated subculturing on the same medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The disease produced by <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> is characterized by leaf spots which develop beside the thick veins (Fig. 2A).</s><s>These spots are angular, 1 to 3 mm across, and dark green. to dark brown, with a water-soaked appearance.</s><s>The individual spots enlarge gradually and coalesce to form large lesions which invariably are surrounded by a yellow halo.</s><s>Severely infected leaves often defoliate.</s><s>In early spring, the disease also develops on new shoots, causing shoot blight which results in dieback of the twigs (Fig. 2B).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In inoculation tests, <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> produced small, water-soaked dark green spots on the leaves of <i>F. erecta</i> 4 to 5 days after inoculation by the spraying method.</s><s>These spots enlarged slowly to form angular lesions with or without halos, were 1 to 2 mm across after 10 days, and turned dark brown.</s><s>The strains of <i>Pseudomonas amygdali</i>, <i>Pseudomonas pseudoalcaligenes</i> subsp. <i>citrulli</i>, <i>Pseudomonas andropogonis</i>, and <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>phaseolicola</i> tested did not produce any symptoms on <i>F. erecta</i>.</s><s>None of the bacteria studied, including <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i>, was pathogenic on <i>F. carica</i> L., M. <i>alba</i> L., or <i>Prunus armeniaca</i> L. when either the pricking method or the spraying method of inoculation was used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The base composition of <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> DNA is 59 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain L7 (= ATCC 35104 = PDDCC 7848).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In 1980, <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>fici</i> was reported from India as the pathogenic agent of bacterial leaf spot of <i>Ficus palmata</i> Forsk. (3).</s><s>This bacterium shares with <i>Pseudomonas ficuserecrae</i> many biochemical properties; however, these two organisms do differ in utilization of carbohydrates.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>fici</i> has not been designated, and no culture has been available from any culture collection; thus, a direct comparison between <i>Pseudomonas ficuserectae</i> and <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>fici</i> could not be undertaken.</s></p></content></protolog>