<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.10045" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10045" rank="genus">Methylibium</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Methylibium</em> Nakatsu <em>et al.</em> 2006</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description of the genus was emended by Yoon <em>et al.</em> (2007) to omit the hydrolysis of urea.</s><s>With the transfer of <em>Methylibium fulvum</em> to the genus <em>Rhizobacter</em>, the description of <em>Methylibium</em> is as defined by Nakatsu <em>et al.</em> (2006) supplemented with our own data as follows.</s><s>Cells are motile, Gram-negative, straight rods.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Negative for gelatinase and catalase.</s><s>Hydrolyse urea and reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Cells possess poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules as a storage material and reproduce by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs heterotrophically under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Facultative methylotrophs, able to use methanol as a sole carbon source in addition to a variety of other, more complex carbon sources.</s><s>The major quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH are present.</s><s>Major polyamines are 2-hydroxyputrescine and putrescine; cadaverine and spermine are present as minor compounds.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine; one unidentified aminolipid is present.</s><s>On the basis of 16S rRNA gene sequence comparison, the genus belongs to the class <em>Betaproteobacteria</em>, order <em>Burkholderiales</em>, having <em>Aquabacterium</em>, <em>Methylibium</em>, <em>Rhizobacter</em> and <em>Piscinibacter</em> as its nearest neighbours.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain of the type species is 69 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>The type species is <em>Methylibium petroleiphilum</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>