<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3495_nm.5051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5051" rank="genus">Paraliobacillus</organism><reference id="rid.3495"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishizaki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new Gram-positive, slightly halophilic, extremely halotolerant, facultative anaerobe isolated from a decomposing marine alga.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>269</fpage><lpage>279</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2323/jgam.48.269</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12501437</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paraliobacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paraliobacillus</i> (Pa.ra.lio.ba.cil'lus. Gr. adj. <i>paralios</i> littoral; L. n. <i>bacillus</i> rod; M.L. masc. n. <i>Paraliobacillus</i> rod inhabiting littoral [marine] environment)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, endospore-forming rods that are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Endospores are spherical to ellipsoidal and terminal.</s><s>Sporangia is definitely swollen.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, catalase-positive when cultivated aerobically, pseudocatalase-negative, and requires carbohydrate, sugar alcohol, or related compounds for growth.</s><s>Glucose is aerobically metabolized to produce acetate and pyruvate as main organic acids.</s><s>In anaerobic cultivation, lactate, formate, acetate, and ethanol are the end products from glucose, with a molar ratio of approximately 2:1:1 for the last three products, without gas production.</s><s>Slightly halophilic and extremely halotolerant.</s><s>Slightly alkaliphilic.</s><s>Contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid in cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The menaquinone type is menaquinone-7.</s><s>Occupies an independent lineage within the halophilic/halotolerant/alkaliphilic and/or alkalitolerant group in rRNA group 1 of the phyletic group classically defined as the genus <i>Bacillus</i>, with a 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity of 95.2% to the genus <i>Gracilibacillus</i>.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 35.6 mol%.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <i>Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>