<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.40_nm.4918" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4918" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4918" rank="species">Bacillus halodenitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.40"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denariaz</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Payne</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gall</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A halophilic denitrifier, Bacillus halodenitrificans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>151</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-145</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus halodenitrificans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus halodenitrificans</i> (ha.lo.de.ni.tri'fi.cans. Gr. n. <i>halos</i>, salt, the sea; M.L. v. <i>denitrifico</i>, to denitrify; M.L. part. adj. <i>halodenitrificans</i>, salt [-requiring] and denitrifying)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (0.6 to 0.8 by 2.5 to 4.0 μm) and occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Anaerobically grown cells are often more elongated and flexuous, with lengths of up to 15 μm.</s><s>Motile with frequent spinning and twisting.</s><s>Only a few flagella are observed in both lateral and polar arrangements.</s><s>Gram stain variable.</s><s>Asporulated.</s><s>On solid, complex media containing 10% salt, colonies are entire, smooth, semitranslucent, cream colored, and about 2 mm in diameter; darkening and limited spreading occur after extended incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultative anaerobe capable of anaerobic growth only when nitrate (or nitrite) is present.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite and nitrous oxide; no dinitrogen produced.</s><s>Moderate halophile.</s><s>The salinity range for growth is between 0.35 and 4.35 M, with an optimum between 0.5 and 1.35 M NaCl.</s><s>Salt requirement not specific for sodium or chloride ions.</s><s>Grows in anaerobic liquid media containing up to 1.65 M (14%) NaNO<sub>3</sub> or 0.29 M (2%) NaNO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.8 to 9.6 (optimum pH, around 7.4).</s><s>Grows at temperatures ranging from 10 to 45°C (optimum temperature, around 38°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Requires growth factors and an organic (reduced) sulfur source.</s><s>Utilizes ammonia and glutamine as nitrogen sources, but not nitrate, arginine, or urea.</s><s>Grows well on fructose, mannose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, maltose, sucrose, fumarate, lactate, L-malate, pyruvate, succinate, glycerol, mannitol, alanine, asparagine, aspartate, glutamine, glutamate, serine, threonine, and tryptophan as carbon and energy sources and more slowly on lactose, acetate, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, proline, and valine.</s><s>Does not grow on xylose, D- and L-arabinose, butyrate, citrate, formate, propionate, ethanol, methanol, sorbitol, arginine, cysteine, glycine, lysine, methionine, and phenylalanine.</s><s>Produces acid (weakly) but no gas from glucose.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase positive.</s><s>Hydrolyzes gelatin and casein but not starch, esculin, or Tween 80.</s><s>β-Galactosidase positive.</s><s>Urease, deoxyribonuclease, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, and lecithinase negative.</s><s>Indole negative.</s><s>Does not produce dihydroxyacetone from glycerol or hydrogen sulfide from cysteine.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer reaction negative.</s><s>Does not decompose tyrosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to streptomycin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), and novobiocin (30 μg), but not to penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (300 U), or vibriostatic agent O/129.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces a menaquinone of the MK-7 type.</s><s>Contains large amounts of type b and c cytochromes that confer a pinkish orange color to concentrated cell suspensions.</s><s>Synthesizes a nonheme, copper-containing nitrite reductase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a solar evaporation pond (saltern) in Berre l'étang, France.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A subculture of <i>B. halodenitrificans</i> has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strain ATCC 49067; this is the type strain by monotypy.</s></p></content></protolog>