<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8547_nm.13480" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13480" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13480" rank="species">Nocardioides daphniae</organism><reference id="rid.8547"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tóth</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kéki</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Homonnay</surname><given-names>Z.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Borsodi</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márialigeti</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides daphniae sp. nov., isolated from Daphnia cucullata (Crustacea: Cladocera).</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>78</fpage><lpage>83</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65305-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175687</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides daphniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides daphniae</em> (daph′ni.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>daphniae</em> pertaining to the water flea genus <em>Daphnia</em>, as the type strain was isolated from <em>Daphnia cucullata</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive bacterium.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, short rods or coccoids (0.8–1.0×1.2–2.2 μm).</s><s>Colonies on King B agar medium are circular, convex, smooth, glistening and of yellowish colour.</s><s>Spores and mycelia are not formed.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–38 °C, with optimum growth at 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.5–10.5, with optimum growth between pH 7 and 9.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs on King B and nutrient agar.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Negative for the Voges–Proskauer and <em>α</em>-glucosidase reactions.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Haemolysin is not detected.</s><s>Positive for production of chitinase.</s><s>Weakly positive for caseinase.</s><s>d-Fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannose, trehalose, d-ribose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, psicose, sorbitol, stachyose, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, methylpyruvate, glycyl l-glutamic acid, pyruvic acid, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate and uridine 5′-monophosphate are utilized as sole carbon source.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, d-mannitol, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-xylose, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycerol, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, lactulose, maltotriose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, salicin, sedoheptulosan, tagatose, xylitol, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, l-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-serine, putrescine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, fucose, 3-methyl glucose, turanose, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, l-glutamic acid, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, and glucose 1-phosphate are not utilized.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid of the peptidoglycan is ll-2,6 diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol occur as polar lipids.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69.9 mol%.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, D287<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18664<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7403<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the water flea <em>Daphnia cucullata</em> originating from Lake Balaton in Hungary.</s></p></content></protolog>