<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3308_nm.7865" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7865" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7865" rank="species">Treponema lecithinolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.3308"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wyss</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüpbach</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moter</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guggenheim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Göbel</surname><given-names>U.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema lecithinolyticum sp. nov., a small saccharolytic spirochaete with phospholipase A and C activities associated with periodontal diseases.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1329</fpage><lpage>1339</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1329</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555310</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema lecithinolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema lecithinolyticum</i> (le.ci.thi.no.ly'ti.cum. Gr. n. <i>lekithos</i> egg yolk; Gr. v. <i>lytikos</i> able to loose, dissolve ; M.L. adj. <i>lecithinolyticum</i> effecting the breakdown of egg yolk)</s></p><p class="description"><s>An obligately anaerobic, helically coiled, motile treponeme.</s><s>Cells are approximately 5 x 0.15 μm, with a wavelength of 0-7 μm and an amplitude of 0.3 μm.</s><s>They contain two periplasmic flagella, one originating at each cell end and overlapping in the central region of the cell.</s><s>In liquid media, flexing and rotation of cells does not appear to result in directional motility.</s><s>However, in media of higher viscosity, or when cells creep along a surface, translational movement is readily detectable.</s><s>Cells can be stored frozen (liquid nitrogen or mechanical freezer) in OMIZ-Pat-w/oPC medium supplemented with 10-20 % glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When streaked onto OMIZ-Pat-w/oPC agarose, <i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> forms off-white, diffuse subsurface colonies up to 3 mm in diameter within 7 d incubation at 37°C. <i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> does not grow in the chemically defined medium OMIZ-W 1, but requires addition of yeast extract and/or Neopeptone (or fractions thereof).</s><s>Growth is inhibited by lecithin, which must be omitted from the media formulation (OMIZ-Pat-w/oPC).</s><s>Growth is strictly dependent on N-acetylglucosamine and is strongly enhanced by further addition of D-arabinose, L-fucose or D-ribose ; some strains also respond to D-fructose (excluding OMZ 684<sup>T</sup>) and/or to D-xylose (including OMZ 684<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Growth is not influenced by L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucose, D-glucuronic acid, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, D-sucrose, D-trehalose or L-xylose.</s><s>Heat-inactivated human serum (1 % v/v) is tolerated or stimulatory, whereas 1 % foetal calf serum is completely inhibitory.</s><s>All strains are resistant to rifampicin (1 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and fosfomycin (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In all eight isolates, activities of alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, phospholipase A and phospholipase C are prominent, whereas only intermediate activities of C4-esterase, C8-esterase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and α-fucosidase are expressed.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>OMZ 684<sup>T</sup>, OMZ 685 and BL2B have strong sialidase activity (the other five strains were not tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> is phylogenetically distinct from other cultivable treponemes on the basis of its 16s rRNA sequence.</s><s>Protein and antigen patterns (SDSPAGE) are also readily distinguished from those of other cultivable treponemes, though more conventional criteria may suffice to distinguish it from the seven previously characterized oral spirochaetes.</s><s>Simultaneous expression of strong activities of phospholipase C, phospholipase A, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and sialidase and intermediate activities of C4-esterase, C8-esterase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and a-fucosidase distinguish <i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> from all other oral spirochaetes.</s><s>Size, flagellation and growth characteristics additionally distinguish it from <i>T. amylovorum</i>, <i>T. denticola</i>, <i>T. medium</i> and '<i>T. vincentii</i>'.</s><s>Finally, <i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> is phenotypically distinguished from the two other lecithinolytic isolates described in this report, OMZ 702 and BL2A (which are phylogenetically classified as <i>T. maltophilum</i>), by its protein profile after SDS-PAGE, by a prominent antigen of ~30 kDa and by activities of phospholipase A, sialidase, β-glucuronidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. lecithinolyticum</i> has thus far been detected only in human subgingival plaque, with a strong association suggested for diseased versus control sites in patients with adult periodontitis and rapidly progressive periodontitis.</s><s>Strains OMZ 684<sup>T</sup> and OMZ 685, isolated from subgingival plaque of human deep periodontal lesions, have been designated as type and reference strains and deposited under accession numbers ATCC 700332<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 700333, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>