<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7451_nm.2027" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2027" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2027" rank="species">Azoarcus toluclasticus</organism><reference id="rid.7451"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Häggblom</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palleroni</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic characterization of denitrifying bacteria that degrade aromatic compounds and description of Azoarcus toluvorans sp. nov. and Azoarcus toluclasticus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1129</fpage><lpage>1140</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1129</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425771</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azoarcus toluclasticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azoarcus toluclasticus</i> (to.lu.clas'ti.cus. N.L. n. Fr. Sp. <i>tolu</i> balsam from Santiago de Tolu, toluene; Gr. adj. <i>clasticus</i> breaking; M.L. adj. <i>toluclasticus</i> toluene-breaking)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The members of groups 3 and 4 (strains MF7, MF23, MF58, MF63<sup>T</sup> and MF441) among the isolates from Moffett Field are assigned to this new species.</s><s>The strains are short motile rods with polar monotrichous flagellation and can grow on acetate, benzoate, pyruvate, succinate, D-xylose, L-arabinose, D-ribose, Dgalactose, sucrose, lactose, maltose, adipate, lactate, mannitol, aspar tate, proline or arginine under aerobic and denitrifying conditions.</s><s>All strains except strain MF23 can use toluene as a growth substrate and strains MF58 and MF63<sup>T</sup> can also grow on phenol under denitrifying conditions.</s><s>The strains grow on brain-heart infusion, nutrient and trypticase soy agar, except for strain MF63<sup>T</sup>, which does not grow on nutrient agar.</s><s>The oxidase test is positive and the catalase test is negative.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 16:O and 16:1ω7c.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 67.3 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetic analyses of 16s rRNA and DNA-DNA hybridization show the relatedness of strains to the genus <i>Azoarcus</i> and the differences from the species <i>A. tolulyticus</i>.</s><s>Thus, strains MF58, MF63<sup>T</sup> and MF441 are considered to be members of a new species, <i>Azoarcus toluclasticus</i>, and strains MF7 and MF23 represent a genomovar of this species.</s><s>The type strain is MF63<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700605<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>