<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3492_nm.6364" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6364" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6364" rank="species">Mycobacterium interjectum</organism><reference id="rid.3492"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirschner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rost-Meyer</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schröder</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Böttger</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium interjectum, a new species isolated from a patient with chronic lymphadenitis</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>3083</fpage><lpage>3089</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7508452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium interjectum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium interjectum</i> (in.ter.jec'tum, L. neut. adj. of <i>interiectus</i></s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Mycobacterium interjectum</i> corresponding to the phylogenetic position between rapid and slow-growing mycobacteria) is an acid-alcohol-fast, rod-shaped coccobacillus (0.6 to 1.0 μm by 0.7 to 2.0 μm) which may exhibit few filaments (up to 6.0 μm).</s><s>It does not form spores, a capsule, or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Visible growth from a dilute inoculum requires 3 to 4 weeks; colonies on LJ agar are dysgonic, smooth, scotochromogenic, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of between 31 and 37°C.</s><s>The organism is susceptible in vitro to rifampin; it is resistant in vitro to isoniazid and ethambutol.</s><s>It is positive in reactions for urease, nicotinamidase, α-esterase, pyrazinamidase, and heat-stable catalase.</s><s>It is negative in reactions for niacin production, nitrate reduction, Tween hydrolysis, β-esterase, acetamidase, benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, and succinidamidase. <i>M. interjectum</i> synthesizes α-, keto-, ω-carboxy-, and epoxy-mycolates.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis, based on an evaluation of 16S rRNA sequences, places <i>M. interjectum</i> in an intermediate position between rapid and slow-growing mycobacteria.</s><s>The type strain of <i>M. interjectum</i> is strain 4185/92.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures as strain DSM 44064.</s><s>It was isolated from a child with cervical lymphadenitis.</s></p></content></protolog>