<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2188_nm.2330" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2330" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2330" rank="species">Thiomicrospira crunogena</organism><reference id="rid.2188"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jannasch</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wirsen</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiomicrospira crunogena sp. nov., a colorless sulfur-oxidizing bacterium from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>422</fpage><lpage>424</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-422</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiomicrospira crunogena</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiomicrospira crunogena</i> (cru.no.ge'na. Gr. n. <i>crunos</i> spring; Gr. v. <i>genomai</i> to be generated; <i>crunogena</i> spring born)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new isolate (strain TH-55<sup>T</sup>) is a gram-negative vibrioid bacterium (0.4 to 0.5 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm) which is motile by means of a single, polar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>On T-ASW agar it produces white, smooth, entire colonies (diameter on 2% agar, 2 mm; diameter within 1% agar, up to 1 cm) in which sulfur is deposited and acid is produced, Isolate TH-55<sup>T</sup> is an obligate aerobe and does not denitrify.</s><s>However, it can grow under microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>It does not fix molecular nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 1 shows the major differences among isolate TH-55<sup>T</sup>, <i>T. pelophila</i>, and <i>T. denitrificans</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth did not occur in unsupplemented ASW medium or in ASW medium supplemented solely with organic substrates.</s><s>Isolate TH-55<sup>T</sup> oxidized and grew when thiosulfate, sulfide, or molecular sulfur was provided as an energy source but not with sulfite or thiocyanate.</s><s>The optimum concentration of sulfide for carbon dioxide fixation was 100 μM, and the rate was 80% of the rate of the T-ASW medium control.</s><s>Carbon dioxide fixation continued at sulfide concentrations up to 800 μM, and sulfide was toxic at a concentration of 2,000 μM.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> was the primary source of carbon.</s><s>During exponential growth, 8.5% of the CO<sub>2</sub> fixed was excreted as low-molecular-weight organic compounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The maximum growth rate of this organism, as determined by direct counts, was remarkably high compared with other <i>Thiomicrospira</i> species (Table 1 ) .</s><s>Therefore, the growth rate was checked by CO<sub>2</sub> fixation, observing precautions necessary for relating metabolite incorporation to growth rate (13).</s><s>The results obtained were in good agreement.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolate TH-55<sup>T</sup> can grow at pH values ranging between 5.0 and 8.5 and at temperatures ranging between 4.0 and 38.5°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 7.5 and 8.0, and the optimum temperature is between 28 and 32°C.</s><s>At 250 atmospheres (2.52 x 10<sup>4</sup> kPa), CO<sub>2</sub> fixation was 80% of that found at 1 atmosphere (1.01 x 10<sup>2</sup> kPa).</s><s>Growth did not occur at 400 atmospheres (4.04 x 10<sup>4</sup> kPa) or above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolate TH-55<sup>T</sup> requires NaCl at a concentration which is at least 10% of that of seawater for growth.</s><s>It does not require Mg<sup>2+</sup> or Ca<sup>2+</sup> concentrations above those found in the standard terrestrial-freshwater medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A culture of this organism has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 35932 and in the Delft Culture Collection as strain LMD 84.00; this is the type strain of the species <i>T. crunogena</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>