<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1232_nm.6489" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6489" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6489" rank="species">Rhodococcus marinonascens</organism><reference id="rid.1232"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Helmke</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weyland</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus marinonascens sp. nov., an actinomycete from the sea</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>138</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus marinonascens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodococcus marinonascens</i> (ma. ri. no. nas'cens. L. adj. <i>marinus</i> of the sea; L. part. adj. <i>nascent</i> nascent, born; M. L. part. adj. <i>marinonascens</i> nascent in the sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, slow-growing nocardioform actinomycetes that are isolated from marine bottom sediments and are unable to develop in freshwater media and at temperatures above 28°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs around 20°C and in media with a seawater content of 75 to 100% or an equivalent salt concentration. <i>R . marinonascens</i> is gram positive, nonmotile, and partially acid fast and develops well-branched mycelia which fragment into bacillary and coccoid elements on solid media after 14 or more days of incubation.</s><s>The colonies are cream-colored with a tinge of pink, irregularly wrinkled with lobate margins, and not easy to emulsify.</s><s>Aerial mycelia and extracellular pigments are not formed. <i>R. marinonascens</i> has a type IV cell wall composition and contains group C mycolic acids sensu Minnekin et al. and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) as the main menaquinone component.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 64.9 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. marinonascens</i> produces acid from glucose, fructose, mannose, inulin, and inositol.</s><s>Unlike many other <i>Rhodococcus</i> species, under the specific test conditions which we used, the strains exhibit no acid formation from sucrose, trehalose, mannitol, or ethanol and only weak acid production from dextrin.</s><s>Also in contrast to many other <i>Rhodococcus</i> species, <i>R . marinonascens</i> cannot utilize sodium benzoate, sodium citrate, L-proline, or testosterone as a sole carbon source, but L-α-alanine serves as a sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>Catalase is formed, whereas oxidase, urease, and nitrate reductase are not produced; esculin can be hydrolyzed. <i>R. marinonascens</i> is further characterized by high susceptibility to the antibiotics penicillin G, rifampin, and vancomycin and the inhibitors crystal violet, sodium azide, potassium tellurite, phenyl ethanol, and phenol; on the other hand, this organism is relatively resistant to lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: 3438W (= DSM 43752)</s></p></content></protolog>