<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8619_nm.13431" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13431" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13431" rank="species">Microbacterium aquimaris</organism><reference id="rid.8619"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium aquimaris sp. nov., isolated from seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1616</fpage><lpage>1620</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65763-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium aquimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium aquimaris</em> (a.qui.ma′ris. L. n. <em>aqua</em> water; L. n. <em>mare</em> -<em>is</em> sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>aquimaris</em> of seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, short rods, 0.6–0.8 μm in diameter and 1.0–1.5 μm long.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and at pH 6–10 (optimum, pH 7–8).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, translucent and circular with entire edges.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin, starch and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase is produced, but arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and lysine decarboxylase are not produced.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is positive, but the methyl red test is negative.</s><s>In the API 50 CH gallery, acid is produced from aesculin, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose (weakly), galactose (weakly), gluconate (weakly), glucose, glycerol (weakly), 5-ketogluconate (weakly), maltose, mannitol, mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose (weakly), ribose (weakly), salicin and turanose (weakly), but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, trehalose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>5-Ketogluconate is utilized as a sole carbon source, but acetate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, l-alanine, l-arabinose, caprate, citrate, l-fucose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycogen, histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, dl-lactate, malate, malonate, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, l-serine, d-sorbitol, suberate, sucrose and valerate are not.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-11 (48.2±0.9 % of total quinones), MK-12 (28.2±4.6 %) and MK-10 (17.0±3.8 %).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 15 : 0 anteiso (34.4±0.8 %), 17 : 0 anteiso (34.2±1.4 %) and 16 : 0 iso (20.5±0.4 %).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is of the B2<em>β</em> type [(l-Hsr)–d-Glu(Hyg)→Gly→d-Orn] with glycolyl residues.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose and glucose.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69.3–69.6 mol% (69.3 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JS54-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19124<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19713<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater at Jeju, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>