<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3156_nm.2342" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2342" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2342" rank="species">Legionella anisa</organism><reference id="rid.3156"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gorman</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Feeley</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Edelstein</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella anisa: a new species of Legionella isolated from potable waters and a cooling tower.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>305</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3985609</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella anisa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella anisa</i> ((a'ni.sa) Gr. adj. <i>anisos</i> unequal; N.L. fem. adj. <i>anisa</i> unequal, referring to the fact that blue-white autofluorescence is seen in most but not all strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic characteristics of <i>L. anisa</i> fit the definition of the family <i>Legionellaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Legionella</i>. <i>L. anisa</i> grew on CYE and BCYE agars but not on media lacking L-cysteine HCI.</s><s>It is a gram-negative rod that is motile by means of a few polar, subpolar, or lateral flagella.</s><s>It is positive in catalase, gelatinase, and reactions for beta-lactamase and produces a brown, diffusible pigment on tyrosine-yeast extract agar.</s><s>It is negative in reactions for oxidase, urease, tyrosine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, hydrolysis of hippurate, and acid production from carbohydrates (D-glucose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, lactose, sucrose, and maltose).</s><s>With a Woods light (366 nm), we found that colonies of four of the strains autofluoresced blue-white, whereas the remaining strain, CH-47-C3, did not.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of DNA from the type strain was 42 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s><s>All <i>L. anisa</i> strains contain predominantly branched-chain fatty acids and ubiquinones with 10 or more isoprene units.</s><s>All strains were isolated from potable or industrial water; none were associated with disease in humans or animals.</s><s>The type strain of <i>L. anisa</i> is WA-316-C3 (ATCC 35292).</s><s>It was solated by one of us (G.W.G.) from tap water from the Veterans Administration Medical Center, Wadsworth Division, Los Angeles.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are the same as those given for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>