<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6867_nm.6117" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6117" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6117" rank="species">Cryobacterium psychrophilum</organism><reference id="rid.6867"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uramoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakase</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cryobacterium psychrophilum gen. nov., sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov., an obligately psychrophilic actinomycete to accommodate Curtobacterium psychrophilum Inoue and Komagata 1976.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>474</fpage><lpage>478</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-474</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103638</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cryobacterium psychrophilum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cryobacterium psychrophilum</i> (psy.chro'phi.lum. Gr. adj. <i>psychros</i>, cold; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i>, loving; M. L. fem. adj. <i>psychrophilum</i>, cold loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(basonym "<i>Curtobacterium psychrophilum</i>" Inoue and Komagata 1976).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonmotile, non-endospore- forming, pleomorphic rod 0.5 to 0.7 μm by 1.0 to 1.8 μm in culture on R agar for 5 days at 10°C.</s><s>Circular, opaque pink colonies are formed in 5 days of culture on R agar at 10°C.</s><s>Branching occurs in the early growth phase.</s><s>Rod forms occur in old culture.</s><s>Occasionally gram variable in the old culture.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>DNase and catalase are positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, mannose, glucose, galactose, and sucrose but not from arabinose, mannitol, and glycerol.</s><s>Lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, and hippurate are utilized.</s><s>Gelatin and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 65 mol%.</s><s>2,4-Diaminobutyric acid, alanine, glycine, and glutamic acid are the component amino acids of cell wall peptidoglycan, in the ratio 1.3:0.6:1.0:1.0.</s><s>Rhamnose and fucose are the characteristic cell wall sugars.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are isoand anteiso-branched acids.</s><s>12-Methyl tetradecenoic acid (a-C15:1) accounts for approximately 20% of the cellular fatty acids in cells grown at 10°C.</s><s>The MK composition is predominantly MK-10, followed by MK-11 and MK-8.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and glycolipid.</s><s>The type strain of <i>C. psychrophilum</i> is JCM 1463 (=K.</s><s>Inoue and K.</s><s>Komagata 27-0-b=IAM 12024=ATCC 43563=IFO 15735=NCIMB 2068).</s></p></content></protolog>