<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2770_nm.812" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.812" rank="genus">Rhodospirillum</organism><reference id="rid.2770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petri</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of species of the spiral-shaped phototrophic purple non-sulfur bacteria of the alpha-Proteobacteria: description of the new genera Phaeospirillum gen. nov., Rhodovibrio gen. nov., Rhodothalassium gen. nov. and Roseospira gen. nov. as well as transfer of Rhodospirillum fulvum to Phaeospirillum fulvum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum molischianum to Phaeospirillum molischianum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum salinarum to Rhodovibrio salexigens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>793</fpage><lpage>798</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734033</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Rhodospirillum</i> (Molisch 1907)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodospirillum</i> (Rho.do.spi.ril'lum. Gr. n. <i>rhodon</i> the rose; M.L. neut. n. <i>Spirillum</i> a bacterial genus; M.L. neut. n. <i>Rhodospirillum</i> the rose <i>Spirillum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are vibrioid- to spiral-shaped, 0.8-1.5 μm wide, motile by means of polar flagella, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>They belong to the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i> and have a G + C content between 63 and 66 mol %.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are present as vesicles or lamellae, contain bacteriochlorophyll a and various carotenoids as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Contain ubiquinones and rhodoquinones.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria without a requirement for NaCl or sea salt for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs preferably photo-organotrophically under anoxic conditions in the light, but is also possible under micro-oxic to oxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Growth factors are required.</s><s>Known species of the genus are <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> (Molisch 1907) and <i>Rhodospirillum photometricum</i> (Molisch 1907).</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>