<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11587_nm.18622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18622" rank="species">Bacillus horneckiae</organism><reference id="rid.11587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaishampayan</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Probst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McDowall</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruckmani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venkateswaran</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus horneckiae sp. nov., isolated from a spacecraft-assembly clean room</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1031</fpage><lpage>1037</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008979-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666815</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus horneckiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus horneckiae</em> (hor.nec′ki.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>horneckiae</em> of Horneck, named after Dr Gerda Horneck, a German space microbiologist who carried out pioneering work in exposing spores to several space and radiation conditions).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rod-shaped, 1–1.5 μm in diameter and 4–6 μm long, motile and Gram-stain-positive and form endospores that are subterminal in position.</s><s>Grows under aerobic conditions only.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Colonies formed after 24 h of growth on TSA at 32 °C are yellowish, plain, 3 mm in diameter, show no pigmentation and possess irregular edges.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 30 °C; known strains do not grow below 4 °C or at 50 °C.</s><s>Cells grow in the absence of NaCl and with up to 10 % (w/v) NaCl and up to pH 10.8 with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Produces oval spores in MSM which are resistant to UV radiation up to 1000 J m<sup>−2</sup>.</s><s>Reduces nitrates to nitrites and hydrolyses gelatin.</s><s>Tests for oxidase, indole production, fermentation of glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, hydrolysis of aesculin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG) are negative.</s><s>Assimilates the following as sole carbon sources: maltose, potassium gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate.</s><s>d-Glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, decanoic acid and 2-phenylacetic acid are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following substrates: glycerol, erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction is positive for strains 1P01SC<sup>T</sup> and 1P02SA and weakly positive for three other strains.</s><s>The major fatty acid of strains 1P01SC<sup>T</sup> and 1P08SA is iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid in the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35.6±0.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1P01SC<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-59162<sup>T</sup> =MTCC 9535<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surfaces of the PHSF located at the Kennedy Space Center, where the Phoenix spacecraft was assembled.</s><s>Strains 1P08SA (=MTCC 9536), 1P10SC, 1P10SE and 1P02SA are additional strains of the species, isolated from the same source.</s></p></content></protolog>