<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.14661_nm.24940" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.24940" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.24940" rank="species">Gracilibacillus quinghaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.14661"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus quinghaiensis sp. nov., isolated from salt-lake sediment in the Qaidam Basin, north-west China</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>31</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>183</fpage><lpage>189</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2008.05.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18571887</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilibacillus quinghaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>G. quinghaiensis</em> (quing.hai.en'sis, N.L. fem. adj.) pertains to Qinghai, Western province of China, where the type strain was isolated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive, catalase- and oxidase-positive, obligately aerobic thin rods (4–6×0.4–0.6 μm) that occur predominantly in flexible chains (4–8 cells).</s><s>Filamentous forms are present throughout the growth cycle.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in terminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 4–5 days on Difco marine agar 2216 at 37 °C, colonies are circular, transparent with slightly irregular margins, 1–1.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>The colour varies with culture time from creamy white to pale pink.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–45 °C (optimum 37 °C) and pH 6.0–8.5 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).</s><s>It is slightly halophilic, with growth at 0.5–8% (w/v) NaCl [optimum 1–3% (w/v) NaCl], and is positive for hydrolysis of chitin, aesculin and urea, and negative for hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 80.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>It is resistant to nalidixic acid (20 μg), and sensitive to ampicillin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), licomycin (2 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>It gave positive results for oxidation of arabinose, inositol and sorbitol, and fermentation of glucose, and negative result for citrate utilization (API 20E).</s><s>It can produce acid from d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol, d-sorbitol, d-turanose, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate (API 50CH) and can oxidize amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-frucose, d-galatose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, l-alanine and l-asparagine (Biolog GP2).</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed by YIM-C229<sup>T</sup> are acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase(C4), esterase lipase(C8), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease (API ZYM, API 20E).</s><s>Menaquinone 7 (MK-7) is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (making up 78.8% of the total) are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>, containing <em>meso</em>-diamonopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 40.9 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetic placement based on 16S rRNA gene sequence affiliates the strain to the genus <em>Gracilibacillus</em>, but there is evidence for divergence from the previously recognized four species in this genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM-C229<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17858<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6304<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sediment sample collected from the Xiaochaidamu salt lake in the Qaidam Basin in Qinghai province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>