<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7171_nm.4185" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4185" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4185" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus octavius</organism><reference id="rid.7171"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murdoch</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magee</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of three new species of the genus Peptostreptococcus from human clinical specimens: Peptostreptococcus harei sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus ivorii sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus octavius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>781</fpage><lpage>787</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-781</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus octavius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus octavius</i> (oc.ta'vi.m. L. adj. <i>octavius</i>, eighth, referring to the fact that the organism was previously assigned to Hare group VIII)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, gram-positive cocci (diameter, 0.7 to 0.9 μm) that occur in clumps.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are less than 1 mm in diameter after incubation for 48 h; after 5 days, they are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, yellow-white, glistening, circular, entire, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>Indole, urease, ALP, coagulase, and ADH are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Catalase production is variable.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, ribose, and mannose, but not from lactose, raffinose, trehalose, cellobiose, or arabinose.</s><s>Acid production from maltose, sucrose, sorbitol, and mannitol is variable.</s><s>The proteolytic enzymes proline AMD and pyroglutamyl AMD are produced as determined with the ATB 32A preformed enzyme system (MI-BioMerieux), but saccharolytic enzymes are not detected.</s><s>The major VFAs produced in Robertson's cooked meat broth are butyric, isovaleric, and n-caproic acids. <i>P. octavius</i> has been isolated from intranasal specimens, skin, and normal vaginal flora (20, 24).</s><s>The type strain, NCTC 9810, was isolated from normal nasal flora.</s><s>Strain NCTC 9810<sup>T</sup> does not form catalase; weak acid is produced from sorbitol but not from maltose, mannitol, or sucrose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain NCTC 9810<sup>T</sup> is 28 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>