<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1461_nm.865" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.865" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.865" rank="species">Acetobacter diazotrophicus</organism><reference id="rid.1461"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stephan</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Teixeira</surname><given-names>K.R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acetobacter diazotrophicus sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing acetic acid bacterium associated with sugarcane.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>361</fpage><lpage>364</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-361</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetobacter diazotrophicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetobacter diazotrophicus</i> (di.a.zo.tro'phi.cus.Gr.prefix <i>di</i>, two, double; N.L.n. <i>azotum</i>, nitrogen; Gr.adj. <i>trophikos</i>, nursing, tending or feeding; M.L. masc. adj. <i>diazotrophicus</i>, one that feeds on dinitrogen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods with rounded ends, about 0.7 to 0.9 by ±2 μm.</s><s>Long involution forms occur in unshaken rich liquid media.</s><s>Motile by lateral or peritrichous flagella (Fig. 2).</s><s>Produces brown water-soluble pigments on GYC medium.</s><s>Dark brown colonies are formed on potato agar supplemented with 10% sucrose, and dark orange colonies are formed on a nitrogen-poor medium containing bromothymol blue (1).</s><s>Forms 2-ketogluconic acid and 2,5-diketogluconic acid from glucose.</s><s>These organisms are microaerobic dinitrogen fixers which grow on N<sub>2</sub> as a sole nitrogen source in semisolid media and after initial growth with starter nitrogen in liquid media; they grow well in liquid media with combined nitrogen sources.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, and N<sub>2</sub> fixation occurs at high nitrate concentrations (10 mM).</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is around 30°C, and the optimum pH is 5.5.</s><s>Does not grow at pH 7.0, but does grow and fix N<sub>2</sub> at pH values below 3.0.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not formed from L-cysteine, except by some strains when they are grown in a medium containing sucrose instead of glucose.</s><s>Grows well in mineral media containing NH<sub>4</sub>+.</s><s>Growth is poor on organic acids, but acetate and lactate are oxidized to CO<sub>2</sub> and water.</s><s>High concentrations (10%) of sucrose are the best carbon source for growth, but glucose, fructose, and galactose are also used.</s><s>Growth and N<sub>2</sub> fixation occur with 30% glucose or 30% sucrose.</s><s>Ethanol (1%), mannitol, and glycerol are also used as carbon sources.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is C<sub>18:1</sub> acid.</s><s>The ubiquinone type is QlO.</s><s>Other features are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The average guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 61 to 63 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The habitat is roots and stems of sugarcane.</s><s>The type strain is strain LMG 7603 (= Döbereiner PA 5 = ATCC 49037).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain. <i>A . diazotrophicus</i> LMG 7603<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>Ketogenesis from glycerol is positive, and the guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 61 mol%.</s><s>This strain was isolated by V.</s><s>Cavalcante and J.</s><s>Dobereiner in 1987 from sugarcane roots in Alagoas, Brazil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Recently, we found that sugarcane isolates from Australia also belong in <i>A . diazotrophicus</i> according to their growth characteristics, protein gel electropherograms, and N<sub>2</sub>-fixing ability.</s></p></content></protolog>