<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5868_nm.6199" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6199" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6199" rank="species">Corynebacterium aurimucosum</organism><reference id="rid.5868"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium aurimucosum sp. nov. and emended description of Corynebacterium minutissimum Collins and Jones (1983).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1001</fpage><lpage>1005</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02045-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054216</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium aurimucosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium aurimucosum</i> (au.ri.mu.co'sum. L. n. <i>aurum</i> gold; L. neut. adj. <i>mucosum</i> slimy; N.L. adj. <i>aurimucosum</i> slimy and gold-coloured, pertaining to the appearance of colonies)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive and non-acid-fast.</s><s>They are thin, non-motile, non-spore-forming and pleomorphic coryneform.</s><s>On Columbia blood agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood, the colonies are sticky and slightly yellow in colour.</s><s>On trypticase soy agar they appear colourless and slimy.</s><s>On BHI agar supplemented with 1% Tween 80 some strains are able to form a coralloid precipitin in agar when grown in the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth is facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>It contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e. the cell-wall chemotype is chemotype IV).</s><s>Short-chain corynemycolic acids are present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile contains saturated, unsaturated and tuberculostearic acids.</s><s>It has type PI phospholipid pattern with no nitrogen-containing compounds.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, glucose, maltose and sucrose but not from adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>It hydrolysed hippurate but not aesculin, gelatin or starch.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and pyrazinamidase activities, but negative for acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), lipase (C14), α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucoseaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, naphthol-AS-bi-phosphohydrolase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chemotrypsin, nitrate reductase and urease activities.</s><s>Acetoin-positive, indole-negative.</s><s>Lactate is the major product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>The G+C content of the type species is 63.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Corynebacterium aurimucosum</i> is strain IMMIB D-1488<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44532<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>