<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12561_nm.21794" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21794" rank="genus">Trueperella</organism><reference id="rid.12561"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siering</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comparative chemotaxonomic and phylogenetic studies on the genus Arcanobacterium Collins et al. 1982 emend. Lehnen et al. 2006: proposal for Trueperella gen. nov. and emended description of the genus Arcanobacterium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1265</fpage><lpage>1274</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020032-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20622055</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Trueperella</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Trueperella</em> (tru.e.pe.rel′la. N.L. fem. n. <em>trueperella</em> named after Hans Georg Trüper, the German microbiologist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming coccobacilli and short rods that occur singly, in pairs (V, T and palisade formations) or in clusters.</s><s>Cells vary in shape and size (0.2–0.9×0.3–2.5) in different media.</s><s>Cells from 24-hour-old broth cultures are Gram-reaction-positive, but may be Gram-reaction-variable in older cultures.</s><s>Pinpoint, β-haemolytic colonies occur on sheep’s blood agar after 24 h of incubation.</s><s>After 48–72 h of incubation, colonies are 0.5–1.5 mm in diameter, convex, circular and translucent with entire edges.</s><s>Aerobic and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Strictly fermentative.</s><s>Lactic acid is the primary metabolic product in glucose–yeast extract broth but acetate and succinate are minor products.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the type A5α, variations l-Lys–l-Ala–l-Lys–d-Glu or l-Lys–l-Lys–d-Glu.</s><s>The muramic acid residue of the peptidoglycan is <em>N</em>-acetylated.</s><s>Characteristic whole-cell sugars are rhamnose and glucose.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are primarily straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated in addition to traces of branched-chain fatty acids of the iso-/anteiso-type.</s><s>The phospholipid type is type PI according to Lechevalier <em>et al.</em> (1977), comprising DPG, PG, PI and a PGL of unknown composition.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 56–66 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Trueperella pyogenes.</em></s></p></content></protolog>