<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1403_nm.2767" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2767" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2767" rank="species">Acinetobacter baumannii</organism><reference id="rid.1403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>P.J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of the genus Acinetobacter with the recognition of Acinetobacter baumannii sp. nov., Acinetobacter haemolyticus sp. nov., Acinetobacter johnsonii sp. nov., and Acinetobacter junii sp. nov., and emended descriptions of Acinetobacter calcoaceticus and Acinetobacter lwoffii.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>228</fpage><lpage>240</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-228</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acinetobacter baumannii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acinetobacter baumannii</i> (bau.ma´ni.i. M. L. gen. <i>baumannii</i> in honor of Paul and Linda Baumann, American bacteriologists)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Also called genospecies 2 in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics as given previously for the genus (19, 20).</s><s>Colonies on tryptocasein soy agar are circular, convex, smooth, and slightly opaque with entire margins and sometimes have a butyrous aspect.</s><s>Colonies are 1.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter after 24 h and 3.0 to 4.0 mm in diameter after 48 h at 30°C.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 15 to 44°C.</s><s>Occasional strains may require methionine for growth on minimal medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites in complex medium (exceptions occur).</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose by most strains.</s><s>Strains which produce acid from D-glucose also produce β-xylosidase.</s><s>γ-Glutamyltransferase is produced by most strains.</s><s>Horse or sheep blood is not hemolyzed; gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate (Simmons) is utilized by prototrophic strains.</s><s>Auxotrophic strains utilize citrate when the medium is supplemented with a growth factor.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized: DL-lactate, glutarate, L-aspartate, L-tyrosine, ethanol, 2,3-butanediol, and DL-4-aminobutyrate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized by most strains: L-phenylalanine and phenylacetate (growth on L-phenylalanine is associated with growth on phenylacetate in this species), L-histidine, azelate, D-malate, L-leucine, β-alanine, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, L-arginine, and L-ornithine.</s><s>Histamine is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40 to 43 mol% (as determined by thermal denaturation [17]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens or the natural environment.</s><s>Most <i>Acinetobacter</i> strains isolated from human patients belong to this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CIP 70.34 (= ATCC 19606).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain CIP 70.34<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain utilizes L-phenylalanine, phenylacetate, malonate, L-histidine, azelate, D-malate, L-leucine, L-arginine, and <i>trans</i>-aconitate as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>β-Alanine and L-ornithine are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose.</s><s>γ-Glutamyltransferase and β-xylosidase are produced.</s><s>Isolated from human urine.</s></p></content></protolog>