<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9168_nm.14368" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14368" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14368" rank="species">Saccharospirillum salsuginis</organism><reference id="rid.9168"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharospirillum salsuginis sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium from a subterranean brine.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1382</fpage><lpage>1386</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003616-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502320</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharospirillum salsuginis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharospirillum salsuginis</em> (sal.su′gi.nis. L. gen. fem. n. <em>salsuginis</em> of/from brine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, catalase- and oxidase-positive, obligately aerobic spirilla (0.5–0.7×3.5–7.5 μm), motile with monopolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex, translucent, white–beige-coloured and 2–3 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days on MA supplemented with 3 % (w/v) NaCl at 37 °C.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, mesophilic and facultatively alkaliphilic, with growth occurring in 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 5 %) and at 15–50 °C (optimum 37 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum pH 8.0).</s><s>NaCl cannot be replaced by MgCl<sub>2 </sub>.<sub> </sub>6H<sub>2</sub>O or KCl in media.</s><s>Aesculin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, Tweens 20, 40 and 60, urea and xanthine are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole is produced, but H<sub>2</sub>S is not.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, malate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline and l-tryptophan.</s><s>The following substances are not utilized: melezitose, d-salicin, d-xylose, adonitol, glycerol, butyrate, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, malonate, propionate, succinate, l-arginine, l-cystine, l-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine and l-valine.</s><s>Acids are produced from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose (API 50CH).</s><s>Constitutively expressed enzymes are acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase (API ZYM).</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The main respiratory quinone is Q-8 (98.2 % in the type strain); Q-9 is present in trace amounts.</s><s>Polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethylamine and an unidentified phospholipid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM-Y25<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 207033<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22169<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a subterranean brine sample collected from the Yipinglang salt mine in Yunnan, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>