<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1324_nm.4260" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4260" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4260" rank="species">Eubacterium nodatum</organism><reference id="rid.1324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burmeister</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Descriptions of Eubacterium timidum sp. nov., Eubacterium brachy sp. nov., and Eubacterium nodatum sp. nov. isolated from human periodontitis.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-1-163</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium nodatum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium nodatum</i> (no.da'tum. L. neut. participle <i>nodatum</i> entangled [referring to the tangled arrangement of the cells]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>E. nodatum</i> are obligately anaerobic, grampositive, nonmotile, nonsporeforming rods that occur in clumps in broth cultures.</s><s>A small clump is shown in Fig. 1C to illustrate the shape of the cells.</s><s>Most clumps were much larger.</s><s>Cells were 0.5 to 0.9 by 2 to 12 μm.</s><s>Cells appeared branched,</s></p><p class="description"><s>somewhat filamentous, or club shaped.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days in roll tubes, colonies of all strains were 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, transluscent to opaque, and raspberry shaped.</s><s>After incubation for to 2 to 4 days, surface colonies on BHIA streak tubes or anaerobically incubated BAP were less than 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter, generally circular, entire to lobate, and heaped or with a berry-like appearance.</s><s>The type strain and five other strains tested produced no hemolysis around colonies on anaerobically incubated BAP, and they did not grow on egg yolk agar plates incubated anaerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Broth cultures of all strains were not turbid and had flocculent, granular, or bread-crumb-type sediment.</s><s>Growth was inhibited by 2% oxgall but was neither inhibited nor enhanced by the addition of 0.02% Tween 80, 5% lumen fluid, or 10% serum with cocarboxylase.</s><s>The temperature for optimum growth was 37°C; most strains also grew at 30 and 45°C.</s><s>Only an occasional strain grew at 25°C.</s><s>Growth occurred only in the anaerobic portion of agar deep cultures.</s><s>There was no growth on the surface of BAP incubated in air enriched with CO<sub>2</sub> to 5%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions.</s><s>In addition to the characteristics given in Table 2, no gas was detected in agar deep cultures.</s><s>Growth of the type strain and five other strains tested (each isolated from a different person) was inhibited by 6.5% NaCl but not by 0.05% SPS.</s><s>Ammonia was produced in PY broth cultures, and neutral red was usually reduced by these six strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major product detected from PY or PY-glucose broth cultures of all strains after incubation for 4 to 5 days was butyrate (approximately 1 meq/100 ml).</s><s>Other products sometimes detected were (in milliequivalents per 100 ml): acetate, 0.2; formate, 0.1; and succinate, 0.1.</s><s>No hydrogen was detected in headspace gas.</s><s>Neither lactate nor pyruvate was used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The 32 strains tested were susceptible to test levels of chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin,</s></p><p class="description"><s>penicillin G, and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA was 38 mol% for the type strain and 36 to 38 mol% for three other strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is VPI D6A-5 (=ATCC 33099), which was isolated from a subgingival area associated with periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphologically, strains of <i>E. nodatum</i> resemble members of the genus <i>Actinomyces</i>.</s><s>However, unlike species of <i>Actinomyces</i>, strains of <i>E. nodatum</i> are non-saccharolytic and produce butyrate, presumably from peptone.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. nodatum</i> was detected in 35% of the subgingival samples examined and constituted 3 to 35% of the cultivable flora in those specimens from which it was isolated.</s><s>It was isolated from 19% of the supragingival samples cultured, where it represented 3 to 7% of the flora.</s></p></content></protolog>