<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14704" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14704" rank="species">Limnoluna rubra</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Limnoluna rubra’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Limnoluna rubra’ [Lim′no.lu′na. Gr. n. <em>limnos</em> lake; L. fem. n. <em>luna</em> the moon; N.L. fem. n. <em>Limnoluna</em> lake moon, referring to the habitat occupied by the first strain and its selenoid morphology. rub′ra. L. fem. adj. <em>rubra</em> red, referring to the red pigmentation of the strain]. Represented by the aerobic, red-pigmented strain MWH-EgelM2-3, which was isolated from a small lake near Salzburg, Austria. The strain is cultured as a mixed culture containing a relatively large fraction of a non-actinobacterial strain (Supplementary Fig. S1). Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-EgelM2-3 (GenBank accession no. AM943659) and the combined presence of the oligonucleotide sequences 5′-CTTGCTCYAGTGGATTAGTGG-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 83–105) and 5′-ACGACACCTTGGGGCATCCCRRGGTGTGGAA-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 181–196) within the 16S rRNA gene. This combined oligonucleotide sequence is also present in two environmental sequences of uncultured actinobacteria (Supplementary Fig. S2) originating from a lake in Germany (Warnecke <em>et al.</em>, 2004). The sequences of strain MWH-EgelM2-3 and the two uncultured actinobacteria form a cluster characterized by sequence similarity values &#x003E;99.2 % (Supplementary Fig. S2).</s></p></content></protolog>