<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7114_nm.3987" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3987" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3987" rank="species">Clostridium pascui</organism><reference id="rid.7114"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wilde</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium pascui sp. nov., a new glutamate-fermenting sporeformer from a pasture in Pakistan.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>164</fpage><lpage>170</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-164</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995820</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium pascui</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium pascui</i> (pas'cu.i L. gen. n. <i>pascui</i>, of a pasture [soil], referring to the habitat where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (0.75 to 1.0 by 3.2 to 8 μm), occur singly or in pairs, and are motile.</s><s>Spores are elliptical and subterminal and swell the cells.</s><s>Cells stain gram negative.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are up to 2 mm in diameter, round, white-grey, opaque, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the dibasic amino acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range of growth is 10 to 43”C, and the optimum temperature is 37 to 40°C.</s><s>The pH range is 5.5 to 9.0, and the broad optimum pH is pH 6.4 to 7.8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented (except for a weak reaction by one strain), nitrate and sulfate are not reduced, lipase and lecithinase are not produced, and gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Glutamate and histidine are fermented.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced.</s><s>The fermentation products formed are acetate, butyrate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>cis</i>7, and C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>cis</i>9 acids and aldehydes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA of strain Cm19<sup>T</sup> is 27 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a donkey pasture in Pakistan.</s><s>The true habitat is unknown and may be the intestinal tract of donkeys.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Cm19, which has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10365.</s></p></content></protolog>