<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6401_nm.4561" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4561" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4561" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter yonseiensis</organism><reference id="rid.6401"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grote</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Antranikian</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pyun</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacter yonseiensis sp. nov., a novel extremely thermophilic, xylose-utilizing bacterium that grows at up to 85 ¬∞C.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1539</fpage><lpage>1548</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491356</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter yonseiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter yonseiensis</i> (yon.sei.en'sis. N.L. adj. <i>yonseiensis</i> pertaining to Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea, in recognition of its support of research on extreme thermophiles and their thermostable enzymes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, straight, rod-shaped and motile.</s><s>Size of vegetative cells in exponential growth phase is 0.4-0.8x1.0-3.0 lm.</s><s>Under suboptimal conditions cells occur in long chains and terminal spores are observed.</s><s>Optimal conditions for growth are 75 °C (range 50-85 °C) and pH 6.5 (range 4.5-9.0).</s><s>The doubling time under optimal conditions on medium containing starch}yeast extract}thiosulfate is 60 min.</s><s>Cells grow chemo-organotrophically under strict anaerobic conditions on glucose, fructose, lactose, maltose, D-xylose, D-galactose, mannose, sucrose, cellobiose, starch, pullulan, yeast extract, tryptone and peptone.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-sorbitol, xylan, carboxymethylcellulose, olive oil, Tween 80, collagen and gelatin are not utilized.</s><s>Cells require yeast extract, elemental sulfur, L-cystine, sodium nitrate or sodium thiosulfate for growth.</s><s>Major fermentation products on glucose are lactate, acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Propionate, butyrate, isovalerate, 2-propanol and 1- pentanol are formed in small amounts.</s><s>Growth on glucose is inhibited by tetracycline, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, neomycin, vancomycin, kanamycin and rifampicin (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Growth was observed at NaCl concentrations up to 40 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Respiratory lipoquinones are absent.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 3-OH iso-C<sub>14:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is 37 mol%.</s><s>Type strain KB-1<sup>TP</sup> was isolated from mud samples taken from a hot stream at Sileri in the Dieng volcanic area located on the island of Java, Indonesia, and has been deposited in the Korean Federation of Culture Collections (KFCC 11116<sup>P</sup>) as a patent strain and deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as a type strain (=DSM 13777<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>