<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1357_nm.5646" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5646" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5646" rank="species">Streptococcus hyointestinalis</organism><reference id="rid.1357"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus hyointestinalis, a new species from the gut of swine</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>440</fpage><lpage>441</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-440</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus hyointestinalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus hyointestinalis</i> (hy. o. in. tes. ti. na' lis. G.n.. <i>hyos</i>, pig; L. adj. <i>intestinalis</i>, associated with intestines; L. adj. <i>hyointestinalis</i>, associated with pig intestines)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive cocci forming chains in broth and sediment with clear supernatant.</s><s>Colonies are transparent, 1 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 1 day of incubation, 1.5 to 2.5 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation, and circular with entire edges and narrow zones of incomplete hemolysis on blood agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 37°C.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Not resistant to 6.5% NaCl or 40% bile.</s><s>Positive for amylase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acetoin (Voges-Proskauer test), esculin hydrolysis, and acid production from glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, lactose, N-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, maltose, saccharose, trehalose, and starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negative for β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase, arginine dehydrolase, hippurate, hyaluronidase, and acid production from glycerol, erytritol, D- and L-arabinose, ribose, D- and L-xylose, adonitol, α-methylxyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, L-lyxose, D-tagatose, L-fucose, D- and L-arabitol, gluconate, and 2- and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>No dextran or levan is produced from saccharose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Variable α-galactosidase, β-gentiobiose, raffinose, amygdalin, and cellobiose reactions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reaction with streptococcal group A, B, C, D, F, and G antisera.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type, Lys-Ala (Ser).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA, 42 to 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat, intestines of pigs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 20770 (= S93).</s><s>This strain is α-galactosidase positive and produces acid from β-gentiobiose, raffinose, amygdalin, and cellobiose.</s><s>Other characteristics are as indicated above.</s></p></content></protolog>