<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3827_nm.5773" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5773" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5773" rank="species">Actinomyces bernardiae</organism><reference id="rid.3827"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual Ramos</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of human-derived Centers for Disease Control coryneform group 2 bacteria as Actinomyces bernardiae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>57</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-57</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857808</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces bernardiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces bernardiae</i> (ber.nar'di.ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>bernardiae</i>, of Bernard, named after contemporary Canadian microbiologist Kathryn A. Bernard for her contributions to the study of asporogenous, gram-positive rods)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of morphological and physiological characteristics is based on the results of studies of seven strains (19; unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive rods, with coccobacilli predominating.</s><s>Cells are sometimes arranged in clusters, but primary branching is not observed.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, and slightly convex with a glassy appearance.</s><s>Colony diameters range from 0.2 to 0.5 mm after 48 h of incubation in the presence of 5% CO<sub>2</sub> on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, ribitol, adonitol, D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose, starch, xylitol, D-arabitol, and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Most strains ferment erythritol, ribose, glycogen, and L-arabitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from xylose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, amygdalin, arbutin, sucrose, and 2-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase and α-glucosidase positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase negative.</s><s>Esculin and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Palmitic and stearic acids are the main straight-chain cellular fatty acids, while oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge within the peptidoglycan is L-alanine-L-lysine-D-glutamic acid (type A5α) .</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63 to 66 mol% G+C.</s><s>Strains are isolated from various clinical sources, with blood and abscesses predominating.</s><s>The habitat of the human-derived strains is not known.</s><s>Type strain LCDC 89-0504 has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 9152 and in the Culture Collection of the University of Goteborg, Sweden, as strain CCUG 33419.</s><s>The type strain possesses the characteristics described above for the species; the G+C content of its DNA is 65 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>