<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7459_nm.2043" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2043" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2043" rank="species">Propionibacter pelophilus</organism><reference id="rid.7459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Meijer</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nienhuis-Kuiper</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentative bacteria from estuarine mud: phylogenetic position of Acidaminobacter hydrogenoformans and description of a new type of gram-negative, propionigenic bacterium as Propionibacter pelophilus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1039</fpage><lpage>1044</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1039</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425761</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionibacter pelophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionibacter pelophilus</i> (pe.lo'phi.lus. Gr. n. <i>pelos</i> mud; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>pelophilus</i> mud-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.9-1.1 μm long and 0.5-0.6 μm wide).</s><s>Gram-negative cell envelope ultrastructure with an outer membrane.</s><s>Cells may be motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on anaerobic plates with aspartate as substrate are slimy white.</s><s>Grows in mineral media with a single fermentable substrate.</s><s>Uses the following energy substrates: L-aspartate, fumarate, L-malate, pyruvate, oxaloacetate, citrate, fructose, glucose, xylose, gluconate, arabitol, xylitol, mannitol, arabinose and mannose.</s><s>Does not ferment glycine, L-alanine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-methionine, L-glutamate, L-histidine, L-arginine, L-lysine, lactate, α-ketoglutarate, glycolate, succinate, propionate, butyrate, glycerol, ethanol, propanol, 2,3-butanediol, acetoin, cellulose, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, melibiose, starch, sorbose, rhamnose, galactose, sorbitol, pectin, peptone, xylan or inulin.</s><s>Indole-negative, urease-negative; does not liquefy gelatin.</s><s>Growth on glucose and aspartate possible at initial pH of 6.5-8.5, the optimum being around 7.5-8.0.</s><s>Final pH of glucose-fermenting cultures is 5.5.</s><s>Temperature optimum 27-30°C; no growth at 35°C.</s><s>Sulfate can be used as sulfur source but growth in the absence of sulfide leads to cell clumps.</s><s>Best growth under anoxic conditions in sulfide-reduced media but growth is possible in stationary cultures under air.</s><s>No growth in well-aerated cultures.</s><s>G + C content of the DNA is 60.8 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: anoxic freshwater and estuarine sediments.</s><s>Type strain: strain asp 66T (= DSM 12018<sup>T</sup>)</s></p></content></protolog>