<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12875_nm.22685" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22685" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22685" rank="species">Paenibacillus sacheonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12875"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jugn</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cheong</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>O.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus sacheonensis sp. nov., a xylanolytic and cellulolytic bacterium isolated from tidal flat sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2753</fpage><lpage>2757</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.029066-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216922</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus sacheonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus sacheonensis</em> (sa.che.o.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>sacheonensis</em> of or belonging to Sacheon, the city in Korea where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, motile and rod-shaped (0.8–1.0 µm wide and 2.8–3.8 µm long) (see Supplementary Fig. S2 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>A spherical endospore is formed at a central to subterminal position.</s><s>After 48 h incubation at 30 °C on 10-fold-diluted TSB agar plates, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, round, flat and translucent/white.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–40 °C and the optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>The pH growth range is between 6.0 and 9.0, with an optimum at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and no growth occurs in the presence of &#x003E;1.0 % (w/v) NaCl in 10-fold-diluted TSB medium.</s><s>Xylan, aesculin, starch, gelatin and CMC are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gives a positive result in tests for oxidase, but catalase is negative.</s><s>Positive result in tests for β-galactosidase and acetoin production (weak), but negative result for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, glucose fermentation and nitrate reduction.</s><s>No assimilation of caproate, adipate, citrate, phenylacetate or malate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and turanose, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, inulin, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin, streptomycin, vancomycin, gentamicin, penicillin G, erythromycin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline and piperacillin/tazobactam 10 : 1.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (47.2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (18.9 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (10.5 %).</s><s>The major polar lipids present are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, four unknown aminophospholipids, five unknown phospholipids and an unknown phosphoglycolipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SY01<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23054<sup>T</sup> = KACC 14895<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from tidal flat sediment from Sacheon Bay in South Korea.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 56.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>