<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11714_nm.19331" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19331" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19331" rank="species">Alistipes indistinctus</organism><reference id="rid.11714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alistipes indistinctus sp. nov. and Odoribacter laneus sp. nov., common members of the human intestinal microbiota isolated from faeces</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1296</fpage><lpage>1302</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014571-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667375</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alistipes indistinctus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alistipes indistinctus</em> (in.dis.tinc′tus. L. masc. adj. <em>indistinctus</em> not properly distinguished or indistinct, referring to the biochemical characteristics compared with those of phylogenetically related species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are non-spore-forming, coccoid to rod-shaped with round ends and are strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.5–0.7×1.0–3.8 μm.</s><s>After growth for 4 days with anaerobic incubation on modified GAM agar, colonies are 0.1–0.5 mm in diameter, slightly opaque, circular and grey.</s><s>The major end products of glucose fermentation in PYG broth are succinic and acetic acids.</s><s>Not resistant to 20 % bile.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Catalase is positive.</s><s>Oxidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Positive for acid production from cellobiose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from l-arabinose, glycerol, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol is weakly positive.</s><s>By using the commercially available API test systems (API Rapid ID 32A and API ZYM), positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, and weakly positive for acid phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-arabinosidase.</s><s>Depending on the micro-test kit used, variable results are obtained for <em>α</em>-glucosidase (positive in the API Rapid ID 32A and negative in the API ZYM) and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (positive in the API ZYM and negative in the API Rapid ID 32A).</s><s>Negative for arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, 6-phosphate-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>The main respiratory quinones are MK-10 and MK-11.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and an unknown fatty acid (ECL 17.879).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 12060<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22520<sup>T</sup>=JCM 16068<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>