<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3876_nm.9489" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9489" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9489" rank="species">Arthrobacter parietis</organism><reference id="rid.3876"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbeeren</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Six novel Arthrobacter species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1457</fpage><lpage>1464</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63358-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014466</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter parietis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter parietis</em> (pa.ri.et′is. L. gen. n. <em>parietis</em> of a wall).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods and cocci (diameter 0·8–1 μm) occurring in pairs or clusters.</s><s>They are non-motile and do not form endospores.</s><s>Colonies on NA after 48 h are 1–2 mm in diameter, yellow–orange, round with entire margins, of low convexity, opaque and smooth.</s><s>No growth in an anaerobic chamber on NA.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 22–30 °C.</s><s>No or only weak growth at 37 °C and no growth at 45 °C.</s><s>Good growth after 1 week at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth on medium with 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–9, with an optimum of 7–8.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Using the API CORYNE system, positive reactions are observed for nitrate reduction, pyrazinamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, aesculin (<em>β</em>-glucosidase), gelatinase and fermentation of glucose.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and fermentation of ribose, xylose, mannitol and glycogen.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, urease, and fermentation of maltose, lactose and sucrose.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, activity is detected for acid phosphatase (weak), esterase C<sub>4</sub>, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, phosphoamidase (weak), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase C<sub>8</sub>, lipase C<sub>14</sub>, valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Variable results (if positive, weak) were obtained for cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (approximately 51 and 29 %, respectively).</s><s>Peptidoglycan type, menaquinone content and cell wall sugars are given in Table 1.</s><s>Polar lipids of the type strain are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, one unknown phospholipid and two unknown glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA, determined for the type strain LMG 22281<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16404<sup>T</sup>), is 63·8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is negative for the variable characters listed above.</s><s>Isolated from a biofilm overgrowing a mural painting in the Servilia tomb (Roman necropolis of Carmona, Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>