<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7491_nm.2613" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2613" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2613" rank="species">Pseudomonas gessardii</organism><reference id="rid.7491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Verhille</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baida</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dabboussi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamze</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas gessardii sp. nov. and Pseudomonas migulae sp. nov., two new species isolated from natural mineral waters.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1559</fpage><lpage>1572</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1559</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555337</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas gessardii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas gessardii</i> (ges.sar'di.i. M.L. gen. masc. n. <i>gessardii</i> after C. Gessard, who isolated '<i>Bacterium aeruginosum</i>' for the first time and studied its pigment)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are asporogeneous, rod-shaped and stain Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Pyoverdin is produced on King B medium and on S1 medium (Gould et al., 1985).</s><s>No phenazine pigments are observed on King A medium.</s><s>Cells are oxidase-and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cetrimide (N-acetyl-N,N,N-trimethylammonium) is assimilated.</s><s>Significant growth is observed only at low salt concentrations (up to 0.8%) and not at 5 or 7 %.</s><s>Strains grow at 4°C and not at 41°C.</s><s>Levan is produced from sucrose.</s><s>Starch and <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside cannot be assimilated.</s><s>Does not form indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Does not decarboxylate lysine or ornithine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No elastase, coagulase, β-xylosidase (<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-xylopyranoside test) or phenylalanine deaminase activities are reported.</s><s>No activity against DNA is noticed.</s><s>Strains exhibit no acetyl-methyl-carbinol (acetoin) activity.</s><s>Fibrinolysin test is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-trehalose, D-ribose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, xylitol, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, L-malate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, citrate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, protocatechuate, quinate, betaine, putrescine, DL-α-amino-<i>n</i>-butyrate, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, D-glucosamine, itaconate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-serine, malonate, propionate, L-tyrosine and 2-oxoglutarate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: L-sorbose, D-mehbiose, sucrose, D-raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, 1-O-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl α-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, 1-O-methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, aesculin, L-arabinose, D-xylose, palatinose, α-L-rhamnose, α-L-fucose, D-melezitose, dulcitol, D-tagatose, maltitol, D-turanose, D-sorbitol, hydroxyquinoline β-glucuronide, D-lyxose, 1-methyl α-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl D-glucopyranose, D-saccharate, mucate, L-tartrate, D-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, tricarballylate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, L-tryptophan, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, histamine and L-histidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have the following enzyme activities: esterases C5, C6, C8, C9 and C10, L-pyrrolidone arylamidase, L-phenylalanine arylamidase, L-lysine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, L-arginine arylamidase, L-alanine arylamidase, 𝛾-glutamyltransferase, methionine arylamidase, glycyl-glycine arylamidase, glycyl-phenylalanine arylamidase, L-seryl-tyrosine arylamidase, L-glutamine arylamidase, L-proline arylamidase, β-alanine arylamidase, L-alanyl-L-arginine arylamidase, α-L-aspartyl-L-alanine arylamidase, α-L-aspartyl-L-arginine arylamidase, glycyl-L-alanine arylamidase, glycyl-L-arginine arylamidase and N-carboxybenzoxy-glycylglycyl-L-arginine arylamidase.</s><s>None of the strains possess the following enzyme activities: α-D-galactosidase, β-D-galactosidase, phospho-β-D-galactosidase, α-L-arabinosidase, α-D-glucosidase, β-D-glucosidase, β-D-galacturonohydrolase, β-D-glucuronidase, α-maltosidase, β-maltosidase, N-acetyl-α-<i>o</i>-glucosaminidase, α-L-fucosidase, β-D-fucosidase, /I-L-fucosidase, β-D-lactosidase, α-D-mannosidase, β-D-mannosidase, α-D-xylosidase, β-D-xylosidase, esterase-C 18, Nbenzoyl-leucine arylamidase, N-benzoyl-~-alanine-4-methoxy arylamidase, N-carboxybenzoxy-arginyl-4-methoxy arylamidase, N-acetyl-glycyl-L-lysine arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperatures for growth range from 4 to 35°C with an optimum at 30°C.</s><s>Strains were isolated from natural mineral waters.</s><s>No clinical significance is known.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Pseudomonas gessardii</i> sp. nov. as described includes 13 strains: the type strain, CIP 105469<sup>T</sup>( = CFML 95-251<sup>T</sup>), and the following other strains: CFML 95-244, CFML95-332, CFML 95-258, CFML 95-338,CFML 95-250, CFML 95-256, CFML 95-264, CFML 95-254, CFML 95-245, CFML 95-342, CFML 95-331 and CFML 95-255.</s><s>The above strains have been deposited in the Collection de la Faculti de Midecine, Lille, France (CFML) and the Collection de l'lnstitut Pasteur, Paris, France (CIP).</s></p></content></protolog>