<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9953_nm.14934" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14934" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14934" rank="species">Brevundimonas naejangsanensis</organism><reference id="rid.9953"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>N.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevundimonas naejangsanensis sp. nov., a proteolytic bacterium isolated from soil, and reclassification of Mycoplana bullata into the genus Brevundimonas as Brevundimonas bullata comb. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3155</fpage><lpage>3160</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011700-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643873</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevundimonas naejangsanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevundimonas naejangsanensis</em> (nae.jang.san.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>naejangsanensis</em> pertaining to Naejangsan, the Korean name of Naejang Mountain, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and rod-shaped (0.3–0.5×0.7–4.0 μm).</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, slightly convex, smooth, glistening, greyish yellow and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 50 °C, but not at 55 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.5 and 8.5; growth occurs at pH 5.5 and pH 10.0, but not at pH 5.0 or pH 10.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–4.0 % (w/v) NaCl, with an optimum in the presence of 0–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Casein, l-tyrosine and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, lincomycin, oleandomycin, penicillin G or polymyxin B.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>l-Glutamic acid is assimilated, but the following substrates are not assimilated: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>ρ</em>-hydroxyphenyl acetic acid, itaconic acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BIO-TAS2-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22631<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 57609<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil from Naejang Mountain, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.0 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>