<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6770_nm.2593" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2593" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2593" rank="species">Pseudomonas costantinii</organism><reference id="rid.6770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Munsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alatossava</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marttinen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas costantinii sp. nov., another causal agent of brown blotch disease, isolated from cultivated mushroom sporophores in Finland.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1973</fpage><lpage>1983</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02090-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas costantinii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas costantinii</i> (cos.tant.i.ni'i. N.L. adj. <i>costantinii</i> of Costantin, referring to Julien Costantin, a French mycologist who, in a note dated March 1892 to the `Société de Biologié, described some superficial brown blotch areas on sporophores)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative straight rods, motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Produces a fluorescent diffusible greenish pigment on King's B medium.</s><s>Several-day-sold colonies produce sectors which when subcultured prove to be non-pathogenic on mushroom sporophores.</s><s>Produces one Tween esterase (on Tween 80), are oxidase-positive, arginine-dihydrolase-positive and hydrolyse gelatin.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin and does not produce acid from L-tartrate.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Levan-sucrase-negative, non-pectinolytic and does not degrade polypectates at pH 5 or 8.</s><s>Does not induce a hypersensitive reaction on tobacco leaves.</s><s>Utilizes α-D-glucose, β-D-fructose, D-galactose, D-trehalose, D-mannose, D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, xylitol, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, adonitol, D-lyxose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-saccharate, mucate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, D-malate, L-malate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, citrate, dglucuronate, D-galacturonate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, protocatechuate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, benzoate, betain, putrescine, DL-α-amino-n-butyrate, histamine, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, DL-α-amino-nvalerate, ethanolamine, D-glucosamine, itaconate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-serine, malonate, propionate, L-tyrosine and 2-oxoglutarate.</s><s>Produces acid from DL-lactate, D-tartrate, erythritol, mannitol and sorbitol.</s><s>Does not assimilate L-sorbose, α-D-melibiose, D-raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, methyl 1-O-β-galactopyranoside, methyl 1-O-α-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, methyl 1-O-β-D-glucopyranoside, palatinose, α-L-rhamnose, α-L-fucose, D-melezitose, dulcitol, D-tagatose, maltitol, hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide, methyl 1-O-α-dglycopyranoside, methyl 3-O-D-glucopyranose, L-tartrate, tricarballylate, L-tryptophan, phenylacetate, gentisate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, L-histidine or tryptamine.</s><s>All tested strains contain trace amounts of the cyclopropane fatty acid C"*:! cyc.</s><s>The DNA G­C content of strain PS 3aT is 57.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is PS 3a<sup>T</sup> (=CFBP 5705<sup>T</sup>=HAMBI 2444<sup>T</sup>) (HAMBI, Culture Collection of the Division of Microbiology, University of Helsinki, Finland).</s><s>Isolated from brown blotched mushroom sporophores originating from the Turku region of Southern Finland (Lat 60° N, Long 22.15° E).</s></p></content></protolog>