<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11605_nm.18641" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18641" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18641" rank="species">Rhodovulum steppense</organism><reference id="rid.11605"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komova</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kostrikina</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum steppense sp. nov., an obligately haloalkaliphilic purple nonsulfur bacterium widespread in saline soda lakes of Central Asia</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1210</fpage><lpage>1214</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014639-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667383</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodovulum steppense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodovulum steppense</em> (step.pen′se, N.L. n. <em>steppum</em> steppe; L. neut. suff. <em>-ense</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. neut. adj. <em>steppense</em> pertaining to the steppe, widespread in steppe soda lakes).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid to rod-shaped, 0.3–0.8 μm wide and 1.0–2.5 μm long, motile by means of polar flagella, multiply by binary fission, and contain vesicular internal photosynthetic membranes.</s><s>Cell suspensions are yellow to brown in anoxic conditions and red in the presence of O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids of the spheroidene series. <em>In vivo</em> absorption spectra show maxima at 461, 483, 515, 592, 803 and 861 nm.</s><s>Growth occurs anaerobically in the light (photoheterotrophically) or aerobically in the dark (chemoheterotrophically).</s><s>Growth is best with propionate, butyrate, valerate, pyruvate, lactate and glycerol.</s><s>Asparagine, acetate, caprylate, malate, succinate, formate, fumarate, glutamate, mannose, ethanol, casein hydrolysate and yeast extract are also used.</s><s>Alanine, arginine, aspartate, ornithine, proline, threonine, valine, citrate, benzoate, tartrate, arabinose, glucose, maltose and fructose support slow growth.</s><s>No growth occurs with sucrose, sorbitol, mannitol or methanol.</s><s>No anaerobic respiration takes place with nitrite, nitrate or fumarate.</s><s>Growth at the expense of fermentation does not occur.</s><s>Sulfide, sulfur and thiosulfate support photolithoautotrophic and chemolithoautotrophic growth, in the course of which they are oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>Sulfide as electron donor is oxidized via temporary deposition of extracellular elemental sulfur.</s><s>No growth occurs with hydrogen as electron donor.</s><s>Ammonium salts are used as the nitrogen source.</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur and cysteine are used as the sulfur source.</s><s>Three vitamins (biotin, thiamine, niacin) are needed as growth factors.</s><s>Obligately haloalkaliphilic: growth occurs within a wide range of salinity (0.3–10 %, w/v) and pH (7.5–10).</s><s>Growth optima are at 1–5 % NaCl, pH 8.5 and 25–35 °С.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and/or at pH 7.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated fatty acids are present, with 18 : 1 predominating (81 %).</s><s>Resistant to amikacin, ampicillin, chlortetracycline, bacitracin, vancomycin, gentamicin, nystatin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, penicillin, rifampicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin and streptomycin.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, benzylpenicillin and polymixin B.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.1 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, A-20s<sup>T</sup> (=VKM B-2489<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21153<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soda lake Khilganta (Zabaikal'skii Krai, southern Siberia, Russia).</s></p></content></protolog>