<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8812_nm.13273" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13273" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13273" rank="species">Chryseobacterium bovis</organism><reference id="rid.8812"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hantsis-Zacharov</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Senderovich</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halpern</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium bovis sp. nov., isolated from raw cow's milk.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1024</fpage><lpage>1028</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65500-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398213</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium bovis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium bovis</em> (bo′vis. L. gen. n. <em>bovis</em> of a cow, referring to the isolation from raw cow's milk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile rods, 0.5–0.9 μm wide and 1.1–2.3 μm long.</s><s>After 48 h incubation on sterile SPC agar at 30 °C in the dark, colonies are circular with entire edges, opaque, smooth and cream-coloured.</s><s>When light is provided during growth, colonies are yellow-coloured because of the production of carotenoid-type pigments (absorbance peaks at 454 and 481 nm).</s><s>Weakly positive in the KOH test, indicating the presence of small amounts of flexirubin-type pigments.</s><s>Good growth occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth is also observed after 5 days under anaerobic conditions on SPC agar containing 0.1 % (w/v) potassium nitrate, but not on SPC agar with 0.5 % glucose.</s><s>Grows at 7–37 °C (strain H10 grows at temperatures up to 41 °C) (optimum, 30–32 °C), with 0–2.5 % NaCl (optimum, 0–1.75 % NaCl) and at pH 5.0–9.8 (optimum, pH 6.5–8.5).</s><s>Good growth occurs on SPC and tryptic soy agars, but not on MacConkey or cetrimide agar.</s><s>No haemolysis occurs on 5 % sheep-blood agar.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Casein (except for strain H10) and tributyrin are hydrolysed.</s><s>In API 20NE tests after 48 h incubation at 32 °C, all three strains hydrolyse aesculin and assimilate glucose, mannose and maltose, but only H9<sup>T</sup> and H15 assimilate arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate and adipic and malic acids.</s><s>The following results are obtained from API 20E strips after 24 h incubation at 32 °C: acetoin is produced; <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity is present (except for strain H10); gelatin is hydrolysed (except for strain H10); H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced; urea is not hydrolysed; citrate is not utilized; and arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>In API 50 CH strips incubated for 48 h at 32 °C, acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, d-lactose and d-mannose (except for strain H10).</s><s>In API ZYM strips incubated for 4.5 h, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present in all the three strains.</s><s>Cystine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities are present in strains H9<sup>T</sup> and H15 and trypsin activity is present only in strain H10.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids of the type strain are 15 : 0 iso (38.9 %), 15 : 0 anteiso (15.6 %) and 17 : 0 iso 3-OH (12.7 %).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present as minor components: summed feature 3 (comprising 15 : 0 iso 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>; 8.7 %), 13 : 0 iso (4.8 %), 16 : 0 3-OH (3.9 %), 15 : 0 iso 3-OH (2.6 %), 17 : 1 iso <em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (2.5 %), 16 : 0 (2.1 %), unknown 16.582 (1.7 %), 16 : 0 iso 3-OH (1.6 %) and 17 : 0-2-OH (1.3 %).</s><s>Traces (&#x003C;1 %) of 13 : 0 anteiso, 14 : 0, 14 : 0 iso, 15 : 0, 15 : 0 2-OH and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> are also present.</s><s>In strain H10, 17 : 1 iso <em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> is also a major fatty acid (14.8 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, H9<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24227<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19482<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from raw milk in Israel.</s><s>Strains H15 (=LMG 24229 =DSM 19481) and H10 (=LMG 24228 =DSM 19483) are reference strains.</s></p></content></protolog>