<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3779_nm.5800" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5800" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5800" rank="species">Actinomyces radicidentis</organism><reference id="rid.3779"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalfas</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundquist</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monsen</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nikolaitchouk</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Actinomyces isolates from infected root canals of teeth: description of Actinomyces radicidentis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>3399</fpage><lpage>3403</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10970390</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces radicidentis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces radicidentis</i> (L. n. <i>radix</i> root, L. gen. masc. n. <i>dentis</i> of the tooth, L. gen. masc. n. <i>radicidentis</i> of the root of the tooth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid, stain gram positive, and are non-acid fast and nonmotile, facultatively anaerobic, and catalase positive.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose, maltose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, lactose, D-raffinose, ribose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, pullulan, sorbitol, or tagatose.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin (weak) are hydrolyzed, but hippurate is not.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, and pyrazinamidase are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, ester lipase C<sub>8</sub>, β-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophane arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>Activities for urease are variable.</s><s>Acetoin production is weakly positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is variable.</s><s>Organisms have been isolated from infected root canals of teeth.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 36733 (=CIP 106352<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>