<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.121_nm.4271" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4271" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4271" rank="species">Eubacterium suis</organism><reference id="rid.121"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kinoshita</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Homma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Igarashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ikeno</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hori</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia vinacea sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><source id="668">Nihon Hōsenkin Gakkai shi = Actinomycetologica</source><abbrev>Actinomycetol</abbrev><issn>0914-5818</issn><essn>1881-6371</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium suis</i> (nom. rev.) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Slender, nonmotile, pleomorphic rods, 1 to 3 by 0.5 μm, arranged singly, in pairs (often found at an angle to each other or in palisades), or in small clusters. Gram positive, but rather easily decolorized, especially in old cultures. Not acid fast and non-sporulating; does not survive heating at 80°C for 10 min. Capsules not observed by capsule staining; however, a fringelike outer coat external to the cell wall is seen in thin-section electron micrographs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates are 0.5 to 3.0 mm in diameter after 48 h, white, circular, and granular and have entire to slightly irregular margins.</s><s>Colonies often show slightly raised centers, giving a fried-egg appearance.</s><s>After 1 week, colonies are 3 to 5 mm in diameter and flatter.</s><s>Growth is barely discernible after incubation for 7 days under 6% CO<sub>2</sub> or air.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptone-yeast extract-starch broth supports excellent growth.</s><s>Optimal pH, 7 to 8; no growth occurs at pH 5.0 or less.</s><s>Optimal temperature, 37°C; temperature range for growth, 30 to 43°C; no growth occurs at 22 to 23°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic: metabolism is strictly fermentative.</s><s>Maltose, starch, and glycogen are fermented.</s><s>Acetate, ethanol, and formate are the main products from maltose fermentation.</s><s>Adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, esculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, lactate, pyruvate, and threonine are not fermented.</s><s>Strongly urease positive.</s><s>Does not produce catalase, indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, hydrogen sulfide, lipase, or lecithinase; ammonia is not produced from peptone; esculin and gelatin are not hydrolyzed; meat and milk are not digested; nitrates are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Major amounts of type <i>b</i> cytochrome and minor amounts of type <i>c</i> cytochrome are synthesized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall sugars are rhamnose and mannose; the diamino acid of the peptidoglycan is lysine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 55 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Originally isolated from cases of cystitis and pyelonephritis and cases of metritis in pregnant sows (41, 42).</s><s>Not isolated from healthy sows, but frequently recovered from urine and semen of apparently healthy boars.</s><s>Sows can be infected artificially by intrarenal injection of live organisms plus 5% saponin (41).</s><s>No demonstrable exotoxin is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Soltys 50052 (= ATCC 33144).</s></p></content></protolog>