<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5622_nm.9878" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9878" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9878" rank="species">Streptomyces cheonanensis</organism><reference id="rid.5622"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces cheonanensis sp. nov., a novel streptomycete with antifungal activity</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>471</fpage><lpage>475</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63816-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449460</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces cheonanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces cheonanensis</em> (che.on.an.en′sis N.L. masc. adj. <em>cheonanensis</em> pertaining to Cheonan, Republic of Korea, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile actinomycete that forms extensively branched aerial and substrate hyphae.</s><s>Short or long, straight to flexuous chains of smooth-surfaced spores are evident on the aerial hyphae.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is grey to white in colour and the substrate mycelium appears light yellow when grown on ISP 4 agar.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are 14-methylpentadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; 47·82 %), hexadecanoic acid (C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; 14·44 %) and <em>cis</em>-9-hexadecenoic acid (C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em> 9; 10·24 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 75·5 mol%.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 29 °C.</s><s>Grows well in yeast extract/malt extract broth adjusted to pH 6·5–8·0.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl concentrations up to 7 %.</s><s>Aerial and substrate mycelia grow abundantly on both ISP 3 agar and Bennett's agar.</s><s>Soluble pigments are generated on ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 5 (glycerol/asparagine agar) and ISP 7.</s><s>Capable of utilizing several carbon sources, including adonitol, arabinose, dextran, fructose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, xylitol and xylose.</s><s>Can also use several nitrogen sources: dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyric acid, l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-phenylalanine and l-valine.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin G, but sensitive to neomycin, oleandomycin and rifampicin.</s><s>Secretes compounds that inhibit mycelial growth of plant-pathogenic fungi including <em>Alternaria mali</em>, <em>Colletotrichum orbiculare</em>, <em>Magnaporthe grisea</em>, <em>Fusarium oxysporum</em> f. sp. <em>lycopersici</em> and <em>Rhizoctonia solani</em> and the oomycete <em>Phytophthora capsici</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VC-A46<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42119<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100940<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a soil sample collected from Cheonan, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>