<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1554_nm.11221" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11221" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11221" rank="species">Lactobacillus ghanensis</organism><reference id="rid.1554"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schillinger</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franz</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bresciani</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amoa-Awua</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holzapfel</surname><given-names>W.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jakobsen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus ghanensis sp. nov., a motile lactic acid bacterium isolated from Ghanaian cocoa fermentations.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1468</fpage><lpage>1472</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64811-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625177</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus ghanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus ghanensis</em> (ghan.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>ghanensis</em> pertaining to Ghana, where the micro-organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.7–0.8×1.4–2.5 μm in size and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains comprising three to four cells.</s><s>Gram-positive, catalase-negative, motile with peritrichous flagella and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, white to creamy white, smooth, circular, convex and with entire or slightly uneven edges after 3–4 days of anaerobic growth.</s><s>Weak growth at 15 °C; good growth at 45 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Weak growth at pH 3.9; no growth at pH 8.0.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>d(−)-Lactic acid and l(+)-lactic acid are produced as the end products from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, d-cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-rhamnose, sucrose, salicin and d-trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-adonitol, starch, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, l-xylose, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from glycerol, d-lactose, d-maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside (delayed reaction), d-sorbitol (delayed reaction), l-sorbose and d-tagatose (delayed reaction) is strain-dependent.</s><s>Does not produce dextran from sucrose.</s><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the d-<em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid type.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 37.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, L489<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18630<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53453<sup>T</sup>), and all other known strains of the species were isolated from cocoa fermentations in Tafo, Ghana.</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to the description of the species except that no acid is produced from glycerol, maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-lactose, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Strain L499 (=DSM 18631=CCUG 53454) is a reference strain.</s></p></content></protolog>