<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1430_nm.1505" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1505" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1505" rank="species">Rhodopseudomonas rosea</organism><reference id="rid.1430"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harfoot</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodopseudomonas rosea sp. nov., a new purple nonsulfur bacterium</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>26</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodopseudomonas rosea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodopseudomonas rosea</i> (ro´ se.a. L. adj. <i>rosea</i>, rosy, rose colored, pink)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of strain 941<sup>T</sup> are flask to rod shaped and 2.0 to 2.5 μm long by 1.0 μm wide (Fig. 1).</s><s>Light microscopy often reveals cells with one cellular pole that is more dense than the other end, which is slightly thinner.</s><s>Rosettes typical of <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> are not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Division appears to be budding without a division tube (by a mechanism of sessile budding) (Fig. 2).</s><s>The mode of cell growth and division is similar to that of <i>Rhodopseudomonas biastica</i> (5) and <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i>(8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A few motile cells were observed by phase-contrast microscopy only in very young cultures.</s><s>Once turbidity is clearly visible, motile cells become extremely rare.</s><s>Electron microscopy of negatively stained cells shows that many cells have flagella, and many loose flagella are present in such preparations.</s><s>The flagellar arrangement appears to be monopolar.</s><s>It is possible that the thick slime coat prevents motility in older cultures.</s><s>The capsular material and loose flagella make determination of flagellar insertion difficult.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When cells are stained with ammonium crystal violet, very little stain is taken up.</s><s>Instead a thick capsule is revealed, which stains bright purple.</s><s>The capsule is up to one-half of the cell diameter in thickness.</s><s>Gram staining is not possible</s></p><p class="description"><s>because of this capsule.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron microscopy of ultrathin sections reveals that the internal photosynthetic membrane arrangement is of the type termed lamellar (i. e., lying adjacent and parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine ratio is 66 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photopigments.</s><s>Pink lens-shaped colonies and pink cell suspensions are formed by pure cultures of strain 941<sup>T</sup> when they are grown under anaerobic photoheterotrophic conditions.</s><s>Absorption spectra of living cells show maxima typical of bacteriochlorophyll a at 367,593,801, and 841 nm (Fig. 3).</s><s>Maxima corresponding to carotenoid peaks are detected at 487, 514, and 546 (shoulder) nm, but are poorly resolved.</s><s>Absorption spectra of extracts of cells of strain 941<sup>T</sup> in acetone-methanol (7:2) have maxima at 352, 446, 499, 531, 675, and 756 nm.</s><s>The color of cell suspensions does not change to red when the suspensions are exposed to air, indicating that there is no oxidation of spheroidene carotenoids to their keto derivatives.</s><s>This probably means that the spheroidene group carotenoids are not a major component of the carotenoids of strain 941<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The maxima detected suggest that the carotenoids are members of the normal spirilloxanthin series.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Strain 941<sup>T</sup> grows well on medium containing 0.04% NaCl, but an NaCl concentration of 1.0% results in total inhibition of growth.</s><s>The pH optimum with pyruvate as the carbon source is 7.0 to 8.0.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH 9.0, but is possible at pH 5.5, the lowest pH tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Addition of 0.1 U (0.06 mg) of penicillin G per ml inhibits growth by 22% compared with a</s></p><p class="description"><s>control.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the absence of veast extract, nicotinic acid is required for growth on pyruvate.</s><s>An absence of yeast extract and vitamins results in no growth.</s><s>Good growth still occurs after five transfers on medium containing pyruvate without yeast extract but supplemented with 100 ng of nicotinic acid per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures kept at 25°C in the light for 12 months are viable and grow as readily as 1-month-old cultures when they are inoculated into fresh medium containing pyruvate.</s><s>After growth on 0.1% sodium pyruvate on the pH of the growth medium is virtually unchanged (it decreases a little to pH 7.2 to 7.3 from an initial pH of 7.4 to 7.5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutritional properties.</s><s>Strain 941<sup>T</sup> grows anaerobically in the light on range of organic compounds (Table 1).</s><s>It also grows on pyruvate microaerophilically in the light or dark or anaerobically in the dark.</s><s>Anaerobic dark fermentation of exogenous substrates is well known in the <i>Rhodospirillaceae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is not stimulated by fatty acids containing five or more carbon atoms at concentrations of 0.02% (valerate, hexanoate, heptanoate, octanoate, nonanoate) or 0.05% (decanoate, dodecanoate, tetradecanoate, hexadecanoate, heptadecanoate, octadecanoate), indicating that fatty acids cannot be utilized.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of any concentration of heptanoate, a fatty acid that appears to be tolerated up to a concentration of 0.05% by many strains</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 941<sup>T</sup> fails to grow (in batch cultures) on medium containing 0.5 mM sulfide plus 0.02% yeast extract in the absence of other electron donors.</s><s>Growth is completely inhibited by 0.2 mM sulfide added to media containing 0.1% sodium pyruvate.</s><s>In the presence of 0.1 mM sulfide and 0.1% sodium pyruvate, growth is inhibited 55%.</s><s>This effect is apparently due to the toxic effect of the sulfide rather than to a lowering of the E<sub>h</sub> since addition of thioglycolateascorbate (final concentration of each, 0.005%) or titanium citrate as a reductant to medium containing 0.1% sodium pyruvate does not inhibit growth.</s><s>An increase in growth obtained in the titanium citrate-reduced cultures was presumably due to the ability of the strain to utilize citrate.</s><s>Low sulfide tolerance by members of the <i>Rhodospirillaceae</i> (6) means that the sulfide levels must be kept low when utilization of this compound is tested.</s><s>Tests to determine the ability to utilize sulfide as an electron donor under continuous culture conditions (6) have not been attempted with strain 941<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ability to grow on mineral medium containing nicotinic acid as the only growth factor suggests that sulfate is assimilated, since no other sulfur source is present under these conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiation from other species of the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i>.</s><s>The lack of a division tube, the absence of rosette formation, and a quite different carbon source utilization pattern differentiate strain 941<sup>T</sup> from <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i>.</s><s>The pH optima are quite different for <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> and strain 941<sup>T</sup>; <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> has a pH range for growth of 4.8 to 7.0 and an optimum pH of 5.8 16.</s><s>The carbon source utilization patterns for strain 941<sup>T</sup> annd strains of <i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> are very different (1). <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i>, <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i>, and <i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> also differ from strain 941<sup>T</sup> in that they are red pigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The whole-cell absorption spectrum of strain 941<sup>T</sup> has peaks that are typical of bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> rather than peaks that are typical of bacteriochlorophyll <i>b</i> and thus distinguishes strain 941<sup>T</sup> from <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas sulfoviridis</i>.</s><s>These species are green pigmented, form rosettes, and have carbon source utilization patterns that are quite different from that of strain 941<sup>T</sup> (20).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Rhodopseudomonas blastica</i> is orange-brown (5) and has the ability to oxidize spheroidene carotenoids in air, thus changing the color of cultures to red (19). <i>Rhodopseudomonus blastica</i> apparently does not possess flagella (5) and is able to utilize fatty acids containing five or more carbon atoms (5, 12).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In general morphology and color, strain 941<sup>T</sup> most closely resembles <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i>.</s><s>However, the carbon source utilization patterns and salinity tolerances of these organisms are quite different.</s><s>Most strains of <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> grow well at NaCl concentrations between 0 and 4% (8).</s><s>Strain 941<sup>T</sup> is totally inhibited by an NaCl concentration of 1%. <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> displays a kind of flagellation described by Imhoff (8) to be intermediate between subpolar and lateral to peritrichous.</s><s>As far as can be determined, strain 941T has monopolar flagellation.</s><s>The whole-cell absorption spectrum of strain 941<sup>T</sup> is also quite different from that published for <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> (8).</s><s>In <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> the peak in the 800-nm (803-nm) region is very small, and is similar to that obtained in whole-cell absorption spectra of <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> (20).</s><s>In strain 941<sup>T</sup> the two long wavelength maxima are similar in size and can be used to differentiate the species. <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina </i>is able to grow photoheterotrophically on short-chain (8) and longchain fatty acids (11).</s><s>Thus, there are too many differences between the organisms for strain 941<sup>T</sup> to be regarded as a freshwater strain of <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i>.</s><s>Therefore, strain 941<sup>T</sup> can be differentiated from all seven previously recognized species in the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonus</i> (18) on the basis of morphology, pigmentation, and nutritional characteristics (Table 2).</s><s>We conclude that strain 941<sup>T</sup> represents a hitherto undescribed species of the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i>.</s><s>The new species is named <i>Rhodopseudomonas rosea</i>, with strain 941 as the type (and at present only) strain; this strain has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, Federal Republic of Germany, as strain DSM 5909</s></p></content></protolog>