<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.299_nm.6454" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6454" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6454" rank="species">Nocardia pseudobrasiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.299"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carlotti</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boiron</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernardin</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia pseudobrasiliensis sp. nov., a new species of Nocardia which groups bacterial strains previously identified as Nocardia brasiliensis and associated with invasive diseases.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>259</fpage><lpage>264</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-259</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573505</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia pseudobrasiliensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia pseudobrasiliensis</i> (pseu.do.bra.si.li.en'sis. Gr. adj. <i>pseudes</i>, false; M.L. adj. <i>brasiliensis</i>, pertaining to Brazil, a specific epithet; M.L. adj. <i>pseudobrasiliensis</i>, a false brasiliensis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from this study and the study of Wallace et al. (25).</s><s>Strains are orange-tan to tan.</s><s>The cells have typical <i>Nocardia</i> micromorphology; branched vegetative hyphae (diameter, 0.5 to 1.2 μm) fragment into bacteroid or rod-shaped to coccoid, nonmotile elements.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is produced.</s><s>Endospores, sporangia, scerotia, and synnemata are not formed.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>The cells are strictly aerobic and have an oxidative type of metabolism.</s><s>They exhibit catalase, alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, and N-acetyl-pglucosaminidase activities.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and acid fast or partially acid fast as determined by the modified Kinyoun method (1% sulfuric acid decolorization), but they are not acid fast as determined by the standard Kinyoun method.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37°C but not at 10 or 43°C after 2 weeks.</s><s>Cells are resistant to lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adenine, casein, hypoxanthine, and tyrosine are decomposed, but xanthine is not decomposed.</s><s>Urease is produced, but nitrate reductase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, inositol, D-mannitol, D-mannose, trehalose, and citrate, but not from ribitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-glucitol, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67 to 68 mol%, as determined by the capillary electrophoresis procedure (19).</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, and galactose.</s><s>Nocardomycolic acids are present.</s><s>As determined by HPLC, the mycolic acid patterns include two early peaks that are not found in any <i>N. brasiliensis</i> sensu stricto pattern.</s><s>Contains predominant menaquinones similar to those in <i>N. asteroides</i> ATCC 19247<sup>T</sup> as determined by an HPLC method (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 51512 (=CIP 104600).</s><s>This organism was isolated from a leg abscess on a patient suffering from ulcerative colitis.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 67.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>