<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6606_nm.3021" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3021" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3021" rank="species">Enterovibrio norvegicus</organism><reference id="rid.6606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomez-Gil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterovibrio norvegicus gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the gut of turbot (Scophthalmus maximus) larvae: a new member of the family Vibrionaceae.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2015</fpage><lpage>2022</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02315-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508862</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterovibrio norvegicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterovibrio norvegicus</i> (nor.ve'gi.cus. M.L. adj. <i>norvegicus</i> of Norway, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus with the following additional features.</s><s>Cells are 0.8x1.0-1.2 lm and motile by means of a polar flagellum when grown in liquid medium.</s><s>They form smooth, rounded colonies with raised margins, beige in colour and about 1 mmin diameter after 2 days incubation on MA at 27-28 °C.</s><s>These facultative anaerobic isolates also grow well on TSA and BHI agar supplemented with 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>The isolates grow slowly on TCBS, forming green colonies after 3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl or with ≥8.0% NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or ≥35 °C.</s><s>Prolific growth occurs in media containing 2% NaCl at 20-28 °C.</s><s>Has both an oxidative and a fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Aerobic utilization of different carbon sources is summarized in Table 4.</s><s>All strains ferment α-D-glucose.</s><s>None of the strains ferment arabinose, amygdalin, melibiose, sucrose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol or D-mannitol.</s><s>Produces β-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BIphosphohydrolase, but not tryptophan deaminase, urease, gelatinase, DNase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, H<sub>2</sub>S or acetoin.</s><s>Is not luminescent and is methyl reD-negative and does not degrade poly(hydroxybutyrate).</s><s>Resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10 and 150 μg, streptomycin (10 μg), trimethoprim (1.2 μg) and fusidic acid (10 μg).</s><s>Intermediate susceptibility to penicillin G (10 U), novobiocin (5 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), polymixin B (300 U), ampicillin (10 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg) and nalidixic acid (30 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids of isolates grown on TSA/MA are summed feature 3 (35.8±0.5/36.2±0.9%; comprising 16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> and/or 15:0 iso 2-OH), 16:0 (20.9±1.5/19.3±0.7%), 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> (15.0±2.0/14.8±1.1%), 12:0 (4.2±0.6/3.4±0.2%), 16:1<i>ω</i>9<i>c</i> (3.5±0.3/3.1±0.2%), 16:0 iso (2.9±1.8/ 2.6±0.5%), 14:0 (2.7±0.8/1.3±0.2%), 18:1<i>ω</i>9<i>c</i> (2.7±0.2/3.1±0.2%), summed feature 2 (2.5±0.4/2.4±0.2%; comprising 14:0 3-OH and/or 16:1 iso I and/or an unidentified fatty acid with equivalent chain length of 10.928 and/or 12:0 ALDE), 12:0 3-OH (1.9±0.4/2.9±0.2%), 18:0 (1.8±0.5/2.4±0.2%), an unidentified fatty acid with equivalent chain length of 12.484 (TSA only: 1.1±0.2%), summed feature 7(TSA only: 0.9±0.3%; 19:1<i>ω</i>6<i>c</i> and/or an unidentified fatty acid with equivalent chain-length value of 18.846), 14:0 iso (TSA only: 0.6±0.5%), 17:1<i>ω</i>8<i>c</i> (MA only: 2.1±0.2%), 17:0 (MA only: 1.4±0.2%) and 18:0 iso (MA only: 1.0±0.1%).</s><s>Isolated from the gut of larvae of the turbot (<i>Scophthalmus maximus</i>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain LMG 19839<sup>T</sup> (=CAIM 430<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>