<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.76_nm.3803" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3803" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3803" rank="subspecies">Campylobacter jejuni doylei</organism><reference id="rid.76"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steele</surname><given-names>T.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Owen</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter jejuni subsp. doylei subsp. nov., a subspecies of nitrate-negative Campylobacters isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>316</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-316</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter jejuni</i> subsp. <i>doylei</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter jejuni</i> subsp. <i>doylei</i> (doyle'i. M.L. gen. n. <i>doylei</i>, of Doyle, named in honor of L. P. Doyle, an American veterinarian)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on 20 strains (16 Australian, 3 West German, 1 British).Cells are rod shaped, with s-shaped and spiral rods present.</s><s>Occasional strains are straight.</s><s>Pleomorphism is common, often increasing with ageing of cultures.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Actively motile due to a single polar flagellum at one or both ends of the cell.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 35 to 37°C.</s><s>On primary isolation slow growing at 37"C, but generally fails to grow at 42°C.</s><s>West German strains grow at 30 ± 0.5°C, but the Australian strains and the British strain do not.</s><s>After 2 days of incubation on blood agar, colonies are pinpoint, increasing to 1 to 2 mm in diameter at 5 days, when they are greyish, smooth, glistening, and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Colonies coalesce on moist agar but do not show the swarming growth typical of <i>C. jejuni</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains form catalase, but some strains (4 of 20 strains) show weak or negative catalase reactions.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Hippurate hydrolyzed to glycine.</s><s>Nitrates not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide not produced in peptone- iron agar.</s><s>Urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Carbohydrates not fermented or oxidized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In disk susceptibility tests all strains are susceptible to penicillin (2 U), cephalothin (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), and tetracycline (10 μg).</s><s>Most (19 of 20) strains are susceptible to nalidixic acid (30 μg).</s><s>All strains are inhibited by cefazolin (200 mglliter), potassium permanganate (0.1%), sodium arsenite (0.001%), and DD-cycloserine (6 mg/liter).</s><s>Most (19 of 20) strains are inhibited by nalidixic acid (60 mg/liter), but 10 of 20 strains grow on metronidazole (5 mg/liter).</s><s>The British and Australian strains are inhibited by 0.05% 2,3,5 triphenyltetrazolium chloride, but the West German strains grow on this concentration.</s><s>The latter strains also differ in being tolerant to pyronin Y (0.2%) and to safranin 0 (0.05%).</s><s>All strains grow on 5-fluorouracil (100 mg/liter) when they are tested on blood-free medium incubated for 4 days (2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the DNAs of 10 strains are 29 L 1 mol% (mean L standard deviation; range, 28 to 31 mol%; thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Serotyping with heat-stable antigens (12) shows that the Australian strains belong to Penner types 2, 3, 4, 12, 13,25,43,58, and 59.</s><s>Some strains are nontypable.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from the gastric antral epithelia of adult patients (biopsy specimens) and from the feces of children with diarrhoea.</s><s>The clinical significance of the new subspecies has not yet been established, but Kasper and Dickgiesser (7) reported isolating such bacteria along with Campylobacter pylori from two patients with gastric ulcers and active chronic gastritis. <i>C. jejuni</i> subsp. <i>doylei</i> can be distinguished readily from <i>C. fetus</i> (the type species) and from most other campylobacters by its inability to reduce nitrate and its ability to hydrolyze hippurate.</s><s>Other characteristics useful in identification and for separation of the new subspecies from allied thermophilic campylobacters and <i>C. fennelliae</i>, which is also nitrate negative, are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 11951 (=093=IMVS 1141).</s><s>Its characteristics are the same as those described (above for the subspecies.</s><s>It is catalase positive.</s><s>Its guanine-plus-cytosine content is 29 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Agglutinated by Penner serotype 25 antiserum (heat-stable antigens).</s><s>Isolated in Australia from the feces of a child with diarrhoea.</s><s>The following additional strains of <i>C. jejuni</i> subsp. <i>doylei</i> are deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: NCTC 11847 (= Kasper strain 71), NCTC 11848 (= Kasper strain 247), NCTC 11849 (= Kasper strain 324), NCTC 11924 (= IMVS 1087), NCTC 11925 (= IMVS 542), and NCTC 11950 (= A608/84).</s></p></content></protolog>