<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8542_nm.13613" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13613" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13613" rank="species">Sphingobium rhizovicinum</organism><reference id="rid.8542"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobium rhizovicinum sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil of Fortunella hindsii (Champ. ex Benth.) Swingle.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1801</fpage><lpage>1806</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65564-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676460</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobium rhizovicinum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobium rhizovicinum</em> (rhi.zo.vi.ci′num. Gr. n. <em>rhiza</em> root; L. masc. adj. <em>vicinus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> neighbouring; N.L. neut. adj. <em>rhizovicinum</em> neighbouring a root, referring to the rhizosphere, soil closely related to plant roots, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and rod-shaped (0.4–0.6×1.0–1.5 μm).</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>On nutrient agar, tryptone soya agar and BHI agar, pale-yellow, slightly elevated colonies with entire margins are formed.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-negative, grows at temperatures ranging between 22 and 37 °C, and tolerates pH in the range 5.5–8 and salt concentration of 3.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 59.4±0.2 mol%.</s><s>Exhibits the salient chemotaxonomic characteristic of the genus <em>Sphingobium</em>.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid profile is presented in Supplementary Table S1 (available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Respiratory quinones consist of the major compound ubiquinone Q-10 and minor amounts of Q-9.</s><s>Polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, sphingoglycolipid and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>In addition, minor amounts of an unknown aminolipid, two unknown phospholipids, two unknown phosphoglycolipids, an unknown glycolipid and five unknown polar lipids are detected.</s><s>Polyamine pattern contains the major compound spermidine and moderate amounts of spermine.</s><s>Gelatin, hippurate and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive (Biolog GN2 system) for dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 80, Tween 40, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, citric acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline and l-proline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Employing Biolog GN2 the following substrates are not oxidized: adonitol, d-arabitol, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, <em>m</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, sucrose, turanose, <em>cis-</em>aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, acetic acid, formic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-ornithine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Using ATB Staph (bioMérieux), sensitive to cotrimoxazole, tetracycline, minocycline and gentamicin (intermediately sensitive) and resistant to rifampicin, norfloxacin, levofloxacin, nitrofurantoin, penicillin, clindamycin, erythromycin, fusidic acid, plindamycin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, quinupristin-dalfopristin, coag-oxacillin and oxacillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In API 20NE, positive for nitrate reduction, aesculin, gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, potassium-gluconate, capric acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate, but negative for l-tryptophan, arginine, urease, glucose fermentation, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, phenylacetic acid and adipic acid.</s><s>In API 20E, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer), gelatinase and fermentation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, melibiose and amygdalin, but not indole, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease or oxidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In API ZYM, positive for alkaline acid phosphatase, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), myristate lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, and negative for trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (CC-FH12-1<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7941<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17770<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from rhizosphere soil of <em>Fortunella hindsii</em> (Champ. ex Benth.) Swingle.</s></p></content></protolog>