<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12710_nm.22474" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22474" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22474" rank="species">Bacillus xiaoxiensis</organism><reference id="rid.12710"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Q.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus xiaoxiensis sp. nov., a slightly halophilic bacterium isolated from non-saline forest soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2100</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026286-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870888</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus xiaoxiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus xiaoxiensis</em> (xi.a.o.xi.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>xiaoxiensis</em> pertaining to Xiaoxi National Natural Reserve, China, the source of the sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, slightly halophilic, facultatively anaerobic, straight rods, approximately 0.6–1.2 µm wide and 3.0–5.0 µm long, occurring singly, as pairs or as short chains, producing ellipsoidal endospores that lie in central to subterminal, slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are yellow-pigmented, flat and opaque, have smooth, glistening surfaces and circular/slightly irregular margins, and are 2–3 mm in diameter on MA.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0.5–20 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2–4 %), at pH 6.0–10.5 (optimum pH 8.0) and at 5–40 °C (optimum 25–30 °C).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrite is not further reduced.</s><s>Negative for egg yolk reaction, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production tests.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but cellulose, DNA, ONPG, and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from amygdalin, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, starch and sucrose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: d-glucose, glycogen, d-mannose, d-xylose, amygdalin, glycerol, d-salicin, acetate and l-asparagine.</s><s>The following are not utilized: l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, adonitol, d-arabitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, succinate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are expressed constitutively; acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14),lysine decarboxylase, α-mannosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, trypsin, urease and valine arylamidase activities are not observed.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone, and diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol as the major polar lipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JSM 081004<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AA 208057<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 21943<sup>T</sup>), isolated from non-saline forest soil in Xiaoxi National Natural Reserve, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.1 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p></content></protolog>