<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8359_nm.13538" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13538" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13538" rank="species">Prevotella falsenii</organism><reference id="rid.8359"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kumada</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bakir</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella falsenii sp. nov., a Prevotella intermedia-like organism isolated from monkey dental plaque.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>319</fpage><lpage>322</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002626-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196771</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella falsenii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella falsenii</em> (fal.se′ni.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>falsenii</em> of Falsen, to honour the contemporary Norwegian microbiologist Enevold Falsen, for his lifelong interest in bacterial taxonomy and for his systematic characterization of bacteria at the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, pigmented, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods or coccobacilli (0.5–0.8×1.6 μm or 0.8×0.9–1.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, brown to black, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth on EG agar plates.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in the presence of 20 % (w/v) bile.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose and sucrose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, lactose, d-mannitol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Gelatin is digested.</s><s>Catalase and urease are not produced.</s><s>With API Rapid ID 32A, positive reactions are obtained for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, indole production, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>Mannose and raffinose are fermented.</s><s>All of the other tests performed (for urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, nitrate reduction, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and serine arylamidase) give negative results.</s><s>The major end products (from 1 % peptone/1 % yeast extract/1 % glucose broth cultures) are succinic and acetic acids.</s><s>Both non-hydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 04052<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15124<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 56137<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from monkey dental plaque.</s><s>Seven additional strains [04013 (=JCM 15121), 04021 (=JCM 15122), 04043 (=JCM 15123), 0406 (=JCM 15125), 04113 (=JCM 15126), 04111 (=JCM 15127) and 04161 (=JCM 15128)], from the same source, are included in this species.</s></p></content></protolog>