<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8834_nm.13414" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13414" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13414" rank="species">Megamonas funiformis</organism><reference id="rid.8834"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sutterella parvirubra sp. nov. and Megamonas funiformis sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>970</fpage><lpage>975</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65456-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398204</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Megamonas funiformis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Megamonas funiformis</em> (fu.ni.for′mis. L. masc. n. <em>funis</em> string; L. fem. adj. suffix -<em>formis</em> shaped, N.L. fem. adj. <em>funiformis</em> string-shaped, referring to the cell shape).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>In young plate cultures, cells consist of fairly homogeneous-sized, straight rods, approximately 1×5–10 μm, which stain Gram-negative.</s><s>In broth cultures containing glucose (e.g. PYG broth), cells are filamentous, 1×5–200 μm in size, with or without a central, subterminal or terminal swelling of 2–4 μm diameter.</s><s>Colonies on GAM agar are approximately 0.5–1 cm in diameter, rough, convex, rhizoid with an erose margin.</s><s>Colonies are weakly <em>β</em>-haemolytic on horse-blood agar.</s><s>In API systems, oxidase and catalase are negative.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>l-Arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are utilized.</s><s>Cellobiose, glycerol, melezitose and l-rhamnose are not utilized.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Weakly positive reactions are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Activity is not detected for alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, lipase (C4), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase, urease or valine arylamidase.</s><s>End products of metabolism from PYG broth are propionic and acetic acids and small amounts of lactic and succinic acids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 32.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 11815<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19343<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14723<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s></p></content></protolog>