<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5277_nm.2379" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2379" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2379" rank="species">Legionella sainthelensi</organism><reference id="rid.5277"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibb</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eng</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allard</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella sainthelensi: a new species of Legionella isolated from water near Mt. St. Helens.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6712210</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella sainthelensi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella sainthelensi</i> (saint.he' len.si, <i>sainthelensi</i> M. L. mas. gen. n. from Mt. St. Helens is proposed, since the organism was discovered in water in the devastated areas of Mt. St. Helens after the eruption of that volcano)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> is Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 (ATCC 35248) (it is also the serological reference strain and the DNA hybridization reference strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A number of legionellae were isolated throughout the sampling period from water samples taken near Mt. St.</s><s>Helens.</s><s>The samples which gave the largest number of isolates were obtained from a volcano-produced debris impoundment of a small creek and from the north fork of the Toutle River, which is the main drainage system in the area devastated by volcanic activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>One of 12 water samples collected on 27 April 1981 yielded isolates of <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroups 1 and 4.</s><s>The new species, <i>L. sainthelensi</i>, was isolated along with strains of <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroup 1 and <i>L. dumoffii</i> in 1 of 12 samples collected on 4 May.</s><s>Two of 14 samples taken in mid-June contained both <i>L. sainthelensi</i> and <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroup 4.</s><s>A <i>Legionella</i>-like organism to be described in the future was found in one of 16 samples collected on 29 June.</s><s>One of 10 samples collected in August contained <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroup 1, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, <i>L. gormanii</i>, <i>L. sainthelensi</i>, and <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2.</s><s>Five of 11 samples taken at the end of October yielded various legionellae, including strains of <i>L. sainthelensi</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The first strain of <i>L. sainthelensi</i>, which was designated Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 3, was isolated from a spring located near Spirit Lake.</s><s>Additional strains were subsequently isolated from the north fork of the Toutle River above and below the debris dam and from a cold water impoundment at a 40-foot (ca. 12.2 m) elevation. <i>Legionella</i> species, including <i>L. sainthelensi</i>, were recovered from near the surface to depths of 90 feet (ca. 27.4 m) in lakes and impoundments.</s><s>Legionellae were also recovered from swift-flowing water in the Toutle River.</s><s>The pH of these waters varied from 7.2 to 8.4, and the temperature profiles in the areas where recorded varied from 17째C in April to 10째C in September.</s><s>Other microbial flora collected from these cold-water sites included species of <i>Nodularia</i>, <i>Pseudonabaena</i>, <i>Anabaena</i>, <i>Oscillatoria</i>, <i>Nitzschia</i>, <i>Tribonema</i>, <i>Chlamydomonas</i>, <i>Chlorella</i>, and microflagellates (21).</s><s>At the time that legionellae were recovered, dissolved organic carbon concentrations had decreased, metal concentrations remained higher than normal, and phytoplanktonic photosynthesis was insignificant.</s><s>The predominant algal flora were unicellular green algae and filamentous <i>Tribonema</i> and <i>Anabaena</i> species.</s><s>The total number of algae was between 6 x 104 and 7 x 10<sup>2</sup>/liter.</s><s>Ciliated protozoa were found at concentrations of 10<sup>2</sup> to 10<sup>5</sup> liter (21).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> appeared on all three Legionella enrichment media on day 3 of incubation and increased in size for several days.</s><s>No growth occurred on blood agar.</s><s>The colonies were gray with a smooth, but slightly textured, surface (ground glass appearance).</s><s>Colonies were raised with an entire edge.</s><s>The six isolates of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> (Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 3, 4, 7, 8, 10, and 11) had identical biochemical characteristics.</s><s>They were thin, gram-negative, nonsporeforming, non-acid fast, motile rods. <i>L. sainthelensi</i> strains were positive in reactions for catalase, oxidase, gelatin liquefaction, and beta-lactamase.</s><s>They were negative in tests for urease, hydrolysis of hippurate, fermentation of DAPPL glucose, and reduction of nitrates.</s><s>Colonies of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> did not show blue-white autofluorescence under a Woods lamp.</s><s>These reactions are similar to those of other legionellae.</s><s>Biochemically, <i>L. sainthelensi</i> can be separated from the autofluorescent species <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, and <i>L. gormanii</i> because it does not autofluoresce.</s><s>It is separable from <i>L. pneumophila</i> by its negative hippurate test, from <i>L. micdadei</i> by its production of beta-lactamase, and from <i>L. oakridgensis</i> by its motility.</s><s>It is biochemically indistinguishable from <i>L. jordanis</i>, <i>L. longbeachae</i>, and <i>L. wadsworthii</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular fatty acid composition of six isolates of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> is presented in Table 1.</s><s>Each isolate was grown and tested at least three times, and the values are means from these determinations.</s><s>The fatty acids of these six isolates are qualitatively similar to those of other Legionella species with the characteristic features of the presence of isobranched-chain 14- and 16-carbon acids (i-14:0, i-16:0) and anteisobranched-chain 15- and 17-carbon acids (a-15:0, a-17:0) together with relatively large amounts of a monounsaturated straight-chain 16-carbon acid (16:1) and the absence of individual hydroxy acids at concentrations greater than 1% (6, 16-18).</s><s>Like other legionellae, <i>L. sainthelensi</i> contains relatively large amounts (50 to 62%) of the total acids as branched-chain acids (4, 6, 16-18).</s><s>Quantitatively, the fatty acid composition of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> is most similar to those of <i>L. bozemanii</i> (4, 14, 18), <i>L. longbeachae</i> (16), <i>L. dumoffii</i> (4, 18), L. jordanis (4, 18), <i>L. gormanii</i> (4, 18), and <i>L. wadsworthii</i> (6) but is distinct from those of <i>L. pneumophila</i> (4, 17, 18), L. oakridgensis (18), and <i>L. micdadei</i> (4, 9, 18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Each of the six isolates of <i>L. sainthelensi</i>, Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 3, 4, 7, 8, 10, and 11, contained approximately equal amounts of ubiquinones Q9, Q10, Q1l, and Q12; no menaquinones were detected in any strain.</s><s>This ubiquinone pattern is similar to those of <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, and <i>L. longbeachae</i> but is distinct from those of <i>L. pneumophila</i>, <i>L. micdadei</i>, <i>L. jordanis</i>, <i>L. wadsworthii</i>, <i>L. oakridgensis</i>, and <i>L. feeleii </i> (10; unpublished data).</s><s>The patterns were very reproducible, since essentially identical results were obtained with each of the isolates grown and processed three separate times.</s><s>The presence of Q1l and Q12 as major components in <i>L. sainthelensi</i> is consistent with our previous data which show that all <i>Legionella</i> contain ubiquinones with more than 10 isoprene units in the side chain (10).</s><s>Thus, analysis for ubiquinones and cellular fatty acids provide chemical data for clear definition of <i>Legionella</i>; in some instances the quantitative data from these analyses are useful for definition of groups or species within the genus (10, 14).</s><s>On the bases of biochemical reactions, fatty acid analysis, and ubiquinone content, one still cannot separate <i>L. sainthelensi</i> from <i>L. longbeachae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>L. sainthelensi</i> isolates were tested with diagnostic dilutions of fluorescein conjugates made to the reference strains of <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroups 1 to 8, <i>L. micdadei</i>, <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffli</i>, <i>L. gormanii</i>, <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2, <i>L. jordanis</i>, <i>L. oakridgensis</i>, and <i>L. wadsworthii</i>.</s><s>Cells of all six Mt. St.</s><s>Helens strains stained dimly (2+) with conjugates for <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 2 (Tucker 1) and <i>L. oakridgensis</i> (Oak Ridge 10) and gave no reaction with all other conjugates.</s><s>As a further stringent test of serological relatedness, the isolates were tested with 1:8 dilutions (10 mg of immunoglobulin G per ml, considered undilute) of conjugates made to the above organisms.</s><s>At.this dilution, cells of the Mt. St.</s><s>Helens isolates stained brightly with conjugates to <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 1 (Long Beach 4), <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 2, and <i>L. oakridgensis</i>.</s><s>When these three organisms were similarly tested with conjugates prepared to Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 3, 4, and 7, <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 1 cells stained 3 to 4+ and <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 2 cells stained to a lesser extent (2+) with the three conjugates.</s><s>At the diagnostic working dilution, these conjugates stained the cells of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 1, but not <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 2, dimly (2+).</s><s>The staining patterns of all Mt. St.</s><s>Helens isolates were identical with all heterologous and homologous conjugates tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Conjugates for Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 3, 4, and 7, which were cross-absorbed with cells of the heterologous Mt. St.</s><s>Helens strains, were not reactive with either the homologous or heterologous Mt. St.</s><s>Helens antigens (including Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 8, 10, and 11).</s><s>Absorption of <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2 and <i>L. oakridgensis</i> conjugates with Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 cells removed all reactivity for cells of all Mt. St.</s><s>Helens isolates (Table 2).</s><s>The cross-reactions between <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2 were also eliminated or greatly reduced after this absorption.</s><s>When the Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 conjugate was absorbed with cells of <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 1, reactions of this conjugate with both <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2 were removed, but reactivity with <i>L. oakridgensis</i> remained intact.</s><s>Subsequent absorption of the conjugate with cells of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> eliminated this cross-reaction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on direct fluorescent antibody testing, <i>L. sainthelensi</i> is antigenically related to L. oakridgensis and to both serogroups of <i>L. longbeachae</i>.</s><s>The reciprocal cross-reactions of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> with the two serogroups of <i>L. longbeachae</i> appear to be due to the same antigen, since absorption of the conjugates to Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 with cells of <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroup 1 removes reactivity of the conjugate for both <i>L. longbeachae</i> serogroups 1 and 2.</s><s>Another distinct antigenic locus is evidently involved in the reciprocal cross-reaction with <i>L. oakridgensis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The heterologous cross-reactions observed are not of significant intensity to cause confusion when conjugates are used at their diagnostic dilutions.</s><s>However, because of possible antigenic variation and differences in reagent specificity, it is desirable to absorb conjugates with cells of the heterologous organism to achieve complete specificity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At this point in the investigation <i>L. sainthelensi</i> could have represented a new serogroup in <i>L. longbeachae</i>, a new serogroup in another <i>Legionella</i> species that differed slightly in its biochemical characteristics, or a new species.</s><s>DNA hybridization was necessary to choose between these alternatives.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>L. sainthelensi</i> strain Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 DNA was labeled in vitro with <sup>32</sup>P<sub>i</sub> and tested for relatedness to DNAs from other <i>L. sainthelensi</i> strains and DNAs from the type strains of all described Legionella species (Table 3).</s><s>Two other <i>L. sainthelensi</i> strains were more than 90% related to Mt. St.</s><s>Helens 4 in reactions done at both 60째C (optimal for DNA reassociation) and 75째C (a stringent reassociation criterion where only closely related sequences can form stable DNA heteroduplexes).</s><s>The thermal stability of the related DNA sequences indicated that there were 0.5% unpaired nucleotide bases (divergence).</s><s>Thus, these strains all belonged to the same species.</s><s>Since all six strains of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> were identical biochemically, in analyses of cellular fatty acids and quinones, and in their 0 antigens, it was therefore considered sufficient to test only three of the six strains for DNA relatedness. <i>L. sainthelensi</i> was 36% related to the type strain of <i>L. longbeachae</i>, with evidence of 8.5% divergence in the related sequences.</s><s>Interestingly, these two species showed antigenic cross-reactions.</s><s>Relatedness of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> to the other described Legionella species was 3 to 14%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of genetic relatedness, strains of <i>L. sainthelensi</i> are a single species that showed a significant amount of relatedness to <i>L. longbeachae</i> and some degree of relatedness to all other legionellae. <i>L. sainthelensi</i> thus belongs in the genus <i>Legionella</i> because of its cultural characteristics, biochemical and serological characteristics, branched-chain fatty acid composition, ubiquinone content, and DNA relatedness.</s></p></content></protolog>