<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7870_nm.6946" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6946" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6946" rank="species">Streptomyces cochleatus</organism><reference id="rid.7870"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakagaito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Three new species of the genus Streptomyces: Streptomyces cochleatus sp. nov., Streptomyces paracochleatus sp. nov., and Streptomyces azaticus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>120</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces cochleatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces cochleatus</i> (coch.le.a.tus. L. adj. <i>cochleatus</i>, spiral, referring to the formation of spiral aerial mycelia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The color of vegetative mycelia is grayish brown.</s><s>The color of aerial mycelia is gray.</s><s>Mature spore chains are long, forming hooks or spirals on glycerol-asparagine agar, tyrosine agar, oatmeal agar, glucoseasparagine agar and water agar.</s><s>Spores are cylindrical with a smooth surface.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Brown soluble pigments are produced on yeast extract-malt extract agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 13 to 38°C.</s><s>The concentration of NaCl at which growth occurs is less than 3%.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, starch is hydrolyzed, gelatin is not liquefied, and milk is peptonized but not coagulated.</s><s>D-Glucose and L-arabinose are utilized, but D-fructose, D-mannitol, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, rafinose, inositol and sucrose are not or poorly utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains both LL- and <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>2pm and a small amount of glycine.</s><s>Galactose and a trace of madurose are detected as whole-cell sugars.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is type II.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) are detected.</s><s>The G + C content of DNA is 72.4 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 14768 (=M-5).</s></p></content></protolog>