<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6073_nm.10179" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10179" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10179" rank="species">Effluviibacter roseus</organism><reference id="rid.6073"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suresh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Effluviibacter roseus gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from muddy water, belonging to the family Flexibacteraceae.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1703</fpage><lpage>1707</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64144-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825654</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Effluviibacter roseus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Effluviibacter roseus</em> (ro′se.us. L. masc. adj. <em>roseus</em> rose-coloured, pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following features in addition to those listed in the description of the genus.</s><s>Cells are non-sporulating, irregular rods, 1.0–3.0 μm in length and 0.3–0.5 μm in width.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are dark pink, circular, convex, smooth and 2–3 mm in diameter after incubation for 6–8 days.</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C, but not at 42 °C, and at pH 6.0–10.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive in methyl red, amylase, protease, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase tests but is negative for arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch and gelatin but not urea, Tween 20 or aesculin.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite and is negative in the Voges–Proskauer test and for indole production, citrate utilization and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, raffinose and sucrose but not acetate, adonitol, arabinose, citrate, fumarate, lactate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, salicin, sorbitol or succinate as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>Assimilates histidine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, ornithine, l-proline and glycine as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-arginine, dl-alanine or l-methionine.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose but not from lactose or sucrose.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin and tobramycin but sensitive to vancomycin, lincomycin, streptomycin, gentamicin and chlortetracycline.</s><s>The whole-cell fatty acids are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The phospholipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SRC-1<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 7260<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17521<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from muddy water from an occasional drainage system in Chandigarh, India.</s></p></content></protolog>