<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9693_nm.14838" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14838" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14838" rank="species">Tepidimicrobium xylanilyticum</organism><reference id="rid.9693"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tepidimicrobium xylanilyticum sp. nov., an anaerobic xylanolytic bacterium, and emended description of the genus Tepidimicrobium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2698</fpage><lpage>2701</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005124-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625437</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tepidimicrobium xylanilyticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tepidimicrobium xylanilyticum</em> (xy.la.ni.ly′ti.cum. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan, a plant polymer; Gr. adj. <em>lytikos</em> able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus</em> <em>-a</em> <em>-um</em> dissolving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>xylanilyticum</em> xylan-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, straight or slightly curved rods with slightly pointed ends, 0.4–0.5 μm in diameter and 4.0–10.0 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and exhibit twitching motility due to peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Occasionally, terminal spherical spores are formed.</s><s>Colonies on PYG agar are white, round and 0.5 mm in diameter after cultivation at 60 °C for 72 h.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–67 °C (optimum 60 °C) and pH 5.8–9.3 (optimum pH 8.5).</s><s>Growth occurs in the range of 0–4.5 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth at 3.0 % (w/v).</s><s>Utilizes a variety of substrates, including peptone, tryptone, Casamino acids, yeast extract, beef extract, casein hydrolysate, l-cysteine, l-serine, l-lysine, l-glycine, l-threonine, l-methionine, pyruvate, xylan, xylose, glucose and cellobiose.</s><s>Acetate, ethanol, butyrate and hydrogen are the main products when glucose is available as the sole substrate, and a trace amount of propionic acid is also produced.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine, l-glutamine, l-tyrosine, tryptophan, l-isoleucine, l-proline, aspartate, l-alanine, l-arginine, ribose, fructose, mannose, lactose, galactose, l-arabinose, rhamnose, sucrose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, aesculin, glycogen, inulin, casein, starch, glycerol, lactate, malate, fumarate, salicin, sorbose, trehalose, adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribitol, methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, citrate, fumarate, malate, malonate, hippurate, sodium gluconate, butane diacid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid, CM-cellulose, chitin and filter paper.</s><s>Milk is not curdled and gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Produces NH<sub>3</sub> from PYG and H<sub>2</sub>S from thiosulfate.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PML14<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.5080<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15035<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the sludge of a thermophilic anaerobic digester treating municipal solid waste and sewage in Beijing, China.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 36.2±0.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>