<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.547_nm.8081" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8081" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8081" rank="species">Flavobacterium degerlachei</organism><reference id="rid.547"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandecandelaere</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium degerlachei sp. nov., Flavobacterium frigoris sp. nov. and Flavobacterium micromati sp. nov., novel psychrophilic bacteria isolated from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>85</fpage><lpage>92</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02857-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742463</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium degerlachei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium degerlachei</em> (de.ger.lach′e.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>degerlachei</em> of Adrien de Gerlache, in honour of the Belgian pioneer who conducted the first scientific expedition to Antarctica in 1897–1899).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (&#x003C;1×3–4 μm) that often form pairs or short chains.</s><s>Gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–30 °C with an optimal growth temperature of 20 °C, whereas no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Yellow, convex, translucent colonies with entire margins and a diameter of 1–3 mm are formed on R2A plates after 6 days incubation.</s><s>Colonies on Anacker &#x0026; Ordal's agar are flat, round with entire margins and 0·5–1·0 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on trypticase soy agar, nutrient agar and marine agar; colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are degraded.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Growth is observed (API 20NE) on glucose, mannose and maltose, whereas no growth is detected on arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, casein, CM-cellulose, DNA, gelatin, tyrosine and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed and no flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>No production of brown diffusible pigment occurs on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction, Voges–Proskauer reaction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains shows activity for the enzymes arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for cystine arylamidase, medium activity is observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, and strong activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM).</s><s>Cells contain the fatty acids C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (which comprises iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> or both) as the main constituents.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–5 % NaCl but not in 10 % NaCl, indicating that the strains are not halophilic, but are moderately halotolerant.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 33·8–34·2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21915<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15718<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from Lakes Ace and Pendant in the Vestfold Hills and Lake Reid in the Larsemann Hills, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>