<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10353_nm.16868" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16868" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16868" rank="species">Aestuariibacter litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.10353"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aestuariibacter litoralis sp. nov., isolated from a sandy sediment of the Sea of Japan</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>320</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012435-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651716</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aestuariibacter litoralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aestuariibacter litoralis</em> (li.to.ra′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>litoralis</em> of the seashore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive, motile, rod-shaped bacterium (approx. 2 μm in length).</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, opaque, whitish and shiny, with wrinkled surface and regular edges of 2–3 mm in diameter on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–40 °C, with optimum growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium containing 0.5–6 % NaCl without other sea salts added.</s><s>No growth is observed on media containing 0.5–12 % (w/v) artificial sea salts, but is observed on media containing 20–100 % (w/v) artificial sea salts.</s><s>pH range for growth is 5.5–10.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.5–8.0.</s><s>Positive for Tween 80, starch, aesculin and DNA hydrolysis.</s><s>Negative for casein and chitin hydrolysis, and for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Gelatin is slowly hydrolysed over 4–5 days routinely and in API 20NE, and 2 days in API 20E tests.</s><s>Does not produce melanin-like pigments or clearance zone on medium containing l-tyrosine.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, d-mannitol, sucrose, d-lactose, maltose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>In addition, according to API 20NE tests, positive for aesculin hydrolysis and nitrate reduction, and negative for indole production, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease production and the <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside test, and assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannitol, maltose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for trisodium citrate utilization, and negative for ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, acetoin production, and utilization of d-glucose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and d-arabinose.</s><s>In API 50 CH tests, weakly positive for utilization of potassium 5-ketogluconate and negative for utilization of glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate and gluconate.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (detailed fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2).</s><s>Susceptible to the following antibiotics (content per disc): ampicillin (10 μg), vancomycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), oleandomycin (15 μg), ofloxacin (5 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), cephazolin (30 μg) and cephalexin (30 μg); and resistant to benzylpenicillin (10 U), lincomycin (15 μg), neomycin (30 μg) and oxacillin (10 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3894<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0754<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15896<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sandy sample, collected offshore of the Sea of Japan, Russia at a depth of 3 m.</s></p></content></protolog>