<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.688_nm.8603" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8603" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8603" rank="species">Haloferax sulfurifontis</organism><reference id="rid.688"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Elshahed</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Savage</surname><given-names>K.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutierrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloferax sulfurifontis sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from a sulfide- and sulfur-rich spring.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2275</fpage><lpage>2279</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63211-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545470</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloferax sulfurifontis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloferax sulfurifontis</em> (sul.fu.ri.fon′tis. L. masc. n. <em>fons</em>, <em>fontis</em> spring; L. neut. n. <em>sulfur</em> sulfur; N.L. gen. n. <em>sulfurifontis</em> of a sulfurous spring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, extremely pleomorphic, occurring mainly as irregularly shaped cells (1·0–1·5 μm in diameter), particularly during the stationary phase, and as rods (1·5–1·7×0·5–0·6 μm), especially during the exponential growth phase.</s><s>Occurs mostly as single cells, sometimes in pairs and clusters.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium with 150 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup> are small (0·8–1·0 mm), salmon pink, transparent and elevated with undulate margin.</s><s>Halophilic.</s><s>Cells lyse immediately in distilled water, within 24 h in 10–20 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup> and within 72 h in 30 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Cells survive prolonged incubation in 40–50 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Grows in a wide range of NaCl concentrations (60 g l<sup>−1</sup> to saturation).</s><s>Requires at least 1 mM Mg<sup>2+</sup> for growth and grows best at 30 mM Mg<sup>2+</sup> and above.</s><s>The optimum pH and temperature values for growth are pH 6·4–6·8 and 32–37 °C.</s><s>The type strain, M6<sup>T</sup>, grows at 18–50 °C and at pH 4·5–9·0.</s><s>Cannot utilize , , , DMSO or TMAO as electron acceptors.</s><s>Reduces elemental sulfur to sulfide under strictly anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Grows on complex media with yeast extract, Casamino acids and peptone as carbon sources.</s><s>Capable of growing in defined media.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources: acetate, benzoate, citrate, fumarate, l-glutamate, malate, succinate, glycerol, maltose, glucose, fructose, sucrose, arabinose, galactose and xylose.</s><s>Alanine, aspartate, arginine, glycine, lactose, mannitol, sorbitol, ribose and starch are not utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced in unbuffered medium from the following compounds: glycerol, xylose, maltose, sucrose, arabinose, fructose, glucose and galactose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from mannitol, arabinose, lactate or sorbitol.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Reduces thiosulfate aerobically to sulfide.</s><s>Capable of aerobic nitrate reduction.</s><s>Indole is formed from tryptophan.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed, whereas starch, casein and urea are not.</s><s>Produces polyhydroxyalkanoates.</s><s>Phosphatase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase tests are negative.</s><s>Ornithine and lysine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, carbenicillin, gentamicin, ceftriaxone, ciprofloxacin, doxycycline, cefaclor, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, oxytetracycline, penicillin G, rifampicin and bacitracin up to 100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Sensitive to aphidicolin, anisomycin and novobiocin, and to high concentrations of bacitracin.</s><s>The major polar lipids in the membrane are the diphytanyl ether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, the methyl ester of phosphatidylglycerophosphate, and S-DGD-1 as the main glycolipid.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M6<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12327<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7217<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16227<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108334<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of M6<sup>T</sup> is 60·5 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the Zodletone spring in south-western Oklahoma, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>