<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7310_nm.1396" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1396" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1396" rank="species">Ochrobactrum intermedium</organism><reference id="rid.7310"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Velasco</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romero</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>López-Goñi</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leiva</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Díaz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moriyón</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Evaluation of the relatedness of Brucella spp. and Ochrobactrum anthropi and description of Ochrobactrum intermedium sp. nov., a new species with a closer relationship to Brucella spp.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>759</fpage><lpage>768</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-759</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ochrobactrum intermedium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ochrobactrum intermediu</i>m (in’ter.me’dium. L. neut. adj. <i>intermedium</i> of intermediate position)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from the results of this work and that of Holmes <i>et al.</i> (1988), and is based on the data obtained with five strains (LMG 3301, LMG 3306, CUN 559, CUN 2944 and CUN 6130, Table 1).</s><s>The cells are rod-shaped, usually occur singly, and are motile by 1-3 polar or subpolar flagella.</s><s>After growth on nutrient agar for 24 h at 37 °C,colonies are typically circular, low convex, about 1 mm in diameter, smooth, shining and entire.</s><s>A total of 47 characteristics are common to the five strains tested (either positive or negative).</s><s>The cells have the following positive characteristics: growth at 37 °C; growth at room temperature (18-22 °C); growth on MacConkey agar; and cytochrome-c oxidase activities; nitrate reduction, SH<sub>2</sub> production; utilization of citrate, glycerol and maltose; and enzymic hydrolysis of p-nitrophenyl α-β-glucoside, p-nitrophenyl phosphate and γ-L-glutamyl p-nitroanilide.</s><s>All the strains gave negative responses</s></p><p class="description"><s>in the following tests: indole production; gelatinase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, and arginine dihydrolase activities; utilization of arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, mannitol, raffinose, sorbitol, saccharose, inositol, rhamnose and paracoumaric acid; enzymic hydrolysis of proline nitroanilide, o-nitrophenyl-galactoside, p-nitrophenyl-β-galactoside, p-nitrophenyl-bisphosphate, p-nitro-phenyl-xyloxide, p-nitrophenyl-β-glucuronide, p-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline, p-nitrophenyl-β-N- acetylglucosaminide, p-nitrophenyl-α-arabinoside, p-nitro-DL-phenylalanine and esculine; and assimilation of adipate, phenyl-acetate, 2,4,4’-trichloro-2’-hidroxy-diphenylether, acetamide and malonate.</s><s>In contrast to seven <i>O. anthropi</i> strains tested, five strains of the proposed new species were resistant to colistin.</s><s>More-over, PCR test with primers F4 (5’-TCGAGCGCCCGCAAGGG-3’) and R2 (5’-AACCATAGTGTCTCCACTAA-3’) are positive with <i>O. intermedium</i> and negative with <i>O. anthropi</i> (Romero <i>et al</i>., 1995).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNAs of strains LMG 3301 and 3306 are between 57.7 and 58.3 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 3301<sup>T</sup>(= NCTC 12171<sup>T</sup>= CNS 2-75<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>