<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12850_nm.22657" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22657" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22657" rank="species">Kaistia dalseonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12850"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kaistia geumhonensis sp. nov. and Kaistia dalseonensis sp. nov., two members of the class Alphaproteobacteria</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2577</fpage><lpage>2581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028894-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21131499</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kaistia dalseonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kaistia dalseonensis</em> (dal.se.o.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>dalseonensis</em> pertaining to the Dalseo Stream, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, non-motile short rods and cocci, varying in size between 0.6 and 1.0 µm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are round with a greasy surface and cream in colour.</s><s>Good growth is observed on R2A agar at 28–32 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 18–37 °C but not at 10 or 42 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is pH 7–8; growth occurs at pH 6–9 but not at pH 5 or 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, chitin, DNA, starch, CM-cellulose or xylan.</s><s>Positive for urease, aesculin hydrolysis, β-galactosidase activity and reduction of nitrates to nitrites but negative for nitrite reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase activity and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20 NE test strip).</s><s>Assimilates <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, inositol, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, malic acid, d-melibiose, potassium 2-ketogluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sucrose, salicin and d-sorbitol but does not assimilate adipic acid, l-alanine, capric acid, glycogen, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, lactic acid, phenylacetic acid, potassium gluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, l-proline, propionic acid, l-serine, sodium acetate, sodium malonate, suberic acid, trisodium citrate or valeric acid (API 20 NE and API ID 32 GN test strips).</s><s>Positive for (API ZYM test strip) <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, esterase (C4), β-galactosidase and α- and β-glucosidase activities but negative for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), α-fucosidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin, d- and l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, rhamnose, d-turanose, d-xylose and l-xylose and is produced weakly from d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, d-fucose, galactose, gentiobiose, glucose, inositol, mannose, melezitose, methyl β-d-xylose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose and xylitol, but is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, methyl α-d-mannoside, sorbitol, starch or d-tagatose.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> cyclo.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B6-8<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 12850<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 18800<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the Dalseo Stream in Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of type strain is 66.5 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>