<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3720_nm.10890" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10890" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10890" rank="species">Natrinema ejinorense</organism><reference id="rid.3720"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Castillo</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutiérrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cowan</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Natrinema ejinorense sp. nov., isolated from a saline lake in Inner Mongolia, China</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2683</fpage><lpage>2687</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64421-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082411</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Natrinema ejinorense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Natrinema ejinorense</em> (e.ji.no.ren′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>ejinorense</em> pertaining to the saline lake Ejinor, Inner Mongolia, China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile and pleomorphic, with triangular, square, rod, disc and other polygonal shapes, and are 1.5–4.0×0.8–2.0 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, entire, opaque, pale red pigmented and 0.5–1.5 mm in diameter after 5 days at 37 °C on plates containing 20 % (w/v) total salts.</s><s>Extremely halophilic; cells lyse in water.</s><s>At least 1.8 M NaCl is required for growth (optimal growth at 3.4 M NaCl).</s><s>MgCl<sub>2</sub> is not required for growth.</s><s>The pH and temperature ranges for growth are 6.0–8.5 (optimum at pH 7.0) and 25–50 °C (optimum at 37 °C), respectively.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons' citrate tests are negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, glucose, sucrose, fructose, arabinose, maltose, d-xylose, galactose, trehalose or mannose.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate or l-arginine.</s><s>Starch, gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but DNA and casein are not.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced and gas is produced from nitrite.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, fructose, glycerol, maltose, trehalose, starch, propionate, fumarate, acetate, threonine, asparagine and lysine as single carbon and energy sources for growth.</s><s>No growth is observed on mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, arabinose, galactose, mannose, raffinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, malate, succinate or glutamate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: isoleucine, l-serine and glycine.</s><s>Sensitive to bacitracin and novobiocin, but resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> and C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>25</sub> derivates of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and the disulfated glycolipid, S2-DGA-1.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EJ-57<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7144<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13890<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6202<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from saline Lake Ejinor, Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p></content></protolog>