<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3131_nm.7974" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7974" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7974" rank="species">Bacteroides pectinophilus</organism><reference id="rid.3131"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides pectinophilus sp. nov. and Bacteroides galacturonicus sp. nov.: two pectinolytic bacteria from the human intestinal tract</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>880</fpage><lpage>887</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3777933</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides pectinophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides pectinophilus</i> (pec.ti.no'phil.us. M.L. n. <i>pectinum</i> pectin; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>pectinophilus</i> pectin-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown in broth containing polygalacturonate as fermentable substrate (PF broth) are rod shaped, 0.5 by 2.5-5 μm, arranged singly or in pairs, and rarely in short chains.</s><s>Nonsporeforming, gram-negative, nonmotile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on PF agar medium are cream colored, circular, flat, opaque, and smooth and measure 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Final growth yield in PF broth approximates 1.6 x 10<sup>9</sup> cells per ml, and the cell population doubling time is 1.2 h.</s><s>Final pH of PF broth cultures ranges from 5.0 to 5.5.</s><s>Optimum growth is between 35 and 40°C, with no growth at 20 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobes.</s><s>Pectin, polygalacturonate, and D-gluconate are fermented.</s><s>Occasionally, D-fructose is fermented after a lag of 1 to 3 days.</s><s>L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, L-rhamnose, D-galacturonate, D-glucuronate, pyruvate, glycerol, methanol, amino acids, alginate, amylose, arabinogalactan, carboxymethyl cellulose, cellulose, chondroitin sulfate, dextran, hyaluronic acid, inulin, starch, and xylan are not fermented.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is digested.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Excellent growth in PF broth containing 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate and formate are major end products of polygalacturonate or pectin fermentation.</s><s>Lactate and ethanol are formed in minor amounts.</s><s>In addition, pectin fermentation yields methanol.</s><s>Gluconate fermentation yields acetate, formate, lactate, and a small amount of ethanol.</s><s>Pectin is depolymerized extracellularly by the cumulative action of pectinesterase (EC 3.1.1.11) and of an exopolygalacturonate lyase activity that releases unsaturated trigalacturonate molecules from polygalacturonate and that has a pH optimum of 9 to 9.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G + C of the DNA is 45 as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is N3; this strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 43243.</s></p></content></protolog>