<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.599_nm.8915" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8915" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6176" rank="species">Xylanimicrobium pachnodae</organism><reference id="rid.599"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Promicromonospora pachnodae Cazemier et al. 2004 as Xylanimicrobium pachnodae gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1383</fpage><lpage>1386</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63064-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280318</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Xylanimicrobium pachnodae</em> (Cazemier <em>et al.</em> 2004) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Xylanimicrobium pachnodae</em> (pach.no′dae. N.L. gen. n. <em>pachnodae</em> of <em>Pachnoda</em>, referring to the source of the micro-organism, <em>Pachnoda marginata</em>).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Promicromonospora pachnodae</em> Cazemier <em>et al.</em> 2004</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is that of <em>P. pachnodae</em> and data included in the publication of Cazemier <em>et al.</em> (2003), supplemented with our own data.</s><s>In the exponential phase of growth, cells are pleomorphic rods (0·4–0·6×0·6–3·0 μm), whereas, in the stationary phase, spherical cells dominate (diameter 0·5–0·7 μm).</s><s>Under aerobic conditions in basal medium with glucose as carbon source, nocardioform mycelia-like fringes dominate; these forms are absent under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In rich media, cells are more homogeneously distributed.</s><s>Aerobic to facultatively anaerobic, fermenting glucose, xylose, maltose, lactose (weak) and sucrose; fermentation products of glucose or xylose are formate, lactate, ethanol and acetate but not succinate.</s><s>Aerobically, cells grow with high densities with beach litter, NaOH-pretreated beach litter, xylan, carboxymethylcellulose, cellobiose, glucose, xylose and brain heart infusion medium.</s><s>Optimum growth at pH 7·5 and 35 °C.</s><s>Similar pH and temperature optima are found under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive, gelatin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Major fatty acids are aiC<sub>15 : 0</sub> (58·7 mol%), iC<sub>16 : 0</sub> (8·5 mol%), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8·0 mol%), iC<sub>15 : 0</sub> (6·8 mol%), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (6·1 mol%) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (5·5 mol%). iC<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3·9 mol%) and aiC<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1·9 mol%) occur in smaller amounts.</s><s>In addition to the reaction indicated in Table 2, the following reactions are observed in the Biolog GP2 microtitre plate substrate panel (only strong positive reactions that are not already listed in Table 2 are listed): glycogen, mannan, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, d-lactose, d-glucose, lactulose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-ribose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, methyl pyruvate, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Isolated from the intestine of the rose chafer <em>Pachnoda marginata</em> (Scarabaeidae, Coleoptera).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VPCX2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12657<sup>T</sup>=NCCB 100020<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>