<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6956_nm.4566" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4566" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4566" rank="species">Thermovenabulum ferriorganovorum</organism><reference id="rid.6956"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zavarzina</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuznetsov</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonch-Osmolovskaya</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermovenabulum ferriorganovorum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel thermophilic, anaerobic, endospore-forming bacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1737</fpage><lpage>1743</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02214-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361281</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermovenabulum ferriorganovorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermovenabulum ferriorganovorum</i> (fer.ri.or.ga.no.vo'rum. L. n. <i>ferrum</i> iron; N.L. n. <i>organum</i> organic compound; L. v. <i>voro</i> to eat, consume; N.L. adj. <i>ferriorganovorum</i> using iron and organic compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, sometimes branched rods, 0.5-0.6 μm in diameter and 1.5-7.0 μm in length, forming round, refractile, heat-resistant endospores in terminally swollen sporangia.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in short chains and exhibit slight tumbling motility due to peritrichous flagellation.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 45-76°C, with an optimum at 63-65°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 4.8-8.2, with an optimum at 6.7-6.9.</s><s>Growth occurs in NaCl concentrations of 0-3.5% (w/v).</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Substrates utilized include peptone, yeast extract, beef extract, Casamino acids, starch, pyruvate, melibiose, sucrose, fructose, maltose, xylose and ribose.</s><s>Utilizes molecular hydrogen in the presence of Fe(III) and an organic electron donor.</s><s>No growth occurs with formate, acetate, propionate, lactate, methanol, ethanol, glycerol, glucose, mannose, galactose, arabinose, cellobiose or glycogen.</s><s>The fermentation products from melibiose are ethanol, acetate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Reduces amorphous Fe(III) oxide, Fe(III) citrate, AQDS, fumarate, nitrate, sulfite, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur and MnO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to ammonium.</s><s>Sulfite, thiosulfate and elemental sulfur are reduced to hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>None of the electron acceptors utilized, except fumarate, stimulates growth.</s><s>Does not reduce sulfate and is incapable of growth with O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, neomycin, polymyxin B, kanamycin and streptomycin but not by penicillin.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 36 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is a freshwater hydrothermal source in the Uzon caldera on the Kamchatka peninsula, Russia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Z-9801<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14006<sup>T</sup>), which has also been deposited in the Unique Micro-organism Classification and Storage Laboratory of the Institute of Microbiology, Russian Academy of Sciences, under the accession number UNIQEM 210<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>