<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5588_nm.6237" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6237" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6237" rank="species">Corynebacterium macginleyi</organism><reference id="rid.5588"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genomic diversity and phylogenetic relationships among lipid-requiring diphtheroids from humans and characterization of Corynebacterium macginleyi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>128</fpage><lpage>133</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-128</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857793</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium macginleyi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium macginleyi</i> (mac.gin'ley.i. NL. gen. n. of MacGinley, name in honor of Kenneth John McGinley, who made important contributions to the knowledge of lipid-requiring diphtheroids)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data for the three strains included in this study.</s><s>Bacteria are nonmotile pleomorphic rods, non-spore forming, and gram positive with occasionally metachromatic granules arranged in palisades or V-shaped forms.</s><s>They are not acid fast, the rod-coccus cycle is absent, and they are catalase positive, oxidase negative, and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>There is no growth in brain heart infusion broth after 72 h at 37°C, but growth is visible after 24 h in the same broth supplemented with 0.01 to 1% Tween 80.</s><s>Very small (less than 1 mm in diameter) and non-β-hemolytic colonies appear after 48 h on sheep blood agar, but on 1% Tween 80-supplemented sheep blood agar reddish-beige colonies are large (2 to 4 mm in diameter) and Tween esterase activity is noted.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, ribose, and sucrose but not from maltose, lactose, D-xylose, trehalose, or glycogen.</s><s>Fermentation of D-mannitol occurs variably.</s><s>Tyrosine, gelatin, starch, and urea are not degraded or hydrolyzed.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>DNA is degraded.</s><s>Hydrolysis of hippurate is variable.</s><s>Arginine is not degraded.</s><s>Cells produce alkaline phosphatase, but pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl, arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are not produced.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, and galactose.</s><s>Mycolic acids of short chain lengths (C<sub>26</sub> to C<sub>26</sub>) are present.</s><s>DNA base composition is 58 mol% G+C (HPLC procedure). <i>C. macginleyi</i> strains were isolated from human eye specimens.</s><s>The type strain is strain JCL-2 (CIP 104099).</s><s>It was isolated in Sarrebourg, France, from the eye of a patient suffering from a corneal ulcer.</s><s>This strain has all the above properties for the species.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-mannitol, and hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s></p></content></protolog>