<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3482_nm.9413" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9413" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9413" rank="species">Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</organism><reference id="rid.3482"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rhodes</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kator</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McNabb</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Deshayes</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reyrat</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown-Elliott</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trott</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Parker</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lifland</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osterhout</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaattari</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reece</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vogelbein</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ottinger</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii sp. nov., a slowly growing chromogenic species isolated from Chesapeake Bay striped bass (Morone saxatilis).</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1139</fpage><lpage>1147</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63343-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</em> (pseu.do.shott′si.i. Gr. adj. <em>pseudes</em> false; N.L. gen. n. <em>shottsii</em> name of a species; N.L. gen. n. <em>pseudoshottsii</em> a false <em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em>, not the true <em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid-fast coccobacillus (0·4–0·6×0·8–1 μm) that forms cell aggregates in culture.</s><s>Spores and cell branching are not present.</s><s>Colonies on Middlebrook 7H10 agar are rough, photochromogenic and, typically, flat with an irregular margin, becoming umbonate with age.</s><s>A pale-yellow to gold pigment develops following exposure to light and intensifies with age.</s><s>Visible colonies are observed from a dilute inoculum after 4–6 weeks incubation at 23 °C.</s><s>Little or no growth occurs at 30 °C and none occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Isolates do not grow on MacConkey agar without crystal violet or on Löwenstein–Jensen medium with 5 % NaCl, are negative for arylsulfatase (at 3 and 14 days), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, nitrate reductase, pyrazinamidase (at 7 days), semi-quantitative catalase and Tween 80 hydrolysis, and have variable reactions for acid phosphatase and catalase at 68 °C.</s><s>Positive pyrazinamidase reactions do not occur when incubation is extended to 14–21 days.</s><s>Isolates are typically positive for urease production and niacin accumulation.</s><s>These mycobacteria tolerate isoniazid at 1 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> (but not at 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), thiacetazone and thiophene-2-carboxylic hydrazide.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in media containing hydroxylamine and oleate.</s><s>Isolates are resistant to <em>p</em>-aminosalicylic acid and isoniazid but susceptible to ethambutol, kanamycin, rifampicin and streptomycin in disc-based antibiotic-susceptibility tests.</s><s>The mycolic acid HPLC pattern consists of a single cluster of peaks resembling that of <em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em>.</s><s>The 16S rRNA, <em>erp</em> and <em>hsp65</em> gene sequences are unique among recognized species of <em>Mycobacterium</em> and are most similar to those of <em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em>, <em>Mycobacterium ulcerans</em> and <em>Mycobacterium marinum</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, L15<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-883<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13318<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from granulomatous lesions in splenic tissue from a striped bass (<em>Morone saxatilis</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slowly growing mycobacteria, which grow either poorly or not at all at 37 °C, or produce niacin, are compared with <em>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</em> in Table 2.</s><s>Although the combined traits of photochromogenicity and niacin production distinguish <em>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</em> from other species that grow optimally at ≤30 °C, expression of both features is dependent on sufficient incubation, i.e. 2–3 months.</s><s>Other slowly growing mycobacteria that may accumulate niacin are differentiated from <em>Mycobacterium pseudoshottsii</em> by growth at 37 °C and by the profiles for resistance to inhibitory agents.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics of selected <em>Mycobacterium</em> species</s></p><p class="description"><s>1, <em>M. pseudoshottsii</em> sp. nov.; 2, <em>M. shottsii</em>; 3, <em>M. chesapeaki</em>; 4, <em>M. marinum</em>; 5, <em>M. ulcerans</em>; 6, <em>M. simiae</em>; 7, <em>M. tuberculosis</em>.</s><s>Data for species other than <em>M. pseudoshottsii</em> are from Heckert <em>et al.</em> (2001) and Lévy-Frébault &#x0026; Portaels (1992).</s><s>All of the species were negative for resistance to 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Abbreviations: n, non-pigmented; p, photochromogenic; s, scotochromogenic, +, at least 85 % strains positive; −, less than 15 % strains positive; m, 50–80 % strains positive; f, 15–49 % strains positive; na, information not available.</s></p></content></protolog>