<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12284_nm.20299" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20299" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20299" rank="species">Flavobacterium haoranii</organism><reference id="rid.12284"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>R.-B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hang</surname><given-names>B.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.-P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium haoranii sp. nov., a cypermethrin-degrading bacterium isolated from a wastewater treatment system</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2882</fpage><lpage>2886</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020776-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20081015</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium haoranii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium haoranii</em> (hao.ran′i.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>haoranii</em> of Hao-Ran, in honour of Hao-Ran Jian, a respected Chinese microbiologist, for his enormous contributions to the establishment and development of environmental microbiology in China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.3–0.7 μm in width and 1.3–2.0 μm in length, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed and flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are yellow, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 15–37 °C, at pH 6.0–8.5 and in 0–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs on nutrient agar and TSA; weak growth occurs on R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurs on cetrimide agar, Simmons' citrate agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Starch, gelatin and aesculin are degraded, but casein, cellulose, agar, pectin, chitin, DNA, tyrosine and egg yolk are not.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are negative, but urease and aesculin hydrolysis are positive; does not assimilate all carbohydrates tested.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present.</s><s>Lipase C14, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In API 50CH tests, acid is produced from aesculin, maltose, inulin and starch.</s><s>Sensitive to erythromycin, chloramphenicol, rifampicin, spectinomycin, cefradine, streptomycin, ampicillin, polymyxin B, tetracycline, penicillin G, lincomycin, carbenicillin, amoxicillin and vancomycin; resistant to roxithromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin and bacitracin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LQY-7<sup>T</sup> (=ACCC 05409<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 23008<sup>T</sup>), isolated from activated sludge in a synthetic pyrethroid-manufacturing wastewater treatment facility (Yangnong Chemical Group Co., Jiangsu Province, China).</s></p></content></protolog>