<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5238_nm.2975" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2975" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2975" rank="species">Vibrio hollisae</organism><reference id="rid.5238"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of Vibrio hollisae sp. nov. from patients with diarrhea.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>395</fpage><lpage>401</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7076812</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio hollisae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio hollisae</i> (<i>hollisae</i>, is treated as a neo (modem)-Latin genitive noun meaning "of Hollis.")</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram-negative rods, straight to slightly curved, and are about 0.5 μm wide by 1.5 to 2 μm long with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>No lateral flagella were seen on flagellar stains of the type strain when it was grown on solid media.</s><s>The strains are NaCl-requiring, oxidase-positive, nitrate-positive fermenters.</s><s>All are indole positive and produce acid from D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-galactose, and D-mannose.</s><s>They are slowly and weakly motile (88% at 7 days) at 36°C; the type strain was also slow and weak when tested at 25°C.</s><s>The following tests were negative: methyl red, VP, Simmons citrate, urea, L-lysine and L-omithine decarboxylase, L-arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis, and fermentation of most sugars and polyhydroxyl alcohols.</s><s>The G+C content for the type strain is 49.8 mol%.</s><s>This organism has most commonly been isolated from stool specimens of persons with diarrhea.</s><s>The strains had relatively large zones around all antibiotics tested (agar diffusion).</s><s>A more detailed description of the species and its type strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>The type strain (holotype) is designated ATCC 33564 (CDC 0075-80) and was isolated from the feces of a patient in Maryland.</s></p></content></protolog>