<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12891_nm.22709" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22709" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22709" rank="species">Nocardia artemisiae</organism><reference id="rid.12891"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia artemisiae sp. nov., an endophytic actinobacterium isolated from a surface-sterilized stem of Artemisia annua L.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2933</fpage><lpage>2937</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.029306-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21278414</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia artemisiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardia artemisiae</em> (ar.te.mi′si.ae. L. n. <em>artemisia</em> mugwort, and also a plant genus; L. gen. n. <em>artemisiae</em> of mugwort, of <em>Artemisia</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from <em>Artemisia annua</em> L.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, non-motile, Gram-stain-positive actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate mycelium and aerial mycelium that bears smooth-surfaced rod-shaped spores.</s><s>Good growth occurs on ISP media 2–5, Czapek’s agar, potato-glucose agar and nutrient agar.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white or brown; substrate mycelium is white, brown, orange or yellowish orange on media tested.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are observed on ISP 3 agar (grey–yellow) and potato-glucose agar (yellowish orange).</s><s>Grows at 10–37 °C (optimum 20–28 °C), at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum pH 6.0) and with 0–7 % NaCl (optimum 0–3 % NaCl).</s><s>Positive for catalase and urease, but negative for milk coagulation, milk peptonization, nitrate reduction, oxidase, gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of cellulose and starch and production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>As sole carbon sources, utilizes cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, ribose and xylose, but not l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, raffinose, sodium acetate or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol and ribose.</s><s>As sole nitrogen sources, utilizes l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-hydroxyproline, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-valine and xanthine.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates are rich in <em>meso</em>-DAP, arabinose, galactose, glucose and mannose.</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4ω cyclo</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 10-methyl, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 65623<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 45379<sup>T</sup>  = CCTCC AA 209038<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface-sterilized stem of <em>Artemisia annua</em> L., collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>