<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5844_nm.123" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.123" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.123" rank="species">Methanobrevibacter gottschalkii</organism><reference id="rid.5844"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Methanobrevibacter gottschalkii sp. nov., Methanobrevibacter thaueri sp. nov., Methanobrevibacter woesei sp. nov. and Methanobrevibacter wolinii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>819</fpage><lpage>822</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02022-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054244</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanobrevibacter gottschalkii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanobrevibacter gottschalkii</i> (gott.schal'ki.i. N.L. gen. n. gottschalkii of Gottschalk, named in honour of Gerhard Gottschalk for his notable contributions to the understanding of the biochemistry of methanogenesis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccobacillus with rounded ends, about 0.7 μm in width and 0.9 μm in length, occurring in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Gram-positive reaction.</s><s>Cell walls are composed of pseudomurein (König, 1986).</s><s>The peptide moiety contains glutamate, alanine and lysine (strains HO<sup>T</sup> and PG) and may contain ornithine (strain HO<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Galactosamine may be present at very low concentrations or absent from cell-wall hydrolysates (König, 1986).</s><s>Cells are resistant to lysis by SDS.</s><s>Optimum temperature 37 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH 7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict anaerobe.</s><s>Cells grown in rumen fluid medium are catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows and produces methane from H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> (Miller et al., 1986).</s><s>Does not grow or produce methane from formate, acetate, methanol, trimethylamines or methanol with H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Requires either acetate and/or one or more components of trypticase or yeast extract for growth.</s><s>Does not require coenzyme M or branched-chain fatty acids for growth.</s><s>Grows in medium with salt concentrations similar to sea water (medium 3 of Balch et al., 1979).</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by bile salts (Miller et al., 1986).</s><s>Neither strain HO<sup>T</sup> nor strain PG reacts with polyvalent antibody probes raised against <i>M. ruminantium</i> (strain M1<sup>T</sup>), <i>M. smithii</i> (strains PS<sup>T</sup>, ALI), <i>M. arboriphilicus</i> (strains DH1<sup>T</sup>, AZ, DC) or any other methanogen antisera in the antibody probe bank (Conway de Macario et al., 1987).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 29 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain HO<sup>T</sup> was isolated from enrichments of horse faeces.</s><s>Strain PG was isolated from enrichments of pig faeces.</s><s>The two species share &#x003E;99% 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity and their genomic DNA reassociates at 73-108%, indicating that they are strains of the same species (Lin &#x0026; Miller, 1998).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain HO<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11977<sup>T</sup>=OCM 813<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number of its 16S rRNA sequence is U55238.</s><s>Strain PG (=DSM 11978=OCM816) is a reference strain.</s><s>The GenBank accession number of its 16S rRNA sequence is U55239.</s></p></content></protolog>