<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3348_nm.6864" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6864" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6864" rank="species">Streptomyces atroaurantiacus</organism><reference id="rid.3348"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakagaito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimazu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Streptomyces atroaurantiacus sp. nov. and Streptomyces kifunensis sp. nov. and transferring Kitasatosporia cystarginea Kusukabe and Isono to the genus Streptomyces as Streptomyces cystargineus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>627</fpage><lpage>633</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces atroaurantiacus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces atroaurantiacus</i> (atro.aurantiacus. L. adj. <i>atro</i>, dark; L. adj. <i>aurantiacus</i>, orange; <i>atroaurantiacus</i>, dark orange)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The color of vegetative mycelia is dark orange to slightly orange.</s><s>The color of aerial mycelia is white.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are formed slightly on yeast extract-malt extract agar, oatmeal agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, tyrosine agar, Bennett's agar and water agar.</s><s>Mature spore chains are long and straight to slightly flexious.</s><s>Spores are cylindrical with a smooth surface.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Brown soluble pigments are produced on yeast extract-malt extract agar and yellow pigments are produced on oatmeal agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 37°C.</s><s>The concentration of NaCl at which growth occurs is less than 2%.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, starch is hydrolyzed, gelatin is not liquefied, and milk is peptonized and coagulated.</s><s>D-Glucose and D-arabinose, D-fructose, sucrose and D-xylose are utilized, but D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, raffinose and inositol are not utilized or are poorly utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains both LL- and <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>pm and glycine.</s><s>Galactose and a trace of madurose are detected as whole-cell sugars.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is type II.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) are detected.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 70.2 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 14327.</s></p></content></protolog>