<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1817_nm.10946" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10946" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10946" rank="species">Photobacterium lutimaris</organism><reference id="rid.1817"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium lutimaris sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat sediment in Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>332</fpage><lpage>336</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64580-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267974</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Photobacterium lutimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Photobacterium lutimaris</em> (lu.ti.ma′ris. L. n. <em>lutum</em> mud; L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>lutimaris</em> of mud of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, oval-shaped and 0.9–1.3×1.5–2.1 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular to slightly irregular, flat, smooth, glistening, pale yellow in colour and 2.0–4.0 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Not bioluminescent.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA and on MA with nitrate.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 41 °C with an optimum temperature of 25–30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5–8.5; growth occurs weakly at pH 5.0, but not at pH 4.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2–3 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs in the presence of 6 % (w/v) NaCl, but no growth occurs without NaCl or in the presence of &#x003E;7 % NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tyrosine is hydrolysed weakly.</s><s>Urea, hypoxanthine, xanthine and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system (bioMérieux), alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-xylose, citrate, succinate, l-malate, salicin and pyruvate are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but benzoate is not.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-xylose, d-ribose, d-fructose and d-cellobiose, but not from d-melezitose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, lactose, maltose, d-trehalose or d-raffinose.</s><s>Susceptible to polymyxin B, streptomycin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, ampicillin, cephalothin, gentamicin, novobiocin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin and carbenicillin, but not to oleandomycin or tetracycline.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DF-42<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12723<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13586<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat sediment at Saemankum, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>