<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7624_nm.14050" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14050" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14050" rank="species">Maribacter forsetii</organism><reference id="rid.7624"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Barbeyron</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carpentier</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>L'Haridon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüler</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Michel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Maribacter forsetii sp. nov., a marine Flavobacteriaceae isolated from North Sea water, and emended description of the genus Maribacter.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>790</fpage><lpage>797</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65469-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398171</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maribacter forsetii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maribacter forsetii</em> (for.set′ti.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>forsetii</em>, of Forseti, a god in Scandinavian mythology that lived on Helgoland, the German island from where the bacterium was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-flagellated, Gram-negative rods 0.3–0.5 μm wide and 3.0–4.0 μm long, occurring singly or in pairs, with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells are non-motile in liquid phase, but show active gliding motility on solid surfaces.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are circular, shiny, light yellow and 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days.</s><s>Spreading occurs at the margins of the colonies; the extent of spreading is strain-dependent.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 25 °C; growth occurs between 4 and 32 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5; growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5, but not at pH 5.0 and 9.0.</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 2.5 % (w/v).</s><s>Very weak growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and no growth occurs at concentrations &#x003E;9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Under optimal growth conditions, the doubling time is about 3.0 h.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, alkaline and acid phosphatases, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activities are present, but <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activity is absent (API ZYM).</s><s>Trypsin activity is strain-dependent (negative for the type strain).</s><s>Alginic acid, Tween 40 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but agar, <em>κ</em>-carrageenan, ι-carrageenan, starch, gelatin, DNA, glycogen and inulin are not.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, d-lactose, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, glucuronic acid, lactic acid, l-glutamic acid and l-ornithine are used as sole carbon sources, but d-arabinose, glycerol, amygdalin, acetic acid, citric acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-threonine and l-phenylalanine are not.</s><s>Utilization of l-serine is strain-dependent (negative for the type strain).</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-arabinose, d-xylose, l-fucose, cellobiose, d-lactose, amygdalin and salicin, but not from l-arabinose, l-rhamnose and melezitose (API 50 CH).</s><s>Acid production from gentiobiose is strain-dependent (positive for the type strain).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of kanamycin (200 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and tetracycline (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 34.2–34.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KT02ds18-6<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109504<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18668<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from North Sea surface water at station Kabeltonne (5 °11′ N;  °54′ E) near the island of Helgoland, Germany.</s><s>Other reference strains are KT02ds18-4 (=CIP 109503=DSM 18666) and KT02ds18-5 (=CIP 109505=DSM 18667).</s></p></content></protolog>