<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3509_nm.1397" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1397" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1397" rank="species">Ochrobactrum tritici</organism><reference id="rid.3509"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lebuhn</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schloter</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berge</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barakat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic characterization of Ochrobactrum sp. isolates from soil samples and wheat roots, and description of Ochrobactrum tritici sp. nov. and Ochrobactrum grignonense sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2207</fpage><lpage>2223</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155998</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ochrobactrum tritici</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ochrobactrum tritici</i> (tri'ti.ci. M.L. gen. n. <i>tritici</i> from Triticum, generic name for wheat, from which the strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative (aminopeptidase-positive), aerobic (oxidase- and catalase-positive), pleomorphic short rods (0.6-1.4 x 0.4-0.6 μm) and highly motile by subpolar or peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Grows between 4 and 40 °C (optimum 30 °C) and between pH values of 3 and 9 (optimum pH 6-pH 7).</s><s>Colonies are opaque and mucoid and quickly become confluent during incubation on NA.</s><s>No colony pigment development was observed.</s><s>Able to utilize (oxidize) 62 of 95 carbon sources of BIOLOG-GN microtitre plates and showed positive reactions in 4 of 22 tests and in 10 of 20 tests of API 20E and API 20NE systems, respectively.</s><s>Susceptible to polymyxin B and colistin.</s><s>Within the genus <i>Ochrobactrum</i>, the following characters were of unique diagnostic value for <i>O. tritici</i>:(i) BIOLOGGN: utilization of sebacic acid and no utilization of chydroxybutyric acid; (ii) API 20NE: assimilation of gluconate (48 h).</s><s>In addition, 24 other phenotypic characters were identified by which <i>O. tritici</i> can be differentiated from <i>. anthropi</i>, <i>O. intermedium</i> and <i>O. grignonense</i>.</s><s>At the genome level, <i>O. tritici</i> is clearly different from other <i>Ochrobactrum</i> species in total DNA composition. <i>O. tritici</i> is separated from <i>O. intermedium</i> and <i>O. grignonense</i> by sequence heterogeneity of 16S rDNA, but delineation from <i>O. anthropi</i> by 16S rDNA heterogeneity is not significant. <i>O. tritici</i> DNA has a G+C content of 59 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>O. tritici</i>, strain SCII24<sup>T</sup>, was deposited in BCCM/LMG and DSMZ culture collections as LMG 18957<sup>T</sup> and DSM 13340<sup>T</sup>, respectively;similarly the <i>O. tritici</i> reference strain LAIII106 was deposited as LMG 18958 and LMG 13341.</s></p></content></protolog>