<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4459_nm.11766" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11766" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8206" rank="species">Zobellia galactanovorans</organism><reference id="rid.4459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Barbeyron</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>L'Haridon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Corre</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kloareg</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potin</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zobellia galactanovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine species of Flavobacteriaceae isolated from a red alga, and classification of [Cytophaga] uliginosa (ZoBell and Upham 1944) Reichenbach 1989 as Zobellia uliginosa gen. nov., comb. nov. </article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>985</fpage><lpage>997</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Zobellia galactanovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Zobellia galactanovorans</i> (ga.lac.ta.no.vo'rans. M.L. n. <i>galactan</i> polygalactose; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; M.L. fem. adj. <i>galactanovorans</i> galactan-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(basonym '<i>Cytophaga drobachiensis</i>' Barbeyron et al. 1998) Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar plate are yellow and spread rapidly on the surface of the plate.</s><s>Cells are rods (0.3-0.4 by 3.0-8.0 μm), with rounded ends and are non-motile in liquid phase.</s><s>On solid surfaces, gliding motility is easily observed.</s><s>Cells hydrolyse agar and L-carrageenan.</s><s><i>i</i>-Carrageenan is liquefied within 1 week at room temperature.</s><s>Gelatin and DNA are also hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed in starch agar and starch Phytagel plates.</s><s>Cells are positive for catalase, cytochrome-c oxidase, β-glucosidase (aesculin test) and β-galactosidase activities (<i>o</i>- and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactoside tests).</s><s>Cells do not produce H#S nor indole from tryptophan.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Do not possess urease or arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>D-Glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, L-fucose, maltose, N-acetylglucosamine, D/L-glycerol phosphate or L-serine can serve as the sole carbon source, but not D-lyxose, dtagatose, α-ketobutyric acid, L-threonine, urocanic acid, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenyl acetate.</s><s>Acid production is observed from D-glucose, sucrose, maltose, L-arabinose, rhamnose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-mannose, D-mannitol and starch, but not from D-sorbitol or glycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Zobellia galactanovorans</i> Dsij<sup>T</sup>, isolated from pieces of the red alga <i>Delesseria sanguinea</i> (Huds.) Lamour.</s><s>Strain Dsij<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the DSMZ and in the Institut Pasteur Collection under the accession numbers DSM 12802<sup>T</sup> and CIP 106680<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>