<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8437_nm.13568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13568" rank="species">Rhizobium oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.8437"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium oryzae sp. nov., isolated from the wild rice Oryza alta.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2158</fpage><lpage>2163</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65632-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768622</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, the origin of the first strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, straight, non-spore-forming rods (0.8–1.0×1.4–1.8 μm) with polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on YMA medium are circular, cream coloured and semi-translucent, with a diameter of 3 mm within 3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C (optimum 28–37 °C).</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.0–8.0 (optimum pH 6.0–7.0).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth above 1.5 %.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and neomycin (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Tests for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, urease, cytochrome oxidase and the Voges–Proskauer reaction are positive.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon sources: l- and d-arabinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-alanine, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, succinic acid, citric acid, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, d-gluconic acid, monomethyl succinate, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanyl glycine, glycerol, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-proline, hydroxy-l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, d-xylose, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, dulcitol, l-malate, d-ribose, xylose, sorbitol and d-tagatose.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 64.1±0.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain Alt 505<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24253<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.7048<sup>T</sup>), and seven other strains were isolated from the wild rice species <em>Oryza alta</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>