<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2594_nm.11545" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11545" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11545" rank="species">Azospirillum zeae</organism><reference id="rid.2594"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mehnaz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weselowski</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lazarovits</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azospirillum zeae sp. nov., a diazotrophic bacterium isolated from rhizosphere soil of Zea mays.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2805</fpage><lpage>2809</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65128-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048728</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Azospirillum zeae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Azospirillum zeae</em> [L. gen. n. <em>zeae</em> of spelt, of <em>Zea mays</em>, referring to its isolation from rhizosphere soil of corn (<em>Zea mays</em>)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, 0.9–1.5×1.9–6.8 μm in size, Gram-negative, motile via a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Pink colonies form after 48–72 h, which become wrinkled and dried with time.</s><s>Growth occurs on M medium at 20–41 °C, pH 5–7 and in 0.5–1.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 5–7.</s><s>Positive for nitrogen fixation and IAA production; negative for phosphate solubilization.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-psicose, d- and l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-hydroxybutyric acid, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-galacturonic acid, l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malic acid, phenylacetic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, urocanic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, potassium gluconate, Tweens 80 and 40, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide and glycerol can be used as unique carbon sources.</s><s>d-Arabitol, d-cellobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, gentiobiose, sucrose, maltose, xylitol, succinamic acid, quinic acid, malonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, l-erythritol, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, l-histidine, d-serine, trisodium citrate, capric acid and adipic acid are not utilized.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, urease, nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Variable response for acetoin production.</s><s>Biotin is not required for growth.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 18 : 1 2-OH and 16 : 0.</s><s>The predominant quinone system is ubiquinone (Q-10).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, N7<sup>T</sup> (=NCCB 100147<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23989<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of corn (<em>Zea mays</em>) from London, Ontario, Canada.</s></p></content></protolog>