<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8457_nm.13486" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13486" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13486" rank="species">Nocardioides salarius</organism><reference id="rid.8457"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides salarius sp. nov., isolated from seawater enriched with zooplankton.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2056</fpage><lpage>2064</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65569-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768604</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides salarius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides salarius</em> (sa.la′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>salarius</em> of, or belonging to, salt, referring to the isolation of this micro-organism from seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, strictly aerobic rods approximately 0.6–1.6 μm long and 0.3–0.6 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies on MA are creamy white and circular, smooth and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C (optimally at 25–30 °C) and at pH 6–10 (optimally at pH 6–7).</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1–10 % (w/v) (optimally at 3 %).</s><s>Positive for catalase but negative for oxidase and nitrate reductase.</s><s>Casein, starch, Tween 80 and l-tyrosine are hydrolysed but hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, aesculin hydrolysis and gelatinase are positive but nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are negative.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase are positive but <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are negative.</s><s>Utilizes l-arginine, cellobiose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, l-ornithine, d-ribose, sucrose and trehalose, but not <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-asparagine, citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, l-lysine, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, succinate and d-xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The major fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (65.3 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-Z59<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42320<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18239<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater enriched with zooplankton.</s></p></content></protolog>