<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4742_nm.1506" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1506" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1506" rank="species">Rhodopseudomonas rutila</organism><reference id="rid.4742"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akiba</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Usami</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodopseudomonas rutila, a new species of nonsulfur purple photosynthetic bacteria.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>551</fpage><lpage>556</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-551</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> (ru.ti'la. L. adj. <i>rutila</i> red, bloody).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, facultatively aerobic, nonsporeforming rods with rounded ends; cells are 1.5 to 3.0 μm long and 0.4 to 1.0 μm wide and are motile by means of a single flagellum.</s><s>Cell multiplication is by budding.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The photosynthetic membrane system is the lamellar type in the form of stacks underlying and parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both photoorganotrophic growth under anaerobic conditions in the light and chemoorganotrophic growth under aerobic conditions in the dark are possible.</s><s>Anaerobic cultures are red; aerobic cultures are pale pink to white.</s><s>No vitamins are required as growth factors.</s><s>Yeast extract appreciably stimulates growth.</s><s>The optimum pH is 6.0 to 7.0, and the optimum temperature is 25 to 35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following organic substrates are photoassimilated: malate lactate, succinate, malonate, caproate, glycerol, propionate, glutamate, fructose, ethanol, and citrate.</s><s>No growth occurs with acetate, formate, glucose, gluconate, mannitol, tartrate, aspartate, methanol, benzoate, caprylate, or valerate.</s><s>Sulfide and thiosulfate are not utilized as electron donors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Starch, gelatin, and Tween 80 are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, nitrogenase, and molecular hydrogen are produced, but hydrogenase is not produced, Nitrates are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ammonium salts and amino acids are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs on media containing 3.0% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells contain the following photopigments: bacteriochlorophyll a (37.5, 590, 805, and 860 nm) and carotenoids (rhodovibrin and spirilloxanthin).</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 is present in the cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 67.6 to 69.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: mud in rice fields.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain R1 (= ATCC 33872).</s></p></content></protolog>