<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6724_nm.5520" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5520" rank="genus">Trichococcus</organism><reference id="rid.6724"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKenzie</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Trichococcus, description of Trichococcus collinsii sp. nov., and reclassification of Lactosphaera pasteurii as Trichococcus pasteurii comb. nov. and of Ruminococcus palustris as Trichococcus palustris comb. nov. in the low-G+C gram-positive bacteria.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1113</fpage><lpage>1126</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02085-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148615</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Trichococcus</i> (Scheff et al. 1984b)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Spherical to ovoid, sometimes olive-shaped cells with a mean cell diameter of 1.0-1.5 μm and a mean cell length of 1.0-2.5 μm, usually arranged in chains but sometimes appearing as single or paired cocci. Aerotolerant, fermentative organisms in the low-G+C Gram-positive bacteria. Cells grow with glucose to produce lactate and acetate oxically, and to produce lactate, acetate, formate and ethanol anoxically. Cells also grow with sucrose and lactose, with acid production. All members of the genus utilize arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, α-D-glucose, D-mannose, salicin, sucrose and pyruvate with the BIOLOG system. None of the following substrates are utilized: β-cyclodextrin, inulin, Tween 40, Tween 80, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-fucose, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, <i>myo</i>-inositol, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-mannoside, sedoheptulosan, D-sorbitol, D-tagatose, xylitol, D-xylose, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyrate, β-hydroxybutyrate, c-hydroxybutyrate, β-hydroxyphenylacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, 2-oxovalerate, lactamide, D-lactic acid methyl ester, L-lactic acid, D-malic acid, L-malic acid, monomethylsuccinic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, N-acetylglutamic acid, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-pyroglutamic acid, L-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, inosine, thymidine, adenosine 5'-monophosphate, thymidine 5'-monophosphate, uridine 5'-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, DL-α-glycerol phosphate. No indole is produced. The DNA base compositions range from 45 to 49 mol% G+C. The peptidoglycan type is type A4α, L-Lys-D-Asp (A 11.31). The natural habitats of members of the genus are activated sludge, soil and sediment. The type species of the genus is <i>Trichococcus flocculiformis</i> Echt<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>