<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2245_nm.10811" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10811" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5420" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus plantarum plantarum</organism><reference id="rid.2245"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bringel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Castioni</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olukoya</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Felis</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torriani</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus plantarum subsp. argentoratensis subsp. nov., isolated from vegetable matrices.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1629</fpage><lpage>1634</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63333-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014493</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus plantarum</em> subsp. <em>plantarum</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus plantarum</em> subsp. <em>plantarum</em> (plan.ta′rum. L. fem. n. <em>planta</em> a sprout; M.L. n. <em>planta</em> a plant; M.L. gen. pl. n. <em>plantarum</em> of plants).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming straight rods with rounded ends, usually 0·9–1·2 μm by 3–8 μm, that occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic; growth occurs at 15 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Both isomers of lactic acid are produced.</s><s>Gas from glucose is not produced.</s><s>Catalase is not produced, but some strains may exhibit pseudocatalase activity especially if grown under glucose limitation.</s><s>Amygdalin, cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, trehalose, salicin and sucrose are fermented.</s><s>Adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabitol, erythritol, dl-fucose, 5-ketogluconate, methyl <em>β</em>-xylose, 2-ketogluconate, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, l-sorbitol, d-tagatose and dl-xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Arginine is not deaminated.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell wall and ribitol or glycerol have been described to be present as teichoic acids.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is 44–46 mol%.</s><s>Considering phylogenetic placement based on 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis, <em>L. plantarum</em> belongs to the <em>L. plantarum</em> phylogenetic subgroup (Hammes &#x0026; Hertel, 2003), very closely related to <em>L. paraplantarum</em> and <em>L. pentosus</em>.</s><s>The three species are easily distinguishable by means of molecular techniques: Southern hybridization with a <em>pyr</em> probe on <em>Bgl</em>I digestion of chromosomal DNA (Bringel <em>et al.</em>, 1996, 2001), multiplex species-specific PCR analysis (Torriani <em>et al.</em>, 2001) and <em>recA</em> gene sequencing.</s><s>Such techniques also allow the differentiation of the two subspecies of <em>L. plantarum</em>, <em>L. plantarum</em> subsp. <em>plantarum</em> and <em>L. plantarum</em> subsp. <em>argentoratensis</em>.</s><s>When analysed by a specific multiplex-PCR approach (Torriani <em>et al.</em>, 2001), DNA of strains belonging to <em>L. plantarum</em> subsp. <em>plantarum</em> produce a single amplification product of 318 bp.</s><s>A rough separation of the two subspecies of <em>L. plantarum</em> may also be obtained based on fermentation profiles of dulcitol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-arabinose, d-turanose (Table 2): usually, <em>L. plantarum</em> subsp. <em>plantarum</em> strains do not ferment dulcitol but do metabolize melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-arabinose and d-turanose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 14917<sup>T</sup> (=NCDO 1752<sup>T</sup>=DSM 20174<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>