<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6263_nm.4901" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4901" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4901" rank="species">Bacillus endophyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6263"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reva</surname><given-names>O.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smirnov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pettersson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus endophyticus sp. nov., isolated from the inner tissues of cotton plants (Gossypium sp.).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>101</fpage><lpage>107</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837291</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus endophyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus endophyticus</i> (en.do.phy'ti.cus. <i>endophyticus</i> adj. derived from Gr. <i>endo</i> within and <i>phyt</i>- relating to plants; N.L. adj. <i>endophyticus</i> within plant, pertaining to the original isolation from plant tissues)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive rods, 0.5-1.5x2.5-3.5 μm occurring singly and as short or long chains which appear filamentous.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores are located subterminally or terminally in a non-swollen sporangium.</s><s>Cells grown on media containing 2% glucose have vacuoles in the cytoplasm.</s><s>Circular colonies may be red, pink or white, slimy or rough with entire or slightly indented edges, about 1-3 mm diameter.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive, urease-negative.</s><s>Does not produce indole from tryptophan or gas from glucose.</s><s>Egg-yolk reaction is negative.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test and nitrate reduction are negative, ONPG-positive.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin or casein.</s><s>Produces acid from L-arabinose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, D-rhamnose, ribose and sucrose, but not from adonitol, galactose, glycerol, glycogen, melezitose, methyl D-glucoside, methyl D-mannoside, lactose or trehalose.</s><s>Acid production from D-raffinose and D-xylose is variable.</s><s>Utilizes sodium citrate and gluconate, but not acetate, propionate or tartrate.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and phenylalanine deaminase reactions are negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10-45 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is about 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 10% NaCl, 100 μg ampicillin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 1 mg lysozyme ml<sup>-1</sup>.Habitat : associated with plants and isolated from inner tissues of plants.</s><s>Type strain is 2DT<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited with the Ukrainian Collection of Microorganisms and the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur as UCM B-5715<sup>T</sup> and CIP 106778<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>