<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5667_nm.9911" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9911" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9911" rank="species">Chryseobacterium taeanense</organism><reference id="rid.5667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Do</surname><given-names>J.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium soldanellicola sp. nov. and Chryseobacterium taeanense sp. nov., isolated from roots of sand-dune plants</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>433</fpage><lpage>438</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63825-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium taeanense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium taeanense</em> (tae.an.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>taeanense</em> of Tae-an, a geographical region in Chungnam, Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Good growth is observed on R2A agar, TSA and nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Grows at 5 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, circular and shiny.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5–9 and that for optimal growth is pH 5.</s><s>Growth occurs aerobically, but not anaerobically.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl within 14 days.</s><s>The most abundant cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0 and iso-C17 : 0 3-OH.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Positive for cytochrome oxidase but negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, tryptophan deaminase and urease.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing aesculin and gelatin.</s><s>Weakly assimilates glucose, arabinose, mannose and maltose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, mannitol (weakly), d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid (weakly), itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline (weakly), l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, inosine (weakly) and uridine (weakly).</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized; <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-melibiose, acetic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-histidine, d-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are given in Table 3.</s><s>The G+C content is 32·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PHA3-4<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12381<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100863<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the roots of <em>Elymus mollis</em> growing on a coastal area in Tae-an, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>