<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1187_nm.8077" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8077" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8077" rank="species">Flavobacterium breve</organism><reference id="rid.1187"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Owen</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium breve sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>233</fpage><lpage>234</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium breve</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The morphological and biochemical reaction patterns of strains of <i>F. breve</i> are remarkably uniform (4). <i>F. breve</i> is a gram-negative, nonmotile rod. Indole is produced, and among named <i>Flavobacterium</i> species this character is otherwise confined to <i>F. balustinum</i> and <i>F. meningosepticum</i>. However, <i>F. breve</i>, unlike <i>F.	bulustinum</i> and the majority of <i>F. meningosepticum</i> strains, does not hydrolyze esculin and does not generally produce acid oxidatively from carbohydrates other than glucose and maltose. These characters distinguish <i>F. breve</i> from other recognized <i>Flavobacterium</i> species (3, 4). A study of the deoxyribonucleic acids of <i>F. breve</i> strains (6) showed that the species constitutes a relatively homogeneous taxon, all the strains of which are readily distinguishable from allied flavobacteria. The history of the species has been described elsewhere (4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F . breve</i> is NCTC 11099, and it has been described previously (4).</s><s>The type strain is typical of the species both phenotypically and genotypically (4, 6) and was chosen for that reason.</s></p></content></protolog>