<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2439_nm.11318" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11318" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11318" rank="species">Rheinheimera chironomi</organism><reference id="rid.2439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Halpern</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Senderovich</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snir</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rheinheimera chironomi sp. nov., isolated from a chironomid (Diptera; Chironomidae) egg mass</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1872</fpage><lpage>1875</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64927-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684273</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rheinheimera chironomi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rheinheimera chironomi</em> [chi.ro′no.mi. N.L. gen. n. <em>chironomi</em> of <em>Chironomus</em>, named after the non-biting midge insect from the genus <em>Chironomus</em> (Diptera; Chironomidae) from which the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-pigmented rods, 1.0–2.4 μm long and 0.3–0.7 μm wide, occurring as single cells or in pairs, and they are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are circular, non-pigmented, smooth and convex.</s><s>Oxidase-positive, catalase-negative and able to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Growth is observed in 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 4–40 °C, but not at 41 °C.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin and casein but not DNA.</s><s>Grows on LB and half-strength marine agar.</s><s>Does not haemolyse bovine blood and does not grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>The major measurable fatty acid components (exceeding 5 %) of the type strain are 11 : 0 3-OH (5.53 %), 12 : 0 3-OH (8.54 %) 15 : 0 (6.86 %), 16 : 0 (14.80 %), summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 : 0 iso 2-OH; 25.76 %), 17 : 0 (5.76 %), 17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (7.56 %) and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (6.68 %).</s><s>The following fatty acids are detected in the type strain as minor components: 9 : 0 (0.2 %), 10 : 0 (1.2 %), 11 : 0 (1.35 %), 10 : 0 3-OH (0.53 %), unknown ECL 11.799 (2.63 %), 12 : 0 (1.06 %), 13 : 0 (0.62 %), 12 : 0 iso 3-OH (0.41 %), 14 : 0 iso (0.19 %), 14 : 0 (0.89 %), summed feature 1 (one or more of 13 : 0 3-OH, 15 : 1 iso I and 15 : 1 iso H; 1.9 %), 15 : 0 anteiso (0.28 %), 15 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (2.75 %), 15 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1.04 %), summed feature 2 (14 : 0 3-OH and/or 16 : 1 iso I; 0.28 %), 16 : 0 iso (1.45 %), 17 : 0 iso (0.19 %), 17 : 0 anteiso (0.41 %), 17 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (0.87 %) and 18 : 0 (0.25 %).</s><s>Cells are resistant to neomycin, penicillin G and bacitracin but susceptible to tetracycline, ampicillin, vancomycin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, novobiocin and SXT (sulfamethoxazole and trimethoprim).</s><s>In the API 20NE test system, nitrate is reduced to nitrite, glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose and malate are assimilated and enzyme activities of protease (gelatinase) and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are detected.</s><s>In the API ZYM test system, 12 enzyme activities are detected: alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4 and C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>In the Biolog GN2 test system, Tweens 40 and 80, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid and glycyl l-glutamic acid are utilized as substrates; all other Biolog GN2 substrates are not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 49.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain K19414<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18694<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23818<sup>T</sup>), which is of freshwater origin.</s></p></content></protolog>