<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2120_nm.2879" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2879" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2879" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.2120"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tudela</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lalucat</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinea</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas antarctica sp. nov., isolated from an Antarctic coastal environment.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>345</fpage><lpage>351</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-345</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103620</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoalteromonas antarctica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas antarctica</i> (ant.arc'ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <i>antarctica</i>, of the Antarctic environment, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, rod-shaped cells that are 0.3 to 0.9 μm wide and 1 to 3 μm long when the organism is grown in TSB.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs, and after 24 h of incubation in liquid medium filaments 10 μm long are observed.</s><s>Microcysts or endospores are not formed.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Peritrichous flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solid media.</s><s>Cells grow at 4 to 30°C.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are beige, smooth, convex, and mucoid with entire edges and grow to diameters of 1 to 2 mm in 5 days at 15°C and 5 mm or more when colonies are incubated for longer periods of time (10 to 14 days).</s><s>A low level of sodium ions, 17 mM NaCl, is required for growth.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Positive in oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine aqlamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolasete sts.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin and casein.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, starch, galactose, and mannitol.</s><s>Grows on D-glucose, D-mannitol, and maltose.</s><s>Malate, sorbitol, and <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate are not used as sole carbon sources, The main cellular fatty acids are 16:1 ω7c, 16:0, 17:1 ω8c, and 12:0 3OH.</s><s>Isolated from muddy soils and sediments collected from Antarctic coastal areas.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 to 42 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain CECT 4664.</s><s>Strains NF3<sup>T</sup>, NF2, NF13, NF14, and EN10 have been deposited in the Spanish Type Culture Collection as strains CECT 4664<sup>T</sup>, CECT 4665, CECT 4666, CECT 4667, and CECT 4668, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>