<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2285_nm.9709" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9709" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9709" rank="species">Enterococcus devriesei</organism><reference id="rid.2285"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koort</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naser</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vihavainen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Björkroth</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus devriesei sp. nov., associated with animal sources</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2479</fpage><lpage>2484</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63851-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280513</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus devriesei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus devriesei</em> (de′vrie.se.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>devriesei</em> of Devriese, in honour of the Belgian microbiologist Luc A. Devriese for his outstanding contributions to the taxonomy of enterococci).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-negative, facultatively anaerobic cocci.</s><s>Colonies on blood or MRS agar are white to light grey and translucent.</s><s>On bovine blood agar there is <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Strains grow on azide-containing enterococcal selective agar as light- to dark-maroon colonies and cause blackening of bile–aesculin agar.</s><s>Strains grow well at 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>At 4 °C, growth can be somewhat slow; at 2 °C, growth does not occur.</s><s>No growth is observed at 42 or 45 °C.</s><s>All strains grow well in the presence of 2, 4 or 6·5 % NaCl.</s><s>Strain 6/1 also grows in the presence of 8 % NaCl but not at 10 %.</s><s>Strains react positively in the Voges–Proskauer test and negatively in tests for alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and hippurate.</s><s>Reactions in the tests for leucine arylamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase are strain-dependent.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, galactose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, ribose, sucrose, salicin and trehalose; all these reactions may be weak or delayed for strain LMG 22830, and reactions with amygdalin, d-arabitol, galactose and trehalose may be weak or delayed for strain LMG 14595<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>No acid is produced from starch, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, d-fucose, l-fucose, dulcitol, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, melibiose, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, l-xylose, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Reactions with adonitol, gluconate, glycerol, melezitose, rhamnose, sorbitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, d-lyxose, d-raffinose, d-tagatose and l-sorbose are strain-dependent (see Table 2).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain-dependent characteristics for <em>E. devriesei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results were obtained in the present study, and are scored as described in Table 1 with the following additions; w, positive, but the reaction is weak and/or delayed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from bovine material, is LMG 14595<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7299<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Reference strains are LMG 13603 (=CCM 7298), 6/1 (=LMG 22829) and IE38.4 (=LMG 22830).</s></p></content></protolog>