<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12879_nm.22689" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22689" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22689" rank="species">Elizabethkingia anophelis</organism><reference id="rid.12879"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matthews</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glaeser</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faye</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Elizabethkingia anophelis sp. nov., isolated from the midgut of the mosquito Anopheles gambiae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2670</fpage><lpage>2675</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026393-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21169462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Elizabethkingia anophelis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Elizabethkingia anophelis</em> (a.no.phe′lis. N.L. gen. n. <em>anophelis</em> of/from a mosquito of the genus <em>Anopheles</em>, as the type strain was isolated from the midgut of <em>Anopheles gambiae</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic Gram-reaction-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, approximately 1 µm in width and 2 µm in length.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h on NA, R2A agar and TSA (all Oxoid) at 11–36 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar (Oxoid) at 28 °C.</s><s>Unable to grow at temperatures below 10 °C or above 37 °C.</s><s>Two growth optima are detected on LB medium: 30–31 °C with a doubling time of 50 min; and 37 °C with a doubling time of 42 min.</s><s>Colonies on NA are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges.</s><s>The non-diffusible and non-fluorescent yellow pigment is not of the flexirubin-type (KOH test-negative).</s><s>Resistant to a number of antibiotics; MICs in LB medium are &#x003E;400 µg ml<sup>−1</sup> for ampicillin, &#x003E;250 µg ml<sup>−1</sup> for kanamycin, &#x003E;250 µg ml<sup>−1</sup> for streptomycin, &#x003E;30 µg ml<sup>−1</sup> for chloramphenicol and &#x003E;10 µg ml<sup>−1</sup> for tetracycline.</s><s>Tests for haemolytic activity on blood agar plates show no lytic zones around the colonies.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, lactose (weak), d-mannitol, maltose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and cellobiose (weak).</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>i</em>-inositol, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis, indole production from tryptophan and β-galactosidase activity (ONPG) are positive.</s><s>Urease activity, hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine, hydrogen sulfide production, activity of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase, and utilization of malonate are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltitol, α-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, β-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP)-β-d-glucopyranoside, pNP-β-d-galactopyranoside, pNP-α-d-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP-phosphate, bis-pNP-phenyl-phosphonate, bis-pNP-phosphoryl-choline, 2-deoxythymidine-2′-pNP-phosphate, l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), γ-l-glutamate-pNA and l-proline-pNA are hydrolysed but not pNP-β-d-xylopyranoside or pNP-β-d-glucuronide.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/<em>t</em>).</s><s>The only menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, a characteristic unknown phospholipid, and unknown polar lipids and glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R26<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 60038<sup>T</sup> = CCM 7804<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the midgut of <em>Anopheles gambiae</em> G3, originating from McCarthy Island, The Gambia, and deposited by Dr William Collins at Malaria Research Reference Resource Centre.</s></p></content></protolog>