<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1033_nm.4551" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4551" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4551" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter italicus</organism><reference id="rid.1033"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kozianowski</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canganella</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Antranikian</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Purification and characterization of thermostable pectate-lyases from a newly isolated thermophilic bacterium, Thermoanaerobacter italicus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>171</fpage><lpage>182</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s007920050031</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9680298</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter italicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter italicus</i> (i.ta.li.cus. L.n. <i>italica</i> Italy; M.L. masc. adj. <i>italicus</i> pertaining to Italy, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of strain Ab9 were rod-shaped, measuring 0.4-0.75 x 2-6μm.</s><s>Chains up to 50μm in length could be observed during growth in KOKO medium with glucose (Fig. 1a).</s><s>Motility was never detected.</s><s>Cells stained Gram-negative.</s><s>Spherical, terminally located spores were produced in MOPS-buffered media (Schink and Zeikus 1983b) with 0.2% (w/v) xylose as the substrate (Fig. 1b).</s><s>Colonies on KOKO glucose agar were 2-3 mm in diameter, round with an entire margin, greyish-white, opaque, and with a glossy surface.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth was 70°C and growth occurred between 45°C and 78°C.</s><s>The pH optimum was around 7.0.</s><s>NaCl up to 1% (w/v) did not affect growth.</s><s>Growth was totally inhibited by 10μg/ml of the antibiotics cephalosporin, erythromycin, kanamycin, or rifampicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain Ab9 was capable of fermenting a large number of sugars (amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose) as well as polymers such as starch, glycogen, inulin, pectin, and xylan.</s><s>Cellulose was not utilized and gelatin was not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Preferred substrates (OD ≥ 1.0) were arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, xylose, D-glucosamine, lactose, maltose, saccharose, and pectin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>During growth on glucose or other fermentable sugars, the pH of the KOKO medium fell from 6.8 to 4.7-5.0, and optical densities (600nm) of ≥1.0 were reached.</s><s>The growth rate using glucose as substrate was 0.33h<sup>-1</sup> and the doubling time (t<sub>d</sub>) was 2.1 h.</s><s>If glucose was replaced by pectin the growth rate and the t<sub>d</sub> were 0.23h<sup>-1</sup> and 3 h, respectively.</s><s>The products formed after 15 h of growth on 0.5% (w/v) glucose were ethanol (26.6 mM), lactate (12.4 mM), acetate (2.2 mM), succinate (0.3 mM), H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain Ab9 was able to reduce thiosulfate to elemental sulfur.</s><s>Massive sulfur formation occurred after 24 h of growth in the 20-mM-thiosulfate-containing medium of Schink and Zeikus (1983b) (Fig. 1c) If KOKO medium was supplemented with both thiosulfate and 2 g/l of ferrous sulfate, the medium turned black soon after growth became visible, and this was followed by sulfur formation.</s><s>The blackening of the medium indicated that strain Ab9 was capable of reduction of thiosulfate to sulfide, which precipitated as ferrous sulfide, in addition to the reduction to elemental sulfur.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA mol% G+C content was 34.4 as determined by HPLC.</s></p></content></protolog>