<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10_nm.6797" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6797" rank="genus">Saccharothrix</organism><reference id="rid.10"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amendment of the genus Saccharothrix Labeda et al. 1984 and descriptions of Saccharothrix espanaesis sp. nov., Saccharothrix cryophilis sp. nov, and Saccharothrix mutabilis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>420</fpage><lpage>423</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-420</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Saccharothrix</i>.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix</i> (Sac' char. o. thrix. Gr. neut. n. <i>sacchar</i>, sugar; Gr. fem. n. <i>thrix</i>, hair; <i>Saccharothrix</i>, sugar-containing hair).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Branching vegetative mycelia (diameter, approximately 0.5 μm) and, on some media, aerial mycelia are produced.</s><s>Both vegetative and aerial hyphae fragment into ovoid elements.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Lysozyme resistant.</s><s>Catalase positive and aerobic.</s><s>The cell wall is type III (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, L-alanine, D-alanine, D-glutamic acid, glucosamine, muramic acid), and the whole-cell sugar pattern consists of major amounts of galactose (in the absence of arabinose) and rhamnose.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern consists of phosphatidylethanolamine as the diagnostic phospholipid with or</s></p><p class="description"><s>without glucosamine-containing phospholipids (type PII or PIV).</s><s>Nocardomycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The guanine-pluscytosine content of the DNA is 70 to 76 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>S. australiensis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Upon emendment of the genus description, <i>S. espanaensis</i> and <i>N . mutabilis</i> can be placed in this genus based on morphological and chemotaxonomic criteria.</s><s>The proposed new species <i>Saccharothrix espanaensis</i> and <i>Saccharothrix mutabilis</i>, resulting from the transfer of <i>Nocardiopsis mutabilis</i> Shearer et al. 1983 (15) to the amended genus, are formally described below.</s></p></content></protolog>