<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1363_nm.10664" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10664" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6114" rank="species">Clavibacter xyli</organism><reference id="rid.1363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillaspie</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clavibacter: a new genus containing some phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria, including Clavibacter xyli subsp. xyli sp. nov., subsp. nov. and Clavibacter xyli subsp. cynodontis subsp. nov., pathogens that cause ratoon stunting disease of sugarcane and bermudagrass stunting disease.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clavibacter xyli</i> subsp. <i>xyli</i> sp. nov., subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clavibacter xyli</i> subsp. <i>xyli</i> (xy'li. <i>xylon</i> wood; N. L. gen. n. <i>xyli</i> of the xylem)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-endospore-forming, pleomorphic rods that are nonmotile and measure approximately 0.2 by 5.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on SC agar are circular with entire margins (diameter, 0.1 to 0.3 mm), convex, glistening, and butyrous.</s><s>All strains are obligate aerobes.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 26 and 30°C; strains do not grow at 32°C.</s><s>Colonies of all strains gradually produce a white color that intensifies with the age of the culture.</s><s>All strains produce acid from oxidative fermentation of glucose, maltose, starch, and dextrin; acid is not produced from adonitol, arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, esculin, ethanol, fructose, galactose, geraniol, inositol, inulin, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, propanol, propylene glycol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, or xylose.</s><s>Gas is not produced from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Casein, corn oil, esculin, gelatin, starch, Tween 20, Tween 80, tyrosine, and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>KCN is tolerated at a concentration of 0.0075% in RSD broth.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Catalase and acetoin are produced, but H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, ammonium from peptone, and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Acetate, acetamide, anthranilate, benzoate, citrate, citroaconate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, β-hydroxybutyrate, formate, fumarate, galacturonate, gluconate, glucuronate, glycolate, lactate, levulinate, malate, maleic acid, malonate, oxalate, propionate, saccharate, succinate, <i>m</i>-tartrate, and tryptamine are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This taxon is distinguished from other coryneform bacteria on the basis of the G+C content (66 mol%) of its DNA, the presence of diaminobutyric acid in its peptidoglycan, and its distinct pattern of protein bands in polyacrylamide gels.</s><s>It is distinguished from the other subspecies of <i>Clavibacter xyli</i> sp. nov. by its colony pigment, colony size, inability to utilize citrate and malate, inability to hydrolyze starch, protein pattern in polyacrylamide gels, and ability to induce ratoon stunting disease in sugarcane (<i>Saccharum</i> interspecific hybrids).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the species and subspecies is strain L1A (= NCPPB 3152 = PDDCC 7127 = ATCC 33974).</s><s>The description given above is based on 17 strains which are virtually indistinguishable; thus, the subspecies description is also the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>