<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1383_nm.5626" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5626" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5626" rank="species">Streptococcus downei</organism><reference id="rid.1383"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>R.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus downei sp. nov. for strains previously described as Streptococcus mutans serotyp h.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>25</fpage><lpage>29</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-772</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus downei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus downei</i> (dowń.e.i. Lat. derivative of Downe, the village in Kent where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, catalase-negative cocci that grow in chains.</s><s>They form small, dark blue, crinkled colonies up to 1 mm in diameter with an erose edge slightly pitting the agar but easily dislodged although difficult to disperse when grown on mitis salivarius agar.</s><s>Growth on 5% sucrose agar (TYC, Lab M) produces large, white, conical colonies 2 to 3 mm in diameter with an erose edge surrounded by a distinctive white halo.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, sucrose, fructose, galactose, mannose, mannitol, lactose, maltose, salicin, trehalose, and inulin but not from adonitol, melezitose, melibiose, sorbose, cellobiose, glycogen, soluble starch, inositol, xylitol, sorbitol, glycerol, arabinose, or raffinose.</s><s>Starch, esculin, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Strains do not grow at 45°C, at pH 9.6, or in the presence of 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Variable growth is obtained on 10 and 40% bile agar.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide and intracellular polysaccharides are not produced.</s><s>Acetyl methyl carbinol is produced from glucose.</s><s>Strains possess a serologically distinct polysaccharide antigen designated h.</s><s>Cellular long-chain fatty acid composition consists of major (&#x003E;10% of total fatty acids present) amounts of hexadecanoic (16:0, palmitic), octadecanoic (18:0, stearic), octadecenoic (18:1, vaccenic), and eicosenoic (20:1) acids together with minor amounts of tetradecanoic (14:0, myristic), hexadecenoic (16: 1, palmitoleic), octadecenoic (18: 1, oleic), and eicosisnoic (20:0, arachidic) and cyclopropane acid (<i>cis</i>-9,10-methyleneoctadecanoic acid).</s><s>It has been isolated from the dental plaque of monkeys (<i>M. fascicularis</i>).</s><s>It is cariogenic when monoassociated with germfree rats.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 to 42 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is MFe28 (=NCTC 11391).</s></p></content></protolog>