<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7202_nm.2923" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2923" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2923" rank="species">Shewanella frigidimarina</organism><reference id="rid.7202"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McCammon</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Skerratt</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rea</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McMeekin</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella gelidimarina sp. nov. and Shewanella frigidimarina sp. nov., novel Antarctic species with the ability to produce eicosapentaenoic acid (20:5 omega 3) and grow anaerobically by dissimilatory Fe(III) reduction.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1040</fpage><lpage>1047</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1040</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336903</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Shewanella frigidimarina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Shewanella frigidimarina</i> (fri.gid.i.ma.ri'na. L. adj. <i>frigidus</i>, cold; L. fem. adj. <i>marina</i>, of the sea; M. L. adj. <i>figidimarina</i>, of the cold sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. frigidimarina</i> cells are rod shaped and either curved or straight (length, 1.0 to 2.5 μm; width, 0.5 to 0.8 μm) and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cells are motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs by fermentation of D-glucose or alternatively by anaerobic respiration with ferric compounds, nitrate, or TMAO as the electron acceptor and either sodium lactate or sodium acetate as the electron donor.</s><s>Psychrotrophic.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures from &#x003C;O to 27 to 28°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 20 to 22°C.</s><s>Nonhalophilic.</s><s>Tolerates up to 9% NaCl.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Uses inorganic and organic nitrogen sources.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Proteolytic and lipolytic.</s><s>DNase is formed.</s><s>May hydrolyze esculin and produce hydrogen sulfide from thiosulfate.</s><s>A few strains show weak positive reactions in the o-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranosid(eO NPG), arginine dihydrolase, and ornithine decarboxylase tests.</s><s>Amylase and chitinase are not produced.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from cellobiose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannitol, and sucrose.</s><s>Acid may also be formed from D-galactose, D-mannose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-arabinose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-adonitol, glycerol, m-inositol, or D-sorbitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized by all strains: cellobiose, D-glucose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, D-mannitol, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, valerate, succinate, fumarate, DL-lactate, L-malate, pyruvate, oxaloacetate, and L-leucine.</s><s>Strains may also use D-fructose, D-galactose, D-xylose, caproate, nonanoate, L-glutamate, L-phenylalanine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-proline, and L-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Produces EPA.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 40 to 43 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from sea ice, sea ice algal biomass, cyanobacterial mats, and the water columns of marine salinity meromictic lakes in Antarctica.</s><s>The type strain is ACAM 591, which was isolated from Antarctic sea ice.</s></p></content></protolog>