<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1502_nm.5265" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5265" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5265" rank="species">Staphylococcus piscifermentans</organism><reference id="rid.1502"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hashimoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kozaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus piscifermentans sp. nov., from fermented fish in Thailand.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>577</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-577</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1390108</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus piscifefmentans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus piscifefmentans</i> (pis.ci.fer.men'tans. L. n . <i>piscis</i>, fish; M.L. part.adj. <i>fermentans</i>, fermenting; M.L. adj. <i>piscifermentans</i>, fish fermenting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci (diameter, 1.0 μm) that are nonmotile and nonsporeforming and occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads, and in clusters.</s><s>Colonies on glucose-yeast extract-peptone agar are usually opaque, circular, low convex with entire margins, and nonpigmented or white with a yellowish orange tint.</s><s>They are positive for catalase activity, the benzidine test, nitrate reduction, phosphatase activity, β-glucosidase activity, and arginine hydrolysis and negative for coagulase activity, hemolysis of horse blood, oxidase activity, the Voges-Proskauer reaction, the lecithovitellin reaction, gelatin hydrolysis, citrate utilization, β-glucuronidase activity and β-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Most strains are positive for hydrolysis of urea, Tween 80, and esculin.</s><s>All are facultatively anaerobic and split glucose fermentatively.</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically from D-glucose, D-fructose, and D-trehalose, but not from D-arabinose, D-cellobiose, L-fucose, gluconate, D-mannose, raffinose, D-turanose, D-xylose, and xylitol.</s><s>Compounds which give variable acid production are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains grow in thioglycolate medium, grow at 18 and 42°C, and grow well between pH 6.8 and 9.0.</s><s>All strains grow weakly at pH 5.0 but not at pH 4.5 and at 45°C.</s><s>All strains grow in medium containing 6, 8, or 10% NaCl, and some strains grow in medium containing 15% NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to lysostaphin (200 μg/ml) and novobiocin (1.6 and 5.0 μg/ml).</s><s>Most strains are resistant to lysozyme (400 and 1,600 μg/ml).</s><s>Variable characteristics are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 36.3 to 37.3 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s><s>The strains contain anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> fatty acid as a dominant fatty acid.</s><s>MK-7 is the major menaquinone, and MK-6 and MK-8 are minor menaquinones.</s><s>The strains tested contain peptidoglycan of the L-Lys-Gly<sub>4-5</sub> type and produce DL lactic acid from glucose.</s><s>The strains were isolated from kung-chom (fermented shrimp), pla-ra (fermented fish), and bu-du (fermented fish in liquid form).</s><s>Strain SK03 (= NRIC 1817 = JCM 6057 = TISTR 824) is the type strain and was isolated from kung-chom.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Type strain SK03 has the characteristics given above in the description of the species.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of strain SK03<i>T</i> DNA is 36.8 mol% (as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography).</s></p></content></protolog>