<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4740_nm.1402" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1402" rank="genus">Aminobacter</organism><reference id="rid.4740"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Araki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oyanagi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pseudomonas aminovorans (den Dooren de Jong 1926) to Aminobacter gen. nov. as Aminobacter aminovorans comb. nov. and Aminobacter niigataensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>84</fpage><lpage>92</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-1-84</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aminobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aminobacter</i> (Am.i.no.bac-'ter. M.L.n. <i>aminum</i>, amine; M.L.n. <i>bacter</i>, rod, staff; M.L. masc.n. <i>Aminobacter</i>, amine rod). Nonsporeforming, gramnegative, rod-shaped, methylamine-utilizing organisms that are 0.5 to 0.9 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm and have rounded ends. The cells occur singly (rarely in pairs) and are motile by means of subpolar flagella. Reproduction occurs by budding (12). Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid are accumulated in the cells. Colonies are white to light yellow. Cells grow abundantly in nutrient broth and PYG broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A water-soluble fluorescent pigment is not produced.</s><s>The methyl red test and the Voges-Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin and starch is not observed.</s><s>Ammonia is produced.</s><s>Denitrification is negative.</s><s>Litmus milk is not changed.</s><s>Acids are produced from sugars oxidatively, but not fermentatively .</s><s>Monomet hylamine, trime thylamine, trime thylamine- N-oxide, and sugars are utilized, but methanol, methane, and hydrogen are not utilized.</s><s>Growth factors are not required as essential supplements.</s><s>Ammonia, nitrate, urea, peptone, and methylamine are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are produced, but urease is not.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory and not fermentative.</s><s>Good growth occurs between pH 6.0 and 8.0, but growth does not occur above pH 9.0 and below pH 5.0.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 and 37°C, but does not occur at 42°C.Growth does not occur in the presence of 3% sodium chloride.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 62 to 64 mol% G+C.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids include a large amount of straight-chain unsaturated C<sub>18:1</sub> acid.</s><s>The hydroxy acids include a large amount of 3-OH C<sub>12:0</sub> acid.</s><s>The ubiquinone system is ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>The type species is <i>Aminobacter aminovorans</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>