<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6292_nm.4141" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4141" rank="genus">Johnsonella</organism><reference id="rid.6292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oribaculum catoniae gen. nov., sp. nov.; Catonella morbi gen. nov., sp. nov.; Hallella seregens gen. nov., sp. nov.; Johnsonella ignava gen. nov., sp. nov.; and Dialister pneumosintes gen. nov., comb. nov., nom. rev., Anaerobic gram-negative bacilli from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186083</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Johnsonella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Johnsonella</i> (Johnson.el'la. N. L. masc. n. <i>Johnsonella</i>, in honor of John L. Johnson, a United States microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Johnsonella</i> cells are obligately anaerobic, gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporing, nonfermentative rods that produce a moderate amount of acetate and trace amounts of isovalerate, lactate, succinate, isobutyrate, and butyrate in PYG broth cultures.</s><s>No dark colonies are produced on rabbit blood agar plates.</s><s>The major cellular constituents include an unidentified compound with a retention time that indicates that it has an equivalent chain length of 9.740 and C<sub>16:0</sub> fatty acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Johnsonella ignava</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type species is 32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This genus can be differentiated from other genera of anaerobic gram-negative bacilli by its cellular fatty acid profile (an unidentified acid with an equivalent chain length of 9.74 accounts for 42% of the fatty acids) and by its G+C content and metabolic products.</s></p></content></protolog>