<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12637_nm.22176" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22176" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22176" rank="species">Streptococcus porcorum</organism><reference id="rid.12637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mentaberre</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lavín</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus porcorum sp. nov., isolated from domestic and wild pigs</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1585</fpage><lpage>1589</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022657-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20675439</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus porcorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus porcorum</em> (por.co′rum. L. n. <em>porcus</em> -<em>i</em> a hog, pig; L. gen. pl. n. <em>porcorum</em> of/from pigs).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, non-spore-forming cocci, 0.5–1 µm in diameter, occurring in pairs or in chains, commonly over 15 cells long.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small, circular and non-pigmented, 0.75–1.0 mm in diameter and α-haemolytic at 37 °C.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, catalase-negative and non-motile.</s><s>No Lancefield carbohydrate antigens (Slidex Strepto kit; bioMérieux) are detected.</s><s>Cells are able to grow at 10, 22, 30, 37 and 42 °C but do not grow in the presence of 3, 4.5 or 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>With the API 50CH and Rapid ID32 Strep kits, acid is produced from lactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, trehalose, maltose, methyl β-d-glucopyranoside, d-galactose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, gentiobiose and sucrose but not from melibiose, l- or d-arabinose, d-xylose, starch, glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l- or d-arabitol, glycogen, d-mannitol, inositol, dulcitol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, pullulan, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, l-sorbose, turanose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-lyxose, xylitol, d- or l-fucose, d-sorbitol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, cyclodextrin or tagatose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from raffinose (Rapid ID32 Strep; type strain positive) but not from inulin (API 50CH; type strain negative).</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase (API ZYM), β-glucosidase and alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep) are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin (API ZYM), alkaline phosphatase, β-glucuronidase (API ZYM and Rapid ID32 Strep), glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, β-mannosidase or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Arginine, hippurate and urea are not hydrolysed (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Most strains do not produce α-galactosidase or acetoin (Rapid ID32 Strep; type strain negative for both tests).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 682-03<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7593<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 58479<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a joint of a pig with arthritis.</s><s>Full range of habitats is not known.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>