<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4549_nm.4172" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4172" rank="genus">Peptostreptococcus</organism><reference id="rid.4549"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawamura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of the genera Anaerococcus gen. nov., Peptoniphilus gen. nov. and Gallicola gen. nov. for members of the genus Peptostreptococcus.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1521</fpage><lpage>1528</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Peptostreptococcus</i> Kluyver and van Niel 1936</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Obligately anaerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile cocci and coccobacilli. Cells are usually arranged in chains. Cell wall diamino acid is L-lysine and the interpeptide bridge is D-aspartate. The G+­C content of the DNA is 33-34 mol%(<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>). Weakly saccharolytic. Negative for indole, urease, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase and coagulase. Most strains produce acid from glucose. Some strains produce acid from mannose, maltose or sucrose. The metabolic end-products from PYG medium are acetic, butyric, isobutyric, isovaleric and isocaproic acids. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. Aesculin is not hydrolysed. The type species is <i>Peptostreptococcus anaerobius</i>, the only remaining member of the genus. <i>Peptostreptococcus anaerobius</i> is classified phylogenetically in clostridial group XI. The type strain of <i>Peptostreptococcus anaerobius</i> is NCTC 11460<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>