<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2721_nm.5786" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5786" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5786" rank="species">Actinomyces hordeovulneris</organism><reference id="rid.2721"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Buchanan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scott</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gerencser</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaman</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biberstein</surname><given-names>E.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces hordeovulneris sp. nov., an agent of canine actinomycosis.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>439</fpage><lpage>443</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-439</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces hordeovulneris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces hordeovulneris</i> (hor. de. o. vul' ne. ris. L. n. <i>Hordeum</i> genus of grass; L. n. <i>vulnus</i> wound, injury; N. L. adj, <i>hordeovulneris Hordeum</i> injury)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are pleomorphic rods and filaments that are 0.5 to 1.0 μm in diameter and usually exhibit a noticeable degree of branching on blood agar (Fig. 1A).</s><s>In broth supplemented with 15% fetal calf serum, the filaments are long and extensively branched and have swollen termini (Fig. lB), where spheroplast-like bodies occasionally develop (data not shown).</s><s>Dissociation to diphtheroid cells is incomplete in broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on bovine blood agar are white, agar adherent, and molar toothed (data not shown, but similar to <i>A. israelii</i> [16]), with a tendency to shift to a white, conical, domed, buttery, less adherent type (Fig. 1C) upon laboratory passage.</s><s>Diameters are 0.5 to 1.0 mm after 48 h at 37°C and 2 mm after 3 days.</s><s>On clear media (Trypticase soy or brain heart infusion agar plates supplemented with 10 to 20% fetal calf serum) microcolonies after 24 h of incubation at 37°C are regularly filamentous and similar to those of <i>A . israelii</i> (16).</s><s>Young colonies are more white and raised and have smaller diameters than those of the 6-deoxytalose-negative <i>A. viscosus</i> strains isolated from dogs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is weak in unvented or vented Trypticase soy broth cultures unless they are supplemented with serum; it is flocculant with 15 % fetal calf serum.</s><s>All strains are facultatively anaerobic, but require CO<sub>2</sub> for growth.</s><s>Acetic acid, lactic acid, and major amounts of succinic acid are detectable upon analysis of 3-ml samples withdrawn from Trypticase soy broth cultures supplemented with 5% fetal calf serum.</s><s>All strains have weak to moderate catalase activity and are negative in the benzidine test (7).</s><s>Most strains, including the type strain, are nonhemolytic on bovine blood agar, but a few exhibit weak activity which becomes noticeable after 7 days.</s><s>Acetylmethyl carbinol and urease are not produced, and nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce acid from cellobiose, glucose, lactose, maltose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannose, melibiose, and raffinose, but production is weak by some strains other than the type strain.</s><s>All strains fail to produce acid from arabinose, glycerol, mannitol, mesoinositol, rhamnose, and ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycans of all strains contain lysine, alanine, and glutamic acid.</s><s>Ornithine is present in the walls of most strains.</s><s>The wall carbohydrates include glucose and galactose.</s><s>Rhamnose and 6-deoxytalose are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As shown in Table 1, all three strains tested cross-reacted with antisera against <i>A. israelii</i> serotype 1 strain ATCC 12102 and <i>A. viscosus</i> serotype 1 strain ATCC 15987 <sup>T</sup> but in titers much lower than homologous levels.</s><s>The reactions of these dog strains with <i>A. israelii</i> serotype 1 antisera exceeded those with <i>A. viscosus</i> ATCC 15987<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>No serological reactions were observed with antisera against <i>A. viscosus</i> serotype 2 strain ATCC 19246, <i>A. israelii</i> serotype 2 strain ATCC 29322, <i>A. bovis</i> serotypes 1 and 2, <i>A. naeslundii</i> serotypes 1, 2, and 3, <i>A. odontolyticus</i> serotypes 1 and 2, <i>A. suis</i>, <i>A. pyogenes</i> (formerly <i>C. pyogenes</i>), <i>R. dentocariosa</i> serotypes 1, 2, and 3, and <i>Rothia</i>-like strain WVU 1556.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Five of five <i>A. hordeovulneris</i> strains tested were susceptible to ≤.25 μg of penicillin G per ml and ≤.25 μg of cephalothin per ml, and all were inhibited by 1 μg of chloramphenicol per ml and 1 μg of trimethoprim sulfa per ml.</s><s>Strain UCD 81-332-9<sup>T</sup> had a tetracycline minimal inhibitory concentration of 4 μg/ml, whereas the other four strains tested were susceptible to 0.5 or 1.0 μg of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The <i>A. hordeovulneris</i> strains were isolated from cases of pleuritis, peritonitis, visceral abscesses, septic arthritis, and recurrent localized infections often occurring secondary to tissue-wandering foxtailawns.</s><s>Three animals died despite ampicillin treatment.</s><s>A second drug, usually tribrissen, was added to or substituted for ampicillin to achieve favorable responses in other cases due to <i>A. hordeovulneris</i>.</s><s>Occasionally, <i>A. viscosus</i> and <i>A. hordeovulneris</i> were present in the same sample.</s><s>The unfavorable responses to ampicillin may be related to a marked tendency to produce L-forms spontaneously with coincident uptake of calcium (A.</s><s>M.</s><s>Buchanan and J.</s><s>L.</s><s>Scott, submitted for publication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of <i>A. hordeovulneris</i> UCD 81-332-9<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC 35275<sup>T</sup>) was 67 mol%, compared with 69 mol% for <i>A. viscosus</i> ATCC 15987<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>This value for strain ATCC 15987<sup>T</sup> is in agreement with the data of Coykendall and Munzenmaier (5) whose calculation was based on the thermal denaturation temperature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain ATCC 35275 (=UCD 81-332-9) is the type strain of <i>A. hordeovulneris</i>.</s><s>Characteristics that are useful in distinguishing this new <i>Actinomyces</i> species from other fermentative actinomycetes are given in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>