<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8571_nm.13408" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13408" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13408" rank="species">Marinobacterium rhizophilum</organism><reference id="rid.8571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacterium rhizophilum sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of the coastal tidal-flat plant Suaeda japonica.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>164</fpage><lpage>167</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65176-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175703</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacterium rhizophilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacterium rhizophilum</em> (rhi.zo.phi′lum. Gr. n. <em>rhiza</em> root; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>rhizophilum</em> root-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, straight rods, approximately 0.3–0.4 μm wide and 0.6–0.8 μm long, and motile by means of monopolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, entire, convex and creamy white.</s><s>After 3 days on MA at 30 °C, colonies are approximately 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures in the range 5–30 °C (optimally at approx. 25 °C) and at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0).</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1–5 % (optimally at 3 %, w/v).</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, amylase and Tween 80 hydrolysis are present.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, nitrate reductase, gelatinase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (PNPG), urease, aesculin hydrolysis and indole production are absent.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present, whereas esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, acids are produced from l-arabinose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, turanose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate, are produced weakly from glycerol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, trehalose, inulin, melezitose and xylitol and are not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, potassium gluconate or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes l-arginine, l-asparagine, betaine, d-galactose, l- and d-leucine, glucose, glutamic acid, glycine, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-fructose, glycerol, mannitol, trehalose and sucrose as sole carbon sources, but does not utilize citrate, dimethyl sulfide, lactose, l-cysteine, maleic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetate, succinate or urea.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Fatty acids comprising &#x003E;1 % of the total are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, 40.3 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (26.6 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (16.6 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (7.1 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (4.0 %) and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (3.9 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-YJ9<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42386<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18822<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of a coastal plant (<em>Suaeda japonica</em>) inhabiting a tidal flat of Youngjong Island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>