<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9467_nm.14607" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14607" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14607" rank="species">Kineococcus rhizosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.9467"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineococcus rhizosphaerae sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2204</fpage><lpage>2207</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008599-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605726</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kineococcus rhizosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kineococcus rhizosphaerae</em> (rhi.zo.sphae′rae. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhiza</em> a root; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> ball, sphere; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>rhizosphaerae</em> of the rhizosphere, referring to the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-positive-staining, non-spore-forming, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, motile cocci.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth and orange.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C and pH 5.1–10.1.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not casein, chitin, cellulose, elastin or starch.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase but negative for glucose fermentation, nitrate reduction, and degradation of hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, dextran, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose and melibiose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize d-dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose or d-xylitol.</s><s>Acetate, benzoate, formate, dl-malate, succinate and l-tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain arabinose, galactose and xylose as characteristic sugars.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and two unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (72.5 % of the total in the type strain).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RP-B16<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19366<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19711<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of a cliff-associated plant (<em>Peucedanum japonicum</em> Thunb.) on Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>