<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2218" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2218" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2218" rank="species">Xanthomonas cucurbitae</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas cucurbitae</i> (ex Bryan 1926) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. cucurbitae</i> is the same as that of the genus. Strains of this species are isolated from diseased <i>Citrullus vulgaris</i>, <i>Cucumis sativus</i>, and <i>Cucurbita</i> spp. (Cucurbitaceae).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. cucurbitae</i> can be distinguished from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species on the basis of its SDS-PAGE protein patterns (48), by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, maltose, D-psicose, D-trehalose, monomethylsuccinate, DL-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, L-glutamic acid, and L-serine, and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, L-arabinose, gentiobiose, α-D-lactose, lactulose, D-mannitol, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, acetic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, glucuronamide, D-alanine, L-asparagine, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, L-histidine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, L-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, DL-a-glycerolphosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, and glucose 6-phosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 66.1 to 66.8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 690 (= NCPPB 2597 = ICMP 2299).</s></p></content></protolog>