<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8443_nm.13687" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13687" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13687" rank="species">Aestuariicola saemankumensis</organism><reference id="rid.8443"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aestuariicola saemankumensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from tidal flat sediment.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2126</fpage><lpage>2131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65717-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768617</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aestuariicola saemankumensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aestuariicola saemankumensis</em> (sae.man.kum.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>saemankumensis</em> of Saemankum, from where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, oval or coccoid and 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 0.5–7.0 μm in length; cells greater than 10.0 μm in length occur in older cultures.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular with entire edges, convex, smooth, glistening, yellow and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 33 °C, but not at 34 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 7.0–8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.5, but not at pH 5.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs in the presence of 0.5–4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Carotenoid pigments are produced, but flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are weakly hydrolysed, but casein, hypoxanthine, xanthine, l-tyrosine and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on Casamino acids, peptone and tryptone, but not on l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, trehalose, d-xylose, acetate, benzoate, l-malate, salicin, formate, l-arginine, l-ornithine, dl-aspartate or dl-cysteine.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, lincomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin and tetracycline, but not to ampicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B or streptomycin.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) activities are weak and lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 37.2 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SMK-142<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22171<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55329<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat sediment at Saemankum on the Yellow Sea coast of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>