<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4261_nm.9917" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9917" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9917" rank="species">Rhodococcus phenolicus</organism><reference id="rid.4261"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rehfuss</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urban</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus phenolicus sp. nov., a novel bioprocessor isolated actinomycete with the ability to degrade chlorobenzene, dichlorobenzene and phenol as sole carbon sources</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>28</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>695</fpage><lpage>701</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.05.011</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16261859</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodococcus phenolicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>R. phenolicus</em> (<em>phenolicus</em> (phe.nol.i’.cus. N. L. n. <em>phenol</em> common name for industrial solvent hydroxybenzene; N.L. masc. adj. <em>phenolicus</em> pertaining to phenol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore forming, non-motile, Gram-positive and pleomorphic.</s><s>Extensive substrate mycelia are observed on TSA, BUG and nutrient agar plates during early growth phases.</s><s>Mycelia branch into rods and cocci of variable size during later growth phases.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are formed when grown using phenol, chlorobenzene, 1,4-dichlorobenzene and chlorobenzoic acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are variable in morphology, being predominantly rugose and radiate in texture, undulate in margin and umbonate in elevation.</s><s>Mucoid, smooth and irregular colonies are a minority.</s><s>All colonies develop pale pink pigmentation during stationary phase.</s><s>A wide pH range is tolerated.</s><s>Optimal, lush growth occurs at pH 6–8, and moderate growth occurs at pH 4, 5, 9 and 10 TSB or M9 with 0.1% glucose as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Phenol degradation as a sole carbon source also occurred over a pH range of 4–10, and growth at a phenol concentration of 0.75% (w/v) at pH 7 was observed after 8 days of incubation at 30 °C: catalase positive; oxidase and DNAse negative.</s><s>Tween-80 is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Tyrosine is hydrolyzed slowly, with clearing of tyrosine around colonies occurring after 1 week of incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Xanthine, urea, esculin, arbutin, casein and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid was produced from trehalose, but not from d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-cellobiose, inulin, lactose, d-galactose, d-raffinose, L-arabinose or starch.</s><s>Acetate, succinate, ethanol, maltose and pyruvate are utilized.</s><s>Utilizes the aromatic compounds phenol, chlorobenzene, 1,4-dichlorobenzene and chlorobenzoic acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Exhibits weak growth using toluene and biphenyl as the sole carbon source.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>18:1</sub><em>cis</em>9, 10 methyl-C<sub>18:0</sub>, and a summed feature of C<sub>16:1</sub><em>cis</em>7 and/or C<sub>15:0</sub> iso 2-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 66.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, G2P<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSMZ 44812 and in the ARS collection (Peoria, Illinois, USA) as B-24343.</s></p></content></protolog>