<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1356_nm.1393" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1393" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1393" rank="species">Ochrobactrum anthropi</organism><reference id="rid.1356"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Popoff</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kiredjian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum anthropi gen. nov. from human clinical specimens and previously known as group Vd.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>406</fpage><lpage>416</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ochrobactrum anthropi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ochrobactrum anthropi</i> (an. thro'pi. Gr. n. <i>anthropos</i>, a human being; N.L. gen. n. <i>anthropi</i>, of a human being, since virtually all strains thus far recovered are from human clinical specimens)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are motile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C); they are motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 2).</s><s>After growth on nutrient agar for 24 h, colonies are typically circular, low convex, about 1 mm in diameter, smooth, shining, and entire.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A total of 163 characteristics are common to all strains (either all positive or all negative).</s><s>There are 121 characteristics in which one or more of the strains differ (Table 4).</s><s>All strains have the following positive characteristics in common: growth at 37°C; growth at room temperature (18 to 22°C); growth on MacConkey agar; catalase production; oxidase production; production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, arabinose, ethanol, fructose, rhamnose, and xylose; and growth on β-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains have the following negative characteristics in common: pigment production; gluconate oxidation; lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase production; acid and gas produced in glucose peptone water medium; reduction of 0.4% (wt/vol) selenite; casein digestion; production of extracellular deoxyribonuclease; production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from raffinose; indole production (Kovacs and Ehrlich reagents); arginine desimidase production; hydrolysis of Tween 20 and Tween 80; production of a brown melaninlike pigment on tyrosine agar; accumulation of lipids after growth on phydroxybutyrate; fluorescence on King medium B ; growth at 5°C; production of 3-ketolactose and lecithinase ; hydrolysis of starch; and production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains utilize the following substrates (tests done with API 50AA, API 50AO, and API 50CH galleries): glycine, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-valine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-histidine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-ornithine, L-lysine, L-citrulline, L-arginine, L-proline, betaine, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-4-aminobutyratesa, sarcosine, glucosamine, acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, N-valerate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate , DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, D-malate, L-malate, 2-ketoglutarate, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, adonitol, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, N-acetylglucosamine, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, gluconate, and 2-ketogluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No strain utilizes the following substrates (tests done with API 50AA, API 50AO, and API 50CH galleries): D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, trigonelline, DL-kynurenine, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate , urea, acetamide, ethylamine, butylamine, amylamine, benzylamine, diaminobutane, spermine, histamine, tryptamine, heptanoate, caprylate, pimelate, L-tartrate, levulinate, itaconate, mesaconate, o-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, terephthalate, methyl-xyloside, D-melibiose, inulin, D-raffinose, and glycogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains hydrolyze the following substrates (tests done with API ZYM galleries): L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride and L-seryl-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains hydrolyzes the following substrates (tests done with API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl caprylate, 2-naphthylmyristate, L-valyl-2-nahpthylamide, L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphodiamide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-B1-β-D-glucuronic acid, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside, α-D-galactopyranoside , β-D-galactopyranoside-6-phosphate, α-L-arabinofuranoside, β-D-glucopyranoside, β-D-galacturonide, β-D-glucuronide, α-maltoside, β-maltoside, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, α-L-fucopyranoside, α-L-fucopyranoside , β-D-lactoside, α-D-mannopyranoside, β-D-mannopyranoside, α-D-xylopyranoside, β-D-xylopyranoside, L-aspartyl-β-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide, S-benzyl-L-cysteyl-β-naphthylamide, N-carbobenzoxy-L-arginine-4-methoxy-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride, α-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide, and L-isoleucyl-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of 35 strains of <i>O. anthropi</i> are between 56 and 59 mol%, with a mean of 57.0 mol% and a standard deviation of ± 0.7 mol%; the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 57 mol% (as estimated by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is strain CIP 14970 (= CIP 82.115 = NCTC 12168 = LMG 3331).</s><s>Thus, our results agree well with those of Ohishi et al. (57.6 to 60.5 mol% G+C, 9 strains) (Ohishi et al., Abstr.</s><s>XIV Int.</s><s>Congr.</s><s>Microbiol., 1986) and with those of De Ley et al. (57.3 to 59.2 mol% G+C, 14 strains) (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group Vd strains have been isolated predominantly from blood, respiratory tracts, urogenital tracts, and urine, with only a few isolates from feces and wounds (25).</s><s>Our isolates (Table 1) were obtained from blood (17 strains), wounds (10 strains) , urogenital tracts or urine (7 strains), respiratory tracts (6 strains), ears (3 strains), feces (3 strains), an eye (1 strain), and spinal fluid (1 strain); 2 strains were isolated from hospital apparatus, four strains were isolated from environmental sources, and the sources of 2 strains were unknown.</s><s>Although group Vd strains are widely distributed in clinical specimens, the clinical significance of group Vd remains largely unknown.</s><s>One strain was reported to be a cause of bacteremia in an immunocompromised host (20), but other workers believed that the characteristics presented by the authors were insufficient for unequivocal identification of the strain as a member of group Vd (G.</s><s>L.</s><s>Gilardi and M.</s><s>J.</s><s>Pickett, Letter, J.</s><s>Clin.</s><s>Microbiol. 22:139, 1985).</s><s>However, one strain has been reported in association with a pancreatic abscess (l),a nd another has been associated with puncture wound osteochondritis of a foot (2).</s><s>Group Vd strains are susceptible to aminoglycosides, carbenicillin, nalidixic acid, tetracycline, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole but are resistant to other antimicrobial agents (26). <i>O. anthropi</i> appears to be widely distributed as our study included (Table 1) 22 strains from the United States, 18 strains from France, 7 strains from the United Kingdom, 3 strains from Denmark, 2 strains from Sweden, and 1 strain from Australia; the geographical sources of three strains were unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics for the differentiation of <i>O. anthropi</i> from phylogenetically closely related taxa and from phenotypically similar taxa are given in Table 5.</s><s>Almost all of the strains of <i>O. anthropi</i> (which included two reference strains of <i>Achromobacter</i> species biotype 2) tested produced acid from maltose, mannitol, and sucrose so our results differ from those of Chester and Cooper (3), who found that their reference strains of <i>Achromobacter</i> species biotype 2 (and almost all of their field strains) were unable to acidify these carbohydrates.</s><s>The results of Oberhofer et al. (21) are more in accord with our results, as these authors found that one-half of their strains were able to acidify these carbohydrates, and their strains also fell into more than two biotypes.</s><s>Although these organisms are peritrichously flagellated, the flagella are generally small in number (one flagellum is common) and are laterally attached; apparent polar flagella are occasionally seen as also noted by Chester and Cooper (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The numerical phenotypic analysis confirmed previous observations that the following pairs of species are synonyms: <i>Agrobacterium rudiobacter</i> and <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens</i> (14), <i>Alcaligenes xylosoxidans</i> and <i>Alcaligenes ruhlandii</i> (13, 19, 28), and <i>Alcaligenes faecalis</i> and “<i>Alcaligenes odorans</i>” (13).</s><s>Our analysis also confirmed the distinction as separate taxa of <i>Agrobacterium rhizogenes</i> from <i>Agrobacteriurn tumefaciens</i> (14) and of <i>Alcaligrnes denitrificans</i> and <i>Alcaligenes piechaudii</i> from each other and from <i>Alcaligenes faecalis</i> (13, 19).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following additional strains of <i>O. anthropi</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: strains CDC A8409 (= NCTC 12169 = LMG 394), CL447/80 (= NCTC 12170 LMG 5429), CNS 2-75 (= NCTC 12171 =LMG 3301), and CL634/77 (= NCTC 12172 = LMG 5426).</s></p></content></protolog>