<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1512_nm.1587" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1587" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1587" rank="species">Methylobacterium fujisawaense</organism><reference id="rid.1512"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Green</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bousfield</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hood</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Three new Methylobacterium species: M. rhodesianum sp. nov., M. zatmanii sp. nov., and M. fujisawense sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>124</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-124</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylobacterium fujisawaense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylobacterium fujisawaense</i> (fu.ji.sa'wa.en.sē N. L. neut. adj. <i>fujisawaense</i> coming from the Fujisawa region of Japan)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mode of respiration, colony and cell morphology, flagellar arrangement, Gram reaction, and oxidase atnd catalase as for the type species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows at 15 and 37°C.</s><s>Some strains grow at 10°C.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, cellulose, lecithin, casein, and Tweens are usually not degraded.</s><s>Urease is produced, but indol, H<sub>2</sub>S, β-galactosidase, L-ornithine and L-lysine decarboxylases, and L-arginine dihydrolase are not.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced by most strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sensitive to kanamycin, tetracyclines, gentamicin, alhamycin T, streptomycin, and framycetin but resistant to rialidixic acid, oleandomycin, polymyxin B, colistin sulfate, penicillin G, and bacitracin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds can serve as sole carbon sources: D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-fucose, D-galactose, glycerol, malonate, succinate, fumarate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, sebacate, 2-oxoglutarate, lactate, malate, acetate, pyruvate, citrate, citraconate, ethanol, methanol, and propylene glycol.</s><s>Some strains can utilize fructose.</s><s>Monomethylamine, trimethylamine, and betaine are not utilized.</s><s>Grows on peptone-rich nutrient agar (Oxoid CM55).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 70.8 to 71.8 mol% (9); for the type strain, this value is 71.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose NCIB 12417<sup>T</sup> (= strain 0-31 [13]) as the type strain.</s><s>As a result of recent work, including DNA-DNA homology studies (9), we also propose that strains 45, 269, and 617 (13) be considered as strains of <i>M . fujisawaense</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other strains assigned to this species solely on the basis of phenotypic data are listed in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>