<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1334_nm.827" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.827" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.827" rank="species">Azospirillum halopraeferens</organism><reference id="rid.1334"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fendrik</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thielemans</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azospirillum halopraeferens sp. nov., a nitrogen fixing organism with roots of Kallar grass (Leptochloa fusca (L.) Kunth)</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>43</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-1-43</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azospirillum halopraeferens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azospirillum halopraeferens</i> (ha. lo' prae. fe. rens. Gr. n. <i>hals</i>, <i>halos</i>, salt, the sea; L. v. <i>praeferre</i>, to prefer; N. L. part. adj. salt preferring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram negative, vibrioid to S shaped; only few helical cells occur in alkaline media.</s><s>Motile in liquid medium with a rapid cork screwlike motion by one polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fluorescent pigments are not produced.</s><s>No growth on plates of BMS medium or congo red medium.</s><s>Good growth on tryptic soy agar, forming cream-colored, circular, flat colonies with an entire margin.</s><s>When culivated on N-free semisolid medium at 30 or 35°C, young cultures which have just developed a fine pellicle contain cells of small cell width, averaging from 0.7 to 0.9 μm.</s><s>When growing at 41°C in medium supplemented with 0.25% NaCl at pH 7.2, the width of young cells is 1 to 1.2 μm.</s><s>In both growth conditions, cells tend to become slightly wider, longer, and S shaped in older, more alkaline cultures.</s><s>Such cells seldom exceed a length of 5 μm.</s><s>Only very few long, helical cells are observed.</s><s>The occurrence of S-shaped cells is also pronounced in the late log phase on liquid SM medium, containing 0.25% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell size: 0.7 to 1.4 μm in diameter and 2.4 to 5 μm in length.</s><s>On semisolid N-free malate medium they form veil-like pellicles which first develop several millimeters below the medium surface and later move to the surface.</s><s>They produce intracellular granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganoheterotrophic.</s><s>Respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>All strains carried out acetylene reduction.</s><s>Nitrate can be used for denitrification; N<sub>2</sub> can be fixed in microaerobic conditions.</s><s>Oxidase and urease positive.</s><s>Grow well on salts of organic acids such as L-malate, succinate, fumarate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, β-hydroxybutyrate, and gluconate.</s><s>Grow on D-mannitol, glycerol, and D-ribose.</s><s>Use and acidify D-fructose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics which differ among the eight strains are the utilization of carbon sources and acidification of carbohydrate-containing media.</s><s>On semisolid N-free medium, growth is produced on mannitol but not on glucose or sucrose.</s><s>Not capable of aerobic acid production on peptone-based glucose medium.</s><s>No acid production on fructose or glucose media anaerobically.</s><s>Biotin required for</s></p><p class="description"><s>growth.</s><s>Better growth at 41 than at 35"C, and no growth at 44°C.</s><s>They are able to grow at 20°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The effect of different NaCl concentrations on the acetylene reduction activity of isolate Au 4T is shown in Fig. 5.</s><s>Acetylene reduction activity and growth is optimal in N-free SM medium supplemented with 0.25% NaCl.</s><s>All eight isolates grew better in 0.25% NaCl than with 0.01% or 0.75% NaCl.</s><s>After 7 days of incubation, growth as a subsurface pellicle is observed in 3% NaCl, although after 48 h of incubation acetylene reduction activity can not yet be detected.</s><s>The addition of 0.25% NaCl to liquid SM medium containing bound nitrogen also increases the growth rate.</s><s>The addition of 0.25% NaCl decreases the <i>t<sub>t</sub></i> from 9.7 to 4.7 h for strain Au 4<sup>T</sup>. (<i>Azospirillum amazonense</i> DSM 2787<sup>T</sup> did not respond to 0.25% NaCl [<i>t<sub>t</sub></i>= 3.3 h with and without addition].</s><s>With <i>Azospirillum brasilense</i> DSM 1690<sup>T</sup> and <i>Azospirillum lipoferum</i> DSM 1691<sup>T</sup> the <sup>T</sup> increased slightly by the addition of 0.25% NaCl, from 1.9 to 2.5 h and from 2.3 to 2.5 h, respectively.) All strains grow well in media at a pH between 6.8 and 8.0 with an optimum at pH 7.2.</s><s>The mol% of G + C of DNA is 70.</s><s>Source: isolated from root surface of <i>Leptochloa fusca</i> (L.) Kunth grown on saline-sodic soils in Shakot area, Punjab, Pakistan.</s><s>The type strain is Au 4 (= DSM 3675 = LMG 7108).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as given above for the species, with the following additions: grows on citrate and D-arabinose.</s><s>Produces acid from D-ribose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, maltose, sorbitol, and <i>myo</i>-inositol.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 70</s></p><p class="description"><s>mol% G + C.</s></p></content></protolog>