<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2978_nm.3395" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3395" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3395" rank="species">Pasteurella volantium</organism><reference id="rid.2978"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Piechulla</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mannheim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pasteurella avium, Hinz and Kunjara 1977 comb. nov. and Pasteurella volantium sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-1-5</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella volantium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella volantium</i> (vo.lan'ti.um. L. fem. gen. pl. n. <i>volantium</i> from fowl)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, immotile, coccoid, nonsporeforming rods which occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>They are mesophilic, chemoorganotrophic, facultatively aerobic, fermentative, and V-factor dependent.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, and alkaline phosphatase reactions are positive.</s><s>Ubiquinones and demethylmenaquinones are produced.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar or on Simmons citrate medium.</s><s>On chocolate agar the surface colonies are smooth and convex and may produce yellowish pigments.</s><s>On sheep blood agar supplemented with NAD no hemolysis occurs.</s><s>The phenotypic features of <i>P. volantium</i> are similar to those of <i>P. avium</i>, but <i>P. volantium</i> differs in being maltose and mannitol positive and often sorbitol positive.</s><s>Ornithine is decarboxylated by some strains.</s><s>The G+C content is 44 to 45 mol%.</s><s>The genome molecular weight is 1.5 x 10<sup>9</sup> to 1.9 x 10<sup>9</sup>.</s><s>Found in the wattles of domestic fowl.</s><s>One strain has been isolated from a human tongue (7).</s><s>The type strain is strain Lovell 6 (= NCTC 3438 = ATCC 14385).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics of the species.</s><s>In addition, it produces acid from D-xylose but not from sorbitol or lactose.</s><s>Ornithine is not decarboxylated.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a chicken.</s><s>Although a third group of former <i>H. avium</i> strains was included in the genus <i>Pasteurella</i> on the basis of DNA homology, it appeared to be heterogeneous (Table 2) and should be described when more strains have been studied.</s><s>We suggest strain IPDH 280 (HIM 789-5) as a reference strain for this species, provisionally named <i>Pasteurella</i> species A.</s></p></content></protolog>