<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4751_nm.10671" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10671" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4023" rank="species">Clostridium stercorarium</organism><reference id="rid.4751"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madden</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and Characterization of Clostridium stercorarium sp. nov., Cellulolytic Thermophile</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>837</fpage><lpage>840</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-837</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> (L. adj. <i>stercorarium</i> pertaining to dung, referring to the source of the isolate, a compost heap)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods 0.7 to 0.8 by 2.7 to 7.7 μm and are motile and peritrichous (Fig. 1 ).</s><s>Endospores are oval and terminal.</s><s>Vegetative cells decolorize readily and usually stain gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies in cellulose agar are lenticular, unpigmented. and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>After incubation for 7 days, colonies are surrounded by clear zones, representing cellulose hydrolysis, that usually are 3 to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Upon continued incubation the colonies become cream colored.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on cellobiose agar are 3 to 5 mm in diameter, glossy, not pigmented, and umbonate.</s><s>The raised centers of the colonies are cream colored, and the margins are flat, entire, and colorless.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth is obtained at 65°C and near pH 7.3.</s><s>Growth at 60 or 70°C is approximately 60% of that obtained at 65°C.</s><s>The mean generation time for cultures grown in cellulose broth at 65°C is 16 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only slight growth occurs in nutrient broth without fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>With a fermentable carbohydrate cultures are moderately turbid, with a smooth sediment.</s><s>The pH of cellobiose broths is 4.8 after incubation for 2 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 1.</s><s>The mean pH of uninoculated media was 6.81.</s><s>The mean pH of the media considered not to have been fermented was 6.62, the reduction in pH probably being due to the fermentation of cellobiose transferred with the inoculum.</s><s>A value of pH 6.0 was chosen to indicate growth, and the mean pH of cultures showing growth was 5.77; hence, growth was indicated by a decrease in pH of approximately 0.8 U.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation products in glucose broths were ethanol, acetate, lactate, hydrogen, and carbon dioxide.</s><s>About 4 mM acetate, 4 mM ethanol, and less than 1 mM lactate were found in typical cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Endoglucanase, exoglucanase, and xylanase are produced in cellulose broths (la) .</s><s>Approximately 60% of the endoglucanase activity is produced after growth has ceased (J.-F.</s><s>Berenger and N .</s><s>Creuzet, unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a compost heap.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 39 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is National Collection of Industrial Bacteria strain NCIB 11754.</s></p></content></protolog>