<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.680_nm.8625" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8625" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8625" rank="species">Idiomarina ramblicola</organism><reference id="rid.680"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martínez-Cánovas</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Páez</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Idiomarina fontislapidosi sp. nov. and Idiomarina ramblicola sp. nov., isolated from inland hypersaline habitats in Spain</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1793</fpage><lpage>1797</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63172-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388745</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Idiomarina ramblicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Idiomarina ramblicola</em> [ram.bli.co′la. Spanish sb. fem. <em>rambla</em> from Arabic sb. <em>ramla</em> lit. sandy ground; L. suff. [<em>in</em>]<em>cola</em> denizen of; N.L. sb. fem. nom. <em>ramblicola</em> denizen of a rambla. A rambla is a steep-sided watercourse, often dry but subject to flash flooding (cf. OED, 2nd edn, 1989, vol. XIII, p. 153), not synonymous with Arabic <em>wadi</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are slightly curved rods, 2–3 μm long and 0·75 μm wide, appearing either singly or forming amorphous aggregates.</s><s>They stain Gram-negative and are motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>No spores or polyhydroxyalkanoate are observed under any conditions.</s><s>Colonies are round, convex, mucoid and cream coloured.</s><s>Exopolysaccharide is produced.</s><s>The growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>The bacterium is chemo-organotrophic and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Anaerobic respiration with nitrate, nitrite or fumarate is negative.</s><s>It does not produce acid from any of the following sugars: adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose or d-trehalose.</s><s>It is moderately halophilic, capable of growing in NaCl concentrations of 0·5 to 15 % w/v, the optimum being 3–5 % w/v.</s><s>It does not require additional magnesium or potassium salts.</s><s>It grows within the temperature range of 15 to 40 °C, the optimum being 32 °C, and at pH values of between 5 and 10, the optimum being 7–8.</s><s>It shows positive activity for catalase, cytochrome oxidase, phosphatase, selenite reduction, gluconate oxidation, haemolysis, H<sub>2</sub>S production from cysteine and the hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin, casein, Tween 20, Tween 80 and DNA, and no activity for the hydrolysis of starch and tyrosine, reduction of nitrate and nitrite, oxidation of urease, lecithinase and phenylalanine and growth on cetrimide agar, haemolysis, indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer.</s><s>It does not grow in synthetic media supplemented with different sole sources of carbon and energy, or carbon, nitrogen and energy (aesculin, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, starch, d-trehalose, acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, lactate, malonate, propionate, succinate, adonitol, ethanol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, dl-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine and l-valine).</s><s>It is susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), polymyxin B (300 UI), rifampicin (30 μg), sulphamide (250 μg) and trimetroprim/sulphametoxazol (1·25/23·75 μg).</s><s>It is resistant to kanamycin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48·7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R22<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5858<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22170<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hypersaline water sample taken from Rambla Salada (Murcia, S.E. Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>