<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.369_nm.4990" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4990" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4990" rank="species">Bacillus thermoaerophilus</organism><reference id="rid.369"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Meier-Stauffer</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheberl</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollaus</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Makristathis</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sleytr</surname><given-names>U.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Messner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Bacillus thermoaerophilus sp. nov., to include sugar beet isolates and Bacillus brevis ATCC 12990.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>532</fpage><lpage>541</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-532</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus thermoaerophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus thermoaerophilus</i> (ther.mo.aer.o'phi.lus. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. masc. n. <i>aer</i>, air; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M. L. adj. <i>thermoaerophilus</i>, loving heat and air, i.e., thermophilic and strictly aerobic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (length, 3.7 to 5.4 μm; diameter, 1.0 to 1.2 μm), gram positive, motile, and peritrichous with central spores in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are flat on nutrient agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures ranging from 40 to 60°C at pH 7 to 8.</s><s>Positive for growth in the presence of 3% sodium chloride, development of an alkaline pH in the Voges-Proskauer reaction, hydrolysis of Tween 80, gelatin, and casein, acid production from glucose and glycerol, weak decomposition of thiamine by thiamine hydrolase type 1, and the presence of a specific glycosylated S-layer protein.</s><s>Negative for anaerobic growth, the Voges-Proskauer reaction, growth in the presence of a sodium chloride concentration of 5% or higher, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, indole production, hydrolysis of starch and urea, degradation of DNA, acid production from sucrose, fructose, D- and L-arabinose, trehalose, xylose, mannitol, galactose, maltose, and raffinose, and decomposition of thiamine by thiamine hydrolase type 2.</s><s>Variable for catalase production and growth in the presence of 0.001% (vol/vol) lysozyme and 0.02% (wt/vol) sodium azide.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>The major quinone is menaquinone 7.</s><s>The G+C contents of the strains examined are 46.7 mol% (L420-91<sup>T</sup>) and 46.3 mol% (<i>B. brevis</i> ATCC 12990).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain L420-91.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 10154. <i>B. thermoaerophilus</i> ATCC 12990 (formerly <i>B. brevis</i> ATCC 12990, which is no longer available from the American Type Culture Collection) has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 10155.</s></p></content></protolog>