<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2233" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2233" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2233" rank="species">Xanthomonas vesicatoria</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas vesicatoria</i> (ex Doidge 1920) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>X. vesicatoria</i> includes the strains of the former taxon <i>X. campestris</i> pv. vesicatoria type B. The description of <i>X. vesicatoria</i> is the same as that of the genus. The strains are isolated from diseased pepper plants (<i>Capsicum</i> spp.) and tomato plants (<i>Lycopersicon</i> spp.), as well as a number of other, mainly solanaceous hosts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species can be distinguished from other xanthomonads on the basis of its SDS-PAGE protein patterns (48), by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, Tween 80, L-fucose, gentiobiose, maltose, D-psicose, D-trehalose, monomethylsuccinate, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, L-alanine, L-glutamic acid, and L-serine, and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates L-arabinose, D-galactose, α-D-lactose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, thymidine, and glucose 6-phosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 65.6 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 911 (= NCPPB 422 = ICMP 63).</s></p></content></protolog>