<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6901_nm.2282" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2282" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2282" rank="species">Thiothrix eikelboomii</organism><reference id="rid.6901"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aruga</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamagata</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kohno</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanagawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of filamentous Eikelboom type 021N bacteria and description of Thiothrix disciformis sp. nov. and Thiothrix flexilis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1309</fpage><lpage>1316</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02177-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148645</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Thiothrix eikelboomii</i> (Howarth et al. 1999)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The formal description remains that given by Howarth et al. (1999), with the following modifications. Volutin inclusions are observed in some strains; some strains grow with mannose, glycerol, xylose, propionate, aspartate and alanine; some strains may show slight growth with melibiose, raffinose and sorbitol; nitrate is reduced to nitrite by some strains. The following is added to the description of Howarth et al. (1999): Filaments are more than 0.5 mm long and can reach several millimetres. Colonies are fingerprint-like. Elongate and swollen cells are often present in filaments. Elongate cells in some strains sometimes reach 8 μm in length and swollen cells in some strains sometimes reach 8 μm in diameter. Septa are clearly visible between individual cells. Sudanophilic granules are observed densely within cells. Catalase-positive. Sulfuric acid is produced when cells are grown in the presence of a reduced inorganic sulfur compound. Butyrate, hydroxybutyrate and glutamate are utilized as sole carbon sources. No growth occurs with 1- propanol, ethanol, benzoate, formate or citrate. Growth is inhibited by 0.5% (w/v) NaCl. The G+C content of the DNA is 44-45 mol% (HPLC). The major quinone is UQ-8. The major fatty acids are C<sub>16:1</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>18:1</sub>.</s></p></content></protolog>