<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6572_nm.6647" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6647" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6647" rank="species">Nocardioides pyridinolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6572"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhee</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides pyridinolyticus sp. nov., a pyridine-degrading bacterium isolated from the oxic zone of an oil shale column.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>933</fpage><lpage>938</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-933</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336889</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardioides pyridinolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardioides pyridinolyticus</i> (py.ri.di.no.ly'ti.cus. M. L. n. <i>pyridin</i>, pyridine; M. L. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; M. L. adj. <i>pyridinolyticus</i>, pyridine dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.5 to 0.6 μm wide and 1.2 to 1.6 μm long in the exponential phase of growth.</s><s>Cells exhibit rod-to-coccus morphogenesis from the early exponential phase to the stationary phase.</s><s>Gram positive and gram variable in old cultures.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, round, and cream colored on nutrient agar.</s><s>They are approximately 1.0 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 5 days at 35°C.</s><s>Neither substrate mycelium nor primary mycelium is formed.</s><s>Strain OS4<sup>T</sup> grows at pH 5 and 9 and at 20 and 40°C.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature and pH for strain OS4<sup>T</sup> are 35°C and 8.0, respectively.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>D-Glucose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, D-cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, D-trehalose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, pyridine, and phenol are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources for growth.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-mehbiose, D-raffinose, adonitol, D-sorbitol, inulin, and glycerol are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid (wall chemotype I).</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>), and minor amounts of MK-7(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) are also present.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of saturated, unsaturated, iso-, anteiso- and 10- methyl-branched types, and the major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> and 10-methyl-branched acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72.5 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from the oxic zone of an oil shale column.</s><s>The type strain is OS4, which has been deposited in the Korean Collection for Type Cultures as KCTC 0074BP.</s></p></content></protolog>