<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12570_nm.21819" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21819" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21819" rank="species">Demequina aurantiaca</organism><reference id="rid.12570"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ue</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Demequina globuliformis sp. nov., Demequina oxidasica sp. nov. and Demequina aurantiaca sp. nov., actinobacteria isolated from marine environments, and proposal of Demequinaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1322</fpage><lpage>1329</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024299-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656823</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Demequina aurantiaca</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Demequina aurantiaca</em> (au.ran.ti′a.ca. N.L. fem adj. <em>aurantiaca</em> orange-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, Gram-stain-positive, short rods, 0.2–0.6 µm in width and 0.3–1.2 µm in length.</s><s>Colonies are orange on LB plates.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–30 °C with optimum growth at 28–30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–9 with optimum growth at pH 6–6.5.</s><s>Cells grow optimally in the absence of salt but tolerate up to 15 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, urease negative, oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction to nitrite is negative, H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced and arginine dihydrolase and indole production are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and gelatin is negative, but hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Fermentation of glucose is negative.</s><s>Based on API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Decomposition of adenine, l-tyrosine, casein, hypoxanthine and xanthine is negative.</s><s>Can also utilize l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-xylose, galactose d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, maltose monohydrate and sucrose as sole carbon source, but cannot utilize d-mannitol.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-xylose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, starch, gentiobiose and d-lyxose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl-β-d-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl-α-d-mannoside, methyl-α-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The major menaquinone is demethylmenaquinone DMK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and the minor menaquinones are DMK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) and DMK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The fatty acids (&#x003E; 1%) comprise C<sub>10 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains Orn, Ala, Ser, Glu and Asp in a molar ratio of 0.8 : 2.1 : 1.1 : 1.0 : 0.6.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol; unknown compounds were also detected.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 65.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM12-102<sup>T</sup> (NBRC 106265<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 19745<sup>T</sup>  = MBIC 08347<sup>T</sup>), isolated from seaweed.</s></p></content></protolog>