<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9928_nm.14896" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14896" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14896" rank="species">Planomicrobium flavidum</organism><reference id="rid.9928"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planomicrobium flavidum sp. nov., isolated from a marine solar saltern, and transfer of Planococcus stackebrandtii Mayilraj et al. 2005 to the genus Planomicrobium as Planomicrobium stackebrandtii comb. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2929</fpage><lpage>2933</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009191-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628589</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Planomicrobium flavidum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Planomicrobium flavidum</em> (fla′vi.dum. L. neut. adj. <em>flavidum</em> pale yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive to Gram-variable and cocci or short rods (0.4–0.8×0.4–1.6 μm); a few cells are rods (2.7–3.3 μm in length) in young cultures.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, raised to slightly convex, glistening, smooth, light yellow in colour and 1.2–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 37 °C, but not at 40 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 6.0, but not at pH 5.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 13 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 14 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA and on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, xanthine and l-tyrosine are not.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-galactose, melezitose, trehalose, <em>myo</em>-inositol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G and streptomycin, but not to polymyxin B or tetracycline.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-8 and MK-7.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ISL-41<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13261<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 56756<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine solar saltern of the Yellow Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>