<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9096_nm.14283" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14283" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14283" rank="species">Parvularcula lutaonensis</organism><reference id="rid.9096"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parvularcula lutaonensis sp. nov., a moderately thermotolerant marine bacterium isolated from a coastal hot spring.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>998</fpage><lpage>1001</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004481-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406781</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parvularcula lutaonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parvularcula lutaonensis</em> (lu.ta.o.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>lutaonensis</em> pertaining to Lutao, a small volcanic island off the eastern coast of Taiwan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, short rods, 1−3 μm in length and 0.3−0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are motile by a single polar flagellum and are non-spore-forming.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h incubation on MA at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies on MA at 38 °C are orange, smooth, shiny and convex with spreading edges, 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter and non-fluorescent.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7 and 9, but not at pH 6 or 10; optimal growth occurs at pH 7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.5−6 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No anaerobic growth is observed on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Accumulates poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules as inclusion bodies.</s><s>Positive in tests for oxidase and negative for catalase.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of strain CC-MMS-1<sup>T</sup> is presented in Table 2.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid and glycerol.</s><s>The following substrates are not oxidized as carbon sources: Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethylester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20E and 20NE) are seen for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, citrate utilization, acetoin production, gelatinase, aesculin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, mannose, maltose and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are seen for reduction of nitrates to nitrogen, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, assimilation of arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, tryptophan deaminase, oxidation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>In API ZYM enzyme reactions, strain CC-MMS-1<sup>T</sup> is positive for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative reactions are seen for myristate lipase (C14), acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Genotypic, phenotypic and nutritional features that distinguish the type strain from <em>P. bermudensis</em> HTCC2503<sup>T</sup> are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-MMS-1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17814<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22245<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a rare coastal hot spring on a Pacific Ocean island.</s></p></content></protolog>