<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8490_nm.13529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13529" rank="species">Phenylobacterium haematophilum</organism><reference id="rid.8490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macedo</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawelczyck</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny by a polyphasic approach of the order Caulobacterales, proposal of Caulobacter mirabilis sp. nov., Phenylobacterium haematophilum sp. nov. and Phenylobacterium conjunctum sp. nov., and emendation of the genus Phenylobacterium.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1939</fpage><lpage>1949</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65567-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phenylobacterium haematophilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phenylobacterium haematophilum</em> (hae.ma.to.phi′lum. Gr. n. <em>haema</em> -<em>atos</em> blood; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>haematophilum</em> blood-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Phenylobacterium haematophilum</em> is the same as that given for the genus (Lingens <em>et al.</em>, 1985) and emended by Kanso &#x0026; Patel (2004) and in this study, with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>The polar lipid fraction contains phosphatidylglycerols, sulfoquinovosyl diacylglycerol of 834 amu and 6-phosphatidyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranosyl diacylglycerol of 1413 amu or higher.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (see Supplementary Table S1), minor fatty acids are summed feature 4, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and <em>trans</em>-11-methyl-12-octadecenoic acid.</s><s>The main hydroxyl fatty acid is C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (see Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>Is able to grow on peptone-yeast extract media with 0–10 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl with optimal growth at around 5 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl.</s><s>Does not tolerate salt concentrations above 20 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl.</s><s>Growth is observed between 10 and 40 °C, with optimal growth around 37 °C.</s><s>Positive in results for activities of acid and alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and for weak activities of cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), trypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Is able to utilize arabinose, citrate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, itaconic acid, maltose, mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl pyruvate, l-proline, propionate, sebacic acid and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>Does not utilize acetate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, adonitol, alaninamide, l- and d-alanine, l-alanylglycine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, d-arabitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, 2,3-butanediol, dl-carnitine, cellobiose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, i-erythritol, formate, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, glucose 1- and 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, d-glucuronic acid, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerolphosphate, glycogen, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, hydroxy l-proline, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactate, <em>α</em>-lactose, l-leucine, malonate, d-mannitol, melibiose, monomethylsuccinate, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, phenylethylamine, psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-saccharic acid, d- and l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinate, sucrose, l-threonine, thymidine, trehalose, turanose, uridine, urocanic acid and xylitol.</s><s>The species can use adonitol but not (+)-l-arabinose, caprate, <em>β</em>-(+)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, <em>α</em>-(+)-d-glucose, glycerol, l-histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, (+)-d-mannose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, (+)-d-trehalose or (+)-d-xylose.</s><s>The G+C content is 67.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 11050<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 26751<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human blood (Göteborg, Sweden).</s></p></content></protolog>