<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11579_nm.18614" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18614" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18614" rank="species">Actinophytocola oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.11579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Indananda</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duangmal</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thamchaipenet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinophytocola oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the roots of Thai glutinous rice plants, a new member of the family Pseudonocar</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1141</fpage><lpage>1146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008417-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666784</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinophytocola oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinophytocola oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. n. <em>oryza</em> rice and also the name of a botanical genus; L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, denoting the isolation of the type strain from roots of Thai glutinous rice plants).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics given in the genus description, has the following properties.</s><s>Grows well on ISP 3 and oatmeal-nitrate agar and grows moderately on ISP 2 and 1/10 yeast extract-starch agar, but grows poorly on ISP 4 and ISP 5.</s><s>Pale peach (5ca) aerial mycelium is produced on ISP 3 and substrate mycelium is light melon yellow (3ea); no soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>A trace of rust tan (5le) soluble pigment is produced on oatmeal-nitrate agar.</s><s>No aerial mycelium is observed on ISP 2 or 1/10 yeast extract starch agar.</s><s>Does not grow on ISP 9 or ISP 6.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 12−30 °C, with optimal growth at 18–28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0−10.0, with optimal growth at pH 6.0−7.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate and production of melanin pigments and H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Degrades starch, but negative for decomposition of benzoate, hypoxanthine, xanthine and milk.</s><s>Liquefaction of gelatin is weakly positive.</s><s>Degradation of citrate is positive.</s><s>d-Fructose, d-glucose and l-rhamnose can be utilized as sole carbon sources, but l-arabinose, dulcitol, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, d-fructose and d-glucose, but not from adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, raffinose or l-rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GMKU 367<sup>T</sup> (=BCC 31372<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 105245<sup>T</sup>), isolated from roots of Thai glutinous rice plants (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L. ‘RD6’) collected from Pathum Thani Rice Research Center, Pathum Thani province, Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>