<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9253_nm.14521" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14521" rank="genus">Actinoallomurus</organism><reference id="rid.9253"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nozawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otoguro</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Actinomadura spadix Nonomura and Ohara 1971 to Actinoallomurus spadix gen. nov., comb. nov., and description of Actinoallomurus amamiensis sp. nov., Actinoallomurus caesius sp. nov., Actinoallomurus coprocola sp. nov., Actinoallomurus fulvus sp. nov., Actinoallomurus iriomotensis sp. nov., Actinoallomurus luridus sp. nov., Actinoallomurus purpureus sp. nov. and Actinoallomurus yoronensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1867</fpage><lpage>1874</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006858-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567582</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinoallomurus</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinoallomurus</em> (Ac.ti.no.al.lo.mu′rus. Gr. n. <em>actis</em>, <em>actinos</em> ray, used to refer to actinomycetes; Gr. adj. <em>allos</em> different; L. masc. n. <em>murus</em> wall; N.L. masc. n. <em>Actinoallomurus</em> actinomycetes with a different wall).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-acid-fast and strictly aerobic actinomycetes that show extensive branching and non-fragmenting substrate hyphae.</s><s>Spore chains develop on the tips of the aerial mycelium.</s><s>Spores form oval to short rods (0.5–1.2 μm wide and 0.7–2.0 μm long).</s><s>Spores are non-motile.</s><s>The surface of colonies is powdery.</s><s>Strains show good growth on most test media; however, they show extremely poor sporulation on these media.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is generally 25–30 °C.</s><s>The cell wall contains d-glutamic acid, d- and l-alanine, d- and l-lysine and <em>meso</em>-A<sub>2</sub>pm.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain madurose and galactose.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids comprise iso-branched, anteiso-branched, 10-methylated branched saturated and unsaturated fatty acids; iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> is the major component.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) are the predominant menaquinones.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol are detected; phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine and ninhydrin-positive unidentified phospholipids are not detected (phospholipid pattern type PI).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>The acyl type of the muramic acid is <em>N</em>-acetyl.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 69–74 mol%.</s><s>Unique nucleotide signatures are present at the following positions of the 16S rRNA gene (corresponding to the numbering of the <em>Escherichia coli</em> 16S rRNA gene; Brosius <em>et al.</em>, 1978): 128 (T), 141 : 222 (G–C), 415 (A), 442 : 492 (C–G), 445 : 488 (C–G), 446 : 489 (C–G), 493 (G), 602 : 636 (C–G), 610 (A), 614 : 626 (G–C), 615 : 625 (A–T), 630 (C), 657 : 749 (G–C), 658 : 748 (T–A), 659 : 747 (A–T), 854 (T), 990(T), 1159 (T) and 1262 (A).</s><s>The genus belongs to the family <em>Thermomonosporaceae</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Actinoallomurus spadix</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to those given in the genus description, the morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics of each species are as follows.</s></p></content></protolog>