<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9224_nm.14481" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14481" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14481" rank="species">Marivita litorea</organism><reference id="rid.9224"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yih</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marivita cryptomonadis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Marivita litorea sp. nov., of the family Rhodobacteraceae, isolated from marine habitats</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1568</fpage><lpage>1575</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005462-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19528201</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marivita litorea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marivita litorea</em> (li.to′re.a. L. fem. adj. <em>litorea</em> of the shore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>After 5 days on MA plates at 30 °C, colonies are creamy and approximately 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.3–0.9 μm wide and 1.0–3.5 μm long.</s><s>Grows at 15–33 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and pH 6–10 (optimum, pH 7–8).</s><s>Growth occurs at sea salt concentrations of 1–10 % (w/v) (optimum, 3–5 %), but no growth occurs in media containing NaCl as the only salt.</s><s>Cells contain poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Amylase is not produced.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities as tested with the API ZYM system: esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Weakly positive for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities as tested with the API 20NE system: aesculin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (PNPG).</s><s>Negative for gelatinase, indole production, nitrate reductase and urease.</s><s>Acetate, l-arabinose, l-arginine, cellobiose, citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-ornithine, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, sorbitol, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and xylose are not utilized as sole carbon source.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids listed in the genus description, a minor amount of an additional unidentified lipid is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-JM1<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 90071<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15446<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal seawater of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>