<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2302_nm.9722" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9722" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9722" rank="species">Photobacterium aplysiae</organism><reference id="rid.2302"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium aplysiae sp. nov., a lipolytic marine bacterium isolated from eggs of the sea hare Aplysia kurodai</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2293</fpage><lpage>2296</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63765-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Photobacterium aplysiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Photobacterium aplysiae</em> (ap.ly′si.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>aplysiae</em> of <em>Aplysia</em>, a zoological genus, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a sea hare, genus <em>Aplysia</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·5–0·8 μm in width and 1·0–4·0 μm in length, motile by means of a polar flagellum and Gram-negative.</s><s>Cream-coloured, opaque, smooth, circular, convex colonies with entire margins are formed after 2 days on MA at 25 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Susceptible to vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 31 °C, with an optimum at 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 4–9, with an optimum at pH 8.</s><s>Obligate requirement for NaCl for growth; growth occurs at concentrations of 1–5 % (w/v) and is optimal at 3 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase/lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities and hydrolysis of gelatin are positive.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite occurs and acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized: dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, dl-lactic acid, l-alanine, methyl pyruvate, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, l-alanyl glycine, glutamic acid, inosine, uridine, glycerol and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80, d-galactose, d-psicose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid and asparagine are utilized weakly.</s><s>The major fatty acids are palmitoleic acid (C16 : 1), palmitic acid (C16 : 0) and oleic acid (C18 : 1).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GMD509<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12383<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12948<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the eggs of a sea hare (<em>Aplysia kurodai</em>) collected in August 2003 at Mogiyeo (depth, 12 m), an uninhabited small island in the South Sea of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>