<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4781_nm.3071" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3071" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3071" rank="species">Aeromonas trota</organism><reference id="rid.4781"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carnahan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakraborty</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janda</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas trota sp. nov., an ampicillin-susceptible species isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1206</fpage><lpage>1210</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1864939</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Designation of <i>Aeromonas trota</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas trota</i> (The species name (pronounced trō'ta) is derived both from the Greek adjective "trotos," meaning "vulnerable," and the modern (neo) Latin feminine adjective "trota," meaning "vulnerable." This designation is predicated upon the susceptibility of the organisms to ampicillin and carbenicillin, which first led us to suspect that the organisms were a separate group of aeromonads.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose the name <i>Aeromonas trota</i> for the 13 strains listed in Table 1 (21).</s><s>The type strain of the species is designated ATCC 49657<sup>T</sup> (formerly AH2), and a complete description of all of the strains is provided in Table 2.</s><s>The unique profile of <i>A. trota</i> includes negative reactions for esculin hydrolysis arabinose fermentation, Voges-Proskauer test, and gluconate oxidation.</s><s>Further, <i>A. trota</i> is positive for cellobiose fermentation, lysine decarboxylation, and citrate utilization but is susceptible to both ampicillin and carbenicillin.</s><s>A comparison of this profile with those of other mesophilic <i>Aeromonas</i> species is given in Table 4 (6, 7, 13-15, 17, 23, 26).</s><s>Negative sucrose fermentation, positive mannitol fermentation, gas production from glucose, production of H<sub>2</sub>S from modified GCF media, and hemolysis on tryptic soy agar with 5% sheep blood could also be used as presumptive markers but showed slight variability within the group and were not as definitive as the profile markers described above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>API 20E profile numbers for these strains identified them all as "<i>A. hydrophila</i> complex," with an identification level of "good" to "excellent," but with the comment that the negative reaction for mannitol and/or sucrose was considered atypical in their data base.</s><s>Likewise, these strains were all identified as <i>A. hydrophila</i> in the Vitek system with a Gram Negative Identification (GNI) Card at 99% accuracy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We have reported on the isolation and identification of a new <i>Aeromonas</i> species, designated <i>A. trota</i>.</s><s>This species has a biochemical profile of negative reactions for esculin hydrolysis, arabinose fermentation, Voges-Proskauer test, and gluconate oxidation, positive reactions for cellobiose fermentation, citrate utilization, and lysine decarboxylation, and a uniform dual susceptibility to ampicillin and carbenicillin.</s><s>Rapid identification systems, such as API 20E, and automated identification systems, such as the Vitek system, will identify these isolates as either <i>A. hydrophila</i> complex or <i>A. hydrophila</i>.</s><s>However, some of the distinguishing biochemical markers mentioned above are incorporated within these two systems and should lead the clinical microbiologist to suspect the possibility of <i>A. trota</i>.</s><s>Although <i>A. trota</i> appears to be predominantly from southern and southeastern Asia, it may in fact be present worldwide.</s><s>Documentation of its possible clinical significance and virulence potential for humans, presented here, strongly suggests that this species should be considered in biotyping of aeromonads from clinical and environmental sources.</s></p></content></protolog>