<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5854_nm.6674" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6674" rank="genus">Pseudonocardia</organism><reference id="rid.5854"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>G.Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal to combine the genera Actinobispora and Pseudonocardia in an emended genus Pseudonocardia, and description of Pseudonocardia zijingensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>977</fpage><lpage>982</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01977-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054266</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Pseudonocardia</i> (Henssen 1957)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The vegetative mycelium varies in thickness (0.3-2.0 μm) and in the degree of branching. Some strains form swollen hyphal segments. Aerial mycelium may or may not be present. The mycelium may or may not be fragmented; if fragmented, both types of mycelium exhibit cell division in different directions. In some species, the mycelium is covered by an electrondense outer layer. Spore sizes vary; the spores are normally smooth and form chains by acropetal budding or septation from the substrate or aerial mycelium, or else are formed in longitudinal pairs on vegetative hyphae and in longitudinal pairs or singly on aerial hyphae. Non-motile. Biochemically versatile. Some species are facultative autotrophs and some strains can oxidize hydrocarbons. Some species can oxidize methyl sulfides to sulfate. <i>P. thermophila</i> can degrade cellulose. The major menaquinone is MK- 8(H<sub>4</sub>). Iso-branched fatty acids are predominant. The main compound is iso-branched hexadecanoic acid. Phosphatidymethylethanolamine is present in most species. The occurrence of phosphatidylethanolmine, phosphatidylcholine and glucosamine-containing phospholipids is variable between the species. Cell wall type IV. Mycolates are absent. The G+C content of the DNA is 68-79 mol%. Members of this genus form a coherent group on the basis of 16S rRNA sequence data. The genus contains the species <i>Pseudonocardia alni</i>, <i>P. asaccharolytica</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia autotrophica</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia compacta</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia halophobica</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia hydrocarbonoxydans</i>, <i>P. petroleophila</i>, <i>P. saturnae</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia spinosa</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia sulfidoxydans</i>, <i>P. thermophila</i> and <i>Pseudonocardia zijingensis</i>. The type species is <i>P. thermophila</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>