<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1241_nm.1477" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1477" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1477" rank="species">Blastobacter natatorius</organism><reference id="rid.1241"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the genus Blastobacter Zavarzin 1961 and description of Blastobacter natatorius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>40</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Blastobacter natatorius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Blastobacter natatorius</i> (na. ta. to´ ri. us. M.L. masc. adj. <i>natatoriirs</i> of a swimming place [pool]. the source of the water from which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, nonsporing, non-encapsulated, and rod shaped or wedge shaped with straight or slightly curved axes.</s><s>Cells are usually 0.5 to 0.8 by 1 to 3 μm in size.</s><s>Older cells may become elongated and reach lengths of 10 μm or more.</s><s>Some cells have a swollen or bloated appearance.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and readily form rosettes.</s><s>Each cell has a simple mucilaginous holdfast at its nonreproductive pole, by which it attaches to other cells or solid surfaces to form rosettes.</s><s>No stalks, prosthecae, or other specialized holdfast structures are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reproduction occurs by asymmetric division (budding) of the mother cell to produce a shorter daughter cell or bud at the free pole of the mother cell.</s><s>Buds are spherical or ovoid and are usually 0.5 to 0.8 by 0.5 to 1 μm in size.</s><s>The free bud cells are motile, and each has a single polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown on peptone-yeast extract agar for 3 days at 28°C are yellow and round and have entire edges, diameters of 0.5 to 1.0 mm, and high convex elevations.</s><s>The colony surface is shiny, and the growth is easily emulsified.</s><s>After further incubation the colonies have a rubbery consistency and may be removed intact from the agar surface by touching with a wire loop.</s><s>Colonies on Staley PYG medium after 4 days at 28°C are pale pink and 0.5 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is strictly aerobic and obligately chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Growth occurs on PYG medium, peptone-yeast extract agar, 0.1% peptone medium, and glucose-ammonium sulfate agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs in citrate-, phenol-, alkylamine-, or methanol-mineral salts medium, in nitrogen-free medium supplemented with glucose, sucrose, or mannitol as a carbon and energy source, or under autotrophic conditions with ammonium sulfate, sodium nitrite, sodium thiosulfate, ferrous sulfate, or hydrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, oxidase, phosphatase, and deoxyribonuclease are produced.</s><s>Gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed. but cellulose, chitin, alginate, starch, tributyrin, casein, and dextran are not.</s><s>There is no hemolysis of erythrocytes, and urease, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>An alkaline reaction occurs in Hugh-Leifson medium.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from fructose, glucose, glycerol, maltose, mannose, melezitose, and sucrose in the medium of Smith et al. (14) modified to contain Andrades indicator.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of the type strain is 65 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain UQM 2507, which was isolated from a freshwater swimming pool.</s></p></content></protolog>