<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9493_nm.14642" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14642" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14642" rank="species">Beijerinckia doebereinerae</organism><reference id="rid.9493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Oggerin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rubio</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marín</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of Beijerinckia fluminensis strains CIP 106281T and UQM 1685T as Rhizobium radiobacter strains, and proposal of Beijerinckia doebereinerae sp. nov. to accommodate Beijerinckia fluminensis LMG 2819</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2323</fpage><lpage>2328</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006593-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620377</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Beijerinckia doebereinerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Beijerinckia doebereinerae</em> (doe.be.rei′ne.rae. N.L. fem. n. <em>doebereinerae</em> to honour the Brazilian microbiologist Johanna Doebereiner, in recognition of her contribution to the study of nitrogen-fixing bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, regular, non-motile and slightly curved rods, about 3.25×1 μm, that do not form spores or zoogleas.</s><s>A large number of fimbriae are present around the cell, but no flagella are observed.</s><s>Two or more polar lipoid bodies of PHB are present per cell.</s><s>Colonies on nitrogen-free mineral agar are irregular, convex, cream in colour, opaque and highly viscous.</s><s>After 5 days of growth in nitrogen-free mineral broth, the medium becomes opaque, creamy and highly viscous.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Molecular nitrogen is fixed under aerobic conditions and requires molybdenum.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–35 °C; no growth at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 3–10.</s><s>Optimal growth at 30 °C and pH 6.5.</s><s>No growth on peptone media.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase and catalase tests are positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Positive for reduction of nitrate to nitrite (API 20NE).</s><s>The remaining tests of the API 20NE kit are negative: indole production, acids from glucose, hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin, arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caproate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are recorded as positive (API ZYM): alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>The remaining activities in the API ZYM system are negative: <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates (API 50 CH): l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, maltose, sucrose, turanose, d-lyxose and d-fucose.</s><s>Does not utilize glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Fatty acids detected are, in decreasing order of abundance, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-15 : 0 2-OH) and 16 : 0.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 2819<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7311<sup>T</sup>), which was deposited by F.</s><s>Hilger at the LMG before 1966 according to the online catalogue (http://bccm.belspo.be/).</s></p></content></protolog>