<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7489_nm.5926" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5926" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5926" rank="species">Brevibacterium avium</organism><reference id="rid.7489"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium avium sp. nov., isolated from poultry.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1527</fpage><lpage>1530</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1527</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555333</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brevibacterium avium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brevibacterium avium</i> (a'vi.um. L. n. <i>avis</i> a bird; L. gen. pl. n. <i>avium</i> of birds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on the results of the present study and the findings of Mohan (1981).</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-acid-fast, non-sporeforming rods which exhibit a coryneform morphology.</s><s>Branching is not observed.</s><s>Colonies are convex, with entire margin, round, smooth, greyish-white in colour and of butyrous consistency.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 22,30 and 37°C but is optimal at 37°C.</s><s>The organism is catalase- and oxidase-positive and has a respiratory mode of metabolism.</s><s>Tyrosine is decomposed and extracellular DNase is produced.</s><s>Casein, gelatin and xanthine are hydrolysed but aesculin, starch and urea are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>No acid is produced from glucose, maltose, mannitol, sucrose or xylose.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-arabitol, galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-fructose, D-mannose and mannitol are utilized but adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, Larabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, Dfucose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, methyl α-D-glucoside, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, D-lyxose, maltose, methyl α-D-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, D-tagatose, trehalose, D-turanose, xylitol, D-xylose, L-xylose and methyl β-xyloside are not.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C<sub>4</sub>, ester lipase C<sub>8</sub>, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and phosphoamidase are detected but lipase C<sub>14</sub>, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, pgalactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase activities are not.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Galactose is present in the cell wall but not arabinose.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>Isolated from bumble-foot-like manifestations of poultry, though their pathogenic role is unclear.</s><s>Isolates have been found to be non-pathogenic for experimentally injected animals and are thought to be secondary invaders (Mohan, 1981).</s><s>The type strain is NCIMB 703055<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>