<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9273_nm.14555" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14555" rank="species">Shewanella marina</organism><reference id="rid.9273"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella marina sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1888</fpage><lpage>1894</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005470-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567571</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella marina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella marina</em> (ma.ri′na. L. fem. adj. <em>marina</em> marine, of the sea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, Gram-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Cells grow best on media such as MA and R2A.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, convex with entire margins, smooth, opaque, pale brown in colour and approximately 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after 5 days at 30 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Cells are motile rods, 0.4–0.5×1.4–2.0 μm in size.</s><s>Growth occurs in 2–9 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 3 %), at pH 5–10 (optimum, pH 7) and at 4–37 °C (optimum, 30 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Casein, DNA and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but carboxymethylcellulose, egg yolk, aesculin, starch, tyrosine and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery: alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin are positive; esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase and valine arylamidase are weakly positive; and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14) and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are negative.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (positive with the Biolog GN2 system): dl-lactic acid, l-arabinose (weak), d-glucose (weak), l-rhamnose (weak), citric acid (weak), malonic acid (weak), propionic acid (weak), l-alanine (weak), l-alanyl glycine (weak) and <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid (weak).</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized (Supplementary Table S1, available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated) amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), gentamicin (10), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30) and polymyxin B (300 IU), but resistant to penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>; the complete fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, C4<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22185<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15074<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater collected from the South Sea, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>