<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3859_nm.8757" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8757" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8757" rank="species">Paenibacillus cineris</organism><reference id="rid.3859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhelst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus cineris sp. nov. and Paenibacillus cookii sp. nov., from Antarctic volcanic soils and a gelatin-processing plant</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1071</fpage><lpage>1076</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02967-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus cineris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus cineris</em> (ci′ne.ris. L. gen. masc. n. <em>cineris</em> of/from ash, referring to the volcanic, ash-based soil from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, round-ended rods (0·7–0·9×2·5–4·0 μm) occurring singly and in pairs.</s><s>Gram-negative or Gram-variable.</s><s>Endospores are formed within 2–3 days incubation on BFA at 30 °C; they are ellipsoidal, lie paracentrally and subterminally and swell the sporangia (Fig. 1, top).</s><s>After 2 days at 30 °C, colonies are 1–5 mm in diameter, low convex and circular with slightly irregular edges; they are opaque and glossy and light beige to greyish in colour with paler margins.</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Minimum temperature for growth lies between 8 and 15 °C and the maximum growth temperature is 50 °C.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 5·0 and 6·5, the optimum pH for growth is 7·0 and the maximum pH for growth varies between strains and lies between 7·5 and 11·0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3 % NaCl, but is inhibited by 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein is weakly positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, reactions for ONPG hydrolysis and nitrate reduction are positive.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is variable and positive reactions are weak.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolysed and reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and indole production are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced without gas from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, methyl d-mannoside (weak), methyl xyloside, d-raffinose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Production of acid is variable for d-arabinose (positives are weak), glycogen, inulin, d-mannose and sorbitol (positives are weak).</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, glycerol, gluconate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Strains are resistant to disks of the antibiotics kanamycin (30 μg) and streptomycin (25 μg) and moderately resistant to tetracycline (100 μg); sensitive to ampicillin (25 μg), chloramphenicol (50 μg), colistin sulphate (100 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg) and nitrofurantoin (50 μg).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 46, 18, 10 and 9 % of total fatty acids).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller, decreasing amounts (between about 6 and 1 %): iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>. (Supplementary Table in IJSEM Online).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 51·5 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG 18439<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108109<sup>T</sup>=Logan collection no. B1768<sup>T</sup>=isolate SSI068); the 16S rDNA sequence of this strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJ575658.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain grows in the temperature range 15–50 °C and in the pH range 5·0–10·5; it is negative for the Voges–Proskauer reaction, production of acid is weak for d-arabinose, inulin and sorbitol and negative for glycogen and d-mannose.</s><s>Reference strains are LMG 21976, R-11672 and R-11674.</s><s>Strains were isolated from the ashy soil of a cold, dead fumarole at the foot of Lucifer Hill, a volcano on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>