<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.755_nm.1775" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1775" rank="species">Comamonas terrigena</organism><reference id="rid.755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comamonas Davis and Park 1962 gen. nov., nom. rev. emend., and Comamonas terrigena Hugh 1962 sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>443</fpage><lpage>453</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-443</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Comamonas terrigena</i> nom. rev., sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Comamonas terrigena</i> (ter.ri.ge'na. L.n. <i>terra</i> soil; L.v. <i>gignere</i> to bear; L.n. <i>terrigena</i> borne by the earth [soil], child of the earth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Comamonas terrigena</i> is the same as that for the genus.</s><s>Growth factors are required (35, 62).</s><s>The following biochemical, physiological, and nutritional characteristics are present in the four strains of the species: growth at 37°C; motility; growth in the presence of 1.5% NaCl or 5 mg of gentian violet per liter; oxidase; catalase; nitrate reduction; esterase (C4); leucine arylamidase; phosphoamidase; growth on D-gluconate, acetate, butyrate, <i>n</i>-caproate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, propionate, <i>n</i>-valerate, adipate, azelate, fumarate (weak), glutarate, pimelate, sebacate, suberate, succinate, DL-glycerate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, DL-lactate, D-malate (weak), aconitate, citraconate, α-ketoglutarate (weak), levulinate, mesaconate (weak), pyruvate, D-α-alanine, L-α-alanine, β-alanine (weak), Laspartate, L-glutamate, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, L-norleucine, DL-norvaline, L-proline , L-valine, and L-threonine (weak).</s><s>The following characteristics are absent in the four strains: growth at 42°C; growth in the presence of 4.5% NaCl; anaerobic growth; formation of pigment; acid production in oxidative-fermentative, 10% lactose, and triple sugar irion media; fluorescence; growth on cetrimide; hydrolysis of Tween 80, gelatin, acetamide, and DNA; amylase; lysine or ornithine decarboxylase; arginine dihydrolase; nitrite reduction; urease; hydrolysis of esculin; indole production; production of H<sub>2</sub>S in triple sugar iron medium; lipase (C<sub>14</sub>); cystine or valine arylamidase; trypsin; chymotrypsin; α-D-galactosidase; β-D-galactosidase; β-D-glucuronidase; α-D-glucosidase; β-D-glucosidase; N-acetyl-β-D-gluco saminidase; α-D-mannosidase; α-L-fucosidase; growth on N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, esculin, D-fructose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, glycogen, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl-α-D-glucoside, methyl-α-D-mannoside, methyl-β-D-xyloside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, D-tagatose, trehalose, D-turanose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, sorbitol, <i>meso</i>-xylitol, caprylate, pelargonate, maleate, malonate, oxalate, glycolate, D-tartrate , L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, citrate, benzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phenylacetate, phthalate, isophthalate, terephthalate, L-arginine, Lcitrulline, L-cysteine, glycine, L-histidine, DL-kynurenine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, Lserine, trigonelline, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, acetamide, 2-aminobenzoate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, DL-2-aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, amylamine, benzylamine, betaine, butylamine, creatine, diaminobutane, ethanolamine, ethylamine, histamine, sarcosine, spermine, tryptamine, and urea.</s><s>The following characteristics are present in only some strains (the strains giving positive reactions are indicated in parentheses): resistance to penicillin (10 μg/disk) (strain CCUG 12940); production of acid phosphatase (strains NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup> and NCIB 2582); and growth on glycerol (strain NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup>), caprate (strain CCUG 12940), L-malate (strain CCUG 12940), heptanoate (strains NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup> and CCUG 12940), itaconate (strains NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup> and CCUG 12940), and L-tyrosine (strains NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup> and CCUG 12940).</s><s>The following API 20NE profiles were obtained: 1000424 for strains NCIB 8193<sup>T</sup>, NCIB 2581, and NCIB 2582 (profile not listed in the API 20NE Analytical Profile Index [3]); and 1000474 for strain CCUG 12940 (<i>P. testosteroni</i>-<i>Pseudomonas alcaligenes</i> according to the Analytical Profile Index).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of <i>C. terrigena</i> are in agreement with those reported by Hugh (33, 34) for strain ATCC 8461<sup>T</sup>, except for the urease reaction, which was negative in our experiments.</s><s>The flagellar morphology of strain ATCC 8461<sup>T</sup> has been described previously (33, 40).</s><s>A peritrichous variant (strain ATCC 17758; not included in this study) of strain ATCC 8461<sup>T</sup> has been described (40).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. terrigena</i> has been isolated from soil and human blood (other habitats are not excluded).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of <i>C. terrigena</i> DNA is 64 to 66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCIB 8193 (=LMG 1253 [=CCUG 153271=ATCC 8451=NCTC 1937=CIP 63.44=CCUG 2185 [=LMG 59291=Veron 31=Hugh 247).</s><s>This strain was isolated in 1921 from a filtrate of hay infusion (47).</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are the same as those given above fQr the species.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64 mol% (our data).</s><s>Similar values have been reported previously (64.6 mol% [53] and 65 mol% [12]).</s></p></content></protolog>