<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9507_nm.13186" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13186" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13186" rank="subspecies">Vibrio alginolyticus iophagus</organism><reference id="rid.9507"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Emod</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soubigou</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>N.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Keil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of "Achrornobacter iophagus" Strain 1.029 to Vibrio alginolyticus Chemovar iophagus</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>451</fpage><lpage>459</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio alginolyticus iophagus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>We propose that strain 1.029, which was originally designated <i>A. iophagus</i>, be included within the species <i>V. alginolyticus</i>, but that this organism be distinguished from other strains of this species by the designation <i>Vibrio alginolyticus</i> chemovar <i>iophagus</i>, with the corresponding collagenase designated “iophagus collagenase” (EC 3.4.24.8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacteriology of <i>V. alginolyticus</i> strains.</s><s>Both strain CIP 82.01 and strain 1.029 are aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, gram-negative, rod- shaped bacteria (length, 2 to 2.5 μm; width, 1 to 1.5 μm) that are motile by means of a simple polar flagellum.</s><s>They form round, yellow colonies that are 2 to 3 mm in diameter after overnight incubation at 30°C on thiosulfate-citrate- bile-sucrose medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both strains produce positive responses in the following assays: cytochrome oxidase; Voges-Proskauer reaction; indole production; lysine decarboxylase; gelatinase (film assay); Tween 80 esterase; tetrathionate reductase; nitrate reduction; acid production from glucose, maltose, mannitol, sucrose, trehalose, mannose, and glycerol; and citrate (Simmons) utilization.</s><s>As determined by the disk assay, they are both susceptible to aminoglycosidic antibiotics, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, colistin, rifampin, sulfonamides, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, and vibriostatic agent O/129 (2,4-diamino-6,7- diisopropylpteridine phosphate).</s><s>Both strains are resistant to trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both strains give negative responses in the following assays: methyl red reaction; arginine dihydrolase; urease; phenylalanine deaminase; o-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside assay; H<sub>2</sub>S production (Kligler iron agar); glucose gas production; and acid production from xylose, arabinose, adonitol, rhamnose, sorbose, sorbitol, dulcitol, lactose, inositol, salicin, raffinose, mellibiose, α-methylglucoside, and mucate.</s><s>Neither strain utilizes malonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 1.029 is markedly more halophilic than strain CIP 82.01, with optimum growth occurring in 13% NaCl and apparent tolerance to 15% NaCl.</s><s>Strain 1.029 is also fully resistant to ampicillin and carbenicillin and partially resistant to cephalothin, antibiotics to which strain CIP 82.01 is susceptible.</s><s>We also observed differences in the results of ornithine decarboxylase and cellobiose fermentation assays (negative for strain CIP 82.01, but positive for strain 1.029).</s></p></content></protolog>