<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2496_nm.11429" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11429" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11429" rank="species">Dethiosulfatibacter aminovorans</organism><reference id="rid.2496"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takii</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamaki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sekiguchi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ibe</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dethiosulfatibacter aminovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel thiosulfate-reducing bacterium isolated from coastal marine sediment via sulfate-reducing enrichment with Casamino acids</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2320</fpage><lpage>2326</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64882-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911304</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dethiosulfatibacter aminovorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dethiosulfatibacter aminovorans</em> (a.mi.no.vo′rans. N.L. neut. n. <em>aminum</em> amine; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>aminovorans</em> devouring amino acids).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells with Gram-positive cell wall but stain Gram-negatively.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, rod-shaped (0.6–0.8 μm×2.2–4.8 μm), occur singly or in pairs and sometimes in short chains with no spore formation.</s><s>Exhibits anaerobic growth by thiosulfate or sulfur reduction or fermentation.</s><s>Lactate, pyruvate, serine, cysteine, threonine, glutamate, histidine, lysine, arginine, Casamino acids, peptone and yeast extract are fermented.</s><s>Fumarate, alanine, proline, phenylalanine, tryptophan, glutamine and aspartate are utilized only in the presence of thiosulfate.</s><s>Acetate, propionate and other short chain fatty acids are produced as the result of fermentation or incomplete oxidation.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, butyrate, malate, succinate, ethanol, glycine, valine, leucine, isoleucine, methionine, tyrosine, asparagine, gelatin and sugars (glucose, mannose, maltose and sucrose) are not utilized.</s><s>Vitamins are required for the growth on glutamate and thiosulfate.</s><s>Yeast extract greatly stimulates growth.</s><s>Mesophilic, neutrophilic organism isolated from a marine environment.</s><s>Optimum growth takes place at a pH of around 7.8, temperature of 28–30 °C and salt concentration of 20–30 g l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Desulfoviridin and catalase are absent.</s><s>Indole production is positive.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA is 41.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, C/G2<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13356<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 101112<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17477<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an enrichment culture with Casamino acids that was inoculated with anoxic sediment from a highly eutrophic area of Tokyo Bay, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>