<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1409_nm.3894" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3894" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3894" rank="species">Clostridium argentinense</organism><reference id="rid.1409"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suen</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatheway</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium argentinense sp. nov.: a genetically homogenous group composed of all strains of Clostridium botulinum toxin type G and some nontoxigenic strains previously identified as Clostridium subterminale or Clostridium hastiforme.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>375</fpage><lpage>381</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-375</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium argentinense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium argentinense</i> (ar.gen.tin.en´se. N. L. neut. adj. <i>argentinense</i>, coming from Argentina)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Clostridium argentinense</i> is a motile, peritrichous, anaerobic, gram-positive rod, with or without spores (9).</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 1.6 to 9.4 μm long and 0.5 to 2.0 μm wide (5).</s><s>Small,.smooth colonies and large, rough, fried-egg colonies are often formed on blood agar anaerobically at 37°C after 48 h (5).</s><s>On rabbit blood the colonies are β-hemolytic, while on sheep blood hemolysis is weak or absent.</s><s>The organism is proteolytic (as determined by milk digestion) and gelatinolytic and produces acetic, isobutyric, butyric, isovaleric, and phenylacetic acids in peptone-yeast extract-glucose medium.</s><s>It does not ferment sugars and is negative in tests for hydrdlysis of starch and esculin and for production of catalase, urease, lipase, deoxyribonuclease, and indole.</s><s>Strains may or may not produce a neuroparalytic toxin that can cause botulism when it is administered to laboratory animals; the toxin is neutralized with type G botulinal antitoxin. <i>C. argentinense</i> is distinguished from <i>C. subterminale</i>, <i>C. hastiforme</i>, and other asaccharolytic, proteolytic clostridia by production of a derivative of indole that is detectable with a <i>p</i>-dimethylaminocinamaldehyde reagent.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 28 to 30 mol%.</s><s>This species has been isolated from soil, amniotic fluid, autopsy specimens, blood, and wounds in Argentina, Switzerland, and the United States.</s><s>No documented association with botulism exists.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 27322, which was isolated from soil in Argentina (9); it has a guanine-plus-cytosine content of 29 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>