<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2634_nm.12161" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12161" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7988" rank="species">Bacteroides tectum</organism><reference id="rid.2634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Calverley</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides tectum sp. nov. and characteristics of other non pigmented Bacteroides isolates from soft-tissue infections from cats and dogs.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>123</fpage><lpage>128</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-123</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides tectum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides tectum</i> (tec'tum. L. adj. from <i>tego</i> to cover, to conceal, referring to difficulty in species identification)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile, gram-negative rods.</s><s>In cooked meat-carbohydrate broth and on sheep blood agar plates, the cells are 0.6 to 0.8 by 1.2 to 5.0 μm and are arranged singly, in pairs, and in short chains.</s><s>On sheep blood agar plates, surface colonies after 48 h are 2 to 3 mm in diameter, circular, entire, dome shaped, grayish, and opaque.</s><s>No pigment is detected after 14 days on sheep blood agar or laked blood agar, and ultraviolet fluorescence (at 365 nm) is not detected at any time up to 14 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation at 37°C for 24 h in prereduced broth media, cultures show uniform turbidity with a small deposit.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days, the pH values in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate generally range as follows: 5.5 to 5.7 in all strains which weakly ferment carbohydrates and 6.5 to 6.8 in media containing sugars that are not fermented by all strains (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grow well in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth containing 20% bile.</s><s>Strains in homology groups I and II weakly ferment glucose, glycogen, and starch, although strains in homology group 111 do not.</s><s>Homology group II organisms ferment salicin on all occasions.</s><s>None of the strains ferments arabinose, esculin, mannitol, rhamnose , ribose, or trehalose.</s><s>All strains liquefy gelatin within 14 days, but none digests meat, reduce nitrates, or produces indole or catalase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The acids produced in cooked meat-glucose broth cultures are acetic, propionic, and succinic acids (average concentrations, 17.5, 7, and 8 μmol/ml of culture, respectively).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small amounts of isobutyric, isovaleric, and phenylacetic acids are also detected (average concentrations, 1.3,4, and 2 μmol/ml, respectively).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin (2 U/ml), amoxicillin (2.5 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), doxycycline (6 μg/ml), carbenicillin (100 μg/ml), and chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 48 mol%, and the G+C contents of the other strains range from 47 to 48 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 11853 (= 160), which was isolated from a subcutaneous fight wound abscess from a cat.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species have been isolated from subcutaneous fight wound abscesses from cats and dogs, from pyothoraxes of cats, and from mouths of normal cats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following phenotypic characteristics are helpful in differentiating <i>B. tecrum</i> from other species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains of <i>B. tecrum</i> grow well in 20% bile; this differentiates them from <i>Bacteroides capillosis</i> (Table 4), which ferments a similar range of sugars and also hydrolyzes esculin. <i>Bacteroides disiens</i>, <i>Bacteroides amylophilus</i>, and <i>Bacteroides corporis</i> can also be differentiated phenotypically from <i>B. tecrum</i> (Table 4).</s><s>In addition, <i>B. corporis</i> produces dark brown colonies after 4 to 7 days.</s></p></content></protolog>