<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.289_nm.5453" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5453" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5453" rank="species">Pediococcus dextrinicus</organism><reference id="rid.289"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Haack</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Breznak</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cytophaga xylanolytica sp. nov., a xylan-degrading, anaerobic gliding bacterium</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>159</volume><fpage>6</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cytophaga xylanolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cytophaga xylanolytica</i> (xy.lan.o.ly'ti.ca. <i>xylan</i> xylan, a xylose-containing heteropolysaccharide in plant cell walls; Gr. v. <i>lyein</i> to loosen, dissolve; M.L. fem. adj. <i>lytica</i>; M.L. fem. adj. <i>xylanolytica</i> xylan-dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slender, flexible, gram-negative rods with slightly tapering ends, 0.4 x 3-24 μm.</s><s>Move by gliding motility.</s><s>No endospores, cysts, or fruiting bodies formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells orange (subsurface colonies in xylan agar medium) or orange to salmon (surface swarms on xylan agar) due to the presence of carotenoid pigment(s).</s><s>Flexirubins absent.</s><s>Subsurface colony morphology (lenticular or spherical) and size (2 mm or spreading up to 1 cm) in xylan agar both depend on agar concentration, the latter characteristics being prevalent in media solidified with &#x003C; 1% agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Best growth occurs in Na<sub>2</sub>S-reduced, HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub>-buffered, anoxic mineral media with mono-, di-, or polysaccharides as fermentable energy sources.</s><s>Vitamins not required (strain XM3).</s><s>Sulfide used as sole S source.</s><s>Poor and inconsistent growth with sulfate, cysteine, or glutathione as sole S source.</s><s>Methionine and thiosulfate not used as S sources.</s><s>NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup> (but not NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> or N<sub>2</sub>), glutamine (but not glutamate), and peptone used as sole N sources.</s><s>HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub> required or greatly stimulatory for growth.</s><s>All strains fermented xylan, laminarin, lichenin, cellobiose, lactose, glucose, galactose, mannose, xylose, and arabinose as energy sources for growth.</s><s>Individual strains fermented starch, pectin, inulin, pullulan, maltose, sucrose, fructose, glucuronic acid, and galacturonic acid.</s><s>None fermented cellulose, carboxymethylcellulose, arabinogalactan, mannan, chitin, N-acetylglucosamine, sorbose, ribose or rhamnose.</s><s>Growth occurs within a pH range of 6.1-8.7 (optimum 7.2-8.2), a temperature range of 19-37°C (optimum 30-32°C) and in media containing up to 3% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aeroduric anaerobe; metabolism fermentative.</s><s>Weakly catalase positive (may be negative when first isolated); oxidase negative.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, and succinate are major products of xylan, xylose, and glucose fermentation.</s><s>Small amounts of CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> also detected in detailed analyses of fermentations by strain XM3.</s><s>NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> and SO<sub>4</sub><sup>-2</sup> not used as terminal electron acceptors during anaerobic growth.</s><s>No growth under conventional aerobic conditions, with or without CO<sub>2</sub> enrichment of the atmosphere.</s><s>O<sub>2</sub> not used as terminal electron acceptor (only strain XM3 tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular fatty acids dominated by C<sub>15:0</sub> isomers, with <i>anteiso</i>&#x003E;<i>n</i>&#x003E;<i>iso</i> forms.</s><s>Hydroxy fatty acids include 3-OH-C<sub>15:0</sub> and 3-OH-C<sub>17:0</sub> types.</s><s>Preliminary analyses suggest the presence in cells of a sulfonolipid(s) of a type slightly less polar than N-acylcapnine (strain XM3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Partial nucleotide sequencing of the 16S rRNA of the type strain places it in the <i>Bacteroides - Flavobaeterium</i> subgroup of the eubacteria.</s><s>The mol% G + C in the DNA of the type strain is 45.5 (Bd).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Freshwater sediments and swine waste lagoon sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Strain XM3; deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig (DSM No. 6779).</s></p></content></protolog>