<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4219_nm.3944" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3944" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3944" rank="species">Clostridium hathewayi</organism><reference id="rid.4219"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steer</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium hathewayi sp. nov., from human faeces.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>357</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11822669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium hathewayi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium hathewayi</i> (ha.the.way.i N. L. gen. n. <i>hathewayi</i> of Hatheway, to honour the late American microbiologist Charles L Hatheway in recognition of his outstanding contributions to the <i>Clostidium botulinum</i> group of organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and consist of gram-type positive, endosporing rods.</s><s>Cells are 0.7–1.0 μm x 2.0–5.0 μm with pointed ends and occur in chains of up to 30 cells.</s><s>Spores were slightly oval to almost round, and sub-terminally located; sporulating cells were a little swollen.</s><s>Some cells form slime capsules.</s><s>May or may not be motile.</s><s>On Columbia sheep blood agar colonies are 2 to 3mm in diam. after 3 days, nonhemolytic, greyish-white, opaque, convex, round with a slightly irregular margin and shiny.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15 °C to 45 °C, with an optimum around 37 °C; pH range for growth is 5.0 to 8.5, with an optimum of around 7.0.</s><s>The doubling time under optimum conditions in PY medium was 50 mins.</s><s>Gowth occurs in 0 to 2.5% NaCl.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Saccharolytic; acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> are the end products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycogen, inositol, inulin or mannitol.</s><s>Esculin and starch are hydrolysed but cellulose, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Lecithinase and lipase negative.</s><s>Indol is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50.7 to 50.9 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from chemostat enrichment for phytic acid degrading bacteria.</s><s>Source: human faeces.</s><s>The type strain 1313<sup>T</sup> of <i>Clostridium hathewayi</i> has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 13479<sup>T</sup> (= CCUG 43506<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Clostridium hathewayi</i> is phylogenetically a member of the <i>Clostridium coccoides</i> group of organisms and displays a close phylogenetic affinity with <i>Clostridium sphenoides</i> and related species.</s><s>Tests which serve to distinguish <i>Clostridium hathewayi</i> from its close phylogenetic relatives are shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>