<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8699_nm.13270" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13270" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13270" rank="species">Chryseobacterium aquaticum</organism><reference id="rid.8699"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium aquaticum sp. nov., isolated from a water reservoir.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>533</fpage><lpage>537</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65491-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319450</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium aquaticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium aquaticum</em> (a.qua′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>aquaticum</em> living, growing or found in or by water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, 0.4–0.5 μm in diameter and 0.8–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–37 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and at pH 6–8 (optimum, pH 6–7).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1, 2 and 3 % NaCl, but not with 5 %.</s><s>No growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, translucent and shiny with entire edges, becoming mucoid after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Non-diffusible, non-fluorescent, bright-yellow, flexirubin-type pigments are produced on nutrient agar; these pigments turn reddish brown upon addition of 20 % KOH.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but urea is not.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl-red test is negative, but Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>In the API 50CH gallery, acid is produced from glucose, fructose, mannose (weakly), rhamnose (weakly), amygdalin (weakly), aesculin, cellobiose (weakly), maltose, melibiose (weakly), sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, galactose, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, lactose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in GN2 microplates: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, uridine, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, i-erythritol, l-fucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, d-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 8.5), 2-naphthyl butyrate, 2-naphthyl caprylate, l-leucyl 2-naphthylamide, l-valyl 2-naphthylamide, l-cystyl 2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-benzoyl-dl-arginine 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 5.4) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate are hydrolysed, but 2-naphthyl myristate, <em>N</em>-glutaryl-phenylalanine 2-naphthylamide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside and 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-l-fucopyranoside are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The only isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone MK-6.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise phosphatidylethanolamine and several unknown aminolipids.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 15 : 0 iso (37.9±0.1 %), 17 : 0 iso 3-OH (16.1±0.1 %) and summed feature 4 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 : 0 iso 2-OH, 13.1±0.2 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38.3–38.5 mol% (38.5 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 10-46<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12483<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7302<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water reservoir in Buyeo, Korea.</s><s>Strain 10-106, isolated from the same source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>