<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8223_nm.14173" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14173" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14173" rank="species">Lactobacillus kisonensis</organism><reference id="rid.8223"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujimoto</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tomii</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Makino</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kido</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus kisonensis sp. nov., Lactobacillus otakiensis sp. nov., Lactobacillus rapi sp. nov. and Lactobacillus sunkii sp. nov., heterofermentative species isolated from sunki, a traditional Japanese pickle.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>754</fpage><lpage>760</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004689-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329601</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus kisonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus kisonensis</em> (ki.so.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kisonensis</em> pertaining to Kiso, the name of the county located in the south-west area of Nagano in Japan, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.4–0.6×0.8–3 μm and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains comprising three or four cells.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>After anaerobic growth at 30 °C for 48 h, colonies on MRS agar are beige, with a smooth to rough surface, circular to slightly irregular and approximately 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>In MRS broth, growth occurs at 10 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 4.0 and pH 8.5.</s><s>Some strains grow at 30 °C in the presence of 5 % NaCl but none grow in the presence of 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Both l- (85 %) and d-lactate (15 %) are produced as the end products from glucose.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, maltose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate or 2- or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from turanose is strain dependent.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Dextran is not produced from sucrose.</s><s>Cells do not contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid in their cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis of the <em>recA</em> gene sequence places the species in the <em>L. buchneri</em> species group of lactobacilli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 11168<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0741<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15041<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19906<sup>T</sup>), and the reference strains YIT 11510 and YIT 11661 were isolated from non-salted pickle solution used in producing sunki products in Kiso county, Nagano prefecture, Japan, in 2004.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>