<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9667_nm.14802" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14802" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14802" rank="species">Xenorhabdus indica</organism><reference id="rid.9667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Somvanshi</surname><given-names>V. S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ganguly</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swiderski</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saxena</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A novel species of Xenorhabdus, family Enterobacteriaceae: Xenorhabdus indica sp. nov., symbiotically associated with entomopathogenic nematode Steinernema thermophilum Ganguly and Singh, 2000</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>519</fpage><lpage>525</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><em>Xenorhabdus indica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>indica</em>, in’. di.ca. L. fem. adj. indica, pertaining to India, the origin of the novel bacterial and nematode species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells Gram negative, oxidase and catalase negative, glucose-fermenting straight rods of 2.5–8.6×0.70–1.30 μm in size.</s><s>Aged rods show pronounced one to two inclusion bodies.</s><s>After 3 days on nutrient agar individual colonies are circular to irregular, 2.5–3 mm in diameter, with smooth to irregular edges, convex, raised, shiny and opaque with a brownish pigmented centre.</s><s>On NBTA the colonies are blue, while red on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Even after several transfers, no change of colony variants (phase II) was observed, which does not accumulate the respective dyes.</s><s>On Trypticase Soy Agar, aged colonies grew with the formation of concentric rings and characteristic brown colour.</s><s>In TSB the maximum growth temperature (<em>T</em><sub>max</sub>) is 41 °C, while it is 36 °C in NB.</s><s>Caused complete haemolysis on Columbia-blood agar plates.</s><s>Strains of the species were different from all the members of the genus in their ability to cause weak starch hydrolysis, being negative for Tween 60 and for adipic acid utilization, and as the only member of the genus strains utilize but do not acidify esculin, acidify but not utilize ribose and 5-ketogluconate on API panels.</s><s>Variable for utilization of trehalose.</s><s>On Biolog substrate panels, the strains were found negative for utilization of succinic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-asparagine and l-glutamic acid, where as all the other members of <em>Xenorhabdus</em> are reported positive for all these substrates.</s><s>The other biochemical tests for the strains are reported in <a href="#tbl1">Table 1</a> and <a href="#tbl2">Table 2</a>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the crushed infective juveniles (IJs) of <em>S. thermophilum</em> collected in soils of the Indian Agricultural Research Institute, New Delhi, India.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is strain 28<sup>T</sup> (DSM 17382<sup>T</sup>, CIP 108830<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>