<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9933_nm.14905" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14905" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14905" rank="species">Anaerosphaera aminiphila</organism><reference id="rid.9933"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaku</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerosphaera aminiphila gen. nov., sp. nov., a glutamate-degrading, Gram-positive anaerobic coccus isolated from a methanogenic reactor treating cattle waste</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3161</fpage><lpage>3167</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011858-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643871</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anaerosphaera aminiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anaerosphaera aminiphila</em> (a.mi.ni.phi′la. N.L. n. <em>aminum</em> amine; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>aminiphila</em> amino acid-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Spherical cells are 0.7–0.9 μm in diameter and often occur in pairs, but not in chains.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are negative.</s><s>Growth temperature range is 10–37 °C; optimum is 35–37 °C.</s><s>Growth pH range is 5.8–7.8; optimum pH is 6.7.</s><s>NaCl concentration range for growth is 0–4 % (w/v); optimum growth occurs with no addition of NaCl to PY medium.</s><s>Grows in PY medium without additional substrates and produces acetate, butyrate and a small amount of propionate.</s><s>Does not utilize carbohydrates or organic acids (arabinose, ribose, xylose, fructose, galactose, glucose, mannose, rhamnose, sorbose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, cellulose, CMC, inulin, dextrin, starch, xylan, pectin, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, fumarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, succinate or ethanol).</s><s>Utilizes l-glutamate, l-glutamine and l-histidine and produces abundant amounts of acetate and butyrate.</s><s>Also utilizes l-arginine as a growth substrate.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Does not utilize other amino acids such as l-threonine, l-aspartate, l-asparagine, l-serine, l-alanine, glycine, l-methionine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, l-valine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-tyrosine, l-proline and l-ornithine.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not starch or gelatin.</s><s>Produces hydrogen sulfide but not indole.</s><s>Does not have nitrate-reducing, lecithinase, lipase or urease activities.</s><s>Does not change milk and does not grow in chopped meat broth.</s><s>Sensitive to bile salts.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 DMA and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Monounsaturated components of fatty acids and DMAs constitute &#x003E;60 % of the total composition of CFAs.</s><s>Glutamic acid, glycine, alanine and aspartic acid are present in the cell wall in addition to lysine as the diagnostic diamino acid in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Does not possess respiratory quinones.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WN036<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15094<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21120<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rice-straw residue in a methanogenic reactor treating waste from cattle farms in Japan.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 32.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>