<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9706_nm.14856" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14856" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14856" rank="species">Halomonas zhanjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.9706"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Q.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas zhanjiangensis sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a sea urchin</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2888</fpage><lpage>2893</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010173-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628603</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas zhanjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas zhanjiangensis</em> (zhan.ji.ang.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>zhanjiangensis</em> pertaining to Zhanjiang, a city in China near where the sample was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slightly halophilic, strictly aerobic, non-sporulating, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, Gram-negative rods, approximately 0.7–1.4 μm wide and 1.5–2.5 μm long, occurring singly or as doublets and motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, but do not produce exopolysaccharide.</s><s>Colonies are yellow-pigmented, flat and non-translucent with glistening surfaces and circular/slightly irregular margins, 2–3 mm in diameter after incubation on MA at 28 °C for 3–5 days.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1–20 % (w/v) total salts (optimum, 3–5 %), at pH 6.0–10.5 (optimum, pH 7.5) and 4–40 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C).</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl or with NaCl as the sole salt.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and oxidation of glucose, but negative for nitrite reduction, fermentation of glucose, phenylalanine deaminase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Respiration on nitrate, nitrite and fumarate under anaerobic conditions is not observed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from l-cysteine.</s><s>Indole production and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Tween 60 is hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, cellulose, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20, 40 and 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, starch, d-xylose, adonitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole source of carbon and energy or sole source of carbon, nitrogen and energy: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, acetate, butyrate, citrate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline and l-serine; the following substances are not utilized: aesculin, cellobiose, dextrin, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-arabitol, ethanol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, benzoate, caprylate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, hippurate, malate, malonate, propionate, succinate, l-arginine, l-cysteine, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase; <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin are not observed (API ZYM).</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc): ampicillin (30), carbenicillin (30), gentamicin (10), nalidixic acid (20), polymixin B (30), rifampicin (5) and streptomycin (10), but not to chloramphenicol (30), kanamycin (30), lincomycin (2), nitrofurantoin (30), novobiocin (30), tetracycline (30) or tobramycin (10).</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Predominant respiratory quinone is Q-9.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.8 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 078169<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 208031<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21076<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22279<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from homogenates of a sea urchin (<em>Hemicentrotus pulcherrimus</em>) collected from a tidal flat of Naozhou Island in the South China Sea, near a southern city, Zhanjiang.</s></p></content></protolog>