<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8229_nm.13671" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13671" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13671" rank="species">Veillonella magna</organism><reference id="rid.8229"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kraatz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taras</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Veillonella magna sp. nov., isolated from the jejunal mucosa of a healthy pig, and emended description of Veillonella ratti.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2755</fpage><lpage>2761</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001032-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060053</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Veillonella magna</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Veillonella magna</em> (mag′na. L. fem. adj. <em>magna</em> big, referring to the cell size in comparison with other species of the genus <em>Veillonella</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical to coccoid, 0.65–0.85 μm in diameter (mean, approx. 0.75 μm) and are arranged singly or in pairs (rarely in short chains or small masses).</s><s>Adjacent sides of cell pairs are flattened and the cell surface is convoluted (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative, with an enhanced tendency to resist decolorization after 48 h incubation.</s><s>They are non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>After anaerobic incubation on modified <em>Veillonella</em> agar at 37 °C for 24 h, colonies are circular, up to 1.2 mm in diameter, have entire margins and smooth, shiny surfaces and are raised, opaque, creamy grey, soft and moist.</s><s>After 48 h, colonies look similar but are up to 2.0 mm in diameter and greyish beige.</s><s>Cells are non-haemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase is not present.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The benzidine test for porphyrin is positive.</s><s>Catalase activity is negative or delayed (approx. 30–45 s) and weak.</s><s>The type of catalase is not determined in the benzidine test.</s><s>Benzidine reacts non-specifically with the porphyrin compounds of the haem group in respiratory systems including (besides catalase) cytochromes and nitrite reductase (Bascomb &#x0026; Manafi, 1998).</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> accumulation is weak under anaerobic conditions and moderate under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from l-cysteine.</s><s>Biochemical profiling with Rapid ID 32A yields positive results for arginine dihydrolase, reduction of nitrates, alkaline phosphatase and histidine arylamidase (identification profile 2000500001).</s><s>The leucine arylamidase reaction is ambiguous using modified <em>Veillonella</em> medium [identification profile 200050(0/2)001].</s><s>API ZYM results are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>Putrescine is required for normal growth.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of fructose.</s><s>Lactate is metabolized anaerobically to more propionate and less acetate.</s><s>Gas is also produced, often abundantly.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is approximately 21–45 °C.</s><s>Growth is very weak at approximately 21 °C, absent at 46 °C, good at 30 °C and very good at 37 and 40 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5–9.5 (optimum, pH 6.5–7.5).</s><s>Alkalinization of modified <em>Veillonella</em> medium occurs at pH 5.5–6.0 (maximally to pH 6.5) and acidification occurs at pH 6.5–9.5 (maximally to pH 6.2).</s><s>Cells are anaerobic and microaerotolerant (less than approx. 5 % O<sub>2</sub>, by vol.), showing no growth on agar plates but producing vigorous growth and long-lasting viability (up to at least 2 weeks) in broth medium suspended in air-tight, screw-capped roll tubes under aerobic, unreduced conditions at 37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Scanning electron micrographs of strain lac18<sup>T</sup> grown on modified <em>Veillonella</em> agar for 22 h under anaerobic conditions at 37 °C.</s><s>Bars, 1000 nm (a) and 250 nm (b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, lac18<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 55454<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109767<sup>T</sup>= DSM 19857<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15053<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the mucosal jejunum of a healthy pig in Berlin, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>