<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.14657_nm.7788" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7788" rank="genus">Rhabdochlamydia</organism><reference id="rid.14657"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Corsaro</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goy</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venditti</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Radek</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greub</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>‘Candidatus Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’, an intracellular bacterial pathogen of the cockroach Blatta orientalis (Insecta: Blattodea)</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>30</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>221</fpage><lpage>228</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2006.06.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16934426</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The name ‘<em>Rhabdochlamydia</em>’ is derived from the Greek word &#x003C;<em>rhabdo</em>&#x003E;, which means stick/rod and from the Greek word &#x003C;<em>chlamys</em>&#x003E; which means coat; &#x003C;<em>chlamydia</em>&#x003E; is the taxonomic name of a bacterial genus; &#x003C;<em>rhabdochlamydia</em>&#x003E; refers to the rod-like shape of coated elementary bodies <a href="#bib25">[25]</a>. The name ‘<em>crassificans</em>’ is derived from the Latin words &#x003C;<em>crassus</em>&#x003E;, which means thick and &#x003C;<em>facere</em>&#x003E; to make; it refers to the severe body swelling caused by ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’ in infected cockroaches <a href="#bib33">[33]</a>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’ encompasses the intracellular bacteria present within an inclusion in the fatbodies of the cockroach <em>B. orientalis</em>.</s><s>Bacterial cells could not be grown on axenic media (data not shown).</s><s>Bacteria exhibit a chlamydia-like developmental cycle, with elementary bodies, reticulate bodies and two additional intermediate stages, the flat bodies, which look like an enlarged, flattened elementary bodies, and the condensing sphere, which may undergo binary fission like reticulate bodies <a href="#bib33">[33]</a>.</s><s>The elementary body is about 500 nm in length and 250 nm in width <a href="#bib33">[33]</a>.</s><s>Its cell wall is typically composed of five layers (<a href="#fig1">Fig. 1a</a>).</s><s>The cytoplasm of the elementary bodies is especially dense at one pole of the rod where 1 or 2 electron-light lamellae are present (<a href="#fig1">Fig. 1a</a>).</s><s>At the other pole there is an oval structure with an array of ribosome-like granules.</s><s>The reticulate bodies, that divide by binary fission (<a href="#fig1">Fig. 1b</a>), are the largest developmental stages (diameter of about 900 nm).</s><s>Their cell wall is composed of three layers, including the plasma membrane <a href="#bib33">[33]</a>.</s><s>On the basis of its 16S rRNA gene sequence, ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’ appears distinct from its closest neighbor, ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis’, and both are two yet uncultured bacteria of the order <em>Chlamydiales</em>.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’ has been deposited on the NCBI website (<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/" target="externObjLink">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/</a>) under the GenBank accession no. <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=search&#x0026;db=nucleotide&#x0026;doptcmdl=genbank&#x0026;term=AY223862[accn]" target="externObjLink">AY223862</a>. ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia crassificans’ is also characterized by rod-shaped elementary bodies with an oblong structure in the cytoplasm and a typical five-layered cell wall.</s></p></content></protolog>