<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5772_nm.1281" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1281" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1281" rank="species">Rhizobium ciceri</organism><reference id="rid.5772"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nour</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleyet-Marel</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium ciceri sp. nov., consisting of strains that nodulate chickpeas (Cicer arietinum L.).</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>511</fpage><lpage>522</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-511</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520739</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium ciceri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium ciceri</i> (ci' ce. ri. N. L. gen. n. <i>ciceri</i>, of Cicer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Colonies on yeast extract-mannitol agar are circular, opaque, and 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 3 to 5 days at 28°C.</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 40°C for most strains.</s><s>These bacteria are able to grow on minimal media, can generally tolerate 2% (wt/vol) NaCl, and grow at pH values of 5.0 to 10.0.</s><s>They are nalidixic acid, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, and trimethoprim-sulfametoxazole resistant and are able to assimilate up to 73 compounds as sole carbon sources (33).</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 63 to 64 mol%.</s><s>These bacteria are distinguished from other <i>Rhizobium</i> and <i>Bradyrhizobium</i> spp. and particularly from their closest relative, <i>R. loti</i>, on the basis of phenotypic and genomic characteristics.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Furthermore, <i>R. ciceri</i> can be differentiated from group A chickpea rhizobium strains on the basis of the results of multilocus enzyme electrophoresis and polymorphisms of amplified 16s-IGS tRNA genes (33).</s><s>Group A strains cannot grow at pH 5, generally cannot grow at pH 10, and are highly susceptible to chloramphenicol. <i>R. ciceri</i> assimilates 70% of the amino acids which we tested, whereas the group A strains utilize 50%.</s><s>The following carbon sources are assimilated by <i>R. ciceri</i> and not by group A strains: D-lyxose, DL-glycerate, L-aspartate, L-ornithine, β-alanine, L-xylose, L-alanine, and L-leucine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain UPM-Ca7, which was isolated from nodulated chickpeas grown in Spain, is the type strain.</s><s>It has the characteristics described above for <i>R. ciceri</i> sp. nov. with respect to morphology, physiology, G+C content, and genotype.</s></p></content></protolog>