<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3436_nm.3448" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3448" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3448" rank="species">Mannheimia ruminalis</organism><reference id="rid.3436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Angen</surname><given-names>Ø.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caugant</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic relationships of the [Pasteurella] haemolytica complex as evaluated by DNA-DNA hybridizations and 16S rRNA sequencing with proposal of Mannheimia haemolytica gen. nov., comb. nov., Mannheimia granulomatis comb. nov., Mannheimia glucosida sp. nov., Mannheimia ruminalis sp. nov. and Mannheimia varigena sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>67</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-67</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028248</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mannheimia ruminalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mannheimia ruminalis</i> (ru.mi.na'lis. L. n. <i>rumen</i> stomach, esp. first stomach of ruminants; L. adj.-forming suff. -<i>alis</i>; M.L. adj. <i>ruminalis</i> referring to ruminants, from which the bacteria have been isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-haemolytic small rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Colonies are smooth and greyish on blood agar and are 1-2 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation.</s><s>All strains are negative for ornithine decarboxylase, NPG, ONPF and ONPX and do not ferment L-arabinose, <i>meso</i>-inositol or glucosides (Table 9).</s><s>For further biochemical characteristics, reference is made to the description of the genus <i>Mannheimia</i>. <i>M. ruminalis</i> consists of two distinct phenotypic groups.</s><s>Biovar 1 consists of strains which do not ferment maltose and dextrin and show variable reactions in fermentation of D-sorbitol and D-xylose and correspond to Bisgaard taxon 18 biovars 1 and 3 (Bisgaard <i>et al</i>., 1986; Angen <i>et al</i>., 1997b).</s><s>Biovar 2 corresponds to [<i>P</i>.] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroup 8D (Angen <i>et al</i>., 1997a).</s><s>All strains have been isolated from the rumen of sheep or cattle and were not associated with disease conditions.</s><s>The strains have previously been decribed as <i>A. lignieresii</i> (Phillips, 1961, 1964, 1966).</s><s>The type strain is HPA92<sup>T</sup> (numbering according to RVAU Strain Collection =CCUG 38470<sup>T</sup>), originally isolated as strain S1/15/6 from rumen of sheep in UK by J.</s><s>E.</s><s>Phillips, previously classified as Bisgaard taxon 18 biovar 1 (Bisgaard <i>et al</i>., 1986).</s><s>The type strain belongs to biovar 1 and does not ferment D-sorbitol and D-xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>