<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9688_nm.14832" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14832" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14832" rank="species">Streptomyces silaceus</organism><reference id="rid.9688"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Price</surname><given-names>N.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Donahue</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sells</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces atriruber sp. nov. and Streptomyces silaceus sp. nov., two novel species of equine origin</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2899</fpage><lpage>2903</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008862-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces silaceus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces silaceus</em> (si.la′ce.us. L. masc. adj. <em>silaceus</em> like ochre, ochre-coloured referring to the orange–yellow colour of the substrate mycelium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium is yellow to yellowish orange in colour.</s><s>Aerial mycelium, where produced, on media such as yeast extract-malt extract agar (ISP 2) are white to yellowish white.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Spores are borne on flexuous aerial hyphae (<em>Rectiflexibiles</em>), are ovoid to cylindrical (0.6–0.7×0.7–0.8 μm) and have a smooth surface.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced.</s><s>Adenine, casein, aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are hydrolysed, but allantoin is not.</s><s>Nitrate reductase is produced but phosphatase is not.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, d-lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, raffinose, salicin and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>Grows on adonitol, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, galactose, glucose, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose and salicin as sole carbon sources and weak growth on maltose and sucrose, but no growth on l-arabinose, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, melezitose, l-rhamnose or d-xylose.</s><s>Assimilation of acetate, citrate, dl-malate and oxalate, weak assimilation of propionate and succinate, and no assimilation of benzoate, dl-lactate, mucate or l-tartrate.</s><s>Grows on l-asparagine, l-arginine, potassium nitrate and l-threonine as sole nitrogen sources, weak growth on l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-serine and l-valine, and no growth on l-methionine or l-phenylalanine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRRL B-24166<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41861<sup>T</sup>=LDDC 6638-99<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an equine placenta.</s></p></content></protolog>