<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4512_nm.8153" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8153" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8153" rank="species">Chryseobacterium joostei</organism><reference id="rid.4512"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hugo</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium joostei sp. nov., isolated from the dairy environment.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>771</fpage><lpage>777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium joostei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium joostei</em> (joos′te.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>joostei</em> of Jooste, in honour of P. J. Jooste, who isolated the first strains of this species from South African raw milk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, approximately 1·0×0·5 μm with parallel sides and rounded ends (Fig. 2).</s><s>The cell wall is approximately 50 nm thick (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells do not show gliding motility on CY agar and are non-motile after incubation in nutrient broth at 22 and 37 °C (phase-contrast microscopy).</s><s>Growth is aerobic.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, shiny, circular with entire edges and butyrous in consistency, becoming mucoid after incubation for 5 days.</s><s>A bright-yellow pigment (flexirubin) is produced on nutrient agar: it is non-diffusible, non-fluorescent and turns reddish brown upon the addition of 20 % KOH.</s><s>A water-soluble, non-diffusible brown pigment is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Strains grow at 5 °C and room temperature, but not at 37 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed on cetrimide agar, MacConkey agar and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate (without the production of <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate inclusion granules), but not on Simmons' citrate agar.</s><s>All strains show catalase, oxidase, phosphatase, DNase and lecithinase (opalescence on lecithovitellin agar) activity, but not arginine, lysine or ornithine decarboxylase or phenylalanine deaminase activity; there is no gluconate oxidation.</s><s>They produce indole when Kovács' reagent is used, but not when Ehrlich's reagent is used.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide and 3-ketolactose are not produced.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20 and 80 and tyrosine.</s><s>Negative for the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, does not tolerate KCN (0·0075 %), does not utilize malonate and cannot reduce nitrate, nitrite or 0·4 % selenite.</s><s>Acid is produced from 1 % (w/v) d-fructose, d-glucose (not 10 %, w/v), maltose and trehalose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, ethanol, inositol, lactose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are given in Table 4.</s><s>Susceptible to the following antimicrobial agents: chloramphenicol (50 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (5 μg) and sulphamethoxazole (25 μg).</s><s>Variable results for ampicillin (25 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cephaloridine (30 μg) and clindamycin (2 μg); full details are available as supplementary material in IJSEM Online.</s><s>The cellular long-chain fatty acids characterizing the species are 15 : 0 iso, 15 : 0 iso 3-OH, 16 : 0 3-OH, 17 : 0 iso 3-OH, 17 : 1 iso <em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, summed feature 4 (15 : 0 iso 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7<em>c</em> and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>t</em>) and two unidentified fatty acids with equivalent chain lengths of 13·566 and 16·580 (Table 2).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 36–37 mol% (36·7 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Transmission electron micrograph of a cross-section of cells of <em>C. joostei</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 18212<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Bar, 500 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>API ZYM profiles of <em>Chryseobacterium</em> species and related bacteria</s></p><p class="description"><s>Species are listed as: 1, <em>C. joostei</em> sp. nov.; 2, <em>C. gleum</em>; 3, <em>C. indologenes</em>; 4, <em>C. balustinum</em>; 5, <em>C. indoltheticum</em>; 6, <em>C. scophthalmum</em>; 7, <em>C. meningosepticum</em>; 8, <em>B. zoohelcum</em>; 9, <em>Empedobacter brevis</em>.</s><s>Only type strains of each species were included.</s><s>All the organisms gave positive reactions for 2-naphthyl phosphate, 2-naphthyl caprylate, l-leucyl 2-naphthylamide, l-valyl 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl phosphate and naphthol-AS-BI phosphate and gave negative reactions for 2-naphthyl myristate, 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide and 6-br-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside.</s><s>API ZYM scores were interpreted as described in Methods.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 18212<sup>T</sup> (=Ix 5a<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 46665<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated in 1981 from raw milk in the Ixopo district of Kwazulu-Natal in South Africa.</s><s>All <em>C. joostei</em> strains reported in this study were isolated from raw milk samples taken from different farms and from tankers arriving at dairy factories across South Africa.</s></p></content></protolog>