<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7088_nm.5089" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5089" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5089" rank="species">Sulfobacillus disulfidooxidans</organism><reference id="rid.7088"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dufresne</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bousquet</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boissinot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guay</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sulfobacillus disulfidooxidans sp. nov., a new acidophilic, disulfide-oxidizing, gram-positive, spore-forming bacterium.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1056</fpage><lpage>1064</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1056</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863435</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sulfobacillus disulfidooxidans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sulfobacillus disulfidooxidans</i> (di.sul.fi.do.ox'i.dans. L. adj. <i>duplus</i>, double; L. n. <i>sulfur</i>, sulfur; M.L. v. <i>oxido</i>, oxidize; M.L. adj. <i>disuljidooxidans</i>, disulfideoxidizing bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new species appears as a aerobic, endospore-forming rod shaped bacterium (length, 0.9 to 3.6 pm; width, 0.3 to 0.5 μm).</s><s>The strain is nonmotile; it is a typical gram-positive bacterium, even if Gram staining is variable. <i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> produces oval spores, located subterminally in a swollen sporangium.</s><s>Cells sometime appear pleomorphic and increase in width with aging.</s><s>Long chains of rods appear only on selected substrates. <i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> does not grow alone on solid medium, but it forms colonies only when an accompanying acidifying bacterium is present and growing.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> grows in liquid medium where it literally flocculates.</s><s>Growth is maximal between pH 1.5 and 2.5, and culture is possible within a wide range of pH, from 0.5 to 6.0.</s><s>The <i>Sulfobacillus</i> strain grows best at 35°C and within an interval of 4 to 40°C. <i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> utilizes glucose, glutamate, oxidized glutathione, or dithio(bis)benzothiazole during its heterotrophic growth.</s><s>When the bacterium uses elemental sulfur as its sole energy source, it does not oxidize it to sulfuric acid, but yeast extract is needed as a growth factor.</s><s>No acid formation has been observed during culture on carbohydrates (MI 50 CH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the extracted DNA is 53 ± 1 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation profiles.</s><s>Its highest 16s rDNA sequence identities were 95.5 and 95.2% with <i>A. cycloheptanicus</i> and <i>S. thermosulfidooxidans</i>, respectively.</s><s>As determined by neighbor-joining, parsimony, and maximumlikelihood approaches, the closest phylogenetically to <i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> is <i>S. thermosulfidooxidans</i>, followed by strains from the genus <i>Alicyclobacillus</i>, both genera forming a highly supported clade of low-percentage-G+ C gram-positive strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. disulfidooxidans</i> SD-11 has been deposited at the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., and has been designated ATCC 51911.</s></p></content></protolog>