<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6310_nm.10005" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10005" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10005" rank="species">Lutibacter litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.6310"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lutibacter litoralis gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from tidal flat sediment.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>771</fpage><lpage>776</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64146-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585692</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lutibacter litoralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lutibacter litoralis</em> (li.to.ra′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>litoralis</em> of the shore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0·3–0·8 μm wide and 1·0–5·7 μm long.</s><s>Spherical cells appear in ageing culture.</s><s>Cells are non-motile.</s><s>On MA medium, colonies are circular, entire, convex, shining, opaque and yellow.</s><s>Absorption spectral peaks of the pigments are observed at 450 and 475 nm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–30 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH values of between 7 and 8.</s><s>Growth occurs at sea salt concentrations of 1–5 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase, amylase, gelatinase and DNase activities are positive.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase, nitrate reductase and Tween 80 hydrolysis activities are negative.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, aesculin hydrolysis and gelatinase activities are positive, whereas nitrate reductase, indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase and urease are negative.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetone, citrate, d-fructose, d-raffinose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, glycine, glycogen, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-arginine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, pyruvic acid, succinate, tartrate, urea, Casamino acids, l-leucine, peptone, tryptone and yeast extract.</s><s>No growth occurs on acetate, acetamide, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, benzoate, dl-cysteine, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, ethanol, formic acid, glycerol, inulin, 2-propanol, lactose, l-arabinose, l-ascorbate, l-asparagine, l-rhamnose, maleic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, polyethylene glycol, salicylate, sucrose, thiamine, dl-aspartate, l-proline or l-glutamate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 33·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-TF09<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42118<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13034<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat sediment in Ganghwa, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>