<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11570_nm.18606" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18606" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18606" rank="species">Halonotius pteroides</organism><reference id="rid.11570"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Echigo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dyall-Smith</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halonotius pteroides gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon recovered from a saltern crystallizer</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1196</fpage><lpage>1199</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010017-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667389</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halonotius pteroides</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halonotius pteroides</em> [pte.ro.i′des. Gr. n. <em>pteron</em> wing; Gr. adj. (<em>e</em>)<em>ides</em> like; N.L. masc. adj. <em>pteroides</em> wing-like, named after the shape of many of the cells, which are flattened rods with rounded ends that appear similar to the wings of small insects].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are flattened and display some variability in morphology, but many are flat rods, 0.7–1.5 μm wide and 2–6 μm long (Fig. 1).</s><s>The ends of the rods are often rounded.</s><s>Weakly motile with polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium are red with entire edges.</s><s>Strictly aerobic; only oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.</s><s>Cannot utilize nitrate or DMSO as alternative electron acceptors.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5, 25–45 °C and 16–36 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cells lyse immediately in distilled water.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs under neutrophilic conditions, above 18 % (w/v) salinity.</s><s>Capable of growing in defined media, but very restricted in the substrates utilized.</s><s>Grows best on pyruvate, but also capable of utilizing glucose or glycerol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not grow with any of the following substrates as the sole carbon and energy source (all at 10 mM): acetate, alanine, arabinose, arginine, aspartate, benzoate, betaine, butanol, butyrate, cellobiose, citrate, ethanol, formate, fructose, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconuronate, glycine, glycolate, lactate, lactose, leucine, lysine, malate, malonate, mannitol, mannose, methanol, propanol, propionate, ribose, serine, succinate, sucrose, tartrate, threonine, urea, valine and xylose.</s><s>Does not grow on cellulose, chitin or starch (each at 0.1 %, w/v).</s><s>Acid is not produced from carbohydrate utilization.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and indole production.</s><s>Sensitive to anisomycin, novobiocin, rifampicin and simvastatin, and resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, cycloheximide, erythromycin, kanamycin, mycostatin, neomycin, streptomycin and tetracycline at 50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>All four known strains were isolated from solar saltern crystallizer ponds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 1.15.5<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14355<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7525<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18729<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Cheetham Salt Works, Geelong, Australia, with additional reference strains 2.27.5 (=JCM 14356 =DSM 18671), 5.24.4 (=JCM 14357 =DSM 18673) and 6.14.5 (=JCM 14358 =DSM 18692).</s></p></content></protolog>