<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6832_nm.8502" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8502" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8502" rank="species">Bacillus muralis</organism><reference id="rid.6832"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Study of mural painting isolates, leading to the transfer of 'Bacillus maroccanus' and 'Bacillus carotarum' to Bacillus simplex, emended description of Bacillus simplex, re-examination of the strains previously attributed to 'Bacillus macroides' and description of Bacillus muralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63221-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus muralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus muralis</em> (mu.ra′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>muralis</em> pertaining or belonging to walls).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·7–0·8 μm in diameter, and occur singly, in pairs or chains.</s><s>They are straight with round or occasionally slightly tapered ends.</s><s>They are motile when occurring singly but non-motile when in chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, lie centrally or paracentrally and do not swell the sporangia or swell them only slightly.</s><s>Gram reaction is variable.</s><s>Colonies grown for 2 days on nutrient agar at 30 °C are 3–6 mm in diameter, butyrous, pink-pigmented, glossy, with irregular margins, slightly raised and umbonate.</s><s>Growth under anaerobic conditions on nutrient agar is weak.</s><s>Optimal growth at 30 °C, weak growth at 20 °C and no growth at 45 °C.</s><s>Strains grow at pH 9 less profusely than at pH 7 and growth at pH 5 is negative.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is variable and a diffusible salmon-pink tint appears in the medium.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed.</s><s>Strains tolerate 7 % NaCl, but grow weakly.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the API 20E strip, the ONPG reaction is positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase reactions are negative, citrate is not utilized, hydrogen sulphide and indole are not produced, urease production and the Voges–Proskauer reaction are negative and gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>In the API 50 CHB gallery, hydrolysis of aesculin is positive and acid is produced (sometimes weakly) without gas from the following carbohydrates: l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, trehalose and salicin.</s><s>Results are variable for acid production from sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, d-lyxose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, rhamnose, starch, sorbitol, sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, d- and l-xylose and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, present at about 43 and 23 % of the total fatty acids, respectively.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present at ≥1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content is 41·2 mol% for the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain LMG 20238<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16288<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mural paintings in the Lutheran church of Greene-Kreiensen, Germany.</s><s>In the characters for which a variable result was obtained, the type strain does not hydrolyse casein and does not produce acid from sucrose.</s><s>In the Biotype 100 kit, the type strain hydrolyses aesculin and is able to grow on the following substrates as sole carbon sources: <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, d- and l-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, d-cellobiose, citrate, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, glycerol, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, dl-lactate, <em>α</em>-lactose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, palatinose, phenylacetate, l-proline, putrescine, d-raffinose, d-ribose, l-serine, sucrose, d-trehalose, l-tryptophan, d-turanose, l-tyrosine and d-xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>