<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10580_nm.17830" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17830" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17830" rank="species">Devosia yakushimensis</organism><reference id="rid.10580"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bautista</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monsalud</surname><given-names>R.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Devosia yakushimensis sp. nov., isolated from root nodules of Pueraria lobata (Willd.) Ohwi</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>627</fpage><lpage>632</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011254-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654342</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Devosia yakushimensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Devosia yakushimensis</em> (ya.ku.shi.men′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>yakushimensis</em> pertaining to Yakushima, from where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately aerobic, Gram-negative, motile rods of 1.2–2.0 μm long and 0.4–0.6 μm wide that are non-endospore-forming and possess a polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular with an entire margin (1–2 mm in diameter) and are convex, shiny and beige in colour after 2 days of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth, but tolerates up to 2.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth is narrow at pH 5.5–7.0; good growth occurs at pH 7.0.</s><s>The major (85 %) respiratory quinone is ubiquinone 10 (Q10).</s><s>Polar lipids consist of phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Positive in tests for the assimilation of d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose (bovine origin), d-melibiose, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, potassium 5-ketogluconate, d-fructose, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, raffinose, d-sorbitol, trehalose and d-gluconic acid.</s><s>Produces urease, catalase, oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but not lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzyme activity for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Susceptible to amikacin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalotin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, rifampicin, tetracycline and vancomycin, but resistant to ciproflacin, gentamicin, kanamycin, oxacillin and polymyxin B.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Yak96B<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22147<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 103855<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24299<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a root nodule of the kudzu plant [<em>Pueraria lobata</em> (Willd.) Ohwi] thriving on the coast of Yakushima Island, Kagoshima Prefecture, Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>