<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4226_nm.5078" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5078" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5078" rank="species">Alicyclobacillus hesperidum</organism><reference id="rid.4226"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sunna</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grote</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Antranikian</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alicyclobacillus hesperidum sp. nov. and a related genomic species from solfataric soils of Sao Miguel in the Azores.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>451</fpage><lpage>457</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758847</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alicyclobacillus hesperidum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alicyclobacillus hesperidum</i> (hes.pe.ri'dum. L. fem. plur. N. <i>hesperidum</i> of the Hesperides, mythological figures whom the Greeks believed to have lived at the Western edge of the Earth in a miraculous garden, which we interpret as the Azores)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells that are 2.1-3.9 μm long and 0.5-0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Gram stain is positive.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile and terminal spores are formed; sporangia are not swollen.</s><s>Colonies on BAM medium are 1-2 mm in diameter after 72 h of growth and are not pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs above 35 °C and below 60 °C; the optimum growth temperature for strains FR-11<sup>T</sup> and FR-1b is 50-53 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 3.5-4.0; growth does not occur at pH 2.0 or pH 6.0.</s><s>Strains are cytochrome oxidase-negative and catalase is weak or negative.</s><s>Yeast extract or growth factors are not required for growth.</s><s>The major fatty acids are ω-cyclohexyl C17:0 and ω-cyclohexyl C19:0; branchedchain fatty acids are also present in large proportions.</s><s>Strains do not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin, hide powder and starch are hydrolysed, but elastin and fibrin are not.</s><s>Strains FR-11<sup>T</sup> and FR-1b utilize many hexoses and disaccharides, but pentoses and polyols, with the exception of mannitol and glycerol, are not utilized as single carbon sources.</s><s>L-Serine, L-asparagine, L-glutamate, L-glutamine, L-proline and L-arginine are not utilized as single carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from virtually the same sugars that are utilized as single carbon sources.</s><s>The DNA of strain FR-11<sup>T</sup> has a G­+C content of 53.3 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from solfataric soils in the Furnas area of the Island of São Miguel, the Azores.</s><s>Strain FR-11<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany as strain DSM12489<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Strain FR-1b (=DSM 12766) is an additional strain of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>