<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1331_nm.4430" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4430" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4430" rank="species">Selenomonas noxia</organism><reference id="rid.1331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas noxia sp. nov., Selenomonas flueggei sp. nov., Selenomonas infelix sp. nov., Selenomonas dianae sp. nov., and Selenomonas artemidis sp. nov., from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas noxia</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas noxia</i> (no'xia. L. fem. adj. noxia harmful [referring to its presence in periodontitis)).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, motile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods.</s><s>Cells are curved, crescent shaped, and 1.1 μm in diameter by 1.1 to 3.2 μm long.</s><s>With Leifson flagellum stain, cells appear to have one or more central-to-polar flagella arising from the concave side.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On rabbit blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h, colonies are minute to 0.5 mm, circular, entire, low convex to flat, transparent, smooth, shiny, and colorless to yellowish.</s><s>Strains produce only slight turbidity in peptoneyeast extract (PY) broth.</s><s>PYG broth cultures have abundant growth and are turbid with a smooth sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 to 37°C.</s><s>There is moderate growth at 45°C and no growth or only very slight growth at 25°C.</s><s>Growth often is more abundant in PY broth containing fructose, glucose, mannose, sorbitol, sorbose, or fumarate and sometimes in broth containing sucrose than in PY broth alone, but the pH of these cultures usually is equal to the pH of cultures in PY broth alone.</s><s>No ammonia is detected in PY, PYG, or chopped meat cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Neutral red is reduced.</s><s>In glucose agar deep cultures, resazurin is not reduced and little or no gas is detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml) , erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation acids of the type strain, in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture, are 1.0 of acetic and 1.1 of propionic from PYG cultures; 0.03 of acetic, 0.1 of propionic, and 0.1 of lactic from PY broth cultures; and 1.9 of acetic and 2.3 of propionic from PYG-fumarate cultures.</s><s>Pyruvate and lactate are not used; threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>Trace-to-moderate amounts of hydrogen usually are detected in the headspace gas of PYG cultures; abundant hydrogen is detected from some cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The PAGE protein patterns are shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>The cellular components are given in Table 5 .</s><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 57 mol%.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the 12 other strains tested are 56 to 58 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 43541, isolated from the gingival crevice of an affected site in a person with rapidly progressive periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is isolated from the gingival crevice of persons with gingivitis or periodontitis and from the adjacent supragingival plaque coronal to the sites affected wih periodontitis.</s><s>This species has been referred to as <i>Selenomonas</i> D-4 and D-12 in previous publications.</s></p></content></protolog>