<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1460_nm.4914" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4914" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4914" rank="species">Bacillus glucanolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.1460"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Alexander</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus glucanolyticus, a new species that degrades a variety of beta-glucans.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>115</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-112</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus glucanolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus glucanolyticus</i> (gluc.an.o.lyt'i.cus. Gr. adj. <i>glukos</i>, sweet, glucose; Gr. n. <i>an</i>, polymer; Gr. adj. <i>lytos</i>, dissolvable; M. L. adj. <i>glucanolyticus</i>, hydrolyzing glucose polymers)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are long (usually &#x003E;3.0 μm) and thin (&#x003C;0.9 μm) and produce oval terminal spores that markedly distend the sporangium.</s><s>Colonies are flat, smooth, and opaque and are motile during growth on dry nutrient agar plates.</s><s>Growth at pH 5.7.</s><s>Growth at 17 to 37°C but not at 5 or 50°C.</s><s>Variable growth at 45°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, raffinose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced by most strains (including the type strain) from L-arabinose, glycerol, and mannitol.</s><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth is less than 5.5.</s><s>Acid is not produced from dulcitol, erythritol, or sorbitol.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze arbutin, carboxymethyl cellulose, esculin, DNA, pullulan, pustulan, ribonucleic acid, and starch.</s><s>No strain hydrolyzes allantoin, chitin, elastin, lecithin, pectin, tyrosine, or urea.</s><s>Most strains hydrolyze casein and gelatin and utilize citrate and succinate.</s><s>Strains grow in the presence of 5% NaCl but not in the presence of 10% NaCl and are negative for indole production and the Voges-Proskauer reaction.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 48.3 to 48.6 mol%. <i>B. glucanolyticus</i> strains were isolated from soil by plating pasteurized suspensions onto nutrient agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 5162<i>T</i> (= NCIMB 12809 = S93).</s><s>The G+C content of this strain is 49 mol%.</s><s>The type strain conforms to the description given above.</s></p></content></protolog>