<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1465_nm.6754" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6754" rank="genus">Saccharopolyspora</organism><reference id="rid.1465"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Korn-Wendisch</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kempf</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grund</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kutzner</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Faenia rectivirgula Kurup and Agre 1983 to the genus Saccharopolyspora Lacey and Goodfellow 1975, elevation of Saccharopolyspora hirsuta subsp. taberi Labeda 1987 to species level, and emended description of the genus Saccharopolyspora.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>430</fpage><lpage>441</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Saccharopolyspora</i> (Lacey and Goodfellow 1975)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora</i> (Sac' cha. ro. po. ly. spo. ra. M.L. <i>Saccharum</i>, generic name of sugar cane; Gr. adj. <i>polys</i>, many; Gr. n. <i>spora</i>, a seed; M.L. fem. n. <i>Saccharopolyspora</i>, the many-spored [organism] from sugar cane)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram positive, non-acid fast.</s><s>Substrate mycelium yellow, orange, or brownish red on GYM agar and TSA, well developed, branched, septate, and 0.4 to 0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Substrate hyphae either (i) fragment into rodshaped elements, (ii) do not fragment, or (iii) are transformed partially into chains of spores.</s><s>Aerial mycelium white to pinkish red or no aerial mycelium on GYM agar and TSA.</s><s>When present, the aerial mycelium is 0.5 to 1.2 μm in diameter and well developed in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>Spores occur in straight or open spiral chains on short, unbranched, lateral or terminal sporophores.</s><s>Spore surfaces are smooth, rough, hairy, or spiny.</s><s>Mesophilic, moderately thermophilic, or thermophilic, growing at temperatures up to 63°C.</s><s>Lysozyme sensitive.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is not produced.</s><s>No egg yolk reaction and no hemolysis.</s><s>Able to utilize a wide range of organic compounds as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth and to degrade a number of substrates.</s><s>Sensitive to genus-specific phages isolated from lysogenic cultures or from soil (e.g., FR-C).</s></p></content></protolog>