<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5589_nm.11009" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11009" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6800" rank="species">Saccharothrix aerocolonigenes</organism><reference id="rid.5589"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of "Nocardia aerocolonigenes" (Shinobu and Kawato 1960) Pridham 1970 into the genus Saccharothrix Labeda, Testa, Lechevalier and Lechevalier 1984 as Saccharothrix aerocolonigenes sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>109</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-1-109</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Saccharothrix aerocolonigenes sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The following description is based on a previously published study (4) and evaluation of strain NRRL B-3298<sup>T</sup> in my laboratory by using previously described methods (3, 6, 15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yellowish to brownish substrate mycelium with extremely sparse white aerial mycelium.</s><s>A yellowish to brownish . soluble pigment is produced on several media.</s><s>Casein, esculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine, and urea are hydrolyzed; adenine, cellulose, and guanine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite; phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol. <i>Myo</i>-inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raflinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose; no acid is produced from dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, melezitose, alpha-methyl-D-glucoside, beta-methylxyloside, and sorbitol.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, lactate, DL-malate, oxalate, propionate, succinate, and DL-tartrate are used as sole carbon sources; benzoate and mucate are not used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 45°C.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 70 to 71 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain of <i>Saccharothrix aerocolonigenes</i> is strain NRRL B-3298 (=ATCC 23870=IFO 3837=ISP 5034).</s></p></content></protolog>