<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2702_nm.8023" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8023" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8023" rank="species">Porphyromonas canoris</organism><reference id="rid.2702"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karjalainen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanervo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsblom</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sarkiala</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wigney</surname><given-names>D.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jousimies-Somer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Porphyromonas canoris sp. nov., an asaccharolytic, black-pigmented species from the gingival sulcus of dogs.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>204</fpage><lpage>208</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186085</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas canoris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas canoris</i> (can' or. is. L. n. <i>canis</i>, dog; L. gen. n. <i>oris</i>, of the mouth; N.L. gen. n. <i>canoris</i>, of a dog’s mouth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, nonsporing, nonmotile, gram-negative rods or coccoid forms.</s><s>In cooked meat carbohydrate medium (14) and on sheep blood agar plates, cells are 0.3 to 0.6 by 0.8 to 1.5 μm and are arranged singly and in groups; filaments up to 16 μm long are seen occasionally.</s><s>On sheep blood agar plates, surface colonies after 48 h are 1.5 mm in diameter, circular, and rough and have orange pigmentation.</s><s>Colonies exhibit brick red fluorescence (265 nm) after 3 and 6 days, and after 13 days the fluorescence is light orange.</s><s>On laked rabbit or sheep blood medium, colonies are light brown to greenish brown after 2 to 4 days and black after 12 days of incubation.</s><s>Vitamin K and hemin are required for growth.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days, the pH values in media containing carbohydrates (uninoculated pH, 6.8 to 7.4) generally range from 6.3 to 6.5.</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentation is not detected in the presence of adonitol, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from cooked meat medium (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The short-chain fatty acids produced in cooked meat medium are acetate (average concentration, 36.7 μmol/ml), propionate (average concentration, 42.5 μmol/ml), isovalerate (average concentration, 10.1 μmol/ml), and succinate (average concentration, 15.6 μmol/ml); in addition, minor amounts of isobutyrate (average concentration, 2.8 μmol/ml) and butyrate (average concentration, 4.3 μmol/ml) are produced.</s><s>No phenylacetic acid is detected.</s><s>Lactate is converted to propionate, but pyruvate is not utilized, and threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>Strains are catalase positive and indole positive, liquefy gelatin, and are alkaline and acid phosphatase positive, but do not exhibit trypsin-like activity or produce lipase or lecithinase.</s><s>They produce chymotrypsin, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, and β-galactosidase but do not produce α-galactosidase or α-fucosidase.</s><s>Cells do not hemagglutinate sheep erythrocytes.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, urea is not split, and esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Malate, glutamate, glucose-6-phosphate, and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenases are present.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid is 13-methyltetradecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>); smaller amounts of the acids shown in Table 2 are also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are susceptible to penicillin (2 U/ml), amoxicillin (2.5 μg/ml), carbenicillin (100 μg/ml), and erythromycin (3 μg/ml).</s><s>All strains were isolated from subgingival pockets of dogs with naturally occurring periodontitis.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49 to 51 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation method (16).</s><s>The average level of intraspecies DNA-DNA hybridization is 90%.</s><s>The average levels of DNA-DNA hybridization between strain VPB 4878<sup>T</sup> (= NCTC 12835<sup>T</sup>) and other members of the genus <i>Porphyromonas</i> are as follows: <i>P. gingivalis</i> ATCC 33277<sup>T</sup>, 4%; <i>P. salivosa</i>, 4%; cat strains of <i>P. gingivalis</i>, 5%; <i>P. endodontalis</i> ATCC 35406<sup>T</sup>, 2%; <i>P. circumdentaria</i>, 3%; and <i>P. asaccharolytica</i> ATCC 25260<sup>T</sup>, 3%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCTC 12835 (= VPB 4878).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics which distinguish <i>P. canoris</i> sp. nov. from other members of the genus <i>Porphyromonas</i> are summarized in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>