<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.630_nm.8677" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8677" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8677" rank="species">Loktanella vestfoldensis</organism><reference id="rid.630"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Loktanella salsilacus gen. nov., sp. nov., Loktanella fryxellensis sp. nov. and Loktanella vestfoldensis sp. nov., new members of the Rhodobacter group, isolated from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1263</fpage><lpage>1269</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03006-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280301</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Loktanella vestfoldensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Loktanella vestfoldensis</em> (vest.fold.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>vestfoldensis</em> referring to the isolation source, lakes Ace and Pendant, Vestfold Hills, Antarctica).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (&#x003C;1 μm by 3–4 μm), often forming pairs or short chains.</s><s>Strains grow at 5–37 °C, but no growth is observed at 45 °C.</s><s>Pale-pink, convex, translucent colonies with a diameter of &#x003C;1 mm, with entire margins formed on marine agar plates.</s><s>Growth also occurs on trypticase/soy agar (weak growth), nutrient agar (weak growth) and R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Degrades aesculin, Tween 80, citrate and urea.</s><s>No growth is observed (API 20NE) on carbohydrates and acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Agar, casein, DNA, gelatin, tyrosine and starch are not degraded.</s><s>Tests for indole production, nitrate reduction, hydrogen sulfide production and the Voges–Proskauer reaction are negative.</s><s>None of the strains shows activity for the enzymes arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E) and lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, medium activity for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>) and acid phosphatase, and strong activity for trypsin (API ZYM).</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–5 % NaCl and weak growth in 10 % NaCl.</s><s>The G+C content of the strains is 62·1–63·1 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from lakes Ace and Pendant in the Vestfold Hills, Antarctica.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 22003<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108321<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>