<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2689_nm.1878" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1878" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1878" rank="species">Thiobacillus aquaesulis</organism><reference id="rid.2689"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Thiobacillus aquaesulis sp. nov., a novel facultatively autotrophic moderate thermophile</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>149</volume><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00411653</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus aquaesulis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus aquaesulis</i> (a.quae.su'lis.L.n. <i>aquae</i>, waters; L.n. <i>Sulis</i>, pertaining to the Temple of Sulis Minerva (Minerva, the Roman goddess of wisdom); M.L. adj. <i>aquaesulis</i>, from the waters of Sulis Minerva)</s></p><p class="description"><s>THe description of <i>Thiobacillus aquaesulis</i> given here is based on the type strain which has been deposited with Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, FRG (DSM 4255) and the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC 43788).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, non spore forming, short rods 0.3 x 0.9 μm, and contain some polyphosphate inclusions.</s><s>The organism is facultatively heterotrophic on complex media (yeast extract or nutrient broth), but unable to grow on common sugars, organic acids, formate or methylamine, as single substrates.</s><s>It is autotrophic and chemolithotrophic, using the oxidation of thiosulphate, trithionate and tetrathionate for growth.</s><s>In liquid batch culture in thiosulphate medium sulphur precipitation and a drop in pH without tetrathionate accumulation, occur.</s><s>Chemostat cultures do not accumulate sulphur or other intermediates during growth on thiosulphate, trithionate or tetrathionate at pH 7.6 and 43 °C.</s><s>Initiates growth at pH 7.0-9.0 (30-55°C), dropping pH to 6.0-7.0.</s><s>No growth at pH 6.4 or 9.4, or at 26° or 58°C.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed by means of ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>Colonies on thiosulphate agar at 43°C are small (1-2 mm), circular, convex and smooth, becoming white or yellow with precipitated sulphur.</s><s>Capable of anaerobic autotrophic growth during thiosulphate-dependent denitrification.</s><s>Uses ammonium salts as nitrogen source.</s><s>Optimum temperature 40-50°C optimum pH 7.5-8.0.</s><s>The DNA contains 65.7 mol% G + C.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-8.</s></p></content></protolog>