<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3226_nm.4553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4553" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter mathranii</organism><reference id="rid.3226"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Larsen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ahring</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacter mathranii sp. nov., an ethanol-producing, extremely thermophilic anaerobic bacterium from a hot spring in Iceland.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>168</volume><fpage>114</fpage><lpage>119</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050476</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9238102</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter mathranii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter mathranii</i> (ma.thra'ni.i. M.L.gen.n., of Mathrani, in honor of the late Indra M. Mathrani, who contributed greatly to our understanding of thermophilic anaerobes from hot springs during his short career)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-variable, straight, rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Vegetative cells in exponential growth phase are 0.7x1.8–3.9 μm.</s><s>Terminal spherical spores that swell the cells.</s><s>Cells are longer when sporulating or at suboptimal conditions.</s><s>Occur singly or, at sub-optimal conditions, in long chains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Grows on amygdalin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melizitose, raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylan, and D-xylose, but not on avicel, casein-peptone, cellulose, D-galactose, glycerol, inulin, pectin, L-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, or yeast extract (Difco).</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth when a vitamin solution is added at 0.1 ml/10 ml culture.</s><s>Inhibited by tetracycline, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, neomycin, and vancomycin at 100 mg/l.</s><s>Grows in the presence of chloramphenicol and neomycin at 10 mg/l.</s><s>Insensitive to 50.66 kPa overpressure of H<sub>2</sub> and 2% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition of 37 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from biomat and sediment from a slightly alkaline hot spring in Hverðagerdi-Hengil, Iceland.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, <i>Thermoanaerobacter mathranii</i> A3, has been deposited in the DSM culture collection under accession no. 11426.</s></p></content></protolog>