<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12093_nm.20082" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20082" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20082" rank="species">Amycolatopsis xylanica</organism><reference id="rid.12093"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>J.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>We</surname><given-names>Y.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>L.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis xylanica sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2124</fpage><lpage>2128</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016865-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19880636</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis xylanica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis xylanica</em> (xy.la.ni′ca. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan; L. fem. suff. -<em>ica</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>xylanica</em> pertaining to xylan, referring to the energy source used for the isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, aerobic and non-motile and form well-developed aerial and vegetative mycelium.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colony colour is dependent on the test medium.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white on ISP 2, 4 and 5 and Bennett agar.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium is brown on ISP 2 and Bennett agar, white–brown on ISP 4 and white on ISP 5.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are light brown on ISP 2, yellow–brown on ISP 4 and ISP 5 and brown on Bennett agar; no discernible diffusible pigments on ISP 6.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–45 °C and good growth is observed at 28 °C.</s><s>Cells can grow with 0–5 % NaCl, but not with more than 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Utilizes l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-cystine, l-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan, l-valine and potassium nitrate as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, trehalose, d-xylose, aesculin ferric citrate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and glycerol as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but not d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fucose, lactose (bovine origin), melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbose, sucrose, d-tagatose, l-xylose, arbutin, amygdalin, d-adonitol, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, potassium gluconate, d-glycogen, d-inulin or salicin.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, weakly positive for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase and trypsin, but negative for cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>); small amounts of MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) are detected.</s><s>In the phospholipid profile, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine are predominant and glucosamine-containing phospholipids, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and phosphatidylinositol dimannosides can also be detected.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 and C<sub>17 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CPCC 202699<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45285<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19581<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7627<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil in Qinghai, China.</s></p></content></protolog>