<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3921_nm.4638" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4638" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4638" rank="subspecies">Mycoplasma capricolum capricolum</organism><reference id="rid.3921"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leach</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ernø</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macowan</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for designation of F38-type caprine mycoplasmas as Mycoplasma capricolum subsp. capripneumoniae subsp. nov. and consequent obligatory relegation of strains currently classified as M. capricolum (Tully, Barile, Edward, Theodore, and Ernø 1974) to an additional new subspecies, M. capricolum subsp. capricolum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>603</fpage><lpage>605</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-603</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347517</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capricolum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capricolum</i> (cap. ri. co'lum. L. gen. n. <i>capri</i>, of a goat; L. v. <i>incolere</i>, to dwell; L. part. adj. <i>capricolum</i> dwelling in a goat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The taxonomic description of <i>M. capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capricolum</i> is the same as the description of <i>M. capricolum</i> (20), except that members of this subspecies exhibit strong serological cross-reactivity with members of the newly designated taxon <i>M. capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capripneumoniae</i>; otherwise, <i>M. capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capricolum</i> is serologically distinguishable from previously described Mycoplasma species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain California kid (= ATCC 27343 = NCTC 10154); this is the type strain of both <i>M. capricolum</i> and <i>M. capricolum</i> subsp. <i>capricolum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>