<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3468_nm.9205" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9205" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5648" rank="species">Streptococcus infantarius</organism><reference id="rid.3468"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schlegel</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Régnault</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus infantarius sp. nov., Streptococcus infantarius subsp. infantarius subsp. nov. and Streptococcus infantarius subsp. coli subsp. nov., isolated from humans and food.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1425</fpage><lpage>1434</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939646</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus infantarius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus infantarius</i> (in.fan.ta'ri.us. L. adj. <i>infantarius</i> relating to infants, the source of the type strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-positive cocci that occur in pairs or short chains and are non-motile, non-sporulating and catalase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are circular, 1 mm in diameter after a 24 h incubation at 37 °C, unpigmented and α-haemolytic.</s><s>Growth is enhanced in a 5% CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere.</s><s>Strains show homogeneous growth in buffer dextrose and in brain-heart infusion broths.</s><s>Growth also occurs in MRS broth, without gas production.</s><s>No growth in 6.5%(w/v) NaCl broth.</s><s>No exopolysaccharide production on 5% sucrose medium.</s><s>The Lancefield group D antigen is present in 40% of the strains.</s><s>Strains are positive for Voges-Proskauer, leucine aminopeptidase and alanylphenylalanyl-proline arylamidase tests.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase and pyrrolidonylarylamidase tests are negative.</s><s>Urea and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Nearly all strains are a-galactosidase-positive.</s><s>They are N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase-, β-galactosidase-, β-glucuronidase-, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase- and β-mannosidase-negative.</s><s>All strains produce acid from lactose, maltose and sucrose.</s><s>They do not produce acid from arabinose, arabitol, cyclodextrine, inulin, D-mannitol, melezitose, ribose, sorbitol, D-tagatose or trehalose.</s><s>Variable results occur with glycogen, melibiose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, draffinose and starch.</s><s>Characteristics useful in their differentiation from related organisms and also in the delineation between the two subspecies are listed in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most of the <i>S. infantarius</i> subsp. <i>infantarius</i> strains do not hydrolyse aesculin (five out of seven) and are β-glucosidase- and methyl β-D-glucopyranoside-negative.</s><s>They produce acid from glycogen, melibiose, pullulan and starch, with some exceptions.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. infantarius</i> subsp. <i>infantarius</i> HDP 90056<sup>T</sup> (=NCDO 599<sup>T</sup>) is aesculin- and β-glucosidase-negative.</s><s>It produces acid from glycogen, pullulan, D-raffinose and starch, but not from melibiose or methyl β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the faeces of an infant human.</s><s>Other isolates have been obtained from clinical specimens (three from blood, including one from a case of endocarditis) or food products (a dairy product and frozen peas). <i>S. infantarius</i> subsp. <i>coli</i> is β-glucosidase- and aesculinpositive.</s><s>Glycogen, starch, melibiose and pullulan are not fermented.</s><s>Ten strains of this subspecies were isolated from human specimens including faeces from two infants, urine (one isolate) and blood (three isolates, including one from a case of endocarditis).</s><s>The reference strain for this subspecies is HDP 90246 (=NCDO 964).</s></p></content></protolog>