<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8207_nm.14207" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14207" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14207" rank="species">Marinobacter santoriniensis</organism><reference id="rid.8207"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Handley</surname><given-names>K.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Héry</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lloyd</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter santoriniensis sp. nov., an arsenate-respiring and arsenite-oxidizing bacterium isolated from hydrothermal sediment.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>886</fpage><lpage>892</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003145-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329625</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter santoriniensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter santoriniensis</em> (san.to.ri.ni.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>santoriniensis</em> from the island of Santorini, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, straight rods (0.5–1.3×1.2–4.5 μm) that are motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>They are facultatively anaerobic, moderately halophilic, mesophilic and neutrophilic.</s><s>Colonies on spread plates are slightly raised centrally, circular to irregular in form (7 mm mean diameter).</s><s>On MA, colonies are translucent cream, whereas colonies have translucent to opaque brownish-red centres on LB.</s><s>Streaked colonies tend to be opaque and slightly convex with a diamond-shaped morphology.</s><s>The type strain grows well aerobically on MB, LB and TSB (supplemented with additional NaCl) agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–9.0 and 0.5–16 % NaCl, and is optimal at 35–40 °C, pH 7.0–8.0 and 5–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Lactate supports aerobic growth, and anaerobic growth by fermentation (weak).</s><s>Arsenite is oxidized aerobically in the presence of lactate.</s><s>Carbon substrates assimilated are potassium gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid and phenylacetic acid, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid or citrate.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate (to nitrite) proceeds with the oxidation of formate, acetate, propionate, n-butyrate, pyruvate, lactate, fumarate, succinate, malate, yeast extract and FeSO<sub>4</sub> . 7H<sub>2</sub>O (plus 5 mM acetate).</s><s>Lactate oxidation further supports the reduction of arsenate, Fe(III) nitrilotriacetic acid with or without yeast extract (weak) and fumarate.</s><s>Enzymes expressed are alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease, but not trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.1 mol%.</s><s>Dominant cellular fatty acids are 16 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), 16 : 0 and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NKSG1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21262<sup>T</sup> =NCIMB 14441<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shallow marine hydrothermal sediment at Santorini, Greece.</s></p></content></protolog>