<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5827_nm.3513" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3513" rank="genus">Lawsonia</organism><reference id="rid.5827"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McOrist</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gebhart</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boid</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barns</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Lawsonia intracellularis gen. nov., sp. nov., the obligately intracellular bacterium of porcine proliferative enteropathy.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>820</fpage><lpage>825</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-123</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547305</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lawsonia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lawsonia</i> (Law.son.ia. L.n. <i>Lawsonia</i>, in honor of G. H. K. Lawson, the discoverer of the bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-spore-forming curved rods (ca. 1.5 by 0.35 μm).</s><s>Gram-negative cells retain carbol-fushsin when they are stained by the modified Ziehl-Neelsen method.</s><s>Nonflagellated.</s><s>Nonpigmented.</s><s>Sections reveal the cell wall profile of a gram-negative bacterium and the protoplasmic structure of a procaryote.</s><s>Cells characteristically replicate within the cytoplasm, are not enclosed by membrane-bound vacuoles, and occur in epithelial cells in the ilea of pigs.</s><s>Best revealed in histological sections by silver-staining techniques.</s><s>Intracellular organisms exhibit acidfast staining in smears of intestinal epithelium and enterocytes with the modified Ziehl-Neelsen acid-fast stain.</s><s>Multiplies by septum formation.</s><s>Does not reduce sulfate.</s><s>Cannot be cultivated in cell-free media.</s><s>Grows intracellularly in enterocytes and requires a microaerophilic atmosphere for growth.</s><s>The sequence of 16s rDNA shows that these bacteria are members of the delta subdivision of the <i>Proteohacteria</i>.</s><s>Distinct from certain <i>Desulfovibrio</i> spp. in electrophorctic protein profiles, DNA probe reactions, and monoclonal antibody reactions.</s><s>Isolated from the intestinal epithelial cells of pigs with proliferative enteropathies.</s><s>Pathogenic for pigs with an intestinal flora.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 12656 (= 1482/89).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Designation of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain is 1482/89, which was cocultured in a rat enterocyte cell line that was infected with a suspension of bacteria obtained from a pig with proliferative enteropathy and maintained in a rat enterocyte cell culture.</s><s>This strain reproduces effectively in rat enterocytes without noticeable cytopathic effects or threat to culture survival.</s><s>Strain 1482/89<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures, Colindale, London, United Kingdom, as strain NCTC 12656<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The bacterium growing in a cell culture conforms to the genus and species description given above.</s></p></content></protolog>