<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6753_nm.5409" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5409" rank="species">Lactobacillus pantheris</organism><reference id="rid.6753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus pantheris sp. nov., isolated from faeces of a jaguar.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1748</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02247-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus pantheris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus pantheris</i> (pan'ther.is. L. gen. n. <i>pantheris</i> of the panther, referring to the isolation of the strains from jaguar faeces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, nonmotile rods, 0.5x1.5-2.5 μm in size after 24 h incubation in TPYG liquid medium.</s><s>Catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>D(-)-Lactic acid but no gas is produced from glucose fermentation.</s><s>Colonies are convex, opaque and rough with irregular edges and less than 1 mm in diameter after 24 h cultivation on TPYG plates.</s><s>Growth occurred at 10 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 6.0-6.4 and growth can occur at pH 4.5, but not at pH values above 7.5.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine and aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, N-acetyl glucosamine, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, β-gentiobiose and D-tagatose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D- raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, gluconate, 2- ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain A24-2-1<sup>T</sup> is 52.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and a second strain, A24-1-5, were isolated from the faeces of a jaguar in Beijing Zoo.</s><s>The type strain is strain A24-2-1<sup>T</sup> (=AS 1.2826<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21017<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>