<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5290_nm.9683" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9683" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9683" rank="species">Enterobacter ludwigii</organism><reference id="rid.5290"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoffmann</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stindl</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stumpf</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mehlen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monget</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heesemann</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roggenkamp</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Enterobacter ludwigii sp. nov., a novel Enterobacter species of clinical relevance</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>28</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>206</fpage><lpage>212</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2004.12.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15900967</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>E. ludwigii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s><em>E. ludwigii</em> [lud.wi’gi.i N.L. gen. n. of Ludwig, named in honour to Wolfgang Ludwig, a microbiologist who contributed to the general understanding of bacterial systematics <a href="#bib21">[21]</a>, especially by developing the ARB data bases and opening them to the public <a href="#bib22">[22]</a>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on phylogenetic analyses of partial <em>hsp60</em> sequence data collected in a recent population genetic study <a href="#bib12">[12]</a> as well as on DNA–DNA-hybridization assays and phenotypic characterizations performed in the frame of the present study.</s><s>Phenotypic characterization was performed using API20E, Biotype 100, and a series of conventional tests. <em>E. ludwigii</em> strains are gram-negative rods, which are motile, catalase positive, oxidase and DNAase negative, fermentative, and non-pigmented.</s><s>They exhibit the general characteristics of the family Enterobacteriaceae, the genus <em>Enterobacter</em>, and the <em>E. cloacae</em> complex.</s><s>Growth occurs after 18–24 h at 15–42 °C with an optimum at 36 °C on all non-selective media like Columbia agar with 5% sheep-blood, chocolate-, TSA-, Luria–Bertani-, or Brain–Heart agar as well as on semi-selective media like MacConkey- or ENDO-agar in non-pigmented colonies.</s><s>A detailed biochemical profiling of the species is given in <a href="#tbl3">Table 3</a>. <a href="#tbl4">Table 4</a> shows tests in use for differentiating <em>E. ludwigii</em> from the other species of the genus.</s><s>Its identification is mainly possible by the ability to grow on 3-0-methyl-d-gluco-pyranose and on myo-inositol.</s><s>All strains analysed produced a Bush class 1 beta-lactamase rendering resistance to ampicillin, amoxicillin plus clavulanic acid and cefoxitin in the disk diffusion tests performed. 20% of strain displayed a resistance pattern typical for AmpC hyper-production (resistance to piperacillin, piperacillin plus tazobactam, cefoxitin, cefotaxime, ceftazidime, and susceptibility to cefepime).</s><s>All strains were susceptible to trimethoprim plus sulphamethoxazole, gentamicin, meropenem and ciprofloxacin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain EN-119<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16688<sup>T</sup> =CIP 108491<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from mid-stream urine of an 18-year old male patient with a nosocomial urinary tract infection, while he was hospitalized at the Grosshadern-University-Hospital Munich, Germany.</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rDNA of strain EN-119<sup>T</sup> is AJ853891.</s></p></content></protolog>