<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8625_nm.13705" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13705" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13705" rank="species">Cucumibacter marinus</organism><reference id="rid.8625"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cucumibacter marinus gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium in the family Hyphomicrobiaceae</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1591</fpage><lpage>1597</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65587-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599700</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cucumibacter marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cucumibacter marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> referring to the sea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>After 7 days on MA plates at 35 °C, colonies are circular, convex, creamy and approximately 0.8 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.4–0.6 μm wide and 1.5–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Grows at 15–40 °C (optimum, 30–35 °C) and pH 6–9 (optimum, pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs at sea salts concentrations of 1–10 % (w/v) (optimum, 3–4 %) and at NaCl concentrations of 1–3 % (optimum, 2 %).</s><s>Amylase and gelatinase are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>With the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, betaine, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glutamic acid, glycerol, lactose, d- and l-leucine, d-mannitol, mannose, pyruvate, sucrose and trehalose as sole carbon sources, but not dl-cysteine, dimethyl sulfide, glycine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetate, maleic acid, succinate or urea.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) ampicillin (10), cephalexin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10) and vancomycin (30) but resistant to gentamicin (10), nalidixic acid (30) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 62.9 mol%.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids listed in the genus description, minor or trace amounts of phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine, an unidentified phospholipid, an unidentified aminophospholipid and three unidentified lipids can be detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-GR60<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 90027<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18995<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal seawater from the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>