<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1648_nm.10558" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10558" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10558" rank="species">Actinomadura rudentiformis</organism><reference id="rid.1648"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Le Roes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyers</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura rudentiformis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64438-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17220439</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomadura rudentiformis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomadura rudentiformis</em> (ru.den.ti.for′mis. L. masc. n. <em>rudens</em> rope; L. adj. suffix -<em>formis</em> -like, in the shape of; N.L. fem. adj. <em>rudentiformis</em> shaped like a rope).</s></p><p class="description"><s>During incubation for 14 days on oatmeal agar (ISP 3) supplemented with 0.1 % yeast extract, forms cream-coloured substrate mycelium, with sparse white aerial mycelium.</s><s>Wrinkled, cream-coloured substrate mycelium forms on ISP 2, but no sporulation occurs.</s><s>White substrate mycelium forms on inorganic salts-starch agar (ISP 4), but no sporulation occurs.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced on glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP 5) and melanin production on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP 6) or tyrosine agar (ISP 7) is not observed.</s><s>Very strong antibiosis is exhibited against <em>M. aurum</em> A+ and weak antibiosis is shown against <em>Enterococcus faecium</em> VanA (vancomycin-resistant) in agar overlays.</s><s>Bioautographic analysis of organic solvent extracts of cell mass shows moderate antibiosis against <em>M. aurum</em> A+, <em>Mycobacterium bovis</em> BCG (Tokyo) and <em>M. tuberculosis</em> H37Rv<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative and Gram-positive.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0.3 % 2-phenylethanol, weakly in the presence of 0.0001 % crystal violet, but not in the presence of 4 % NaCl, 0.1 % phenol or sodium azide (0.01 %).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of the following antibiotics (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>, unless indicated otherwise): kanamycin (10), neomycin (50), oleandomycin (100), penicillin G (10 IU ml<sup>−1</sup>), rifampicin (50) and tobramycin (50).</s><s>Growth is not observed in the presence of the following antibiotics (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>): cephaloridine (100), gentamicin (100), lincomycin (100), streptomycin (100) and vancomycin (50).</s><s>Growth occurs at 30, 37 and 45 °C, but not at 4 °C or pH 4.3.</s><s>Utilizes dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyric acid, l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, potassium nitrate, l-serine, l-threonine and l-valine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Utilizes adonitol, (+)-d-cellobiose, (−)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, (+)-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, (−)-d-lactose, (−)-d-mannitol, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-d-melibiose, raffinose, (+)-l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and (+)-d-xylose as sole carbon sources; (+)-l-arabinose, (+)-d-melezitose, (−)-d-ribose, salicin, sodium acetate (0.1 %) and xylitol are weakly utilized.</s><s>Sodium citrate (0.1 %) is not utilized.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production and nitrate reduction do not occur.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase and protease activities are not observed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed, but pectin is not.</s><s>Degrades adenine, aesculin, arbutin, casein, cellulose, gelatin, Tween 80 and xylan; guanine and starch are weakly degraded.</s><s>Allantoin, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine, urea and xanthine are not degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HMC1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44962<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24458<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil collected from the banks of the Gamka River in the Swartberg Nature Reserve, Western Cape Province, South Africa.</s></p></content></protolog>