<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6862_nm.9540" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9540" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9540" rank="species">Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii</organism><reference id="rid.6862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae from Antarctic maritime habitats including Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii gen. nov., sp. nov., Subsaximicrobium saxinquilinus sp. nov., Subsaxibacter broadyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Lacinutrix copepodicola gen. nov., sp. nov., and novel species of the genera Bizionia, Gelidibacter and Gillisia</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii</em> (wynn.wil.li.ams′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>wynnwilliams</em> of Wynn-Williams, named in honour of the late D. D. Wynn-Williams, British Antarctic microbiologist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus plus the following.</s><s>Cell mass is either a bright-orange or golden-yellow colour.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, with an entire edge and a butyrous consistency on MA.</s><s>Colonies exhibit spreading margins on dilute media.</s><s>Growth occurs at −2 °C in marine broth.</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA at 1–20 °C.</s><s>Growth at 25 °C is weak or negative.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth.</s><s>Grows in 0·25–2·0 M NaCl, with optimal growth occurring in approximately 0·3–0·4 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows poorly in media prepared with 2× strength (70 g l<sup>−1</sup>) sea salts; no growth occurs with 4× strength (140 g l<sup>−1</sup>) sea salts.</s><s>Grows well on trypticase soya agar (TSA) containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl, but grows poorly on TSA and nutrient agar (NA).</s><s>Does not require yeast extract or vitamins for growth, and can use inorganic nitrogen sources such as sodium nitrate and ammonium chloride.</s><s>Grows in mineral salts media with various sole carbon and energy sources, including d-glucose, glycogen, maltose, sucrose and l-proline.</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates on Leifson's O–F medium is undetectable.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, Tween 80, l-tyrosine and aesculin, but not DNA or urea.</s><s>Most strains also decompose starch and weakly degrade casein.</s><s>Produces <em>α</em>-glucosidase and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase or lecithinase, or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic data are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Mean DNA G+C content is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is G#7<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1070<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108525<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from cyanobacterial biofilms attached to the undersides of partially buried quartz stones, found in the Vestfold Hills, an ice-free region of East Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>