<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1666_nm.11098" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11098" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11098" rank="species">Terribacillus halophilus</organism><reference id="rid.1666"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Terribacillus saccharophilus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Terribacillus halophilus sp. nov., spore-forming bacteria isolated from field soil in Japan</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>55</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64340-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17220440</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Terribacillus halophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Terribacillus halophilus</em> (ha.lo.phi′lus. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>halophilus</em> salt-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are the same as those given in the description of the genus, with the following additions.</s><s>Cells are 0.6–0.8×2.8–4.8 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies grown on trypticase soy agar containing 0.5× Herbst's artificial seawater are circular, convex and pale yellow.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 5–45 °C; pH range for growth is 5.0–10.0.</s><s>Growth occurs without NaCl and in the presence of 19 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 1–5 % (w/v).</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and citrate utilization.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, l-arabinose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, gentiobiose and d-tagatose but does not utilize erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, maltose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannitol, but not from glucose, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin or arabinose.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The major quinone system is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 002-051<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15310<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 13937<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from field soil in Tama City (Tokyo, Japan).</s></p></content></protolog>