<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5825_nm.10055" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10055" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10055" rank="species">Echinicola pacifica</organism><reference id="rid.5825"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalinovskaya</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Echinicola pacifica gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel flexibacterium isolated from the sea urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>953</fpage><lpage>958</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64156-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627637</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Echinicola pacifica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Echinicola pacifica</em> (pa.ci′fi.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>pacifica</em> referring to the Pacific Ocean, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are 0.3–0.4×1.2–1.9 μm.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are circular, 2–3 mm in diameter, convex, shiny, smooth, pink-coloured and sunken into agar. <em>β</em>-Galactosidase-positive.</s><s>Does not require Na<sup>+</sup> ions or sea water for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 6–41 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25–28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–12 % NaCl.</s><s>No flexirubin-type pigments are formed.</s><s>Degrades agar, gelatin (weakly), aesculin, Tween 40 and starch.</s><s>Can decompose Tween 20 and 80.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, DNA, cellulose (carboxymethyl-cellulose or filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, dl-xylose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Can oxidize d-galactose and d-sucrose.</s><s>Does not form acid from fucose, melibiose, raffinose, sorbose, glycerol, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Can ferment d-glucose.</s><s>According to the API 20E gallery (bioMérieux), the type strain (KMM 6172<sup>T</sup>) utilizes citrate, forms acid from amygdalin and is negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Results of Biolog GN2 (Biolog) testing show that strain KMM 6172<sup>T</sup> utilizes <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentibiose, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline and l-threonine.</s><s>Does not utilize Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) production are negative.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), produces <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase, but not lipase (C14) or <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Susceptible to lincomycin.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, chloramphenicol, doxycycline, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, carbenicillin, oleandomycin, neomycin, polymixin B, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso (17.3–18.0 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (6.7–7.8 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub> iso <em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (6.3–6.9 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (4.3–4.8 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH (3.4–5.0 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH (9.4–10.0 %) and summed feature 3 (30.7–30.8 %), comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH (Table 1).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44–45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KMM 6172<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12368<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23350<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the sea urchin <em>Strongylocentrotus intermedius</em> collected in Troitsa Bay, Gulf of Peter the Great, the East Sea (also known as the Sea of Japan).</s></p></content></protolog>