<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9280_nm.14565" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14565" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14565" rank="species">Dokdonella ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.9280"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dokdonella ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil from a ginseng field, and emended description of the genus Dokdonell</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1947</fpage><lpage>1952</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004945-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567572</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dokdonella ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dokdonella ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar plates for 2 days are smooth, circular, convex and yellowish.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15 and 42 °C but not at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 5.5 and 6.0, optimum pH is 6.5–7.0 and the maximum pH lies between 9.5 and 10.0.</s><s>Growth occurs on trypticase soy agar and nutrient agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Tolerates 4 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 5 %.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin and casein, but not hydroxyethyl cellulose, xylan, chitin, starch or DNA.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-lyxose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, acetate, valerate, lactate, l-aspartate, l-asparagine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-galactose, d-mannose, l-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, pyruvate, formate, propionate, maleate, fumarate, phenyl acetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, salicin, caprate, citrate, gluconate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, suberate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, oxalate, suberate, d-adonitol, dulcitol, ethanol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, amygdalin, glycerol, methanol, glycogen, inulin, dextran, l-alanine, l-cysteine, glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine and l-valine.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase and acetoin production.</s><s>Negative for indole production, urease, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and hydrogen sulphide production.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, dulcitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N-</em>acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8, and the major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, an unknown phospholipid, two unknown aminophospholipids and three unknown aminolipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 191<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12564<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17954<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52462<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>