<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9684_nm.14827" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14827" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14827" rank="species">Serinibacter salmoneus</organism><reference id="rid.9684"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iino</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K-I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serinibacter salmoneus gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from the intestinal tract of a fish, and emended descriptions of the families Beutenbergiaceae and Bogoriellaceae</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2809</fpage><lpage>2814</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011106-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628613</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Serinibacter salmoneus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Serinibacter salmoneus</em> (sal.mo′ne.us. N.L. masc. adj. <em>salmoneus</em> salmon-coloured, yellowish pink, because the cells grown in liquid culture are yellowish pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following characteristics in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.5×1.0–2.0 μm and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth and yellowish orange, but cells grown in liquid culture are yellowish pink.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is positive, while the methyl red test is negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0–10 % (w/v) but not at 15 %, and the optimal NaCl concentration range for growth is 0–5 %.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, and the optimal temperature is 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0, and the optimal pH is 7.0.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, pyrazinamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase are present, whereas alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine- and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan- and phenylalanine deaminases are absent.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, while gelatin, urea and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge of the cell-wall peptidoglycan is l-Lys–l-Glu.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, followed by iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain Kis4-28<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 104924<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21801<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the intestinal tract of sillago fish (<em>Sillago japonica)</em> collected from Kyonan beach on the coast of Tokyo Bay, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>