<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9946_nm.14924" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14924" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14924" rank="species">Maribaculum marinum</organism><reference id="rid.9946"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Maribaculum marinum gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from deep seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3083</fpage><lpage>3087</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008177-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643895</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maribaculum marinum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maribaculum marinum</em> (ma.ri′num. L. neut. adj. <em>marinum</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 1.2–1.4 μm long and 0.8–0.9 μm wide.</s><s>Negative for lipase (Tween 80), amylase, urease, gelatinase, arginine dihydrolase and indole, hydrolysis of aesculin and reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>On 216L agar, forms smooth, grey colonies with regular edges that are 2–3 mm in diameter after 72 h incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows with 2–12 % NaCl (optimum 3–10 %) and at 10–42 °C (optimum 25–37 °C), but not at 4 or 45 °C after 7 days.</s><s>Unable to ferment glucose.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11-methyl.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc unless otherwise stated) co-trimoxazole (25), ofloxacin (5), tetracycline (30), minomycin (30), penicillin G (10), streptomycin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), neomycin (10), vibramycin (30), piperacillin (100), rocephin (30), kanamycin (30), ampicillin (10), gentamicin (10), rifampicin (5), cephradin (30), chloromycetin (30), carbenicillin (100) and erythromycin (15).</s><s>Resistant to cephalexin (30), cephazolin (30), cefobid (30), clindamycin (2), furazolidone (15), lincomycin (2), metronidazole (5), norfloxacin (10), oxacillin (1), polymyxin B (30 U) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for  acid phosphatase,  alkaline phosphatase, cystine aminopeptidase, leucine aminopeptidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphoamidase, trypsin, valine aminopeptidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>α</em>-glucosidase; weakly positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and lipase (C14); negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>With API 20NE, does not utilize adipic acid, capric acid, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-arabinose, malic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, phenylacetic acid, potassium gluconate or trisodium citrate.</s><s>With GN2 MicroPlates, positive for utilization of l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-threonine, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid; weakly positive for utilization of acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-alanine, d-arabitol, cellobiose, dextrin, d-galacturonic acid, d-serine, glucuronamide, glycogen, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, lactulose, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-leucine, l-serine, maltose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, phenylethylamine, propionic acid, quinic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid; negative for utilization of 2,3-butanediol, 2-aminoethanol, adonitol, bromosuccinic acid, dl-carnitine, dl-lactic acid, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, d-fructose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, d-saccharic acid, d-sorbitol, trehalose, formic acid, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, glycerol, hydroxy-l-proline, i-erythritol, inosine, itaconic acid, l-arabinose, l-fucose, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-rhamnose, malonic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, putrescine, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, sucrose, thymidine, turanose, uridine, urocanic acid, xylitol, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside.</s><s>Table 1 and Supplementary Table S1 show characteristics that can be used to distinguish the type strain from related species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P38<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 208227<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24711<sup>T</sup>=MCCC 1A01086<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from deep seawater of the Indian Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>