<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6695_nm.4175" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4175" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4175" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus barnesae</organism><reference id="rid.6695"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schiefer-Ullrich</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andreesen</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Peptostreptococcus barnesae sp. nov., a Gram-positive, anaerobic, obligately purine utilizing coccus from chicken feces.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>143</volume><fpage>26</fpage><lpage>31</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00414763</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus barnesae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus barnesae</i> (bar'nes. ae. ML. gen. noun <i>barnesae</i> of Barnes, named for Ella M. Barnes, who has contributed much to the knowledge of the avian intestinal microflora)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spherical cells, 0.5 to 0.9 μm in diameter, usually paired, with slime capsules, may form aggregations of 4 to 6 cells, non-motile, non-sporeforming.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, flat, circular, and reach a diameter of 3 to 4 mm.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic; optimum temperature 37 to 40°C growth at 20 to 40°C pH range for growth 7.0 to 9.0, optimum at 7.5 (strain HKB-3) and 8.0 (strains HKB-2 and -5), respectively; chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Utilizes purines such as uric acid, 6,8-dihydroxypurine, guanine, hypoxanthine, and xanthine; adenine and glycine utilized, but not readily.</s><s>Selenite, molybdate, and tungstate, vitamins or 0.01% yeast extract are required for growth, but not Tween 80.</s><s>Acetate, formate, ammonia, and CO<sub>2</sub> are products.</s><s>Hydrogen, sulfide, acetoin, diacetyl, 2,3-butanediol, and butyrate are not produced, indole formation might be feeble.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin, starch, and esculin does not occur.</s><s>No hemolysis was observed.</s><s>Catalase, lecithinase, and urease are not produced, however, lipase.</s><s>Growth is enhanced in the presence of bile salts.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains glycine in position 1 and lysine in position 3 and is crosslinked by D-aspartate.</s><s>The guanosineplus- cytosine content of the DNA is 33.6 to 34.8 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>HKB-5.</s><s>The strain was isolated from fresh chicken feces obtained from a commercial laying hen plant in Göttingen, FRG.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 33.6 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The strain has been deposited in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, FRG, under the accession number DSM 3244.</s></p></content></protolog>