<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1621_nm.10846" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10846" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10846" rank="species">Marinobacter koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.1621"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter koreensis sp. nov., isolated from sea sand in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2653</fpage><lpage>2656</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64231-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082406</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter koreensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>koreensis</em> pertaining to Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, motile by means of a single polar flagellum, moderately halophilic, straight-rod-shaped (0.3–0.5×1.5–3.0 μm) and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies on MA are creamy in colour, circular (1–2 mm) and convex with entire edges after 48 h at 28 °C.</s><s>Temperature, salt and pH ranges for growth are 10–45 °C, 0.5–20 % NaCl and pH 5–9.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed, but alginic acid, casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, DNA, gelatin, pectin, tyrosine, starch and urea are not.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-glutamic acid and l-proline are utilized, and glycogen, succinic acid monomethyl ester and l-leucine are used weakly (Biolog GN2 microplate).</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction, but negative for indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Assimilates malic acid and phenylacetic acid, but does not assimilate d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid or trisodium citrate (API 20NE).</s><s>Enzymic activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>No enzymic activity is observed for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-9.</s><s>The main fatty acids are 16 : 0, summed feature 3 and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 54.1 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DD-M3<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11513<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17924<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sea sand at Homo Cape, Pohang, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>