<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5679_nm.9928" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9928" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9928" rank="species">Enterococcus silesiacus</organism><reference id="rid.5679"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naser</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus silesiacus sp. nov. and Enterococcus termitis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>577</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63937-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus silesiacus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus silesiacus</em> (si.le′si.a.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>silesiacus</em> pertaining to Silesia, the region in the Czech Republic from which the type strain originates).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, ovoid cocci, occurring in pairs, short chains or small groups.</s><s>They elongate in the direction of the chains.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia agar supplemented with sheep blood are non-pigmented, shiny, circular, smooth with entire margins and about 1 mm in diameter after 24 h of cultivation at 37 °C.</s><s>The type strain of the species grows well on Todd–Hewitt agar and brain heart infusion (BHI) agar; growth on MRS medium is less abundant.</s><s>Poor growth on Slanetz–Bartley medium containing 0·04 % sodium azide in small dark-red colonies.</s><s>Growth with positive aesculin reaction on kanamycin/aesculin/azide agar and bile/aesculin agar.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Growth occurs in BHI broth at 10 °C, no growth occurs at 45 °C and is weak in the presence of 6·5 % NaCl and at pH 9·6.</s><s>Positive catalase reaction when cultivated on blood-containing agar, but catalase-negative on blood-free medium.</s><s>Produces arginine dihydrolase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, leucine aminopeptidase, acetoin (Voges–Proskauer test) and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Does not produce alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Hippurate hydrolysis is negative; aesculin hydrolysis is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-trehalose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-melibiose, sucrose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from l-arabinose (strain W213 is weakly positive in API 50 CH kit, but negative using API 20 Strep; strain W442<sup>T</sup> is negative) and gluconate (strain W213 is positive, W442<sup>T</sup> is negative) is variable.</s><s>The G+C content of strains W213 and W442<sup>T</sup> is 35·6 and 36·7 mol%, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, W442<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7319<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23085<sup>T</sup>), and the other strain, W213 (=CCM 7318=LMG 23084), were isolated from surface waters.</s></p></content></protolog>