<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1802_nm.2949" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2949" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2949" rank="species">Vibrio aestuarianus</organism><reference id="rid.1802"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tison</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidler</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio aestuarianus: a New Species from Estuarine Waters and Shellfish.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>699</fpage><lpage>702</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-699</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio aestuarianus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio aestuarianus</i> (aes.tu.a.ri.a'nus. L.n. <i>aestuarium</i> estuary; N.L. masc. adj. <i>aestuarianus</i> pertaining to an estuary)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>V. aestuarianus</i> is strain OY-0-002 (=ATCC 35048). <i>V. aestuarianus</i> is a gram-negative, oxidase-positive, straight or curved, rod-shaped bacterium which is motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Cells are about 0.5 μm wide and 1.5 to 2.0 μm long when they are Gram stained. <i>V. aestuarianus</i> grows without swarming on Trypticase soy, blood, thiosulfate-citratebile salts-sucrose, and MacConkey agars containing 0.5% NaCl.</s><s>No growth is observed in media lacking NaCl.</s><s>The type strain and six of eight other strains failed to grow in media containing 7% NaCl.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 20 to 25°C but also occurs at 5 and 37°C but not 42°C. <i>V. aestuarianus</i> is facultatively anaerobic and produces beta-hemolysis on sheep blood agar, indole, catalase, gelantinase, deoxyribonuclease, <i>ortho</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranosidase, and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, collagenase, and elastase are not produced.</s><s>No strain tested produced luminescence on marine agar, acetoin (Voges-Proskauer test), or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>All <i>V. aestuarianus</i> strains tested produced acid without gas in less than 72 h at 37°C from D-amygalin, D-glucose, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, sorbitol, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>The type strain and most of the other strains tested produced acid from cellobiose (seven of nine strains), glycerol (eight of nine strains), and melibiose (seven of nine strains).</s><s>No strain produced acid from adonitol, L-arabinose, dulcitol, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salkin, or xylose.</s><s>The key characteristics of <i>V. aestuarianus</i> are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antimicrobial susceptibility.</s><s>All <i>V. aestuarianus</i> strains tested were susceptible to vibriostatic agent O/129 (10-μg disk) and to amikacin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, colistin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nitrofurantoin, tetracycline, tobramycin, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole at standard concentrations with the disk diffusion method (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The DNA base composition of the <i>V. aestuarianus</i> type strain is 43.2 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s><s>The DNA base compositions of the eight other strains tested range from 43 to 44 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA relatedness.</s><s>The results of DNA-DNA competition experiments conducted under supraoptimal conditions (melting temperature -15°C) (Table 1) show that the nine estuarine isolates represent a genetic species with ≥84% relatedness to <i>V. aestuarianus</i> type strain OY-0-002.</s><s>The <i>V. aestuarianus</i> type strain was found to be genetically distinct (&#x003C;25% relatedness) from other <i>Vibrio</i> species with similar DNA base compositions and the type or reference strains of phenotypically similar species (<i>Vibrio anguillarum</i>, <i>Vibrio damsela</i>, <i>Vibrio diazotrophicus</i>, <i>Vibrio nereis</i> and <i>Vibrio spendidus</i>).</s><s>Generally, DNAs from strains of the same species are 160% related under supraoptimal reassociation conditions (melting temperature -15°C in this case), whereas species within the same genus are usually &#x003C;30% related under supraoptimal reassociation conditions (3).</s><s>Under optimal conditions for hybridization (melting temperature 25°C), the relatedness value between species (e.g., between <i>V . aestuarianus</i> and <i>Vibrio alginolyticus</i>) may increase to as much as 50 to 60%, but it would still be less than that observed between strains within a species.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Vibrio</i> sp. strains UNCC 1077, UNCC 1084, and UNCC 1085, which were isolated from the  southeastern United States coast, were included in the DNA homology studies because these strains were phenotypically similar to <i>V. aestuarianus</i> and to strains grouped in cluster 111 in the numerical taxonomy study of lactose-fermenting marine vibrios by Oliver et al. (9).</s><s>Strains UNCC 1077, UNCC 1084, and UNCC 1085 were not genetically related to <i>V. aestuarianus</i> at the species level (Table 1).</s><s>An extensive phenotypic characterization of these strains and the strains in cluster 111 described by Oliver et al. (9) indicated that the strains isolated from the southeastern United States coast are probably <i>V . diazotrophicus</i>, a recently described species capable of nitrogen fixation (4).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. aestuarianus</i> is easily distinguished from pathogenic lactose-fermenting <i>Vibrio</i> spp. by its arginine dihydrolase activity and lack of ornithine and lysine decarboxylases. <i>Vibrio cholerae</i> and <i>Vibrio vulnificus</i> may also ferment lactose; however, these species lack arginine dihydrolase activity and usually decarboxylate lysine and ornithine.</s><s>Characteristics which are useful in distinguishing <i>V. aestuarianus</i> from other arginine dihydrolase-positive <i>Vibrio</i> species are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The public health significance of <i>V. aestuarianus</i> remains to be determined.</s><s>However, the association of this species with crabs, clams, and oysters warrants an investigation into the potential of <i>V. aestuarianus</i> strains as not only shellfish pathogens but also human pathogens since raw or improperly cooked shellfish serve as vehicles of infection by other pathogenic <i>Vibrio</i> species.</s></p></content></protolog>