<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3223_nm.1660" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1660" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1660" rank="species">Limnobacter thiooxidans</organism><reference id="rid.3223"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Limnobacter thiooxidans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel thiosulfate-oxidizing bacterium isolated from freshwater lake sediment.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1463</fpage><lpage>1470</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491347</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Limnobacter thiooxidans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Limnobacter thiooxidans</i> (thi.o.ox'i.dans. Gr. n. <i>thion</i> sulfur;M.L. v. <i>oxido</i> to make acid, oxidize;M.L. part. adj. <i>thiooxidans</i> oxidizing sulfur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slightly curved rods with pointed ends, 1.5-3.7 μm long with a diameter of 0.6-1.5 μm.</s><s>They occur singly or in short chains and are motile by single polar flagella.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is not deposited intra- or extracellularly during growth on media containing thiosulfate.</s><s>Colonies on R2A medium reach a diameter of 0.8-1.0 mm and are circular, smooth, translucent and flat with entire margins.</s><s>Aggregates are formed during growth in liquid culture.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.5-10.5.</s><s>Yeast extract and vitamins are not required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite by strain CS-K2<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Several carboxylic acids and amino acids are used as sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The following compounds were identified as substrates for growth by the Biotype 100 system: fumarate, succinate, L-malate, L-aspartate and L-glutamate.</s><s>In the presence of an organic substrate, thiosulfate can be used as an energy source, enabling chemolithoheterotrophic growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 55 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>Isolated from the littoral sediment of a freshwater lake.</s><s>The type strain is strain CS-K2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM13612<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19593<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>