<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8549_nm.13587" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13587" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13587" rank="species">Rothia terrae</organism><reference id="rid.8549"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rothia terrae sp. nov. isolated from soil in Taiwan.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>84</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65172-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175688</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rothia terrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rothia terrae</em> (ter′rae. L. gen. n. <em>terrae</em>, of the earth, referring to the organism being isolated from soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain L-143<sup>T</sup> forms visible cream-white colonies, circular and convex in shape with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, non-motile, ovoid to spherical, 0.5–1.0 μm in width and 0.5–1.5 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur either singly or in pairs or tetrads.</s><s>Non-pigmented.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 15–40 °C, in the presence of 0–7.0 % NaCl and at pH 5–10.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 35 °C, with 0–0.5 % NaCl and at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, mannose, glycerol and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol or salicin.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-positive.</s><s>Starch, casein, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60 and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide production is not detected on triple-sugar iron agar.</s><s>Positive (API Coryne) for nitrate reduction, pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and acid production from d-glucose, d-maltose, d-lactose and d-sucrose.</s><s>Negative (API Coryne) for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, urease and acid production from d-ribose, d-xylose, d-mannitol and glycogen.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative (API ZYM) for C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (Biolog GP2 system): dextrin, glycogen, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, 3-methyl-d-glucose, d-psicose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-serine and glycerol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized (Biolog GP2 system): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-galactoside, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-galactoside, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, d-tagatose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine-5′-monophosphate, thymidine-5′-monophosphate, uridine-5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin and nalidixic acid; sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, novobiocin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A3<em>α</em> containing lysine, glutamic acid and alanine.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol, with some unknown phospho- and glycolipids as minor components.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-15 : 0, anteiso-17 : 0 and 16 : 0.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 56.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, L-143<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17588<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23708<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wasteland soil in Tainan County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>