<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2196_nm.3099" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3099" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3099" rank="species">Escherichia vulneris</organism><reference id="rid.2196"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McWhorter</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leete Knutson</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Escherichia vulneris: a new species of Enterobacteriaceae associated with human wounds.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>1133</fpage><lpage>1140</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7107843</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Escherichia vulneris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Escherichia vulneris</i> (vul.ner'is. L.n. <i>vulnus</i> a wound; L. gen. n. <i>vulneris</i> of a wound; <i>Escherichia vulneris</i> the Escherichia of a wound)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and description of <i>E. vulneris</i>.</s><s>Biochemical test reactions for 61 <i>E. vulneris</i> strains and for the type strain are shown in Table 4. <i>E. vulneris</i> is a gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, nonsporeforming rod.</s><s>It is motile, with peritrichous flagella (Fig. 1), reduces nitrate to nitrite, ferments glucose and other carbohydrates with the production of acid and gas, has 58 to 59 mol% G+C in its DNA, and is isolated from wounds and other human clinical specimens. <i>E. vulneris</i> strains are positive in the methyl red test, and most utilize malonate.</s><s>They give a negative Voges-Proskauer reaction, do not produce indole, urea, or H<sub>2</sub>S, and do not utilize citrate.</s><s>They ferment D-mannitol, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, and melibiose.</s><s>They do not ferment dulcitol, adonitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, erythritol, or D-arabitol.</s><s>Strains give variable reactions for the fermentation of lactose, sucrose, and salicin, with many being delayed (3 to 7 days) positive.</s><s>They are negative in tests for phenylalanine deaminase and ornithine decarboxylase, usually positive for lysine decarboxylase, and delayed positive for arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>They are negative in tests for corn oil, DNase, and gelatin liquefaction.</s><s>More than one-half of <i>E. vulneris</i> strains produce a yellow pigment.</s><s>A further description of <i>E. vulneris</i> is found in the tables and text.</s><s>The type strain  (holotype) is ATCC 33821 (CDC 875-72), isolated from the intestine of a cowbird in Michigan.</s></p></content></protolog>