<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6843_nm.8139" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8139" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8139" rank="species">Capnocytophaga haemolytica</organism><reference id="rid.6843"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kajiura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Capnocytophaga haemolytica sp. nov. and Capnocytophaga granulosa sp. nov., from human dental plaque.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>324</fpage><lpage>329</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-324</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Capnocytophaga haemolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Capnocytophaga haemolytica</i> (hae.mo.ly'ti.ca. Gr. n. <i>haema</i>, blood; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; M. L. fem. adj. <i>haemolytica</i>, blood dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are thin, gram-negative rods (2 to 4 by 0.2 to 0.3 μm).</s><s>Flat, thin colonies are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 5 to 7 days of anaerobic incubation at 37°C on TBBP agar.</s><s>Beta-hemolysis is observed on TBBP agar after primary isolation isolation is reduced or lost after a few subcultures.</s><s>The colonial</s></p><p class="description"><s>colors are gray or purple on TBBP agar and blood agar but yellow or orange on Trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Pellets of cells obtained by centrifugation after washing with distilled water are yellow or orange.</s><s>Cultures grow under microaerophilic conditions and can grow well on blood agar incubated at 37°C in the presence of 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and esculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Susceptible to actinomycin D.</s><s>Produces acids from D-glucose, glycogen, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannose, starch, and D-sucrose; 63% of the strains produce acids from dextran and inulin.</s><s>Negative for oxidase activity, catalase activity, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and indole production.</s><s>No acid is produced from cellulose, D-mannitol, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, and D-xylose.</s><s>No aminopeptidase activity is observed with the substrates listed in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products of glucose fermentation are acetate and succinate.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are i-15:O (13-methyltetradecanoic) and 18:O (octadecanoic) acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 to 44 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A0404 (= JCM 8565) is the type strain of C. haemolytica.</s><s>The characteristics of this strain are the same as those given above for the species.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of this strain is 44.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>