<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.17_nm.6814" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6814" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6814" rank="species">Saccharothrix waywayandensis</organism><reference id="rid.17"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lyons</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharothrix texasensis sp. nov. and Saccharothrix waywayandensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>358</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharothrix waywayandensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix waywayandensis</i> (way. way. an. den' sis. L. adj. <i>waywayandensis</i>, referring to the source, Lake Waywayanda, N.J., of the soil samples from which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium is pale yellow to dark yellow.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white, when it is produced, particularly on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Casein, esculin, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine, and urea are hydrolyzed; adenine, allantoin, cellulose, guanine, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, lactate, DL-malate, oxalate, propionate, and succinate are assimilated; benzoate, mucate, and tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose; no acid is produced from dulcitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, and D-sorbitol.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 5% NaCl but not in the presence of 7% NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 37°C.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 71 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S . waywayandensis</i> is strain NRRL B-16159 (=LL-37Z-15).</s></p></content></protolog>