<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5484_nm.2509" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2509" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2509" rank="species">Halomonas israelensis</organism><reference id="rid.5484"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huval</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Latta</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kushner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vreeland</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of two new species of Halomonas: Halomonas israelensis sp.nov. and Halomonas canadensis sp.nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>1124</fpage><lpage>1131</lpage><source id="217">Canadian Journal of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Can J Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0008-4166</issn><essn>1480-3275</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8542554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas israelensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas israelensis</i> (iz.ra.len.sis; an inhabitant of Israel)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Halomonas israelensis</i> (ATCC 43985T) appears as straight Gram-negative rods with rounded ends and divides by transverse fission.</s><s>Single cells predominate. occasionally producing paired cells and short chains.</s><s>Pleomorphic cells are not present.</s><s>Colonies growing at 3O°C on complex CAS medium with 8% w/v NaCl are 2-6 mm wide in 7 days with entire margins.</s><s>Colonies are flat with nondiffusible cream pigment and grow aerobically from pH 5.0 to 9.0 in CAS medium with 8% NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs when NaCl concentration is 8.0% w/v and the growth temperature is 3O°C.</s><s>Colonies grow in media with 3.5-20% NaCl from 15 to 45°C, without added NaCl from 15 to 30°C and in 32% w/v NaCl from 30 to 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Halomonas israelensis</i> requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth.</s><s>It is catalase positive, oxidase negative, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase positive, and phenylalanine deaminase negative.</s><s>It grows in elevated CO<sub>2</sub> (candle jar) on complex medium with 8% NaCl, reduces NO<sub>3</sub> to NO<sub>2</sub>. produces indole. grows only at the surface of thioglycollate-containing 8% NaCl, and is urease and methyl red negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S (TSI, SIM) and acetyl methyl carbinol are not produced.</s><s>Colonies are insensitive to valinomycin, monensin, aphidicolin, penicillin G, ampicillin. and streptomycin when tested at 8% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species utilizes mannose, aesculin, cellobiose, lactose, glycerol, starch, gluconic acid, and sucrose as its sole carbon sources in chemically defined medium with 8% w/v NaCl It produces acid, but no gas, from mannose, lactose, glycerol, and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of this species is 64 mol% by bouyant density.</s><s>The DNA shows 49% homology to <i>H. elongala</i> ATCC 33173<sup>T</sup> and 20% homology to <i>H. canadensis</i> NRCC 41227<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>DNA homology was determined by the dot blot method. <i>Halomonas isradensis</i> was isolated in 1968 from the Dead Sea by Rafaeli-Eshkol (1968).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species is ATCC 43985.</s></p></content></protolog>