<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5592_nm.4001" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4001" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4001" rank="species">Clostridium puniceum</organism><reference id="rid.5592"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lund</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brocklehurst</surname><given-names>T.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wyatt</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of strains of Clostridium puniceum sp. nov., a pink-pigmented, pectolytic bacterium.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>122</volume><fpage>17</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium puniceum</i> sp.nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium puniceum</i> (pu.ni'ce.um. L.adj. <i>puniceus</i> pink)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods 0.6 x 1.8 to 4.2 μm occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Forms boat-shaped, clostridial cells containing granulose and in which spores are subsequently produced in a subterminal position.</s><s>Free spores are oval and surrounded by an extensive exosporium in which are arrays of subunits showing a hexagonal periodicity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On potato infusion agar after incubation under H<sup>2</sup>/CO<sup>2</sup> (9:1, v/v) for 4 d at 25°C typical colonies are circular, 1 to 2 mm in diameter, convex, amorphous, smooth, undifferentiated, edge entire, pale pink, opaque, viscid and difficult to emulsify.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 23 to 33 OC and the range is 7 to 39°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs in media without a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Raw potato tissue is macerated and pectate, starch, gelatin and casein are hydrolysed; some strains fail to hydrolyse casein.</s><s>Major fermentation products from glucose are butyric and acetic acids and butanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are used as carbon sources for growth and acid production: amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Some strains are also able to utilize glycogen, inulin, mannitol, melezitose and ribose, but fail to utilize raffinose.</s><s>Dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, rhamnose, sorbitol and sorbose are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: NCIB 11596 (= BL70/20)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA of the type strain is 28 to 29 mol% (by <i>T<sub>m</sub></i>)</s></p></content></protolog>