<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6378_nm.7971" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7971" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7971" rank="species">Bacteroides oris</organism><reference id="rid.6378"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Churn</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides oris and Bacteroides buccae, a new species from human periodontitis and other human infections.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>125</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides oris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides oris</i> (or'is. L. gen. n. <i>oris</i> of the mouth [referring to a major natural habitat of the species])</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>B. oris</i> cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, nonmotile, gram-negative rods.</s><s>In peptone-yeast extract-glucose (PYG) broth cultures, cells were 0.5 to 0.8 by 0.8 to 2.6 μm and were arranged in pairs and short chains (Fig. 2).</s><s>In supplemented brain heart infusion agar roll tubes (9, subsurface colonies were 1 to 2 mm in diameter, lenticular, and translucent.</s><s>On anaerobically incubated streak tubes or blood agar plates, surface colonies were 0.5 to 1.O mm in diameter, circular with an entire edge, low convex, translucent to semiopaque, white to buff, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>There was no action on rabbit blood or egg yolk agar (6).</s><s>Cultures did not grow on the surface of blood agar plates incubated in air enriched with carbon dioxide to 10%.</s><s>After incubation at 37°C for 24 h in prereduced broth media, cultures were uniformly turbid with a smooth sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation for 3 to 5 days, the pH in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate generally ranged as follows: 4.5 to 4.9 in carbohydrates fermented by all strains and 5.0 to 5.6 in media with sugars that were not fermented by all strains (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains fermented dextrin, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, rafinose, starch, and sucrose; all hydrolyzed esculin and starch; all produced an acid curd in milk.</s><s>None of the strains fermented erythritol, inositol, mannitol, melezitose, sorbitol, or trehalose; none digested milk or meat; none reduced nitrate; none produced indole or catalase.</s><s>Most strains did not grow in PYG broth containing 10% bile; when growth in bile did occur, it was markedly inhibited and delayed.</s><s>Heme was highly stimulatory for growth of the type strain and was required for growth of some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acids produced in PYG broth cultures (in meq/100 ml of culture) were acetic (1 to 2) and succinic (7 to 8).</s><s>Very small amounts of isobutyric and isovaleric acids were detected in some cultures.</s><s>No hydrogen was detected in the headspace gas from PYG broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and 50% of the other strains were susceptible to all five antibiotics tested (chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin G, and tetracycline).</s><s>Fifty percent of the strains were resistant to 2 U of penicillin G per ml, and 20% of the strains were resistant to 6 μm of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain was 42 mol% and ranged from 42 to 46 mol% among the strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 33573 (= VPI D1AlA), isolated from the gingival sulcus of a person with moderate periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species have been isolated from human periodontal flora, from systemic human infections, and from the large intestines of chickens.</s><s>In addition to the sources given in Table 1, human isolates (identified by PAGE patterns) have been obtained from face, neck, and chest abscesses and drainages; abdominal wound drainages and peritoneal fluid; blood; and spinal fluid.</s><s>Strain VPI 7649 (= ATCC 27518, originally deposited as a representative of <i>B. ruminicola</i> subsp. <i>brevis</i> biovar 3) is a strain of <i>B. oris</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>