<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1350_nm.4239" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4239" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4239" rank="species">Eubacterium callanderi</organism><reference id="rid.1350"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mountfort</surname><given-names>D.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asher</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium callanderi sp. nov. that demethoxylates O-methoxylated aromatic acids to volatile fatty acids.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>254</fpage><lpage>258</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-254</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium callanderi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium callanderi</i> (call.and'er. i. L.gen.n. <i>callanderi</i>, named in honor of John Callander for his pioneering work on anaerobic digestion of wood based materials)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Eubacterium callanderi</i> is obligately anaerobic, and cells are nonmotile, nonsporulating rods (0.9 μm wide and 1.5 to 3.0 μm long) which are gram positive in young cultures.</s><s>Cell walls contain the peptidoglycan components muramic acid, glucosamine, lysine, ornithine, serine, glutamic acid, and alanine, but diaminopimelic acid is not present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism cleaves the phenylether bonds of the methoxylated aromatic substrates ferulate, sinapate, syringate, vanillate, 3,4,5-trimethoxycinnamate, and vanillin to give the corresponding hydroxyaromatic derivatives and acetate, butyrate, and formate (26).</s><s>In addition, lactate and H, are produced from the fermentation of glucose.</s><s>No reduction of SO<sub>4</sub><sup>2-</sup> or NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> occurs during fermentation of glucose or methoxylated aromatic compounds (26).</s><s>Methanol, H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, formate, carbon monoxide, and isoleucine are not utilized for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The best conditions for growth are in basal medium supplemented with 5% rumen fluid.</s><s>No growth occurs on glucose in defined medium (rumen fluid absent) unless acetate is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0 to at least 8.5, and the pH optimum is 7.0 (26).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 25 to 43°C, and the optimum temperature is 37°C (26).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base ratio is 47 mol% G+C (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain FD (= DSM 3662).</s><s>The organism was isolated from an anaerobic digestor receiving contents from a wood fiber-to-alcohol fermentation plant.</s></p></content></protolog>