<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7159_nm.5275" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5275" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5275" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus sciuri rodentium</organism><reference id="rid.7159"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ballard</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Webster</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubner</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tomasz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Couto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sloan</surname><given-names>G.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dehart</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Lencastre</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sanches</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heath</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leblanc</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ljungh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ribotype delineation and description of Staphylococcus sciuri subspecies and their potential as reservoirs of methicillin resistance and staphylolytic enzyme genes.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>323</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103615</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus sciuri</i> subsp. <i>rodentium</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus sciuri</i> subsp. <i>rodentium</i> (ro.den'ti.um. L. plur. gen. noun <i>rodentium</i>, of rodents)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics of 18 strains isolated in 1992.</s><s>Colonies grow to 6 ± 2 mm in diameter on P agar and to 10 ± 1 mm in diameter on TSA.</s><s>The concentric ridges formed at the edges of colonies are usually higher and wider than the ridges observed in the other subspecies.</s><s>Growth in the anaerobic portion of semisolid thioglycolate medium ranges from no detectable growth to weak, delayed growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperatures are 35°C on P agar and 35 to 40°C on TSA.</s><s>Growth is absent or very poor at 45°C.</s><s>Culture growth produces partial hemolysis (greening) of bovine blood.</s><s>Some strains (39% of the strains) produce greening of horse blood.</s><s>All strains produce acid aerobically from D-mannose, D-trehalose, and D-mannitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from α-lactose.</s><s>Other characteristics of <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>rodentium</i> that are uniformly positive or negative for the species are listed above.</s><s>The variable characteristics for this subspecies are listed in Table 3.</s><s>The two API STAPH-IDENT profiles are 5710 (67%) and 4710 (33%); the major STAPH Trac profile is 6336150 (72%).</s><s>The major ribotype pattern type is dd 4761 (75%).</s><s>Six different ribotype patterns have been described (Fig. 1).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35 mol%.</s><s>This subspecies is found mainly living on rodent hosts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>rodentium</i> is DD 4761 (= ATCC 700061), which was isolated from the skin of a Norway rat.</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies described above and, in addition, the properties listed below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spherical cells (diameter, 1.0 to 1.2 μm) occur singly, in pairs, and in tetrads.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular P-agar colonies are 6 to 7 mm in diameter, have moderately undulate edges, are raised, are smooth with glistening surfaces, are translucent, and have a light yellow-gray pigment.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are 9 to 10 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Delayed weak growth occurs in the anaerobic portion of thioglycolate medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Partial hemolysis (greening) of bovine blood occurs.</s><s>No hemolysis of horse and sheep blood occurs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No alkaline phosphatase activity and moderate staphylolytic enzyme activity.</s><s>Positive latex agglutination test for clumping factor and/or protein A.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate amounts of acid are produced aerobically from D-sorbitol, salicin, D-mannitol, D-trehalose, and D-fucose.</s><s>Very weak acid is produced from D-cellobiose and maltose.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-mannose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-melezitose, α-lactose, and α-L-rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intermediate resistance to oxacillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type dd 4761 ribotype pattern.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidiglycan is L-Lys-L-Ala-Gly<sub>3</sub>,L-Ser<sub>0.1</sub> the teichoic acid is polyglycerolphosphate-glucose (polyglycerolphosphate substituted by glucose).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>