<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8679_nm.13435" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13435" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13435" rank="species">Microbacterium ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.8679"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>T.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soung</surname><given-names>N.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium ginsengisoli sp. nov., a beta-glucosidase-producing bacterium isolated from soil of a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>429</fpage><lpage>433</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65226-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218944</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium ginsengisoli</em> (gin.seng.i.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, heterotrophic, strictly aerobic, non-motile, short rods, about 0.3–0.4 μm in width and 0.6–0.8 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 2 days are smooth, circular, convex, transparent and yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs at 18–30 °C, pH 5–9 and in the presence of up to 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>Negative for aerobic and anaerobic nitrate reduction.</s><s>Aesculin and DNA are hydrolysed, but starch, xylan, gelatin, chitin, cellulose and skimmed milk are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following carbon sources in the API 50 CH test: fructose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, glycerol and mannitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-fucose, galactose, gentiobiose, lactose, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, sorbitol, xylitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, starch, amygdalin, arbutin, inulin, salicin and glycogen.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in the API 20NE and API 32GN tests: d-glucose, maltose, mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, inositol, mannitol, l-alanine, l-proline, l-serine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, acetate, gluconate, malate, propionate and valerate.</s><s>Negative for the utilization of the following substrates: l-arabinose, l-fucose, melibiose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-histidine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, glycogen, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, adipate, caprate, citrate, itaconate, d- and l-lactate, malonate, phenylacetate and suberate.</s><s>In API ZYM assays, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ornithine.</s><s>Cell-wall sugar is rhamnose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-11 and MK-12.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 259<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19189<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18659<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from a ginseng field in Pocheon in the Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>