<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8351_nm.13731" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13731" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13731" rank="species">Kiloniella laminariae</organism><reference id="rid.8351"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wiese</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thiel</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gärtner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmaljohann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kiloniella laminariae gen. nov., sp. nov., an alphaproteobacterium from the marine macroalga Laminaria saccharina.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>350</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001651-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196777</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kiloniella laminariae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kiloniella laminariae</em> (la.mi.na′ri.ae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Laminaria</em> botanical name of a genus of macroalgae; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>laminariae</em> pertaining to the alga <em>Laminaria</em>, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described above for the genus.</s><s>Cells are slender, slightly curved spirilla, 0.5–0.6 μm wide and 2.5–5.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells carry monopolar flagella.</s><s>Pigments are not produced.</s><s>Colonies are cream in colour and grow up to 1–2 mm in diameter on MB agar.</s><s>Grows at 4–40 °C, pH 3.5–9.5 and from 0.3–10 % artificial sea salts.</s><s>Salt is required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth at 25 °C, pH 5.5 and 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs chemoheterotrophically under oxic conditions.</s><s>Nitrate is used as an alternative electron acceptor under anoxic conditions.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to N<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>Carbon sources (Biolog GN2) used are glycogen, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, dl-lactate, succinamate, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, glycyl l-aspartate, glycyl l-glutamate, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamate, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanate, inosine, uridine and glycerol.</s><s>Enzyme activities are observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained in tests for esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Furthermore, the API 20NE test system shows strong activities of arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Negative reactions occur in tests for indole production, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, H<sub>2</sub>S production and gelatinase.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LD81<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14374<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14845<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a specimen of <em>Laminaria saccharina</em> collected from the Baltic Sea in the Kiel Bight (Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>