<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.258_nm.3550" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3550" rank="genus">Desulfobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.258"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bak</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Widdel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerobic degradation of indolic compounds by sulfate-reducing enrichment cultures, and description of Desulfobacterium indolicum gen. nov. spec. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>146</volume><fpage>170</fpage><lpage>176</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00402346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfobacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfobacterium</i> (De.sul'fo.bar L. pref. <i>de</i> from; L. noun <i>sulfur</i> sulfur; Gr. neut. dim. noun <i>bakterion</i> a small rod; M.L. neut. n. <i>desulfobacterium</i> a rod-shaped sulfate reducer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oval to rod-shaped, non-sporing stulfate reducers.</s><s>Formate; butyrate, higher fatty acids, suecinate, fumarate, malate or pyruvate are usually used as electron donors and carbon sources.</s><s>Growth on acetate or propionate is very slow.</s><s>Several species use H<sub>2</sub> and grow autotrophically.</s><s>Lactate is often used, too.</s><s>Aromatic compounds originating from anaerobic decomposition of amino acids may be used by a number of species.</s><s>Organic electron donors are completely oxidized to COa.</s><s>Sulfate is the common electron acceptor being reduced to sulfide.</s><s>Most isolates reduce also sulfite or thiosulfate, but not elemental sulfur or nitrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobes that have to be cultivated in anoxic, sulfide-reduced media.</s><s>The majority of <i>Desulfobacterium</i> species requires vitamins and brackish or marine concentrations of NaCl and MgCl<sub>2</sub> for optimum growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain cytochromes of the b- and c-type.</s><s>Carbon monoxide dehydrogenase activity is commonly observed.</s><s>Desulfoviridin is not present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine + cytosine content of the DNA ranges between 41 and 48 mol%. <i>Desulfobacterium</i> species are widespread in brackish or marine sediments, but occur less frequently in freshwater habitats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>D. autotrophicum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>