<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6342_nm.10057" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10057" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10057" rank="species">Sandarakinotalea sediminis</organism><reference id="rid.6342"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sandarakinotalea sediminis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>959</fpage><lpage>963</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64055-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627638</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sandarakinotalea sediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sandarakinotalea sediminis</em> (se.di′mi.nis. L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of sediment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, 0.5–0.7 μm in width and 3–5 μm in length.</s><s>Cells may form longer filaments of 5–10 μm after longer incubation (6–7 days).</s><s>Colonies are circular or irregular.</s><s>Growth is supported by 10, 30, 50 and 70 % (v/v) artificial sea water.</s><s>Growth in 1/5-strength LB requires NaCl and either potassium or magnesium salt.</s><s>Starch, DNA and gelatin are depolymerized.</s><s>Agar, cellulose, CM-cellulose, chitin, aesculin and urea cannot be degraded.</s><s>Indole from tryptophan and acid from glucose are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, maltose, mannitol, monomethyl succinate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine are oxidized.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methylpyruvic acid, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate are not oxidized.</s><s>Mannose is oxidized only by strain CKA-5<sup>T</sup> and inosine only by strain CKA-36.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CKA-5<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 100970<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23247<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediment collected on the Pacific Ocean coast at Katsuura, Japan.</s><s>Reference strains are strains CKA-11 (=NBRC 100971), CKA-36 (=NBRC 100973) and CTO-75 (=NBRC 100972), isolated from marine sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>