<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2104_nm.5812" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5812" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5812" rank="species">Actinobaculum urinale</organism><reference id="rid.2104"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inganäs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobaculum urinale sp. nov., from human urine.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>679</fpage><lpage>682</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02422-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807186</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinobaculum urinale</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinobaculum urinale</em> (u.ri.na′le. N.L. neut. adj. <em>urinale</em> pertaining to urine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved Gram-positive rods.</s><s>Branching is not observed.</s><s>Cells are non-acid-fast and non-spore-forming.</s><s>After 48 h anaerobic incubation on fastidious anaerobe agar with 5 % horse blood, colonies are &#x003C;1 mm in diameter, convex, smooth, entire-edged, grey or white and weakly <em>β</em>-haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Lactic acid is the major end product of glucose metabolism, together with minor amounts of acetic acid.</s><s>Using the commercially available API systems, acid is produced from glucose and ribose; acid production from maltose and sucrose is variable and dependent on the test system used.</s><s>Acid is not formed from d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, sorbitol, tagatose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed but gelatin and aesculin are not.</s><s>Arginine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and proline arylamidase are produced and urease may or may not be detected.</s><s>Alanine–phenylalanine–proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, cysteine arylamidase, esterase C-4, ester lipase C-8, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, lipase C-14, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, phosphoamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, serine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Indole-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types, with C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> predominating.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 46093<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107424<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human urine.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>