<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8334_nm.13752" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13752" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13752" rank="species">Paramoritella alkaliphila</organism><reference id="rid.8334"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hosoya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paramoritella alkaliphila gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Moritellaceae isolated in the Republic of Palau.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>411</fpage><lpage>416</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65809-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196787</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paramoritella alkaliphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paramoritella alkaliphila</em> (al.ka.li.phi′la. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>alkaliphila</em> loving alkaline conditions).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are as given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, approximately 2.0–4.0 μm long and 0.8–1.0 μm wide.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase-positive.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 30 °C; growth occurs at 15 and 37 °C and no growth occurs at 8 or 40 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 7.0–11.0 and the optimum pH for growth is 9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs at a seawater strength of 0.3–1.4× ASW (NaCl at 0.9–4.2 %, w/v).</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for degradation of aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite (API 20E; bioMérieux).</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose by fermentation (API 20NE) and is also formed oxidatively from ribose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and gluconate (API 50 CH).</s><s>Does not decompose tyrosine or urea or produce indole.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase (API 20NE), lipase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Does not produce acid from glycerol, erythritol, dl-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate (API 50 CH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is about 57 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, A3F-7<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC06429<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19956<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from hard coral collected from Iwayama Bay in the Republic of Palau.</s><s>A reference strain, ssthio04PA2-7c (=MBIC08307), was isolated from marine sand collected in the Republic of Palau.</s></p></content></protolog>