<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7625_nm.14051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14051" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14051" rank="species">Mariniflexile fucanivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7625"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Barbeyron</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>L'Haridon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Michel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Czjzek</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mariniflexile fucanivorans sp. nov., a marine member of the Flavobacteriaceae that degrades sulphated fucans from brown algae.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2107</fpage><lpage>2113</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65674-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768613</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mariniflexile fucanivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mariniflexile fucanivorans</em> [fu.ca′ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>fucanum</em> fucan (polyfucose); L. part adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring from L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <em>fucanivorans</em> fucan-devouring].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-flagellated, Gram-negative rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 3.0–4.0 μm long, occurring singly or in pairs, with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells are non-motile in the liquid phase but show active gliding motility on solid surfaces.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are circular, shiny, dark yellow and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days.</s><s>Spreading does not occur at the colony margins.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 25 °C; growth occurs between 4 and 32 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5; growth does not occur at pH 5.0 or 10.0.</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 2.5 % (w/v) and no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl or at concentrations &#x003E;6 % (w/v).</s><s>Under optimal growth conditions, the doubling time is around 3.0 h.</s><s>Catalase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, alkaline and acid phosphatases, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, trypsin and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activities are present, but cytochrome oxidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activities are absent.</s><s>Aesculin, DNA, dextrin, glycogen, starch, alginic acid, ι-carrageenan and sulphated fucan are hydrolysed, but Tweens 40 and 80, agar, <em>κ</em>-carrageenan and gelatin are not.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-mannose, d-lactose, maltose, cellobiose, gentiobiose and glucuronic acid are used as carbon sources, but l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, sucrose, raffinose, glycerol, d-mannitol, adonitol, d-arabitol, l-erythritol, inositol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, trehalose, d-xylose, d-ribose, l-fucose, maltose, d-lactose, cellobiose, gentiobiose, amygdalin, mannitol, xylitol, starch, glycogen, arbutin and salicin, but not from d- or l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, melezitose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-xylose, l-sorbose, sucrose, raffinose, glycerol, erythritol, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, d- or l-arabitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine or inulin (API 50CH).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) streptomycin (200) and kanamycin (200), but not in presence of penicillin (200), ampicillin (200), rifampicin (10), tetracycline (10) or chloramphenicol (10).</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SW5<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109502<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18792<sup>T</sup>), isolated from mud collected from a water-treatment facility recycling the effluent of an alginate-extraction plant at Landerneau, Brittany, France.</s></p></content></protolog>