<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2523_nm.9710" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9710" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9710" rank="species">Terrabacter terrae</organism><reference id="rid.2523"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Montero-Barrientos</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monte</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roig</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Terrabacter terrae sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from soil in Spain</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2491</fpage><lpage>2495</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63768-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280515</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Terrabacter terrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Terrabacter terrae</em> (ter′rae. L. gen. n. <em>terrae</em> of the earth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are long irregular rods 2·0×6·0 μm in length.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is not formed.</s><s>Gram-positive in young and old cultures, non-motile, non-spore-forming and aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are glossy and yellow on feather and nutrient agar.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, with simple nutritional requirements.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory; acid is not produced from glucose or other carbohydrates.</s><s>A wide range of organic compounds are utilized for growth, including glucose, mannitol, citrate and chicken feathers.</s><s>Does not assimilate arabinose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Esterase lipase, lipase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, keratinase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and valine aminopeptidase are produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase, leucine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not produced.</s><s>Negative for DNase decomposition, nitrate reduction, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Negative for decomposition of aesculin and Tween 80.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse urea, arginine, gelatin, starch and casein.</s><s>The ll-diaminopimelic acid-containing peptidoglycan of group A3<em>γ</em> has three glycine residues as an interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The main menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The fatty acid profile represents the iso, anteiso type, with 13-methyl tetradecanoic acid and 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid predominating.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 71 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PPLB<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 3379<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22921<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from soil mixed with Iberian pig hair.</s></p></content></protolog>