<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2819_nm.5109" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5109" rank="genus">Paenibacillus</organism><reference id="rid.2819"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ash</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Molecular identification of rRNA group 3 bacilli (Ash, Farrow, Wallbanks and Collins) using a PCR probe test. Proposal for the creation of a new genus Paenibacillus.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>260</lpage><source id="227">Antonie van Leeuwenhoek</source><issn>0003-6072</issn><essn>1572-9699</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00873085</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8085788</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus</i> (pae. ba. cillus., L. adv. paene, almost; bacterial name, bacillus; N.L. mas. n; <i>Paenibacillus</i> almost a bacillus, because it derives from this genus but is phylogenetically distinct.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from several sources (Claus &#x0026; Berkeley 1986).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods of Gram-positive structure but usually stain negatively in the laboratory Gram stain.</s><s>Cells are non-pigmented and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>They differentiate into ellipsoidal endospores that distinctively swell the sporangium.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Acid and sometimes gas are produced from various sugars including glucose and with odd exceptions cellobiose, galactose, raffinose and salicin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol and sorbitol.</s><s>ONPG is hydrolysed.</s><s>Urease-negative (with exception of <i>B. validus</i>) and arginine dihydrolase negative.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized and no growth occurs in the presence of 10% sodium chloride.</s><s>Macromolecules are commonly degraded by extracellular enzymes including carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, protein and starch but not all species hydrolyse all of these substrates.</s><s>The diamino acid in the peptidoglycan is <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and the major isoprenoid quinone is an unsaturated menaquinone with seven isoprene units.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatly acids are primarily of the straight-chain saturated, <i>anteiso</i> and <i>iso</i>-branched types with <i>anteiso</i>-C<sub>15</sub> predominating.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40-54 mole %.Isolated largely from decomposing plant materials and humus-enriched soils.</s><s>The type species is <i>P. polymyxa</i> (oldest member of the group).</s></p></content></protolog>