<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4859_nm.1348" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1348" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1348" rank="species">Sinorhizobium saheli</organism><reference id="rid.4859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maestrojuan</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neyra</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dreyfus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomy of Rhizobia: emendation of the genus Sinorhizobium and description of Sinorhizobium meliloti comb. nov., Sinorhizobium saheli sp. nov., and Sinorhizobium teranga sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>715</fpage><lpage>733</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sinorhizobium saheli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sinorhizobium saheli</i> (sa'hel.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>saheli</i>, of the Sahel, the region in Africa where the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide by 1.5 to 2 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of one or several polar or subpolar flagella in liquid medium.</s><s>Grows on YMA at temperatures up to 44°C.</s><s>On YMA the colonies are circular, white, semi-translucent, and convex.</s><s>When there is confluent growth, the white centers of the original colonies have a marbled appearance.</s><s>A wide range of carbohydrates, organic acids, and amino acids are utilized as sole carbon sources for growth.</s><s>Distinguishing features are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Grows on L-citrulline and glycolate but not on xylitol.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from <i>Sesbania</i> species in the Sahel area and can nodulate different <i>Sesbania</i> species, <i>Acacia seyal</i>, <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>, and <i>N. oleracea</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level this species can be differentiated from other <i>Sinorhizobium</i> species and related genera by the results of DNA-DNA hybridization and DNA-rRNA hybridization experiments, by the SDS-PAGE patterns of proteins, and by the sequence of the 16s rRNA genes.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 65 to 66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain ORS 609 (= LMG 7837) is the type strain; the phenotypic characteristics of this organism are shown in Table 2.</s><s>All <i>Sinorhizobium saheli</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Ghent, Ghent, Belgium, and in the Culture Collection of the Laboratory of Soil Microbiology, ORSTOM, Dakar, Senegal.</s></p></content></protolog>