<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8373_nm.13335" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13335" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13335" rank="species">Gracilibacillus halophilus</organism><reference id="rid.8373"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus halophilus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from saline soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2403</fpage><lpage>2408</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65698-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilibacillus halophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gracilibacillus halophilus</em> (ha.lo′phi.lus. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt; N.L. masc. adj. <em>philus</em> from Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>halophilus</em> salt-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase- and oxidase-positive, obligately aerobic, thin rods (4–8×0.3–0.5 μm) that occur predominantly in flexible chains (5–10 cells).</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Filamentous forms are present throughout the growth cycle.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in terminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 3 days on HSMA15 (pH 7.0) at 45 °C, colonies are circular, creamy white and translucent with slightly irregular margins and 1–1.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Moderately halophilic, with optimum growth at 15 % (w/v) NaCl and a growth range of 7–30 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Moderately thermophilic, with optimum growth at 45–50 °C and a growth temperature range of 28–60 °C.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of chitin, aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tween 80, but negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests and hydrolysis of casein and urea.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (20 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg), but sensitive to ampicillin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Positive for oxidation of arabinose, inositol, sorbitol, amygdalin, rhamnose, sucrose and melibiose and fermentation of glucose, but negative for citrate utilization (API 20E).</s><s>Acids are produced from d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-tagatose, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate and acids are produced weakly from d-glucose, glycogen, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, amygdalin, melibiose and sucrose (API 50CH).</s><s>Oxidizes acetic acid, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, l-alanine and l-asparagine (Biolog GP2).</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Menaquinone 7 (MK-7) is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (making up 77.9 % of the total in the type strain) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM-C55.5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17856<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.6303<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil sample collected from a beach of the Xiaochaidamu salt lake in the Qaidam Basin, Qinghai Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>