<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6839_nm.4709" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4709" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4737" rank="species">Mycoplasma ovis</organism><reference id="rid.6839"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Neimark</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoff</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ganter</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma ovis comb. nov. (formerly Eperythrozoon ovis), an epierythrocytic agent of haemolytic anaemia in sheep and goats.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>371</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02858-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023944</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycoplasma ovis</em> comb. nov. (basonym Neitz, Alexander and du Toit 1934)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycoplasma ovis</em> (o′vis. L. fem. n. <em>ovis</em> a sheep).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Epierythrocytic parasite of sheep and goats.</s><s>Giemsa stain shows small, round bodies attached to the surface of erythrocytes.</s><s>Erythrocytes can reach 100 % infection.</s><s>Organisms also are observed free in the blood during periods of fever in heavily parasitized animals.</s><s>By using phase-contrast microscopy, <em>M. ovis</em> appears as a round cell.</s><s>Cells seen in thin sections by EM are round or oval bodies of 0·3–0·4 μm diameter and are applied closely to the erythrocyte membrane.</s><s>A 20–30 nm wide electron-dense layer partially surrounds many of the organisms. <em>M. ovis</em> can produce mild to severe anaemia in normal sheep.</s><s>Infections are frequently unapparent.</s><s>Mortality from infection is rare, but anaemia and failure to gain weight occur in lambs. <em>M. ovis</em> is reported to share antigens with <em>M. wenyonii</em> (Kreier &#x0026; Ristic, 1963).</s><s>Organisms in blood can be preserved by freezing untreated blood at −18 °C (M.</s><s>Ganter, unpublished results) or in 10 % DMSO (v/v) at −70 °C (Brun-Hansen <em>et al.</em>, 1997); 10 % horse serum/10 % glycerol, which is used for freezing other mycoplasmas at −70 °C, should also be suitable.</s><s>Transmission is by blood-feeding arthropods, including ticks [<em>Haemaphysalis plumbeum</em> and <em>Rhipicephalus bursa</em> (Nikol'skii &#x0026; Slipchenko, 1969)] and mosquitoes [<em>Aedes camptorhynchus</em> (Howard, 1975) and <em>Culex annulirostris</em> (Daddow, 1980)].</s><s>The stable fly (<em>Stomoxis calcitrans</em>) would appear to be a potential vector and subcutaneous injection of sheep with a suspension of fly material has resulted in infection, but transmission under natural conditions has not been demonstrated (Overas, 1969); similarly, injection of head lice (<em>Linognathus ovillas</em>) has also produced infection in sheep (Foogie &#x0026; Nisbet, 1964).</s><s>An attempt to transmit the disease by removing sheep keds (the blood-sucking wingless fly <em>Melophagus ovinus</em>) from carrier sheep and injecting them intravenously into a splenectomized sheep (Neitz, 1937) or a normal susceptible sheep (Foogie &#x0026; Nisbet, 1964) did not produce visible infection.</s><s>Infections can be transmitted by reusing needles during herd immunization and as a very small number of infected erythrocytes is sufficient to transmit disease (Mason &#x0026; Statham, 1991), it has been suggested that blood on tools during shearing or ear-tagging may contribute to spread in flocks (Brun-Hansen <em>et al.</em>, 1997).</s><s>Oral transmission has been shown experimentally (Overas, 1969). <em>M. ovis</em> occurs in sheep-rearing regions throughout the world.</s></p></content></protolog>