<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10578_nm.17828" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17828" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17828" rank="species">Jeongeupia naejangsanensis</organism><reference id="rid.10578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>N.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jeongeupia naejangsanensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a cellulose-degrading bacterium isolated from forest soil from Naejang Mountain in Korea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>615</fpage><lpage>619</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012591-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jeongeupia naejangsanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jeongeupia naejangsanensis</em> (nae.jang.san.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>naejangsanensis</em> pertaining to Naejangsan, the Korean name of Naejang Mountain, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.3–0.7×0.7–2.5 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular to slightly irregular, flat, smooth, glistening, greyish-yellow in colour and 3.0–5.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 50 °C, but not at 4 or 55 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.0, but not at pH 4.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth in the presence of 0–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs on TSA and on TSA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Cellulose is degraded.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, l-tyrosine, urea, xanthine, and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Glucose is fermented.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as carbon and energy sources: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, l-arabitol, caprate, citrate, fructose, gluconate, glucose, d-lyxose, malate, mannose, ribose and xylitol.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon and energy sources: adipate, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, galactose, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, phenylacetate, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system: positive for leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; weakly positive for esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8); and negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, lincomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin or penicillin G.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BIO-TAS4-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22633<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 57610<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil from Naejang Mountain, Jeongeup city, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.8 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>