<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4765_nm.3274" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3274" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3274" rank="species">Proteus penneri</organism><reference id="rid.4765"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of Proteus penneri sp. nov., formerly known as Proteus vulgaris indole negative or as Proteus vulgaris biogroup 1.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>1097</fpage><lpage>1102</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7050147</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Proteus penneri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Proteus penneri</i> (The species name is treated as a neo (modern) Latin genitive noun, <i>penneri</i>, meaning "of Penner," and is coined to honor John L. Penner, a Canadian microbiologist who has made many contributions to studies of the three genera in the tribe <i>Proteeae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. penneri</i> has the general characteristics of the genus <i>Proteus</i>, which are as follows: positive tests for urea hydrolysis, phenylalanine deaminase, gelatin hydrolysis, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and tyrosine clearing; swarming on blood agar; a negative test for D-mannose fermentation; and resistance to colistin.</s><s>The following tests are positive for most <i>P. penneri</i> strains: methyl red; motility; growth in the presence of KCN; and fermentation of D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, and D-xylose.</s><s>The following tests are negative for all or most <i>P. penneri</i> strains: indole production; Voges-Proskauer; lysine and ornithine decarboxylase (Møllers); arginine dihydrolase (Møllers); malonate utilization; fermentation of adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, <i>i</i>-(<i>myo</i>)-inositol, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, and mucate; esculin hydrolysis; and acetate utilization.</s><s>The proposed type strain is CDC 1808-73 (ATCC 33519).</s><s>The G+C content of this strain is 38 mol%.</s><s>A more detailed description of the new species is given in Tables 2, 3, and 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The <i>P. penneri</i> strains were resistant to chloramphenicol by both agar diffusion and broth dilution methods.</s><s>We suspect that this resistance is intrinsic rather than plasmid-mediated because some of our strains were isolated in the 1960s and have been stored over a long period of time, yet all of them have remained resistant.</s><s>The biogroup 2 strains were all sensitive to chloramphenicol; however, preliminary data on biogroup 3 suggest that it may contain both sensitive and resistant strains. von Graevenitz and Nourbakhsh (15) reported that 14% of 66 indole+ strains of <i>P. vulgaris</i> were resistant to chloramphenicol.</s><s>Perhaps these strains belong in biogroup 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It now appears that the indole reaction, along with the reactions for salicin and esculin, separate what was previously known as <i>P. vulgaris</i> into three groups.</s><s>In this study we have shown that the indole<sup>-</sup>, salicin<sup>-</sup>, esculin<sup>-</sup>, chloramphenicol-resistant group is a separate species.</s><s>Our study and a previous study (3) indicate that the biogroup 2 strains also represent a separate species.</s><s>Biogroup 3 is currently the group that should be designated <i>P. vulgaris</i> since the type strain belongs to this group.</s><s>We are currently collecting strains in this group so that a full study can be conducted.</s><s>This study must be completed before a logical classification can be proposed for biogroups 2 and 3, which are still classified as <i>P. vulgaris</i>.</s><s>Table 7 gives a summary of our current classification of the genus <i>Proteus</i> and the tests that are useful for differentiation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The clinical significance of <i>P. penneri</i> is unknown.</s><s>There was one blood isolate, but no other clinical information was available for this strain.</s><s>Perhaps this report will stimulate others to look for this organism and help define its ecology and role in human disease.</s><s>Clinical laboratories should suspect <i>P. penneri</i> for a Proteus strain that is indole- and has a small zone around chloramphenicol but otherwise resembles <i>P. vulgaris</i>.</s><s>Salicin<sup>-</sup>, esculin<sup>-</sup>, ornithine decarboxylase negative, and maltose positive reactions would differentiate it from <i>P. vulgaris</i> and <i>P. mirabilis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>