<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2351_nm.2812" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2812" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2812" rank="species">Alteromonas colwelliana</organism><reference id="rid.2351"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiner</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coyne</surname><given-names>V.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brayton</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>West</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raiken</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alteromonas colwelliana sp. nov., an isolate from oyster habitats.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>240</fpage><lpage>244</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-240</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas colwelliana</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas colwelliana</i> (col. well' i. a. na. L. fem. adj. <i>colwelliana</i>, named for Rita Colwell for her contributions to marine microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on one strain.</s><s>Pleomorphic cells 0.5 to 1.5 μm in diameter and 1.0 to 20 μm long when growing on surfaces, in nutrient-poor media, or during late growth phases.</s><s>Helical forms sometimes evident.</s><s>In rich media, motile cells 0.7 to 1.5 μm in diameter and 1.0 to 3.0 μm long occur.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>No endospores.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Single polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On marine agar 2216 young colonies are circular and about 1 mm diameter, with convex elevations and undulate margins.</s><s>After 1 week of incubation their form becomes irregular, and they enlarge to 5 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In liquid media, growth produces uniform turbidity without pellicle.</s><s>In rich media (e.g., brain heart infusion medium  containing 3% NaCl [final concentration, 3.5%]), large agar 2216 young colonies are circular and about 1 mm diameter, with convex elevations and undulate margins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 1 week of incubation their form becomes irregular, and they enlarge to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>In liquid media, growth produces uniform turbidity without pellicle.</s><s>In rich media (e.g., brain heart infusion medium containing 3% NaCl [final concentration, 3.5%]), large masses of mucoid flocculates form.</s><s>On all media, cells adhere to the surface of the growth vessel.</s><s>In media containing less than 0.5% glucose, <i>A. colwelliana</i> turns the media dark brown during late growth phases.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Amino acids are required for growth; L-aspartic acid and L-glutamic acid together support growth as carbon sources (28).</s><s>Yeast extract is growth stimulating.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 8 to 30°C.</s><s>Most rapid growth occurs at 25°C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration for optimum growth is 2 to 4% (wt/vol).</s><s>The NaCl growth range is 1 to 5%.</s><s>The optimum pH range is 7.4 to 7.8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Constitutive glucose phosphopyruvate transferase system not detected.</s><s>Marine broth 2216 and brain heart infusion medium (Difco) become alkaline with growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, gelatinase, amylase, deoxyribonuclease, and phosphatase are produced.</s><s>Grows on asparagine, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, fumarate, L-histidine, and α-ketoglutarate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>No acid produced from arbutin, trehalose, sucrose, D-cellobiose, D-mannose, myoinositol, D-mannitol, sorbitol, salicin, and L-arabinose in OF basal medium (Difco).</s><s>Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Sensitive to dyes except neutral red.</s><s>Resistant to bile, vibriostatic agent 0/129, and tellurite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to 20 mg of rifampin per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Autochthonous to estuarine oyster water.</s><s>Not known to be associated with diseased invertebrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LST-W (= ATCC 39565).</s></p></content></protolog>