<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3876_nm.9487" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9487" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9487" rank="species">Arthrobacter castelli</organism><reference id="rid.3876"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbeeren</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Six novel Arthrobacter species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1457</fpage><lpage>1464</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63358-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014466</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter castelli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter castelli</em> (cas.tel′li. L. gen. n. <em>castelli</em> of the castle).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods and cocci (diameter 0·8–1 μm) occurring in pairs and chains.</s><s>They are non-motile and do not form endospores.</s><s>Colonies on NA after 48 h are small (&#x003C;1 mm), light yellow, round with entire margins, of low convexity, opaque and smooth.</s><s>No growth in an anaerobic chamber on NA.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 22–37 °C.</s><s>Weak growth at 15 °C and no growth at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Poor growth on media without NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>By using the API CORYNE system, positive reactions are observed for pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and urease.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for nitrate reduction, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, aesculin (<em>β</em>-glucosidase), gelatinase and fermentation of glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose and glycogen.</s><s>By using the API ZYM system, activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase (weak), esterase C<sub>4</sub> (weak), esterase lipase C<sub>8</sub>, lipase C<sub>14</sub> (weak), leucine arylamidase, trypsin (weak), phosphoamidase (weak) and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (approximately 51 and 23 %, respectively).</s><s>Peptidoglycan type, menaquinone content and cell wall sugars are given in Table 1.</s><s>Polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, one unknown phospholipid and one unknown glycolipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA, determined for the type strain LMG 22283<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16402<sup>T</sup>), is 68·1 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a rosy biofilm overgrowing a mural painting in the Saint-Catherine chapel (castle of Herberstein, Austria).</s></p></content></protolog>