<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2752_nm.9785" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9785" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3438" rank="species">Aggregatibacter segnis</organism><reference id="rid.2752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nørskov-Lauritsen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans, Haemophilus aphrophilus, Haemophilus paraphrophilus and Haemophilus segnis as Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans gen. nov., comb. nov., Aggregatibacter aphrophilus comb. nov. and Aggregatibacter segnis comb. nov., and emended description of Aggregatibacter aphrophilus to include V factor-dependent and V factor-independent isolates.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64207-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aggregatibacter segnis</em> (Kilian 1977) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aggregatibacter segnis</em> (seg′nis. L. masc. adj. <em>segnis</em> slow, sluggish).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Haemophilus segnis</em> Kilian 1977.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small, pleomorphic rods, often showing a predominance of irregular, filamentous forms.</s><s>Colonies on chocolate agar are smooth or granular, convex, greyish white and opaque, and may take 48 h to reach a diameter of 0.5 mm.</s><s>Growth in broth and fermentation media is slow, and reactions are negative or weakly positive.</s><s>V but not X factor is required; CO<sub>2</sub> enhances growth for some strains.</s><s>Small amounts of acid result from the fermentation of glucose, fructose, galactose, sucrose and maltose.</s><s>Fermentation of sucrose is usually stronger than fermentation of glucose.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, salicin, sorbose, sorbitol, trehalose and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Catalase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (hydrolysis of ONPG) are variably present.</s><s>Only quantitative differences in the amount of acid produced from carbohydrates may discriminate <em>Aggregatibacter segnis</em> phenotypically from strains of <em>H. parainfluenzae</em> biotype V (negative for indole, urease and ornithine decarboxylase).</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>Aggregatibacter segnis</em> is a regular member of the human oral flora, particularly in dental plaque, and can be isolated from the pharynx.</s><s>It has occasionally been isolated from human infections including infective endocarditis.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43–44 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HK316<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 33393<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 10787<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 12838<sup>T</sup>=CIP 103292<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 10977<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is M75043.</s></p></content></protolog>