<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2249_nm.9671" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9671" rank="genus">Salinispora</organism><reference id="rid.2249"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maldonado</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fenical</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kauffman</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mincer</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bull</surname><given-names>A.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinispora arenicola gen. nov., sp. nov. and Salinispora tropica sp. nov., obligate marine actinomycetes belonging to the family Micromonosporaceae.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1759</fpage><lpage>1766</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63625-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166663</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinispora</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinispora</em> (Sa.li.ni.spo′ra. N.L. adj. <em>salinus</em> saline; Gr. fem. n. <em>spora</em> a seed and, in bacteriology, a spore; N.L. fem. n. <em>Salinispora</em> a spore-forming bacterium originating from a saline habitat, indicating the marine habitat of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon information taken from this study and from Mincer <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast actinomycetes that form extensively branched substrate hyphae (0·25–0·5 μm in diameter) that carry smooth-surfaced spores (0·8–3·8 μm in diameter) singly or in clusters (Fig. 3).</s><s>All strains require sea water or a sodium-supplemented medium for growth.</s><s>Colonies first appear within 3–6 weeks depending on the growth medium.</s><s>They are recognized by their lack of aerial hyphae and their pigmentation; the latter ranges from bright to pale orange to black on M1 medium.</s><s>Spreading substrate mycelia are formed on low-nutrient media M4 and M5.</s><s>Dark brown to black, bright orange or pink diffusible pigments are frequently produced.</s><s>Colonies can become darkened during sporulation, with spores borne either sessily or on short sporophores.</s><s>Vegetative hyphae are finely branched and do not fragment.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 10–30 °C and pH 7–12.</s><s>Arbutin (0·1 %, w/v), casein (1 %, w/v), elastin (3 %, w/v), gelatin (0·4 %, w/v) and starch (1 %, w/v) are degraded, but not cellulose (1 %, w/v), chitin (0·2 %, w/v), tributyrin (0·1 %, v/v) or xylan (0·4 %, w/v).</s><s>(+)-d-Cellobiose, <em>α</em>-lactose, (+)-d-melezitose and starch are used as sole carbon sources, but not (+)-d-fructose, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-d-ribose, (−)-l-sorbose or (+)-d-xylose (all at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Good growth occurs in the presence of gentamicin sulphate (5 and 25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), neomycin sulphate (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), novobiocin (5 and 25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), penicillin G (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and rifampicin (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Strains contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid of the wall peptidoglycan; major amounts of arabinose, galactose and xylose in whole-organism hydrolysates; diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol as diagnostic polar lipids; tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the major isoprenologue; and complex mixtures of saturated iso- and anteiso-fatty acids; but lack mycolic acids.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids (as a percentage of total fatty acid content) are 13-methyltetradecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>; 3·7–13·3 %), 14-methylpentadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>6 : 0</sub>; 36·4–53·5 %), 16-methylheptadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub>; 3·5–10·2 %), heptadecanoic acid (C<sub>17 : 0</sub>; 4·1–7·8 %) and 10-methyloctadecanoic acid (C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 10 methyl; 0·9–6·8 %).</s><s>The muramic acid moiety of the cell wall is glycolated.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA lies within the range 70–73 mol%.</s><s>Unique nucleotide signatures are present at positions 207 (A), 366 (C), 467 (U) and 1456 (G) of the 16S rRNA gene.</s><s>Abundant and widespread in tropical marine sediments.</s><s>The type species is <em>Salinispora arenicola</em>.</s><s>The genus is a member of the family <em>Micromonosporaceae</em> Krasil'nikov 1938 emend. Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em> 1997.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Scanning electron micrograph of <em>Salinispora tropica</em> CNB-440<sup>T</sup> growing on ISP medium 2 supplemented with NaCl (3·5 %, w/v), after incubation at 28 °C for 4 weeks.</s><s>Magnification ×8000.</s><s>Bar, 1 μm.</s></p></content></protolog>