<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7466_nm.5871" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5871" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5871" rank="species">Arthrobacter rhombi</organism><reference id="rid.7466"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Osorio</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barja</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter rhombi sp. nov., isolated from Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides)</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1217</fpage><lpage>1220</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425782</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter rhombi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter rhombi</i> (rhom'bi. L. masc. N. <i>rhombus</i> flatfish; rhombi of flatfish)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods and cocci.</s><s>They are non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>On BHA, smooth convex colonies which are yellowish or whitish in colour and with a diameter of approx. 1 mm are formed after 48 h.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1% (w/v) and 10% (w/v) NaCl and at 4 and 30°C.</s><s>They are strictly aerobic and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>By using the API CORYNE system, positive reactions for β-galactosidase and esculinase are observed.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for nitrate reductase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, urease, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and gelatinase.</s><s>Using the API 50CH system, the following substrates are used as sole carbon sources: glycerol, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, gluconate and D-arabitol.</s><s>Erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, inositol, N-acetyl-β-glucosamine, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate are not utilized.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is A4α (L-Lys-L-Ala-D-Glu).</s><s>The G + C content of DNA is 61 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>Isolated from organs of Greenland halibut (<i>Reinhardtius hippoglossoides</i>) in the deep waters of the Flemish Cap fishing ground (Newfoundland, NW Atlantic).</s><s>The type strain, CCUG 38813<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from the spleen of <i>Reinhardtius hippoglossoides</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>