<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5868_nm.6245" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6245" rank="species">Corynebacterium minutissimum</organism><reference id="rid.5868"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium aurimucosum sp. nov. and emended description of Corynebacterium minutissimum Collins and Jones (1983).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1001</fpage><lpage>1005</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02045-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054216</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium minutissimum</i> Collins and Jones (1983) emend. Yassin et al. (2002)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on the studies of the type strain DSM 20651<sup>T</sup> (Collins &#x0026; Jones, 1983) as well as our own observations. Surface colonies on blood agar are circular, about 1 mm in diameter, low convex with entire margins, and not pigmented; the surface are shiny and moist. On BHI agar supplemented with 1% Tween 80 the organism form coralloid precipitin in agar when grown either aerobically or in an atmosphere of CO<sub>2</sub>. Cells are Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming, non-motile and exhibit some pleomorphism. Catalase-positive. Facultatively anaerobic and non haemolytic. The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acids. As well as arabinose and galactose as cell-wall sugars (i.e. cell-wall chemotype IV). Short-chain mycolic acids (28 to 36 carbon atoms) are present. The fatty acid profile contains saturated, unsaturated and tuberculostearic acid. The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol dimannoside, and some glycolipids (i.e. phospholipid type PI). Major menaquinone components are MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>). Acid is produced from fructose, glucose, maltose and sucrose. No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, trehalose and xylose. Acetoin production is positive. Indole is not produced. Aesculin, gelatin and hippurate are not hydrolysed. Pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase or leucine arylamidase activities are positive. Nitrate is not reduced. Urease is not produced. Acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), lipase (C14), α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucoseaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, naphthol-AS-bi-phosphohydrolase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin or chemotrypsin activities are negative. The G+C content is 58 mol% for the type strain and ranges from 56 to 58 mol% for the species. The type strain of <i>Corynebacterium minutissimum</i> is strain DSM 20651<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 10288<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24143<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>