<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12274_nm.20281" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20281" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20281" rank="species">Hwanghaeicola aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.12274"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chae</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hwanghaeicola aestuarii gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a tidal flat of the Yellow Sea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2877</fpage><lpage>2881</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021048-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20081009</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hwanghaeicola aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hwanghaeicola aestuarii</em> (aes.tu.a′ri.i L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of the tidal flat, from where the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the traits reported for the genus description, cells are 0.8–1.2 μm in diameter and colonies on MA are pale-pink, convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 15–35 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum pH 6.5–7.5) and with 1.5–6.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2.0–3.0 %).</s><s>Urea, aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>ONPG, indole, tryptophan deaminase and the Voges–Proskauer test are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced and citrate is not utilized (API 20E kit).</s><s>Negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, malic acid, potassium gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase activities are present, but trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Resistant to polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, ampicillin, oleandomycin, lincomycin, tetracycline and carbenicillin, but sensitive to penicillin G, chloramphenicol and novobiocin.</s><s>Does not grow in media with NaCl as a sole salt, but grows in media containing Na<sup>+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup> ions.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.0 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Y26<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 13705<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22009<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a tidal flat of the Taean coast in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>