<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5293_nm.9689" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9689" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9689" rank="species">Streptomyces pharetrae</organism><reference id="rid.5293"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Le Roes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyers</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces pharetrae sp. nov., isolated from soil from the semi-arid Karoo region</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>28</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>488</fpage><lpage>493</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.03.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16104349</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces pharetrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces pharetrae</em> (pha.re’trae L. [Gr.] fem. n. <em>pharetra</em> meaning quiver [container for arrows], isolated from soil taken from the base of a Giant quiver tree [<em>Aloe pillansii</em>]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain CZA14<sup>T</sup> is an aerobic, Gram-positive actinomycete which forms green aerial mycelium and yellow-blue substrate mycelium on ISP4 (inorganic salts–starch agar).</s><s>The colour of the substrate mycelium is not pH sensitive.</s><s>No fragmentation occurs and no verticils are present.</s><s>Mature spore chains are of the <em>Spirales</em>-type with hairy spore ornamentation.</s><s>Spores are non-motile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth is observed on Czapek Solution agar, yeast extract malt extract agar (ISP2) and inorganic salts–starch agar (ISP4).</s><s>Substrate mycelium colour is medium-dependent, but aerial mycelium colour is constant.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced on glycerol–asparagine agar (ISP5).</s><s>Melanin is produced on peptone–yeast extract–iron agar (ISP6), but not on tyrosine agar (ISP7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Weak antibiosis is exhibited against <em>Bacillus coagulans</em> ATCC 7050<sup>T</sup>, <em>Mycobacterium aurum</em> A+ and <em>Acinetobacter calcoaceticus</em> C91, but there is no antibiosis against <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 27853 and <em>Staphylococcus aureus</em> ATCC 25923.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain CZA14<sup>T</sup> grows in the presence of 0.3% 2-phenylethanol, 0.0001% crystal violet, 7% NaCl (but not 10%) and 0.1% phenol, but not in the presence of sodium azide (0.01%).</s><s>Growth was also observed in the presence of cephaloridine (100 μg/ml), lincomycin (100 μg/ml), penicillin G (10 IU/ml) and rifampicin (50 μg/ml), but not in the presence of neomycin (50 μg/ml) and streptomycin (100 μg/ml).</s><s>Growth was observed at 30, 37 and 45 °C, but not at 4 °C or at pH 4.3.</s><s>CZA14<sup>T</sup> uses <em>β</em>-alanine, dl-alanine, ammonium phosphate, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, potassium nitrate, l-proline, l-serine, urea and l-valine, but not dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>n</em>-butyric acid as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>It uses dextran, d(−) fructose, d(+) glucose, <a href="content/mmlsi2.ml"><em>α</em></a>-methyl-d-glucoside, glycerol, glycogen, d(−) ribose, sodium butyrate and sodium sorbate as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, meso-erythritol, meso-inositol, inulin, maltose, d(+) melibiose, d(+) melezitose, raffinose, salicin, sodium benzoate, sodium formate, sodium lactate, sodium maleate, sodium oxalate, sodium salicylate, sodium l(+) tartrate, trehalose or xylitol.</s><s>Weak growth was observed after 21 days on l(+) arabinose, d(−) lactose, d(−) mannitol, d(+) mannose, l(+) rhamnose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium gluconate, sodium dl-malate, sodium succinate, sucrose and d(+) xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production occurs and nitrate is reduced (weak reaction after 14 days).</s><s>Lecithinase, protease and lipase activities are observed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Pectin is hydrolysed, but not hippurate.</s><s>Strain CZA14<sup>T</sup> degrades adenine, aesculin, arbutin, casein, cellulose, gelatine, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine, Tween 80 and urea.</s><s>Starch hydrolysis is negative at 7 days, but weakly positive when tested at 14 days and 21 days.</s><s>Allantoin, guanine, xanthine and xylan are not degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 76.0 (±1.4)%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CZA14<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41856<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24333<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>