<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4509_nm.3095" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3095" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3095" rank="species">Escherichia albertii</organism><reference id="rid.4509"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janda</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Escherichia albertii sp. nov., a diarrhoeagenic species isolated from stool specimens of Bangladeshi children.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>807</fpage><lpage>810</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02475-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807204</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Escherichia albertii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Escherichia albertii</em> [al.ber′ti.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>albertii</em> of Albert, named after M. John Albert, a microbiologist previously associated with the ICDDR,B, who first described these strains as a group of <em>Hafnia</em>-like diarrhoeagenic isolates in the early 1990s and who also contributed greatly to the study of other diarrhoeagenic bacteria (Albert, 1994; Albert <em>et al.</em>, 1991a, 1992a, 2000)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on data reported previously by Ridell <em>et al.</em> (1995) and Janda <em>et al.</em> (1999, 2002) and on API 50CH profiling performed in the course of this study.</s><s>All five isolates display the following characteristics typical of the genus <em>Escherichia</em>: cells are Gram-negative, medium to long rods, chemo-organotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism, cytochrome oxidase-negative and catalase-positive and acid and gas are produced from d-glucose.</s><s>Growth occurs after 24 h at 35–37 °C on TSA medium.</s><s>Cells are non-motile at 35 °C.</s><s>Positive for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, methyl red reaction and nitrate reduction but negative for arginine dihydrolase, indole, DNase, urease, gelatinase and Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>No growth in KCN broth.</s><s>Acetate but not citrate or malonate are used as carbon sources.</s><s>3-Hydroxybenzoate but not 2-ketogluconate or histidine is assimilated.</s><s><em>β</em>-d-Glucuronidase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose and d-mannitol but not from adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, lactose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, d-sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Fermentation of d-maltose and d-trehalose is variable (negative for strains LMG 20972 and LMG 20974).</s><s>By disc diffusion testing, resistant to tetracycline and penicillin but susceptible to chloramphenicol, kanamycin and ampicillin (except strain LMG 20974).</s><s>All strains are partially or completely susceptible to cephalothin by the E-test.</s><s>The G+C content is 50·5–50·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain Albert 19982<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 20976<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 46494<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the stool specimen of a diarrhoeal child in Bangladesh.</s><s>The G+C content of this strain is 50·6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>