<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9569_nm.14745" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14745" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14745" rank="species">Halobacillus salsuginis</organism><reference id="rid.9569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhuang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halobacillus salsuginis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium from a subterranean brine</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2505</fpage><lpage>2509</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010801-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622644</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halobacillus salsuginis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halobacillus salsuginis</em> (sal.su′gi.nis. L. gen. fem. n. <em>salsuginis</em> of/from brine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, moderately halophilic, catalase- and oxidase-positive, aerobic rods, approximately 0.5–0.9 μm wide and 1.5–3.0 μm long, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Cells bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in subterminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are cream-coloured, of low convexity and semi-translucent with circular/slightly irregular margins, and are 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation for 3–5 days at 30 °C on MA5.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–23 % (w/v) total salts (optimum, 5–10 %) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 7.5) and 10–45 °C (optimum, 30 °C).</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup> ions are required for growth.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and phenylalanine deaminase, but negative for methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, nitrite reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production, and lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease.</s><s>Aesculin, DNA, gelatin, starch and Tween 40 are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose, hypoxanthine, Tweens 20, 60 and 80, tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-arabitol, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole source of carbon and energy or sole source of carbon, nitrogen and energy: l-arabinose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, raffinose, sucrose, adonitol, d-sorbitol, l-alanine, l-asparagine and l-serine.</s><s>The following are not utilized: cellobiose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, acetate, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, succinate, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, d-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-proline and l-valine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8), but not acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc): ampicillin (30), carbenicillin (30), chloramphenicol (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), lincomycin (2), rifampicin (5) and streptomycin (10), but not to nalidixic acid (20), nitrofurantoin (30), novobiocin (30), polymixin B (30), tetracycline (30) or tobramycin (10).</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 078133<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21185<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 13236<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a subterranean brine sample collected from the Xiangli Salt Mine in Hunan Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>