<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12663_nm.22395" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22395" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22395" rank="species">Rhizomicrobium electricum</organism><reference id="rid.12663"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kodama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizomicrobium electricum sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic, fermentative, prosthecate bacterium isolated from a cellulose-fed microbial fuel cell</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1781</fpage><lpage>1785</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023580-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20802060</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizomicrobium electricum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizomicrobium electricum</em> [e.lec′tri.cum. L. n. <em>electrum</em> amber; L. suff. <em>-icus -a -um</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. neut. adj. <em>electricum</em> referring to generation of electricity (a physical force so called because it first was generated by rubbing amber)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, straight or slightly curved rods, 0.9–2.5 µm long and 0.2–0.3 µm wide.</s><s>Some cells have one or two polar prosthecae with tip-branched structures.</s><s>Prosthecae are ~3 µm in length and 80–110 nm in diameter.</s><s>Cells reproduce by budding from a mother cell having prosthecae.</s><s>Motile by single polar flagella.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30 °C (range 15–40 °C), the optimum pH is 6.7 (range 5.0–7.5), and the optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 0.5 % (w/v) (range 0–1.0 %, w/v).</s><s>Aerobic growth is observed on nutrient agar and 1/10 PYGV agar plates.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, galactose, arabinose, xylose, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose and soluble starch as fermentative substrates.</s><s>Slow growth (lag phase continues for 10 days or longer) is observed on rhamnose, raffinose, mannose, fructose, ribose, trehalose and pyruvate.</s><s>Major fermentation products of glucose are lactate, acetate and fumarate.</s><s>Does not utilize lactate, malate, fumarate, succinate, citrate, glycine, serine, alanine, glutamate, aspartate, xylan, sorbose, cellulose, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, methanol or propanol.</s><s>Utilizes oxygen, nitrate, Fe(III) and fumarate as electron acceptors in the presence of glucose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Sulfate and malate are not utilized as electron acceptors.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Mfc52<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 15089<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 5806<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from biofilm attached to anode graphite of a cellulose-fed microbial fuel cell.</s></p></content></protolog>