<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12346_nm.9866" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9866" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9866" rank="species">Larkinella insperata</organism><reference id="rid.12346"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anandham</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gandhi</surname><given-names>P.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jee</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Larkinella bovis sp. nov., isolated from fermented bovine products, and emended descriptions of the genus Larkinella and of Larkinella insperata Vancanneyt et al. 2006</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>30</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020453-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20139284</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Larkinella insperata</em> Vancanneyt <em>et al.</em> 2006</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description remains as given by Vancanneyt <em>et al.</em> (2006) with the following additions or modifications.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, R2A agar and nutrient agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and starch, but not hypoxanthine, pectin, gelatin or xanthine.</s><s>Negative for glucose fermentation.</s><s>Assimilates maltose, glycogen and melibiose but not d-mannose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-proline, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose or salicin.</s><s>Positive for esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), trypsin, acid phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease activities.</s><s>Susceptible to rifampicin, ampicillin, polymyxin B and novobiocin, but resistant to streptomycin, oleandomycin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, spectinomycin, kanamycin, trimethoprim, hygromycin and nystatin.</s></p></content></protolog>