<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3452_nm.1357" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1357" rank="genus">Bartonella</organism><reference id="rid.3452"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Connor</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winkler</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposals to unify the genera Bartonella and Rochalimaea, with descriptions of Bartonella quintana comb. nov., Bartonella vinsonii comb. nov., Bartonella henselae comb. nov., and Bartonella elizabethae comb. nov., and to remove the family Bartonellaceae from the order Rickettsiales.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>777</fpage><lpage>786</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-777</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Bartonella</i> (Strong, Tyzzer, and Sellards 1915) Ristic and Kreier 1984.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>It is proposed that the genus <i>Rochalimaea</i> should be united with the genus <i>Bartonella</i>. This requires emending the description of the genus <i>Bartonella</i> (36) by integrating portions of the description of the genus <i>Rochalimaea</i> (57) and data for <i>Rochalimaea henselae</i> and <i>Rochalimaea elizabethae</i>, as follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, fastidious, aerobic rods.</s><s>One species is motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Best growth is obtained on media containing 5% rabbit or sheep blood in the presence of 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The optimal incubation temperature varies from 25°C (<i>Bartonella bacilliformis</i>) to 35 to 37°C.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not utilized.</s><s>All but one species are pathogenic for humans.</s><s>Arthropod vectors have been demonstrated for <i>Bartonella bacillifomis</i>, for <i>Bartonella quintana</i>, and probably for <i>Bartonella vinsonii</i> (4).</s><s>One or more species cause bartonellosis, trench fever, bacillary angiomatosis, peliosis hepatis, septicemia, and perhaps cat scratch disease.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs are 38.5 to 41 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Bartonella bacilliformis</i> (Strong, Tyzzer, Brues, Sellards, and Gastiaburu 1913) Strong, Tyzzer, and Sellards 1915.</s></p></content></protolog>