<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8370_nm.13487" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13487" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13487" rank="species">Nocardioides sediminis</organism><reference id="rid.8370"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dastager</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ju</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides sediminis sp. nov., isolated from a sediment sample.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>280</fpage><lpage>284</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002162-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196766</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides sediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides sediminis</em> (se.di.mi′nis. L. n. <em>sedimen</em> a sediment; L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of a sediment, referring to the source from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive-staining, motile without any flagellum, aerobic and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells appear as short, irregular rods, approximately 0.3–0.8×0.9–1.4 μm after 72 h incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Colonies are cream–whitish, glistening, translucent, slightly sticky, irregular and slightly raised with entire margins.</s><s>Optimum growth at 28 °C and pH 7.0–7.5.</s><s>Positive for catalase test and negative for oxidase test.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed but aesculin, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and urea hydrolysis is negative.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β-</em>glucosidase. <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Uses cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, melibiose, mannitol, mannose, maltose, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and xylose as sole carbon and energy sources, but not arabinose, aesculin, adonitol, adipate, d-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, d-lyxose, mannose, malate, melezitose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sorbose, sorbitol, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from any of the carbon sources tested.</s><s>The main cell-wall amino acid is ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSL-01<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19263<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19271<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sediment sample collected from Bigeum Island in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>