<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3860_nm.8891" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8891" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8891" rank="species">Thiocapsa marina</organism><reference id="rid.3860"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Caumette</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guyoneaud</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiocapsa marina sp. nov., a novel, okenone-containing, purple sulfur bacterium isolated from brackish coastal and marine environments.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1031</fpage><lpage>1036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02964-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280266</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thiocapsa marina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thiocapsa marina</em> (ma.ri′na. L. fem. adj. <em>marina</em> belonging to the marine environment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Individual cells are spherical and 1·5–3·0 μm in diameter; cells occur singly or in pairs, tetrads or small aggregates.</s><s>Division is by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Cell suspension is purple–red.</s><s>Photosynthetic membrane system is of the vesicular type.</s><s>Contains bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> as photosynthetic pigment and okenone as main carotenoid.</s><s>Phototrophic growth is observed under anoxic conditions in light; chemolithotrophic and chemoorganotrophic growth is seen under micro-oxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Electron donors for phototrophic growth are H<sub>2</sub>, sulfide, elemental sulfur and thiosulfate.</s><s>Globules of elemental sulfur are stored in cells as an intermediary product when grown photolithotrophically with reduced sulfur compounds.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, the following compounds are photoassimilated: formate, acetate, propionate, lactate, pyruvate, malate, succinate, fumarate, glycerol, fructose, peptone and Casamino acids.</s><s>Chemolithotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and thiosulfate; chemoorganotrophic growth occurs with acetate and pyruvate.</s><s>Not capable of assimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>No vitamins are required.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7·2–7·4 and optimal temperature is 30–35 °C.</s><s>Grows in 0–8 % NaCl (optimum, 1–2 %).</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 5811<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 5653<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 43172<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from Prevost Lagoon on the French Mediterranean coast.</s><s>Isolated from anoxic sediments and microbial mats exposed to light in coastal brackish to marine lagoons.</s></p></content></protolog>