<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1549_nm.10871" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10871" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10871" rank="species">Micromonospora coriariae</organism><reference id="rid.1549"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Trujillo</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carro</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Micromonospora coriariae sp. nov., isolated from root nodules of Coriaria myrtifolia</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2381</fpage><lpage>2385</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64449-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012566</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Micromonospora coriariae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Micromonospora coriariae</em> (co.ri.a′ri.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>coriariae</em> of <em>Coriaria</em>, pertaining to the isolation of the type strain from root nodules of <em>Coriaria myrtifolia</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, chemo-organotrophic, aerobic actinobacterium.</s><s>Colonies are intensely orange, raised and folded.</s><s>Well-developed substrate mycelium carrying single spores mostly on the tips of the hyphae.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is absent.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>pH range for growth is 7–9; does not grow below pH 6.5.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 28 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Arbutin, aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are degraded, but Tween 20, tyrosine and urea are not.</s><s>The following are used as carbon sources: alanine, arabinose, arginine, cellobiose, fructose, gluconate, glucose, histidine, mannose, melibiose, pyruvate, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, serine, starch, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are not used as carbon sources: ascorbic acid, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, galactose, glutaric acid, lysine, melezitose, proline, propionic acid, quinic acid, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, tyrosine, valine and xylitol.</s><s>Positive enzymic reactions are obtained for the following: acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, pyrazinamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for the following enzymes: <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannoside, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Whole-cell sugars present are glucose, xylose, arabinose, mannose and ribose.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NAR01<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44875<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23557<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from root nodules of <em>Coriaria myrtifolia</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>