<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6949_nm.6794" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6794" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6794" rank="species">Lentzea flaviverrucosa</organism><reference id="rid.6949"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ba</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Lentzea flaviverrucosa sp. nov. and transfer of the type strain of Saccharothrix aerocolonigenes subsp. staurosporea to Lentzea albida</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1815</fpage><lpage>1820</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02204-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361291</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lentzea flaviverrucosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lentzea flaviverrucosa</i> (fla.vi.ver.ru.co'sa. L. adj. <i>flavus</i> yellowish; L. adj. <i>verrucosus</i> verrucose; N.L. fem. adj. <i>flaviverrucosa</i> yellowish and verrucose, referring to the yellowish, verrucose colony morphology observed on the agar surface)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-aciD-fast.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is pale yellow to yellowish brown on ISP media 2, 3 and 4 and GYM agar.</s><s>Sparse, white to yellowish white aerial mycelium is produced on oatmeal agar and GYM agar.</s><s>Melanin pigment is not produced on either ISP medium 6 or 7.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Elastin, starch, gelatin, hypoxanthine and tyrosine are hydrolysed or decomposed, but casein, adenine, aesculin, allantoin, guanine, xanthine, urea and chitin are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase and lipase are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1 and 1.5% NaCl but not in the presence of 2 or 4% NaCl.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, adipate, malate, malonate, propionate and pyruvate, but not benzoate, oxalate, citrate, formate, lactate, sebacic acid, succinate or tartrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-cellobiose, dextrin, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, L-raffinose, salicin and dsucrose, but not from adonitol, L-arabinose, lactose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, D-trehalose, D-xylose or methyl α-D-glucoside.</s><s>Grows at 37 and 42 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by lysozyme (0.0025%, w/v), amikacin (discs soaked in 30 μg antibiotic ml<sup>-1</sup>), amoxicillin plus clavulanic acid (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), cefotaxime (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), ciprofloxacin (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), clindamycin (2 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gentamicin (15 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), kanamycin (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), mezlocillin (75 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), novobiocin (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), ofloxacin (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and tetracycline (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), but not by ampicillin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), aztreonam (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), chloromycin (30 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), erythromycin (15 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) or tobramycin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>The cell wall is of type III (<i>meso</i>-DAP).</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern consists of galactose, mannose, glucose and ribose.</s><s>Possesses the type II phospholipid pattern (phosphatidyl ethanolamine, diphosphatidyl glycerol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides).</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) (peak area ratio 31:23).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is i-C<sub>16:0</sub> (35.51% of total) and considerable amounts of C<sub>16:1</sub> (19.51%), i-C<sub>15:0</sub> (9.52%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (6.74%), 10Me-C<sub>16:0</sub> (6.13%) and ai-C<sub>15:0</sub> (5.18%) are also present.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.1 mol%(<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Isolated from a soil sample collected in Wutaishan Mountain, Shanxi Province, China.</s><s>The type strain is strain AS 4.0578<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 11373<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>