<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6862_nm.9543" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9543" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9543" rank="species">Subsaxibacter broadyi</organism><reference id="rid.6862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae from Antarctic maritime habitats including Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii gen. nov., sp. nov., Subsaximicrobium saxinquilinus sp. nov., Subsaxibacter broadyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Lacinutrix copepodicola gen. nov., sp. nov., and novel species of the genera Bizionia, Gelidibacter and Gillisia</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Subsaxibacter broadyi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Subsaxibacter broadyi</em> (broa.dy′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>broadyi</em> of Broady, named in honour of P. A. Broady, Antarctic microbiologist from New Zealand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus plus the following.</s><s>Colonies are small (&#x003C;1 mm), circular and convex, with a spreading or entire edge and a butyrous to viscid consistency on MA.</s><s>Colonies exhibit spreading margins on dilute media.</s><s>Growth occurs slowly at −2 °C in marine broth.</s><s>Psychrophilic.</s><s>Moderate to good growth occurs on MA at 1–15 °C.</s><s>Weak growth occurs at 20 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25 °C or higher.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth.</s><s>Grows in 0·1–1·25 M NaCl, with optimal growth occurring in approximately 0·3–0·4 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows well in media prepared with 2× strength sea salts.</s><s>No growth occurs with 4× strength sea salts.</s><s>Grows on TSA containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs on TSA or NA.</s><s>Requires yeast extract for good growth.</s><s>Peptone also supports poor to moderate growth.</s><s>Cannot use sodium nitrate or ammonium chloride as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Does not utilize any of the common substrates tested as sole carbon and energy sources (see Table 2 for substrates tested).</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates on Leifson's O–F medium is undetectable.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin and Tween 80, but not casein, elastin, starch, DNA or urea.</s><s>May weakly decompose l-tyrosine or aesculin.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase or lecithinase, or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic data are given in Table 2.</s><s>Mean DNA G+C content is 35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is P7<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1064<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108527<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from cyanobacterial biofilms attached to the undersides of partially buried quartz stones, found in the Vestfold Hills, an ice-free region of East Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>