<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1822_nm.1215" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1215" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1215" rank="species">Erythromonas ursincola</organism><reference id="rid.1822"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yurkov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buss</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vermeglio</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beatty</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of the genus Erythromicrobium: description of Erythromicrobium sibiricum as Sandaracinobacter sibiricus gen. nov., sp. nov., and of Erythromicrobium ursincola as Erythromonas ursincola gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1172</fpage><lpage>1178</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1172</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336925</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erythromonas ursincola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erythromonas ursincola</i> (ur.sin'co.la. M.L. adj. <i>ursincola</i>, neighbor or compatriot of bears)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram negative and ovoid, 0.8 to 1.0 by 1.3 to 2.6 μm.</s><s>Long chains are not formed.</s><s>Reproduce by budding or asymmetric division.</s><s>Cells motile by means of a unique polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells contain Bchl <i>a</i> and carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Carotenoids give three main absorption peaks at 430,458, and 485 nm in vivo, and in combination with Bchl <i>a</i> determine the colors of orange in young cultures and dark orange-brown in older liquid or young agar cultures.</s><s>Bchl <i>a</i> is present in membranebound protein-pigment complexes, consisting of the RC with absorption peaks at 751, 801, and 853 nm and core LHI absorbing at 867 nm.</s><s>RC contains tightly bound tetraheme cyt <i>c</i> with molecular size of 40.0 kDa.</s><s>Total cyt <i>c</i> of cells growing in the dark is very abundant and represented by soluble cyt <i>c</i>’s of 6.5, 9.0, and 14.0 kDa and by membrane-bound cyt <i>c</i>’s of 14.3, 21.0, and 24.0 kDa.</s><s>In cells growing in the dark, only quinone Q<sub>10</sub> was found (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, chemoorganotroph, facultative photoorganoheterotroph.</s><s>The best growth is on media containing glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, acetate, glutamate, propionate, casein hydrolysate, or yeast extract.</s><s>Good growth on pyruvate, butyrate, malate, or succinate.</s><s>Poor growth on media supplemented with arabinose, citrate, lactate, glycerol, or mannitol.</s><s>No growth detected in media containing ribose, formate, benzoate, tartrate, methanol, ethanol, or glycolate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The tricarboxylic acid cycle, and glyoxylate shunt during growth on an acetate-containing medium, is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The key enzyme of Calvin cycle, ribulose-bisphosphate carboxylase, is not found.</s><s>No anaerobic growth in the light, fermentation, or denitrification is found.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth temperature is 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Freshwater organism, does not require NaCl for growth.</s><s>Optimum pH is 7.0 to 8.0.</s><s>Yeast extract and vitamin B,, satisfy the requirement for growth factors.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Lipase activity of 64.9 U/g of biomass.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, polymyxin B, amikacin, gentamicin, neomycin, aureomycin, vancomycin, novobiocin, chloramphenicol, and fusidic acid.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, ampicillin, streptomycin, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, lincomycin, mycostatin, bacitracin, and kanamycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Very resistant to tellurite.</s><s>Can grow in the presence of tellurite concentrations up to 2,700 μg/ml in acetate-containing minimal medium.</s><s>Resistance to tellurite depends on the presence of an organic carbon source in the medium.</s><s>Tellurite can be reduced and transformed into metallic tellurium accumulated as metal crystals in cell cytoplasm (42).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Storage compounds: polyphosphates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA GC content is 65.4 mol% (by thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: freshwater cyanobacterial mat developing in the thermal springs at pH 6.7 to 7.0 and at temperatures from 34 to 40°C on Kamchatka Island (Russia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is KR-99.</s></p></content></protolog>