<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1379_nm.5575" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5575" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5575" rank="species">Leuconostoc carnosum</organism><reference id="rid.1379"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shaw</surname><given-names>B.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harding</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leuconostoc gelidum sp. nov. and Leuconostoc carnosum sp. nov. from chill-stored meats.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>217</fpage><lpage>223</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-217</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leuconostoc carnosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leuconostoc carnosum</i> (car.no´sum. L.neut.adj <i>carnosum</i>, pertaining to flesh)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, spherical but sometimes lenticellular cells usually occur in pairs and chains.</s><s>Colonies are small, smooth, round, and greyish white.</s><s>Growth occurs at 1°C, and most strains do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>Heterofermentative, producing gas from glucose.</s><s>More than 95% of the lactate is produced as the D-(-) isomer.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Arginine is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyze esculin.</s><s>All strains are β-galactosidase negative.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Deoxyribonuclease positive.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze Tween 20 and Tween 80, but some strains hydrolyze Tween 40 and Tween 60.</s><s>Most strains produce dextran from sucrose.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose, D-glucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, galactose, gluconate, glycerol, lactose, mannitol, D-melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from cellobiose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, ribose, and salicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated, and cyclopropane ring types, with tetradecanoic, hexadecanoic, <i>cis</i>-9,10-hexadecenoic, <i>cis</i>-11,12-octadecenoic, and <i>cis</i>-11,12-methyleneoctadecanoic acids predominating.</s><s>Some strains produce methylenehexadecanoic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 39 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from vacuum-packaged meat stored at low temperatures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCFB 2776 (= SML40).</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to that of the species, except that no growth occurs at 37°C, dextran is produced from sucrose, esculin is not hydrolyzed, Tween 40 and Tween 60 are not hydrolyzed, acid is produced from D-mannose and ribose, and acid is not produced from cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, or salicin.</s></p></content></protolog>