<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6275_nm.328" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.328" rank="genus">Halosimplex</organism><reference id="rid.6275"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vreeland</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Straight</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krammes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dougherty</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosenzweig</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halosimplex carlsbadense gen. nov., sp. nov., a unique halophilic archaeon, with three 16S rRNA genes, that grows only in defined medium with glycerol and acetate or pyruvate.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>445</fpage><lpage>452</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00792-002-0278-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12486452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halosimplex</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halosimplex</i> (Ha.lo.sim′.plex Gr. n. hals, halos, the sea, salts, L. adj. simplex, simple, uncomplicated. L. neut. n. <i>Halosimplex</i> simple salts, the simple halophile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, primarily rod shaped cells, some pleomorphic forms can be found.</s><s>Colonies are pink to red, small, circular, opaque, smooth, shiny and raised, with entire margins.</s><s>Colonies become wrinkled with age.</s><s>Aerobic, oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.</s><s>Cannot use nitrate, nitrite, or any other alternate electron acceptors.</s><s>Growth occurs only between pH 7.0 and 8.0, temperature 22°–50°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 37° and 40°C.</s><s>Extremely fastidious.</s><s>Grows only on pyruvate, pyruvate plus glycerol, or glycerol plus acetate as carbon sources in defined medium.</s><s>Pyruvate plus acetate will not support growth.</s><s>Unable to grow on any other organic compounds tested, including amino acids, methanol, formaldehyde, vitamins, nucleotides, fatty acids, proteins, or Krebs cycle intermediates.</s><s>Complex nutrients such as yeast extract, casamino acids, starch, or casein do not stimulate growth and may be inhibitory.</s><s>Unable to ferment arginine or to grow autotrophically in the light.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Phosphatidyl glycerol and methylated phosphatidyl glycerol are produced.</s><s>Possesses a total of four sulfated glycolipids.</s><s>Two of the glycolipids have been identified as STeGD and S2-DGD.</s><s>The other two lipids are unidentified.</s><s>Guanine plus cytosine content 64.4 mol% by HPLC.</s><s>Possesses three divergent 16S rRNA genes (designated A, B, and C).</s><s>The type species is <i>Halosimplex carlsbadense</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>