<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3746_nm.8612" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8612" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8612" rank="species">Helcococcus sueciensis</organism><reference id="rid.3746"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brownlee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helcococcus sueciensis sp. nov., isolated from a human wound</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1557</fpage><lpage>1560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63077-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388710</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Helcococcus sueciensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Helcococcus sueciensis</em> (su.e.ci.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>sueciensis</em> from Sweden, the country in which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive and coccoid and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Pinpoint, grey, non-haemolytic colonies form after 48 h anaerobic incubation on fastidious anaerobe agar with 5 % (v/v) horse blood.</s><s>Catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic, but grows best under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>End products of glucose metabolism are acetic and lactic acids.</s><s>In conventional tests, acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose (weakly), sorbitol and starch (weakly).</s><s>Acid is not formed from cellobiose, sucrose or xylose.</s><s>In commercial API systems, acid is produced from glucose, maltose, lactose and trehalose, but not from d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, d-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose or tagatose.</s><s>Activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, glycine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, serine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase.</s><s>Activity is not detected for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed and indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is 29·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 47334<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108183<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from a human wound.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>