<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6611_nm.6238" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6238" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6238" rank="species">Corynebacterium mastitidis</organism><reference id="rid.6611"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monasterio</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marco</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dominguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium mastitidis sp. nov., isolated from milk of sheep with subclinical mastitis</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1082</fpage><lpage>1085</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1082</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336910</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium mastitidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium mastitidis</i> (mas.ti'ti.dis. M.L. gen. n. <i>mastitidis</i>, referring to inflammation of the mammary gland)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on an examination of 14 strains.</s><s>Cells are gram positive and nonmotile, do not form spores, and occur singly or in palisades or V-shaped forms.</s><s>They are catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>On blood agar, small (diameter, less than 1 mm), rough, whitish, low convex colonies are formed after 3 days of incubation at 37°C; these colonies are nonhemolytic.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of urea is variable.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, lactose, maltose, sucrose, and glycogen.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, and cystine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Pyrrolidonylarylamidase, pglucuronidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, trypsin, and chymotrypsin are not produced.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acids are C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>18:0</sub> and C<sub>18:0 <i>ω</i>9<i>c</i></sub>.</s><s>Tuberculostearic acid is not produced.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to penicillin G, ampicillin, amoxicillin-clavulanic acid, gentamicin, cephalothin, and nalidixic acid.</s><s>The strains do not grow in the presence of 6.5% NaC1.</s><s>Type strain S-8 has been deposited in the Spanish Type Culture Collection as strain CECT 4843.</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics of the species described above except that it is urease and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate positive.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the udder of a sheep with subclinical mastitis.</s></p></content></protolog>