<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6710_nm.7954" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7954" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7954" rank="species">Bacteroides gracilis</organism><reference id="rid.6710"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Badger</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Listgarten</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Visconti</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Socransky</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wolinella gen. nov., Wolinella succinogenes (Vibrio succinogenes Wolin et al.) comb. nov., and description of Bacteroides gracilis sp. nov., Wolinella recta sp. nov., Campylobacter concisus sp. nov., and Eikenella corrodens from humans with periodontal disease.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>432</fpage><lpage>445</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-432</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides gracilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides gracilis</i> (gra'cil is. L. adj. <i>gracilis</i> slim, slender, thin, skinny, slight)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small, straight, unbranched cells approximately 0.4 by 4 to 6 μm often having both tapered and rounded ends.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>The isolates demonstrate twitching movement during dark-field examinations of young broth cultures; no flagella have been observed.</s><s>Endospores are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Inner and outer cell membranes are wavy or undulatory.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan layer is poorly resolved.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic, electrondense inclusions approximately 40 nm in diameter, some membrane bound, have been observed (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Translucent colonies are produced on blood agar plates.</s><s>The following three colony types occur: a convex variant with a diameter of 1 mm; an agar-pitting or corroding variant which is up to 5 mm in diameter; and a variant which spreads on agar up to a diameter of 5 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic, but some strains can grow in the presence of 5% oxygen but not in air enriched with 10% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented and do not support growth.</s><s>Growth is stimulated in broth cultures by formate and fumarate.</s><s>Hydrogen and formate are used as energy sources.</s><s>Formate is oxidized to produce hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Fumarate is reduced to succinate.</s><s>Nitrates, nitrites, neutral red, and benzyl viologen are reduced.</s><s>The benzidine test is positive, and hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase negative.</s><s>Lysine, ornithine, and arginine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Starch, dextran, esculin, casein, DNA, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide, urease, lecithinase, lipase, indole, ammonia, and acetylmethylcarbinol are not produced.</s><s>No gas is formed under an agar layer that is over a broth culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44 to 46 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in gingival crevices of humans.</s><s>Pathogenicity in unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is FDC 1084 (= ATCC 33236).</s></p></content></protolog>