<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8717_nm.13311" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13311" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13311" rank="species">Devosia geojensis</organism><reference id="rid.8717"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Le</surname><given-names>N.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yun</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Devosia geojensis sp. nov., isolated from diesel-contaminated soil in Korea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>633</fpage><lpage>636</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65481-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319469</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Devosia geojensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Devosia geojensis</em> (geo.jen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>geojensis</em> pertaining to Geoje in Korea, the location of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, raised and circular with entire margins after 3 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, short, motile rods (about 0.5–0.8 μm wide and 1.0–2.0 μm long) with single polar flagella.</s><s>Growth occurs optimally at 30–35 °C and pH 7.5–9.0.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, urea and l-tyrosine are hydrolysed, but casein, Tween 80, Tween 20, gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Produces acid from raffinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, l-arabinose, melibiose, lactose, arbutin and salicin, but not from d-galactose.</s><s>Negative for indole production, d-glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose, but negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Produces esterase (C4) and leucine arylamidase, but not lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzyme activities are observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Resistant to chloramphenicol, polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, neomycin and lincomycin, but sensitive to ampicillin, penicillin G, tetracycline and carbenicillin.</s><s>Contains a large amount of phosphatidylglycerol and a small amount of diphosphatidylglycerol as the polar lipids.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.8 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BD-c194<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22082<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19414<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from diesel-contaminated soil from Geoje, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>