<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2223_nm.5478" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5478" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5478" rank="species">Facklamia languida</organism><reference id="rid.2223"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Facklamia languida sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>1161</fpage><lpage>1164</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10074542</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Facklamia languida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Facklamia languida</i> (<i>languida</i>, pertaining to the organism’s lack of activity in the biochemical tests used)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On TSA-SB after 24 h of incubation in air plus CO<sub>2</sub>, small grey to colorless colonies which show little hemolytic activity are formed.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation, colonies are surrounded by a small zone of alpha hemolysis.</s><s>Cells are ovoid and usually form pairs, but single cells and short chains may also occur.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Grows in 6.5% NaCl at 37°C.</s><s>Does not grow at 10 or 45°C.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and leucine aminopeptidase positive in conventional tests.</s><s>In commercial API systems acid is produced from trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, melibiose, mannitol, maltose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, or tagatose.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase activities are detected.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, cysteine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, and urease activities are not detected.</s><s>Esterase C4 and ester lipase C8 may or may not be detected.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 37842<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nucleotide sequence accession number.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of strain CCUG 37842<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in Gen-Bank under accession no. Y18053.</s></p></content></protolog>