<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4600_nm.4144" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4144" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4144" rank="species">Lachnobacterium bovis</organism><reference id="rid.4600"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whitford</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yanke</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forster</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Teather</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lachnobacterium bovis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel bacterium isolated from the rumen and faeces of cattle.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1977</fpage><lpage>1981</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760937</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lachnobacterium bovis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lachnobacterium bovis</i> (bo'vis. L. n. <i>bos</i> cow; L. gen. n. <i>bovis</i> of a cow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0.6-0.75¬2.0-3.0 μm long, occurring as chains or filaments.</s><s>Gram-positive and obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Spores are absent.</s><s>Generally non-motile, but rare motile cells observed in old (&#x003E;72 h) cultures.</s><s>Strains grow well overnight at 39 and 42 °C, with limited growth at 27 °C and no growth at 22 or 50 °C.</s><s>Strains ferment, with acid production (final pH in parentheses), glucose (5.3), lactose (5.9), cellobiose (6.1), sucrose (5.6), maltose (6.0), fructose (6.1) and arabinose (6.1).</s><s>Does not grow on pectin, mannitol, glycerol, galactose, starch, xylan, barley straw or cellulose.</s><s>One of four strains ferments xylose (final pH 5.8).</s><s>Volatile fatty acid from glucose fermentation (55 mM) is primarily lactic acid (71-112 mM); very minor amounts of acetic and butyric acids (1.5-3.0 mM) are produced.</s><s>Positive for α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and α-galactosidase, but not N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, α-arabinosidase, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, phosphatase, arginine utilization, indole production, leucine aminopeptidase, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid arylase, tyrosine aminopeptidase, arginine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase, histidine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase or glycine aminopeptidase.</s><s>Produces a temperature-sensitive bacteriocin-like inhibitory substance (BLIS).</s><s>The most abundant fatty acids are 16:0 and isomers of 18:1.</s><s>The G­+C content of the type stain YZ 87T is 33.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Member of the clostridial cluster XIVa based on phylogenetic analysis of 16S rDNA.</s><s>The GenBank accession numbers for the 16S rDNA sequence of strains YZ 140, YZ 87<sup>T</sup>, YZ 39 and YZ 63 are AF298662, AF298663, AF298664 and AF298665, respectively.</s><s>Isolated from the rumen and faeces of cattle.</s><s>The type strain is YZ 87<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-151<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14045<sup>T</sup>=LRC 5382<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>