<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1553_nm.6008" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6008" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6008" rank="species">Arsenicicoccus bolidensis</organism><reference id="rid.1553"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Routh</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saraswathy</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Welinder-Olsson</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arsenicicoccus bolidensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from contaminated lake sediment</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>605</fpage><lpage>608</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02918-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023982</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arsenicicoccus bolidensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arsenicicoccus bolidensis</em> (bol.id.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>bolidensis</em> pertaining to the Boliden region in Vasterbotten district of northern Sweden, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Using commercially available API kits, acid is formed from glucose, glycogen, fructose, mannitol, mannose, sucrose and d-xylose.</s><s>Depending on the test kit, acid may or may not be produced from cellobiose, lactose, ribose and maltose.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase C-4, ester lipase C8, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are positive; acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase are either weakly positive or negative.</s><s>Chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lipase C14, leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>Using the API Coryne test kit, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, pyrazinamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase are detected but <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are not.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed but urea is not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics are given in the genus description.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 72·2 mol%.</s><s>Highly As-tolerant.</s><s>Possesses As(V) reduction mechanisms that are coupled to respiration or to impart resistance to As toxicity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 47306<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15745<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>