<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10571_nm.17816" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17816" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3237" rank="species">Tatumella punctata</organism><reference id="rid.10571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pantoea citrea, Pantoea punctata and Pantoea terrea to the genus Tatumella emend. as Tatumella citrea comb. nov., Tatumella punctata comb. nov. and Tatumella terrea comb. nov. and description of Tatumella morbirosei sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>484</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012070-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tatumella punctata</em> (Kageyama <em>et al.</em> 1992) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tatumella punctata</em> (punc.ta′ta. L. n. <em>punctum</em> a point; N.L. fem. adj. <em>punctata</em> full of points).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Panteo punctata</em> Kageyama <em>et al.</em> 1992.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (1.1–1.2×1.3–2.3 μm) occurring singly or in pairs, non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are pale beige to pale orange, round, convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Nicotinic acid or nicotinamide are required for growth.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and glucose dehydrogenase, gluconate dehydrogenase and 2-ketogluconate dehydrogenase are produced.</s><s>Indole, urease and phenylalanine deaminase are negative, whereas arginine dihydrolase is positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from starch or d-mannitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-arabinose, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, cellobiose (variable), citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucose, 5-ketogluconate, d-mannitol, d-mannose, succinic acid, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 28 °C within 3–6 days: <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-adonitol, l-alanine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, betaine, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, formic acid, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, glutarate, histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, melibiose, l-proline, propionate, pyruvic acid methyl ester, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-serine, l-tartrate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate and trigonelline.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SHS 2006<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 31626<sup>T</sup>=BD 876<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 30159<sup>T</sup>=CIP 105598<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13700<sup>T</sup>=JCM 8885<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22050<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mandarin orange in Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>