<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5626_nm.3898" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3898" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3898" rank="species">Clostridium beijerinckii</organism><reference id="rid.5626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Keis</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shaheen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Clostridium acetobutylicum and Clostridium beijerinckii, and descriptions of Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum sp. nov. and Clostridium saccharobutylicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760952</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Clostridium beijerinckii</i> Donker 1926</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The phenotypic description of <i>Clostridium beijerinckii</i> is essentially the same as that given in Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology (Cato et al., 1986), based on those of Smith &#x0026; Hobbs (1974) and Holdeman et al. (1977). In some instances in this study, we found the percentage of strains able to ferment certain carbohydrates to be higher than that given in Bergey's Manual, perhaps because we analysed fewer strains (16, as opposed to 60). As in Bergey's Manual, we found that the <i>C. beijerinckii</i> strains were unable to hydrolyse gelatin (with the exception of strain NRRL B593). Characteristics additional to the description of <i>C. beijerinckii</i> include the following: the ability to ferment saccharose, and the ability of the majority of the strains to utilize the alcohol sugars D- and L-arabitol, dulcitol and inositol, but glycerol only weakly. All of the strains of <i>C. beijerinckii</i> were also able to ferment methyl-glucopyranoside, turanose, dextrin and pectin.</s></p></content></protolog>