<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1916_nm.10764" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10764" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10764" rank="species">Haloferax larsenii</organism><reference id="rid.1916"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloferax larsenii sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from a solar saltern</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>717</fpage><lpage>720</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64573-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392193</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloferax larsenii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloferax larsenii</em> (lar.se′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>larsenii</em> of Larsen, named in honour of Professor Helge Larsen, one of the pioneers of halophile research).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Extremely pleomorphic, motile, occurring mainly as irregularly shaped cells (0.8–1.5 μm in diameter).</s><s>Cells grown at the highest salinities are often elongated.</s><s>Colonies on complex agar medium are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, elevated and orange–red.</s><s>Halophilic.</s><s>Cells lyse immediately in distilled water after 2 h with 10–20 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>The NaCl concentration for growth is between 1 and 4.8 M, with an optimum at 2.2–3.4 M.</s><s>Saturated NaCl inhibits growth in liquid medium.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing more than 5 mM Mg<sup>2+</sup>, the optimum Mg<sup>2+</sup> concentration being between 20 and 500 mM.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–8.5, with an optimum at pH 6.5–7.0; the temperature range for growth is 25–55 °C, with an optimum at 42–45 °C.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Anaerobic growth with arginine or DMSO does not occur.</s><s>Positive for indole formation.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Grows anaerobically on nitrate, with the production of gas.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Starch and Tweens 40 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed; casein is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: glucose, glycerol, mannose, starch, maltose, sucrose, glutamate, alanine, ornithine, fumarate, malate, pyruvate, succinate and lactate.</s><s>Arabinose, lactose, mannitol, rhamnose, sorbitol, galactose, ribose, xylose, arginine, lysine, aspartate, glycine, acetate, propionate and citrate are not utilized for growth.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol and maltose and, to a lesser extent, on glucose, fructose and sucrose.</s><s>Sensitive to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin, aphidicolin and rifampicin, but not to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, nystatin, penicillin, tetracycline, streptomycin or kanamycin.</s><s>The major polar lipids are the C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, diglycosyl glycerol diether and sulfated diglycosyl diether.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of DNA of the type strain is 62.2±0.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ZJ206<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.5347<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13917<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a solar saltern in Zhe-Jiang Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>