<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12773_nm.22554" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22554" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22554" rank="species">Pseudomonas deceptionensis</organism><reference id="rid.12773"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carrión</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miñana-Galbis</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mercadé</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas deceptionensis sp. nov., a psychrotolerant bacterium from the Antarctic</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2401</fpage><lpage>2405</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024919-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21062736</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas deceptionensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas deceptionensis</em> (de.cep.tio.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. deceptionensis pertaining to Deception Island, Antarctic Sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.8×1.5–2.0 µm), Gram-reaction-negative, oxidase-positive, non-spore-forming and motile by means of a single polar flagella.</s><s>Does not produce fluorescent pigments on King’s B medium.</s><s>After 72 h of incubation at 20 °C on TSA, colonies are 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter, white, round, mucous and slightly convex.</s><s>Growth occurs at −4 to 34 °C and at pH 5–10.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated at concentrations up to 6 % (w/v).</s><s>Growth on MA is very poor under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Positive for catalase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities but negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween 80, gelatin, casein, starch and lecithin but positive for hydrolysis of urea.</s><s>Negative for indole and hydrogen sulfide production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>In API 50 CH tests, acid is produced from d- and l-arabinose, d-fructose, cellobiose, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, glycerol, d-glucose, inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, gentiobiose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>In Biolog GENIII MicroPlates, positive for oxidation of d-galactose, d-glucuronic acid, d-fucose, glucuronamide, acetoacetic acid, l-fucose and quinic acid; also positive for growth in the presence of 1 % sodium lactate, troleandomycin, lincomycin, vancomycin, aztreonam, fusic acid, rifampicin SV, tetrazolium violet, d-serine, niaproof 4 and potassium telurite.</s><s>Fatty acid profile contains C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (34.9 %), summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>; 21.5 %) and C <sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (16.1 %), as the major fatty acids with smaller proportions of C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> (4.9 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5.4 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH (5.8 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5.6 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (3.6 %) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.7 %).</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds PE, DPG and PG; moderate amounts of three unknown aminolipids, two unknown phospholipids and three unknown polar lipids; and minor to trace amounts of 10 unknown polar lipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M1<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25555<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7677<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sediment sample collected from Deception Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>