<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5314_nm.6584" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6584" rank="genus">Couchioplanes</organism><reference id="rid.5314"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagaito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new genus of the order Actinomycetales, Couchioplanes gen. nov., with descriptions of Couchioplanes caeruleus (Horan and Brodsky 1986) comb. nov. and Couchioplanes caeruleus subsp. azureus subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>193</fpage><lpage>203</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-193</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186084</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Couchioplanes</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Couchioplanes</i> (Couch'i.o.pla.nes. N.L. adj. <i>Couchio</i>, referring to J. N. Couch [ 1896 to 1986], a mycologist who contributed to the taxonomy of the family <i>Actinoplanaceae</i>; Gr. n. <i>planes</i>, a wanderer; M.L.masc.n. <i>Couchioplanes</i>, Couch wanderer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are gram-positive, non-acid-fast, aerobic organisms with branching hyphae.</s><s>Nonfragmenting, yellowish orange to blue mycelia are present.</s><s>Spores are formed in chains and are motile.</s><s>The spore chains and aerial mycelia often aggregate into clusters resembling sporangia, but true sporangia are not observed.</s><s>In 14-day-old cultures grown on oatmeal agar aerial mycelia with short spore chains arranged in spirals that have one to five turns and are hooked or rarely flexuous are present.</s><s>Several spores are present per spore chain, and the spores are oval to short rods (diameter, 1.3 to 2.0 μm) and exhibit motility when they are suspended in sterile distilled water.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Good growth occurs at temperatures between 22 and 28°C.</s><s>The organisms grow well on yeast extractmalt extract agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, glycerol-asparagine agar, and Bennett's agar.</s><s>In general, the vegetative mycelia of the strains are pale orange to blue, and the aerial mycelia are white to gray.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain D-glutamate, D- and L-serine, glycine, L-alanine, and L-lysine (molar ratio, ca. 1:1:1:1:1).</s><s>The wall chemotype is type VI according to the classification of Lechevalier and Lechevalier (14), and the peptidoglycan type is type A (most probably type A3α) according to the classification of Schleifer and Kandler (22).</s><s>Xylose, arabinose, and galactose are the characteristic cell wall sugars; iso-pentadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>) and anteiso-heptadecanoic acid (anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>) are the major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C contents of DNAs range from 69 to 73 mol%; the G+C contents of the type species range from 69.9 to 70.5 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>); in addition, small amounts of MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine are the diagnostic phospholipids, but phosphatidylcholine is absent (type PII).</s><s>Habitat: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Couchioplanes caeruleus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>