<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4812_nm.11717" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11717" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4870" rank="species">Bacillus aneurinolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.4812"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shida</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takagi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kadowaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Udaka</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus aneurinolyticus sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>143</fpage><lpage>150</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-143</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus aneurinolyticus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus aneurinolyticus</i> (an. eur. in. o. lytic. us. M. L. n. <i>aneurium</i>, thiamine; M. L. adj. <i>yticus</i>, dissolving; M. L. adj. <i>aneurinolyticus</i>, decomposing thiamine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (0.7 to 0.9 by 3.0 to 5.0 μm).</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Motile and peritrichous.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are flat, smooth, and yellowish gray and do not produced soluble pigment on nutrient agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is weakly positive (the gas bubbles can be visible with a dissecting scope).</s><s>Oxidase is positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction (production of acetylmethylcarbinol) is negative, and the pH in Voges-Proskauer broth is 7.3 to 8.1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Dihydroxyacetone, hydrogen sulfide, and indole are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Casein, gelatin, starch, DNA, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, urea, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tyrosine is decomposed.</s><s>Thiamin is decomposed by thiamin hydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenylalanine is deaminated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Citrate, propionate, alginate, gluconate, malonate, and tartrate are not utilized; and acetate, fumarate, lactate, succinate, L-glutamate, L-asparatate, and α-ketoglutarate are utilized by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate and ammonium are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Egg yolk reaction is positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Litmus milk becomes alkaline and is reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at temperatures and pHs ranging from 20 to 50°C and 5.0 to 9.0, respectively.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature and pH are 37°C and 7.0, respectively.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2% NaCl, 0.001% lysozyme, and 50 μg of gramicidin per ml, and some strains grow in the presence of 0.02% sodium azide.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by the presence of 5% NaCl, 10 μg of ampicillin per ml, 10 μg of chloramphenicol per ml, 50 μg of neomycin per ml, and 30 μg of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glycerol.</s><s>Variable acid but no gas production occurs with D-fructose, sucrose, trehalose, D-ribose, and L-sorbose.</s><s>Acid and gas are not produced from D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-galactose, maltose, lactose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, D-cellobiose, salicine, D-sorbitol, D-mannose, melibiose, L-rhamnose, raffinose, inositol, erythritol, adonitol, and starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth inhibition test against <i>E. coli</i> is negative, and growth of <i>B. subtilis</i> is inhibited by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Specific S layer proteins are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid components are iso-C15:0, iso-C16:0, and C16:0 acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major quinone is menaquinone 7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content ranges from 41.1 to 43.4 mol%, with the G+C content of the type strain being 42.9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 12856 (= IAM 1077), which was isolated from human feces as a thiamin hydrolase producer.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited at JCM and IFO as JCM 9024 and IFO 15521, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>