<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12827_nm.22628" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22628" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22628" rank="species">Bacillus locisalis</organism><reference id="rid.12827"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carrasco</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de la Haba</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa A.</surname><given-names /></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus locisalis sp. nov., a new haloalkaliphilic species from hypersaline and alkaline lakes of China, Kenya and Tanzania</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>34</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>424</fpage><lpage>428</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2011.04.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21640538</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus locisalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0050"&#x003E;<em>Bacillus locisalis</em> (lo.ci.sa’lis. L. n. <em>locus</em> place, locality; L. gen. n. <em>salis</em> of salt; N.L. gen. n. <em>locisalis</em> from a salted place).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0055"&#x003E;Gram-positive rods, 1.0 by 2.0–5.0 μm.</s><s>Motile, oval endospores are produced at terminal and subterminal positions in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies are orange, circular, opaque and entire on alkaline saline medium after 2 days of cultivation.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing in a wide range (1–25%, w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimal growth at 7–10% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 10–45 °C (optimal at 37 °C) and pH 8–12 (optimal at pH 9–10).</s><s>Oxidase negative and catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-ribose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-amygdaline, d-arabinose, l-citruline, dulcitol, dl-ethionine, glycerol, inulin, lactose, d-melezitose, <em>m</em>-inositol, and xylitol.</s><s>Casein is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole production and Voges–Proskauer test are negative. d-fucose, d-fructose and d-glucose are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: aesculin, butanol, <em>m</em>-inositol, sorbitol, xylitol and citrate. l-alanine and cysteine are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources. l-phenylalanine and l-glutamine are not utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources.</s><s>DNA base composition ranges from 42.2 to 43.4 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid type.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, four phospholipids and an aminophospholipid of unknown structure.</s><s>Additional characteristics of the strains are listed in <a href="#sec0030">Table S1</a>.</s><s>Cellular fatty acid composition is given in <a href="#tbl0005">Table 1</a>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0060"&#x003E;The habitats are saline and alkaline waters and soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0065"&#x003E;The type strain is CG1<sup>T</sup> (CCM 7370<sup>T</sup> = CECT 7152<sup>T</sup> = CGMCC 1.6286<sup>T</sup> = DSM 18085<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Lake Chagannor, in Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0070"&#x003E;The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>The base composition of its DNA is 42.2 mol% G+C, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in <a href="#sec0030">Supplementary Table 1</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>