<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5762_nm.9987" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9987" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9987" rank="species">Pseudomonas otitidis</organism><reference id="rid.5762"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Clark</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dajcs</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McLean</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bartell</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stroman</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas otitidis sp. nov., isolated from patients with otic infections</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>709</fpage><lpage>714</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63753-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585681</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas otitidis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas otitidis</em> (o.ti′ti.dis. Gr. n. <em>ous</em>, <em>otos</em> ear; N.L. suff. -<em>itis</em>, -<em>idis</em> used in names of inflammations; N.L. gen. n. <em>otitidis</em> of inflammation of the ear).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile rods.</s><s>Colonies on trypticase soy agar are circular, concave and non-pigmented.</s><s>Colonies grown on trypticase soy agar supplemented with 5 % sheep blood are not haemolytic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 7–45 °C, pH 5–10 and in the presence of up to 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies typically do not produce fluorescent pigment, and all strains are positive for oxidase and catalase, but negative for urease.</s><s>Tween 80 and gelatin are hydrolysed, but casein and aesculin are not.</s><s>Utilizes glycogen, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine and putrescine.</s><s>None of the strains utilizes <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, l-arabinose, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, glucuronamide, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, cytosine or sebacic acid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Susceptible to aminoglycosides, fluoroquinolones and polymyxin B, but resistant to piperacillin, erythromycin, tetracycline, chloramphenicol, trimethoprim and sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MCC10330<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1130<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17224<sup>T</sup>), and other strains were isolated from the ears of patients with acute otitis externa, acute otitis media with otorrhoea and chronic suppurative otitis media.</s></p></content></protolog>