<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1331_nm.4424" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4424" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4424" rank="species">Selenomonas artemidis</organism><reference id="rid.1331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas noxia sp. nov., Selenomonas flueggei sp. nov., Selenomonas infelix sp. nov., Selenomonas dianae sp. nov., and Selenomonas artemidis sp. nov., from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas artemidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas artemidis</i> (ar.te'mi.dis Gr. gen. n. <i>artemidos</i> of Artemis, goddess of the moon. N. L. gen. n. <i>artemidis</i> of Artemis [referring to the crescent shape of the cells])</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, motile, nonsporeforming , gram-negative rods.</s><s>Cells are curved, crescent shaped, and 1.3 to 1.7 by 3.3 to 7.2 μm.</s><s>With Leifson flagellum stain (2), cells appear to have one or more central-to-polar flagella arising from the concave side.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On rabbit blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h, colonies are minute to 0.5 mm, circular, entire, low convex, translucent, smooth, shiny, and colorless.</s><s>Strains produce slight growth in PY broth and abundant growth with slight turbidity and granular-to-flaky sediment in PYG cultures.</s><s>No ammonia is detected in PY or PYG cultures, but a small amount is detected in chopped meat cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C; strains grow poorly if at all at 25, 30, or 45°C.</s><s>Neutral red is not reduced or is only weakly reduced.</s><s>In glucose agar deep cultures, resazurin is not reduced and no gas is detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 pg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation acids of the type strain, in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture, are 1.3 of acetic and 2.0 of propionic in PYG broth cultures, 0.2 of acetic and 0.3 of propionic in PY broth cultures, 1.8 of acetic and 1.1 of propionic in PY-pyruvate cultures, and 4.6 of acetic and 6.8 of propionic in PYG-fumarate cultures.</s><s>Lactate is not used, and threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>Only a trace amount of hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas of PYG broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The PAGE patterns of soluble proteins are shown in Fig. 4.</s><s>Cellular components of the species are given in Table 5.</s><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 58 mol%.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the four other strains tested are 56 to 59 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 43928, isolated from the subgingival crevice of a person with juvenile (localized) periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is isolated from the gingival crevice of persons with gingivitis and periodontitis and has been referred to as <i>Selenomonas</i> D-14 in previous publications.</s></p></content></protolog>