<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.835_nm.304" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.304" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.304" rank="species">Halococcus turkmenicus</organism><reference id="rid.835"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zvyagintseva</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tarasov</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Extreme halophilic bacteria from saline soils.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>839</fpage><lpage>844</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halococcus turkmenicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Coccoid or oval cells, 1.5-2 μ in diameter, nonmotile, rarely single cells, more often in pairs or groups. Strictly aerobic. Catalase and oxidize tests positive; they do not hydrolyze starch or gelatin, do not form indole, coagulate milk with slight alkalization of the medium. Reduce nitrates to nitrites without forming gas. Formation of hydrogen sulfide was not observed. Optimal growth temperature is 45°C. Growth was stimulated by glucose, fructose, mannose, sucrose, and maltose. Lactone and ribose did not stimulate growth. Glucose, saccharose, ribose, and to a somewhat lesser degree, mannose and fructose, were metabolized with the formation of acids. Acidification was not observed in the presence of lactose (Fig. 3). Acid formation occurred when glycerin was aded to the medium. Lysis of cells in hypotonic solutions was not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In morphological and physiological-biochemical properties, strain 4k is similar to the strain <i>Halococcus morrhuae</i> Farlow a.</s><s>Hodgkiss.</s><s>It differs from strains of this species in an important systematic trait [17]: the ability to metabolize sugar and form acids.</s><s>This difference is the basis for describing this strain as a new species of the genus <i>Halococcus</i> with the species designation <i>H. turkmenicus</i> without he species designation <i>H. turkemicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>