<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1527_nm.10974" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10974" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10974" rank="species">Pseudomonas lurida</organism><reference id="rid.1527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas lurida sp. nov., a fluorescent species associated with the phyllosphere of grasses</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>979</fpage><lpage>985</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64793-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473245</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas lurida</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas lurida</em> (lu′ri.da. L. fem. adj. <em>lurida</em> yellowish, to indicate the yellow–greenish fluorescent pigment of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that occur as single cells.</s><s>The white–yellowish colonies that form on King's A and B medium are smooth with regular margins and produce a pigment showing a light yellow–green fluorescence by irradiation with UV-light at 350 nm.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 21 °C.</s><s>At 4 °C growth can be observed, but none of the isolates are able to grow at 41 °C.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Each strain is positive in tests for catalase, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase and lecithinase activities and for the hydrolysis of casein.</s><s>Produces Tween esterase on Tween 60; hydrolysis of Tween 80 is strain dependent.</s><s>Negative result in tests for the following: hydrolysis of aesculin and starch, formation of levan from sucrose, DNase, production of indole, formation of H<sub>2</sub>S from sodium thiosulphate, ice nucleation activity, reduction of nitrate to nitrite and denitrification.</s><s>Results from tests using Biolog GN microplates show that the following substrates are utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, formic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, l-threonine and glycerol.</s><s>None of the strains assimilate <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, i-erythritol, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, d-psicose, d-raffinose, turanose, sebacic acid, l-phenylalanine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Utilization of the following substrates is strain-dependent: sucrose, glycogen, xylitol, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine and uridine.</s><s>Using the Biotype 100-system, tests positive for the utilization of the following additional substrates: d-ribose, l-arabitol, d-xylose, d-lyxose, d-saccharate, mucate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, d-malate, l-malate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, citrate, d-galacturonate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, d-gluconate, protocatechuate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, benzoate, betaine, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>N</em>-butyrate, dl-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>N</em>-valerate, ethanolamine, d-glucosamine, itaconate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, malonate, propionate, l-tyrosine and <em>α</em>–ketoglutarate.</s><s>None of the strains assimilate l-sorbose, maltotriose, 1-0-methyl-<em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 1-0-methyl-<em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, d-celloboise, 1-0-methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, palatinose, d-melezitose, dulcitol, d-tagatose, maltitol, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, 1-0-methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 3-0-methyl-d-glucopyranose, l-tartrate, d-tartrate, tricarballylate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, l-tryptophan, phenylacetate, gentisate, m-hydroxybenzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, m-coumarate, trigonelline, histamine or tryptamine.</s><s>In contrast to the tests using the Biolog GN microplates, l-histidine was not used.</s><s>The assimilation of dl-glycerate is strain-dependent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P 513/18<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15835<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21995<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses in Paulinenaue, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>