<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3414_nm.2861" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2861" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2861" rank="species">Marinobacterium georgiense</organism><reference id="rid.3414"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moran</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hodson</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitman</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbulbifer hydrolyticus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Marinobacterium georgiense gen. nov., sp. nov., two marine bacteria from a lignin-rich pulp mill waste enrichment community.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>376</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-369</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103623</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Marinobacterium georgiense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Marinobacterium georgiense</i> (ge.or.gi.en'se. L. adj. <i>georgiense</i>, from Georgia, the place where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of type strain KW-40 are rod shaped (1.6 to 2.3 μm long and 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide in exponential-phase growth in glucose medium) and have numerous vesicles on their surfaces.</s><s>Has a polar flagellum, fimbriae, and a typical Slayer.</s><s>Cells are gram negative and motile.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 are translucent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 4 to 41°C, and optimal growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 0.01 to 2 M, and optimal growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 0.1 and 0.5 M.</s><s>The optimal pH is 7.5, and the pH range is 5.5 to 9.5.</s><s>KW-40<sup>T</sup> is a strict aerobe, does not denitrify, and does not accumulate polyhydroxybutyrate.</s><s>The sole carbon sources utilized include some carbohydrates and amino acids, as well as aromatic compounds, such as phenol, benzoate, and <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and lignin-related compounds, such as <i>p</i>-coumarate, cinnamate, ferulate, and vanillate.</s><s>Methanol and formate are utilized, but methylamine is not utilized.</s><s>The alcohols utilized include ethanol, 1-propanol, 2-propanol, and 1-butanol.</s><s>Exhibits oxidase, catalase, and Tweenase activities.</s><s>Growth factors are not required, although a complex vitamin solution or yeast extract stimulates growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are resistant to penicillin G and vancomycin and susceptible to tetracycline, streptomycin, kanamycin, chloramphenicol, and ampicillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 54.9 mol%.</s><s>On the basis of its 16s rRNA sequence, KW-40T belongs to the γ subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, forming a deep branch related to the pseudomonads sensu stricto.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a marine enrichment community growing on pulp mill eflluent as the sole carbon source.</s><s>The original inoculum was from a salt marsh on the coast of Georgia.</s><s>Type strain KW-40 has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700074.</s></p></content></protolog>