<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3516_nm.1629" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1629" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1629" rank="species">Burkholderia fungorum</organism><reference id="rid.3516"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laevens</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hannant</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Govan</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia fungorum sp. nov. and Burkholderia caledonica sp. nov., two new species isolated from the environment, animals and human clinical samples.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1099</fpage><lpage>1107</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411678</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia fungorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia fungorum</i> (fun.go'rum. L. n. <i>fungus</i> mushroom; L. gen. pl. n. <i>fungorum</i> of fungi)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, straight rods.</s><s>Growth is observed at 30 °C and in the presence of 0.5% NaCl, but not at 42°C.</s><s>Nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>No DNase activity, β-galactosidase activity, urease activity, liquefaction of gelatin, aesculin hydrolysis or indole production.</s><s>Assimilation of citrate but not of trehalose or sucrose.</s><s>Additional characteristics are listed in Table 4.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in all strains: 14:0, 16:0, 17:0 cyclo, 16:1 2-OH, 16:0 2-OH, 16:0 3-OH, 18:1 <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 19:0 cyclo <i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>, summed feature 2 (comprising 14:0 3-OH, 16:1 iso I, an unidenti®ed fatty acid with an equivalent chain-length value of 10.928, or 12:0 ALDE, or any combinations of these fatty acids) and summed feature 3 (comprising 16:1 <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> or 15 iso 2-OH or both).</s><s>The G­+C content is 61.9-62.2 mol%. <i>B. fungorum</i> strains have been isolated from fungi, animals and human clinical samples.</s><s>Several isolates of this species have been isolated from the white-rot fungus <i>Phanerochaete chrysosporium</i>.</s><s>These bacteria appeared to be very closely associated with the fungus, and attempts to eliminate the bacteria were unsuccessful (Seigle-Murandi <i>et al</i>., 1996).</s><s>It has been suggested that there is a symbiotic relationship between the bacteria and the fungus, since the bacteria were very efficient degraders of the aromatic compounds derived from degradation of lignin by white-rot fungi (Seigle-Murandi <i>et al</i>., 1996).</s><s>Recently, several unidentified <i>B. cepacia</i>-like strains isolated from cystic fibrosis patients were also classified as <i>B. fungorum</i> (our unpublished observations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG16225<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG31961<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the white-rot fungus <i>P. chrysosporium</i>.</s><s>The type strain has the following additional characteristics: growth in O/F medium with fructose and xylose, on cetrimide and in the presence of 1.5% NaCl; assimilation of L-arginine, DL-norleucine, L-arabinose, caprate and adipate; CM<sub>4</sub>-esterase and cysteine arylamidase activity ; G+­C content of 62 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>