<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2395_nm.11262" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11262" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11262" rank="species">Oceanicola marinus</organism><reference id="rid.2395"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oceanicola marinus sp. nov., a marine alphaproteobacterium isolated from seawater collected off Taiwan</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1625</fpage><lpage>1629</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65020-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625206</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Oceanicola marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Oceanicola marinus</em> (ma′ri.nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, marine, referring to the isolation of the type strain from seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative (according to Gram staining and the KOH test), non-motile, non-spore-forming, short rods that are 0.5 μm wide and 0.9–1.0 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on MA are cream–white in colour, circular and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.8–2.0 mm in diameter on MA after 72 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–42 °C, 2–8 % NaCl and pH 6–9.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 28–35 °C, 3–5 % NaCl and pH 7.0.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Neither carotenoid/flexirubin pigments nor bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is found.</s><s>Positive for the following characteristics: indole production, aesculin hydrolysis, oxidase, catalase, urease, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following characteristics: nitrate reduction, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon substrates (Biolog GN2) are oxidized: dextrin, adonitol, arabinose, arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine and 2-aminoethanol.</s><s>Cannot oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, i-erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, nalidixic acid and penicillin G and sensitive to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, novobiocin, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and there are significant amounts of 19 : 0 cyclo and 16 : 0.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 70.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AZO-C<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23705<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17591<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample collected off the Eluanbi coast of Pingtung County, southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>