<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4818_nm.6593" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6593" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6593" rank="species">Dactylosporangium vinaceum</organism><reference id="rid.4818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyadoh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niida</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dactylosporangium vinaceum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>309</fpage><lpage>313</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dactylosporangium vinaceum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dactylosporangium vinaceum</i> (vi.n' ce.um. L. neut. adj. <i>vinaceum</i> wine colored, referring to the color of the diffusible pigment produced)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SF-2127 is the type strain'of D. vinaceum.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, Japan, under the number I F 0 14181.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological characteristics.</s><s>Colonies of strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> were compact, tough, and somewhat leathery.</s><s>The vegetative mycelium was long, irregularly branched, twisted, and 0.5 to 0.7 μm in diameter penetrated the agar.</s><s>Fragmentation of hyphae usually did not occur on agar or in submerged growth in liquid cultures.</s><s>Aerial mycelium was not usually observed on agar cultures; however, a slight trace of rudimentary hyphae developed on oatmeal agar (ISP medium 3).</s><s>Strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> produced finger-shaped sporangia.</s><s>Sporangia were occasionally apparent when the strain was grown on sucrose-nitrate agar and oatmeal agar, less apparent on inorganic salts-starch agar (ISP medium 4) and calcium malate agar, and rarely apparent on glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP medium 5 ) or yeast extract-malt extract agar (ISP medium 2); they appeared after 5 to 15 days of incubation at 28°C and occurred singly or in tufts on the surface of agar media.</s><s>Finger-shaped sporangia (0.8 to 1.1 by 3.0 to 5.5 μm) formed on short sporangiophores (0.5 to 1.5 μm long) which emerged directly from the vegetative hyphae.</s><s>Scanning electron microscoPY revealed finger-shaped sporangia with wrinkled envelopes (Fig.1).</s><s>Naked sporangiospores, which appeared shortly after the sporangial membranes broke, were also observed (Fig. 2 and 3).</s><s>Each sporangium contained three spores arranged in a single row.</s><s>Sporangia and newly emerged naked spores within a tuft were also apparent (Fig. 3).</s><s>Spores were cylindrical (some were oblong) and measured 0.6 to 0.9 by 0.9 to 1.8 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore release was observed by flooding the surfaces of sporangium-containing cultures with sterile water or soil extract solution.</s><s>After sporangium dehiscence occurred, the spores were clearly motile, but there was a time lag of about 30 min before they became highly motile.</s><s>Although motile spores were vigorous swimmers, flagellum staining was not successful.</s><s>Formation of globose bodies, which have been described by Thiemann et al. (15) and Sharples and Williams (11), was observed on both glucose-asparagine agar and nutrient agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Table 1 summarizes the amounts of growth, the formation of sporangia, the colors of reverse vegetative mycelia, and the diffusible pigments produced by strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> on various media.</s><s>Strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> was clearly distinct from the other strains studied in that it elaborated a diffusible pigment.</s><s>The color of this pigment ranged from wine to deep red; vegetative mycelium color varied from wine to ebony brown, depending on the amount of diffusion of extracellular pigment into the agar.</s><s>Pigment in the vegetative mycelia or the diffusible pigment was not sensitive to pH changes, since pigment color was stable when cultures were exposed to either 0.05 N HC1 or 0.05 N NaOH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics.</s><s>The results of a comparative study of the physiological characteristics of strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> with those of the type strains of other established species of <i>Dacrylosporangium</i> are summarized in Table 2.</s><s>All strains hydrolyzed starch, showed strong utilization of D-glucose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, L-arabinose, and L-rhamnose, failed to utilize raffinose, <i>i</i>-inositol, or glycerol, and did not produce melanoid pigment.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth of all strains was between 25 and 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall analysis.</s><s>An analysis of strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> cell wall hydrolysates by paper chromatography demonstrated the presence of 3-hydroxydiaminopimelic acid, which gave the same greenish color with ninhydrin reagent as diaminopimelic acid but moved more slowly than <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Furthermore, cell walls also contained large amounts of muramic acid, glutamic acid, glycine, and alanine and a trace of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Xylose and a trace of arabinose were detected as the sugars in the whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Thus, strain SF-2127<sup>T</sup> can be considered to have type I1 cell walls and whole-cell sugar pattern D in the classification scheme of Lechevalier and Lechevalier (6).</s></p></content></protolog>