<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4603_nm.6071" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6071" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6071" rank="species">Agreia bicolorata</organism><reference id="rid.4603"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobrovolskaya</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Streshinskaya</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Subbotin</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agreia bicolorata gen. nov., sp. nov., to accommodate actinobacteria isolated from narrow reed grass infected by the nematode Heteroanguina graminophila</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2073</fpage><lpage>2079</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760949</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agreia bicolorata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agreia bicolorata</i> (bi.co.lo.ra.ta. M.L. n. <i>bis</i> two; M.L. adj. <i>coloratum</i> coloured; M.L. fem. adj. <i>bicolorata</i> two-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>General morphological, chemotaxonomic and growth characteristics are as given above in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are yellow-orange to orange in young cultures and red-orange to brown-orange with age, semi-fluid or fluid.</s><s>Abundant capsule is usually formed.</s><s>Cells are irregular rods (0.4-0.5x1.2-2.5 μm) that are weakly motile.</s><s>In older cultures, shorter irregular rods predominate as single cells ; pairs or short chains with diphtheroid arrangements may be present.</s><s>A marked rod-coccus growth cycle does not occur.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Thermal optimum for growth is 24-26°C; growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan is of the B-type and contains DAB, ornithine, alanine, glycine and glutamate plus hydroxyglutamate (1:1:2:2:2 molar ratio).</s><s>Cell wall sugars are rhamnose, mannose and fucose.</s><s>DNA G­C content is about 67.0 mol%.</s><s>A wide range of carbohydrate and organic acids are used for growth; utilization of succinate, acetate and propionate varied in the strains.</s><s>Only a few amino acids are utilized as a source of nitrogen.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is weakly produced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is positive and methyl red test is negative.</s><s>No growth with 6% NaCl.</s><s>Strains are susceptible to 10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup> ampicillin, doxycycline, gentamicin, penicillin, rifampicin and tetracycline, but tolerate the same concentration of neomycin and streptomycin.</s><s>Isolated from leaf galls on Calamagrostis neglecta, induced by the plant-parasitic nematode <i>Heteroanguina graminophila</i> (Moscow region, Russia).</s><s>Type strain is VKMAc-1804<sup>T</sup> (=UCMAc-620<sup>T</sup>), deposited in the All-Russian collection of Microorganisms (VKM) and Ukrainian Collection of Microorganisms (UCM).</s></p></content></protolog>