<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1769_nm.3847" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3847" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3847" rank="species">Helicobacter muridarum</organism><reference id="rid.1769"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Rourke</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fraser</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romaniuk</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trust</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter muridarum sp. nov., a microaerophilic helical bacterium with a novel ultrastructure isolated from the intestinal mucosa of rodents.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>27</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-1-27</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1736969</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter muridarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter muridarum</i> (mu.ri.da'rum. L. n. <i>Muridae</i>, family name for Old World rats and mice; L. gen. n. <i>muridarum</i>, of the Muridae)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells that are 0.5 to 0.6 μm wide and 3.5 to 5.0 μm long and have two to three spiral turns.</s><s>Spherical forms 2 to 4 μm in diameter are present in older cultures.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>No endospores are produced.</s><s>Cells are motile with a rapid corkscrewlike motion.</s><s>Cells have bipolar tufts of 10 to 14 sheathed flagella.</s><s>Each cell is surrounded by 9 to 11 periplasmic fibers which appear as concentric helical ridges on the surface of the cell.</s><s>Microaerophilic.</s><s>Good growth occurs in atmospheres containing 1 to 16% oxygen and 5 to 10% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No growth occurs under aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Nutritionally fastidious, growing only on media enriched with blood or serum.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs on a moist agar surface.</s><s>Grows as a fine, translucent, spreading film on agar after 2 to 3 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37°C but not at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>Viability is lost rapidly.</s><s>No acid is produced from arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, or xylose.</s><s>Urease, oxidase, and catalase positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and arginine aminopeptidase are produced.</s><s>Lipase and lecithinase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, starch, tributyrin, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No production of N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, α-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, leucine aminopeptidase, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase , tyrosine aminopeptidase , arginine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase, histidine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase, or glycine aminopeptidase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 2% bile salts, 1% glycine, or 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to nalidixic acid and cephalothin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the intestinal mucosa of the rats and mice.</s><s>Type strain ST1 (= ATCC 49282) was isolated from a rat ileum, and its G+C content is 34 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>