<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12714_nm.22478" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22478" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22478" rank="species">Altererythrobacter dongtanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>Z.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>Y.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>G.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quan</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Altererythrobacter dongtanensis sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2035</fpage><lpage>2039</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024380-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851911</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Altererythrobacter dongtanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Altererythrobacter dongtanensis</em> (dong.ta.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>dongtanensis</em> pertaining to Dongtan, a wetland region in Chongming Island, Shanghai, China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods approximately 0.4–0.5×0.5–1.1 µm in size; no flagellum is detected.</s><s>Visible yellow colonies are formed after 2 days of incubation at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular and wet.</s><s>Cells do not produce flexirubin-type pigment on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C (optimum 30–37 °C), at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum pH 7.0–9.0) and in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl (optimum 0 %).</s><s>Positive for catalase and negative for oxidase.</s><s>Positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and β-galactosidase, but negative for urease, leucine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, lipase (C14), arginine dihydrolase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase, α-mannosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative for acidification of d-glucose, production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, trypsin activity and hydrolysis of starch, aesculin, gelatin and Tween 80.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon source: caprate, adipate, arabinose, citrate, gluconate, maltose, mannitol, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine or phenylacetate.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon source: d-glucose, fructose, acetate, pyruvate, glutamate, succinate and malate.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 (Q10) is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol are the major polar lipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JM27<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22672<sup>T</sup>  = CCTCC AB 209199<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat (Dongtan Wetland, Chongming Island, Shanghai, China).</s></p></content></protolog>