<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12589_nm.21848" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21848" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21848" rank="species">Polaribacter gangjinensis</organism><reference id="rid.12589"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kahng</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polaribacter gangjinensis sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1425</fpage><lpage>1429</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024869-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20622053</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Polaribacter gangjinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Polaribacter gangjinensis</em> (gang.ji.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>gangjinensis</em> referring to Gangjin, the name of the bay in Korea from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, strictly aerobic rods, approximately 0.3–0.4 µm wide and 0.5–0.8 µm long.</s><s>Motile by gliding.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular with entire margins, convex, translucent, orange and 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter after growth on MA at 30 °C for 4 days.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 1 %) as the sole salt, but not with 0 or &#x003E;5 % NaCl, and with 1–6 % (w/v) sea salts (optimum 2 %).</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C (optimum 30 °C), but not at 40 °C, and at pH 6.0–11.0 (optimum pH 6.0).</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A agar, but not on NA, NA plus 2.5 % (w/v) NaCl, TSA or TSA plus 3 % (w/v) sucrose.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are absent.</s><s>Cells produce carotenoid pigments with maximum absorption at approximately 476 nm and two shoulder peaks at approximately 450 and 507 nm.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to penicillin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, lincomycin, oleandomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, tetracycline, vancomycin, novobiocin, nalidixic acid and rifampicin but resistant to polymyxin B, streptomycin, neomycin, kanamycin, amikacin and gentamicin.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Starch, CM-cellulose and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but casein, chitin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are present, but esterase (C4), lipase (C14), α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>According to API 20NE and API 20E tests, nitrate is reduced to nitrogen, the Voges–Proskauer test is negative, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced, aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, β-galactosidase activity is present and glucose and maltose are assimilated.</s><s>With GN2 MicroPlates, glycogen, l-arabinose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, lactose, maltose, l-rhamnose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, thymidine and α-d-glucose 1-phosphate are utilized, all other substrates in the gallery are not utilized.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>15 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, three unidentified amino-group-containing lipids and an unidentified aminophospholipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is K17-16<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22729<sup>T</sup> = JCM 16152<sup>T</sup>), isolated from seawater of Gangjin Bay, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>