<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1601_nm.11305" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11305" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11305" rank="species">Paenibacillus ginsengarvi</organism><reference id="rid.1601"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus ginsengarvi sp. nov., isolated from soil from ginseng cultivation</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1810</fpage><lpage>1814</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64906-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684262</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus ginsengarvi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus ginsengarvi</em> (gin.seng.ar′vi. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>arvum</em> a field; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengarvi</em> of a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile rods that form oval spores positioned centrally in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur.</s><s>Grows between 18 and 45 °C (optimum 37 °C) and at pH 5.0–8.5 (optimum pH 6.5–7.0).</s><s>Tolerates NaCl at 2 % (w/v) but not 3 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA and nutrient agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA weakly, but does not hydrolyse chitin, starch, cellulose, xylan, lipids or casein.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, maltose, d-melibiose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin and gluconate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-mannose, l-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, propionate, caprate, phenylacetate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, acetate, 3-hydroxybutylate, valerate, citrate, lactate, malate, 5-ketogluconate, 2-ketoglutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, inositol, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, gelatin, urea, nitrate, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine and l-proline.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase and the Voges–Proskauer test in API 20E tests.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis, indole and hydrogen sulphide production are negative.</s><s>Acids are produced from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-raffinose and d-turanose.</s><s>Acids are not produced from erythritol, l-xylose, adonitol, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, d-lactose, inulin, d-melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 48.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 139<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13059<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18677<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>