<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5416_nm.3629" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3629" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3629" rank="species">Desulfuromusa succinoxidans</organism><reference id="rid.5416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic Analysis of Five Strains of Gram-Negative, Obligately Anaerobic, Sulfur-Reducing Bacteria and Description of Desulfuromusa gen. nov., Including Desulfuromusa kysingii sp. nov., Desulfuromusa bakii sp. nov., and Desulfuromusa succinoxidans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>753</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-753</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfuromusa succinoxidans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfuromusa succinoxidans</i> (suc.cin.ox'i.dans. L. n. <i>succinum</i>, amber; M.L. n. <i>acidum</i> <i>succinicum</i>, succinic acid [derived from amber]; M.L. v. <i>oxido</i>, make acid, oxidize; M.L. part.adj. <i>succinoxidans</i>, oxidizing succinate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.8 to 1.0 μm wide and 4 to 6 μm long when they are grown on elemental sulfur as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Nitrate, dimethyl sulfoxide, and Fe(III)-citrate are not utilized.</s><s>Cells grow with aspartate or maleate without additional electron acceptors, but growth is considerably slower than growth in the presence of elemental sulfur.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, lactate, propionate, oxalacetate, succinate, maleate, alanine, glutamate, aspartate, and yeast extract are used as electron donors.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized as an electron donor.</s><s>Strains can be cultivated in defined medium without addition of complex nutrients like yeast extract or peptone.</s><s>Cells grow in the presence of NaCl and MgCl, concentrations of 114 and 3.3 mM, respectively.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between 6.5 and 7.9; minimum and maximum pH values for growth are 5.8 and 8.25, respectively.</s><s>The minimum temperature for growth is 4°C; the maximum temperature is 35°C; and the optimum temperature is around 32°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Desulfuromusa succinoxidans</i> is strain Gylac (= DSM 8270); the G+C content of its DNA is 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Desulfuromusa succinoxidans</i> Gylac<sup>T</sup> was isolated from an anoxic mud sample collected at a depth of about 2,000 m from the Guayamas Basin (Gulf of California)</s></p></content></protolog>