<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8284_nm.14127" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14127" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14127" rank="species">Kineosporia babensis</organism><reference id="rid.8284"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakiyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thao</surname><given-names>N.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giang</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyadoh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hop</surname><given-names>D.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ando</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineosporia babensis sp. nov., isolated from plant litter in Vietnam.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>550</fpage><lpage>554</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002907-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244439</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kineosporia babensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kineosporia babensis</em> (ba.ben′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>babensis</em> referring to Ba Be National Park, Vietnam, from which the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The orange-coloured colonies grow prolifically on YS medium and appear moist and raised.</s><s>Each raised colony produces clusters of single spores.</s><s>The spore surface is smooth and the spores are globular and/or ovoid (1.0–2.0 μm in diameter).</s><s>Grows at 10–28 °C, but not at 5 or 37 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 3 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Melanin is not produced on ISP 6 or ISP 7.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction.</s><s>Decomposes aesculin, arbutin, casein, testosterone, l-tyrosine and urea, but not adenine, hypoxanthine or xanthine.</s><s>Utilizes carbon sources such as l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose, but not adonitol, d-arabitol, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-sorbose or xylitol.</s><s>Utilizes organic acids such as fumarate, malate and succinate, but not benzoate, mucate, oxalate or l-tartrate.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, l-rhamnose, sucrose and d-xylose, but not from adonitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, melezitose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>The cell wall contains major amounts of <em>meso</em>-A<sub>2</sub>pm and small amounts of ll-A<sub>2</sub>pm.</s><s>The whole-cell sugars are ribose, mannose, galactose and glucose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69–70 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, VN05A0415<sup>T</sup> (=VTCC-A-0961<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 104154<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from plant litter.</s></p></content></protolog>