<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2840_nm.1881" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1881" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1881" rank="species">Thiobacillus delicatus</organism><reference id="rid.2840"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Katayama-Fujimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawashima</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsuzaki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuraishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Physiological characteristics of the facultatively chemolithotrophic Thiobacillus species Thiobacillus delicatus nom. rev., emend., Thiobacillus perometabolis and Thiobacillus intermedius.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>139</fpage><lpage>144</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-139</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus delicatus</i> Mizoguchi et al. 1976 nom. rev. Katayama-Fujimura and Kuraishi emend. Katayama-Fujimura and Kuraishi</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus delicatus</i> (del.i.ca'tus. L. masc. adj. <i>delicatus</i> delicate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The emended description of the biochemical and physiological characteristics of <i>T. delicatus</i> is based on the characteristics of strain THI 091<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. delicatus</i> is a facultative anaerobe; it grows anaerobically in the presence of nitrate and accumulates nitrite in mixotrophic and autotrophic media supplemented with thiosulfate or tetrathionate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is a facultative chemolithotroph.</s><s>Heterotrophic growth occurs in a mixotrophic medium, but not with a single carbon source.</s><s>In mixotrophic medium supplemented with thiosulfate, this species grows in the presence of alanine, aspartate, glutamate, malate, succinate, citrate, or α-ketoglutarate.</s><s>It grows in liquid mineral salts medium supplemented with elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, or tetrathionate; this growth is accompanied by a decrease in the pH of the medium.</s><s>Thiocyanate does not support growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Potassium nitrate, ammonium chloride, and urea are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Glutamate and aspartate are utilized as both nitrogen and carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 15 to 42°C, but not at 10 or 45°C; optimum growth occurs between 30 and 35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.0 to 7.0, and optimum growth occurs at pH 5 . 5 to 6.0 in SM basal salts-thiosulfate-yeast extract medium and SM basal salts-thiosulfate medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species requires elemental sulfur or thiosulfate for optimum growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content is 66.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ubiquinone system is ubiquinone 8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism contains hexadecanoic acid, hexadecenoic acid plus C<sub>17</sub> cyclopropane acid, and octadecenoic acid plus C<sub>19</sub> cyclopropane acid as major nonhydroxy cellular fatty acids, and 3-hydroxydecanoic acid and a trace amount of 3-hydroxy-8-methylnonanoic acid as hydroxylated fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from mine water (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this organism is strain THI 091; this strain has been deposited with the Institute of Applied Microbiology, University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan, as strain IAM 12624.</s></p></content></protolog>