<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4335_nm.5139" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5139" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5139" rank="species">Paenibacillus koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.4335"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus koreensis sp. nov., a new species that produces an iturin-like antifungal compound.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1495</fpage><lpage>1500</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939655</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus koreensis</i> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus koreensis</i> (ko.re.en«sis, M.L. masc. adj. koreensis indicating Korea, the geographical origin of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, measuring 0.5-0.9x2.3-4.5 μm and motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Three types of colonies are formed when grown on 0.1x TSA: circular, flat, smooth and opaque; circular, convex, glistening and translucent; and circular or irregular, wrinkled hollow and opaque.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, growing at 10-50 °C with an optimum growth temperature of 38-40 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.001%lysozyme, but not in the presence of 7% NaCl.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Negative for urease, lysine decarboxylase, indole production and Voges-Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Casein, chitin, chitosan, aesculin and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes sodium acetate and malonate as sole carbon sources, but not acetamide and citrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol and xylose oxidatively, and fermentatively from arabinose, arabitol, amylopectin, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, palatinose, raffinose, sorbitol and sucrose.</s><s>Carbohydrates not utilized by the species are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-15:0.</s><s>The G+­C content is 54 mol%.</s><s>A 16S rDNA fragment (0.9 kb) is amplified by PCR with primers PAEN515F and 1377R.</s><s>Inhibits the growth of fungi by producing an iturin-like antifungal compound.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Paenibacillus koreensis</i> YC300<sup>T</sup> and has been deposited in the Korean Collection for Type Cultures and the Korean Culture Center of Microorganisms under the accession numbers KCTC 2393<sup>T</sup> and KCCM 40903<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>