<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.756_nm.6476" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6476" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6476" rank="species">Rhodococcus chlorophenolicus</organism><reference id="rid.756"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Apajalahti</surname><given-names>J.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kärpänoja</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus chlorophenolicus sp. nov., a chlorophenol-mineralizing Actinomycete</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>246</fpage><lpage>251</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus chlorophenolicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodococcus chlorophenolicus</i> (chlor.o.phen.ó.li. cus. N.L. adj. <i>chloro</i> containing chlorine, fr. Gr. adj. <i>chloros</i> pale green; N.L. n. <i>pheno</i> phenol, hydroxybenzene, fr. Gr. <i>phaino</i> shine, to be shining, appear; N.L. adj. <i>chlorophenolicus</i> relating to chlorophenols)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive, cytochrome oxidase negative, catalase positive, strictly aerobic, and rod shaped (1.0 to 1.5 by 3 to 4 μm) and become coccoid upon prolonged incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Figure 1 shows the morphological cycle on yeast extractglucose agar (13).</s><s>The inoculum form is coccoid (Fig. 1A).</s><s>After 12 h of incubation, unbranched rods predominate (Fig. 1B).</s><s>After 7 days of incubation the rods fragment into coccoids (Fig. 1E).</s><s>Figure 2A shows an electron micrograph of a culture that was grown for 4 days on yeast extract glucose agar.</s><s>A thick capsule-like material surrounds the cells after 2 weeks of incubation (Fig. 2B).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On yeast extract agar and rhamnose agar, colonies are orange pigmented and slightly mucoid.</s><s>Visible colonies are formed after 1 to 2 weeks of incubation at 28°C; after 1 month of incubation the colonies are 2 to 4 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 18, 28, (optimum), and 37°C, but not at 10 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In APISO CH tests performed with API 20NE medium, growth is produced on erythritol, L-arabinose, ribose (weak), D-xylose, adonitol, glucose (weak), fructose, rhamnose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, N-acetylglucosamine (weak), arbutin (weak), sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, and gluconate.</s><s>No growth is produced on glycerol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, β-methyl-D-xyloside, galactose, mannose, sorbose, dulcitol, α-methyl-Dmannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, amygdalin, esculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, Dturanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, or 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>After 7 days of incubation in a mineral salts medium supplemented with vitamins and trace elements, growth is produced with 1% (wt/vol) inositol, rhamnose, sorbitol, and trehalose, but not with 1% glycerol, 1% maltose, or 0.1% m-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.003 and 3.0% NaCl, but not in the presence of 7% NaCl after 7 days of incubation at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose, and glucose.</s><s>The following simple fatty acids are released by acid methanolysis (relative abundance values are indicated in parentheses): C<sub>14:0</sub> (23.6), C<sub>15:0</sub> (12.2), C<sub>16:0</sub> (100.0), C<sub>16:0</sub> (20.3), C<sub>18:0</sub> (11.6), C<sub>18:1</sub> (87.5), 10CH<sub>3</sub>C<sub>18</sub> (tuberculostearic acid) (67.4), C<sub>20:0</sub> (3.5), C<sub>22:0</sub> (4.3), and C<sub>24:0</sub> (4.7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mycolic acids are present and contain 33 to 43 carbon atoms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Menaquinones with nine isoprenoid units and one hydrogenated double bond (MK-9H<sup>2</sup>) predominate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain PCP-I (=DSM 43826), was isolated from a lake sediment.</s><s>This strain degrades pentachlorophenol, 2,3,4,5-tetrachlorophenol, 2,3,4,6- tetrachlorophenol, 2,3,5,6-tetrachlorophenol, 2,3,5-trichlorophenol, and 2,3,6-trichlorophenol (Apajalahti and Salkinoja-Salonen, submitted).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 2 shows the chemical and morphological characteristics that are essential for differentiating the genera <i>Corynebacterium</i>, <i>Caseobacter</i>, <i>Rhodococcus</i>, <i>Nocardia</i>, and <i>Mycobacterium</i>.</s><s>The question of whether <i>Caseobacter</i> should be included in the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i> or considered a distinct genus is still unanswered.</s><s>However, when the properties shown in Table 2 are taken as classification criteria, strain PCP-I is clearly a member of the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>