<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4337_nm.9835" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9835" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9835" rank="species">Jannaschia seosinensis</organism><reference id="rid.4337"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jannaschia seosinensis sp. nov., isolated from hypersaline water of a solar saltern in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>49</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63835-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403865</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jannaschia seosinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jannaschia seosinensis</em> (se.o.sin.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>seosinensis</em> referring to the Seosin region in Korea, where the type strain was found).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic and straight rods, approximately 0·7–1·2 μm wide and 1·1–2·3 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by one or more monopolar flagella.</s><s>On MA solid medium, colonies are dark red, entire, circular, convex and shiny.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll is not detected.</s><s>After 4 days on MA at 30 °C colonies are approximately 0·8–1·5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 5–35 °C (optimum of 30–35 °C) and pH 7–10.</s><s>Growth occurs in sea salt concentrations of 3–10 % (w/v) (optimum of 3–5 %), but no growth occurs in media containing only NaCl as a salt.</s><s>Positive for catalase, amylase, gelatinase and nitrate reductase, but negative for oxidase, DNase and degradation of Tween 80.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (64 %) and 18 : 0 (12·0 %); 3-OH 14 : 0 and/or iso 16 : 1 (3·6 %), 18 : 3<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (2·2 %) and 10-methyl 19 : 0 (1·9 %) are found in minor quantities.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, the type strain is negative for nitrate reductase, gelatinase, arginine dihydrolase, urease, indole production and acid production from glucose, but positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, the type strain is positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4 and C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: d-glucose, salicin, pyruvic acid, Casamino acids, dl-aspartate, succinate, urea and l-glutamate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CL-SP26<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42114<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13035<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a hypersaline water sample from a solar saltern.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>