<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6887_nm.7285" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7285" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7285" rank="species">Streptomyces stramineus</organism><reference id="rid.6887"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Testa</surname><given-names>R.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces stramineus sp. nov., a new species of the verticillate streptomycetes.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>747</fpage><lpage>753</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226907</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces stramineus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces stramineus</i> (stra.min'e.us. L. adj. <i>stramineus</i>, straw colored, referring to the color of the aerial mycelium and spore mass)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The substrate mycelium is yellow to yellowish brown.</s><s>Aerial mycelium forms verticils on which umbels consisting of straight chains of ovoid, smooth-surface, straw yellow spores (0.5 by 1.0 μm) are produced.</s><s>Soluble pigments that range from yellowish to shades of brown are produced on several media, such as yeast extract-malt extract agar.</s><s>Casein, esculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, and xanthine are hydrolyzed; adenine and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced; nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced from tyrosine.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of glycerol, 5% NaC1, and lysozyme; no growth occurs in the presence of salicylate.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, and succinate are assimilated; benzoate, lactate, mucate, oxalate, and tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, dextrin, fructose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, and trehalose; no acid is produced from arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, galactose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, xylose, or β-methyl-D-xyloside.</s><s>Growth occurs on fructose, glucose, inositol, and mannitol as the sole carbon source but not on galactose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, or xylose.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 42°C, but not 52°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 75 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from a grassland soil sample from South Dakota.</s><s>Produces the antibiotics LL-B01208a and LLB01208P.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. stramineus</i> is NRRL 12292.</s></p></content></protolog>