<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8522_nm.13482" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13482" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13482" rank="species">Nocardioides fonticola</organism><reference id="rid.8522"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>N.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides fonticola sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from spring water.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1864</fpage><lpage>1868</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65810-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676470</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides fonticola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides fonticola</em> [fon.ti.co′la. L. masc. n. <em>fons</em>, <em>fontis</em> a spring, fountain; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> (from L. masc. or fem. n. <em>incola</em>) an inhabitant of a place, a resident; N.L. n. <em>fonticola</em> an inhabitant of a fountain or spring].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and non-acid-fast.</s><s>No endospore formation.</s><s>Cells are non-motile rods, approximately 0.8 μm wide and 2.0–9.0 μm long.</s><s>Substrate or aerial mycelium is not observed.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are pale yellowish in colour, circular and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.9–1.0 mm in diameter after 3 days (on R2A at 25 °C) of incubation and reach a maximum of 2 mm after 5 days of growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0.5–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl, pH 5–9 and 25–37 °C, with optimum growth at 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl, pH 7–8 and 30 °C.</s><s>Starch, skimmed milk, and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>DNase-positive and lipase (corn oil)-negative.</s><s>The following characters are positive (API 20NE test) for the type strain: aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose and mannitol.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, malate, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Strain NAA-13<sup>T</sup> is positive (API ZYM test) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, but is negative for C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Positive (API Coryne test) for pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, and aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, urease, and acid production from d-glucose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-lactose, sucrose, d-ribose and glycogen.</s><s>Resistant to nalidixic acid, ceftizoxime and sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim antibiotics and sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, novobiocin, rifampicin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Cell wall diamino acid is ll-DAP.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (19.9 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (19.9 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (13.3 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (11.7 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NAA-13<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24213<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 16874<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from spring water, southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>