<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5226_nm.5982" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5982" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5982" rank="species">Brachybacterium conglomeratum</organism><reference id="rid.5226"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of the genus Brachybacterium: proposal of Brachybacterium conglomeratum sp. nov., nom. rev., Brachybacterium paraconglomeratum sp. nov., and Brachybacterium rhamnosum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-160</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachybacterium conglomeratum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachybacterium conglomeratum</i> (con.glo.me.ra'tum. L. part. adj. <i>conglomeratum</i>, rolled together)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Brachybacterium conglomeratum</i> is gram positive, nonmotile, and nonsporing.</s><s>In the stationary growth phase, cells are coccoid; however, when a culture is transferred to fresh medium, the cells become oval or rod shaped.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, low convex, smooth, opaque, and whitish yellow or pale brown.</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Grows well in the presence of 7.5% NaCl and weakly in the presence of 10 to 15% NaCl.</s><s>Some strains grow at pH 5.0.</s><s>Starch, esculin, and urea are hydrolyzed, but Tween 20 and Tween 40 are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyze Tween 60 and Tween 80.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-galactose, and D-glucose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from trehalose, mannitol, sorbitol, and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is based on <i>meso</i>-DAP.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are galactose and glucose.</s><s>The cell wall muramic acid occurs in the <i>N</i>-glycolyl form.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are primarily straight-chain, saturated, iso and anteiso methyl-branched fatty acids; anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> are the predominant fatty acids.</s><s>The major polar phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, unidentified glycolipids, and unidentified, ninhydrin-positive phosphoglycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70.2 to 71.6 mol%; the G+C content of the type strain is 70.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCM 2589 (= IFO 15472).</s></p></content></protolog>