<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4542_nm.2530" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2530" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2530" rank="species">Chromohalobacter salexigens</organism><reference id="rid.4542"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vargas</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cánovas</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nieto</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromohalobacter salexigens sp. nov., a moderately halophilic species that includes Halomonas elongata DSM 3043 and ATCC 33174.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1457</fpage><lpage>1462</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chromohalobacter salexigens</i>sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chromohalobacter salexigens</i> (sal.ex'i.gens. L. n. <i>sal</i> salt ; L. v. <i>exigo</i> to demand; M.L. part. adj. <i>salexigens</i>, salt-demanding)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 0.7-1.0x2.0-3.0 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>On solid, complex medium containing 10% (w/v) salts, colonies are cream, opaque and circular and less than 2 mm in diameter; spreading may occur after extended incubation.</s><s>In liquid medium containing 10% (w/v) salts, they produce homogeneous turbidity.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing 0.9-25% (w/v) salt and optimal growth occurs at 7.5-10% (w/v) salts.</s><s>Growth occurs from pH 5 to 10 on liquid media containing 10% total salts (optimal growth at pH 7.5) and between 15 and 45 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 37 °C.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, glycerol, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, sucrose and D-xylose but not from trehalose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Citrate-positive.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, aesculin, DNA and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from cysteine.</s><s>Indole and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red-positive.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: L-arabinose, erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, α-D-glucose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-ribose, D-xylose, ethanol, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, dulcitol, acetate, α-aminovalerate, α-ketoglutarate, citrate, fumarate, DL-glycerate, glutamate, malate, malonate, propionate, D-saccharate, succinate and D-tartrate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, cellobiose, L-fucose, α-lactose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, galactosamine, gluconolactone, inulin, DL-aaminobutyrate, butyrate, caprylate, lactate and oxalate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: L-arginine, L-asparagine, betaine, glycine, L-glutamine, L-lysine, L-ornithine, L-proline and L-serine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: L-alanine, creatine, L-methionine, putrescine, sarcosine, L-threonine and L-valine.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 64.2-66.0 mol%(<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>The EMBL accession numbers of the 16S rRNA gene sequences of strains DSM 3043<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 33174 determined in this study are AJ295146 and AJ295147, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from salterns.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 3043<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-138<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5384<sup>T</sup>=CCM 4921<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106854T¯NCIMB 13768<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>