<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12554_nm.21418" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21418" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21418" rank="species">Niabella tibetensis</organism><reference id="rid.12554"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Niabella tibetensis sp. nov., isolated from soil, and emended description of the genus Niabella</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1201</fpage><lpage>1205</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022103-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20562241</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Niabella tibetensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Niabella tibetensis</em> (ti.be.ten′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>tibetensis</em> of or belonging to Tibet, an autonomous region in north-west China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, short rods, 0.5–0.8 µm in diameter and 1.1–1.7 µm in length, which are non-flagellated, non-gliding and Gram-stain-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A agar after incubation at 30 °C for 48 h.</s><s>Good growth also occurs on TSA and NA, but not on MA.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are orange, convex and circular, with regular margins.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–1 % NaCl (w/v), at 15–34 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and at pH 5.0–8.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–7.0).</s><s>Produces flexirubin-type pigments.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, but not chitin, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA or starch.</s><s>Positive for indole production, aesculin hydrolysis and β-galactosidase activity, but negative for nitrate reduction, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20NE).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin and β-glucuronidase activities are absent (API ZYM).</s><s>d-Glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin and melibiose are assimilated (API 20NE and API ID 32GN).</s><s>d-Mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline are not assimilated.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;13 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 15-4<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AB 209167<sup>T</sup> = NRRL B-59394<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the surface layer of a desert soil from Tibet Province, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>