<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2231" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2231" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2231" rank="species">Xanthomonas translucens</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas translucens</i> (ex Jones, Johnson, and Reddy 1917) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. translucens</i> is the same as that of the genus. The strains of this species cause diseases in various members of the <i>Poaceae</i>. On the basis of phytopathogenic specialization or differences in virulence (3, 11), the following pathovars can be distinguished: <i>X. translucens</i> pv. arrhenatheri, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. cerealis, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. graminis, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. hordei, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. phlei, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. phleipratensis, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. poae, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. secalis, <i>X. translucens</i> pv. translucens, and <i>X. translucens</i> pv. undulosa.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. translucens</i> strains can be distinguished from other xanthomonads by their SDS-PAGE protein patterns and FAME profiles (51, 60), by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, maltose, D-psicose, D-trehalose, alaninamide, L-alanylglycine, and L-glutamic acid, and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, α-D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, acetic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, and DL-α-glycerolphosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 69.1 to 69.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is <i>X. translucens</i> pv. translucens LMG 876 (= NCPPB 973 = ATCC 19319 = ICMP 5752).</s></p></content></protolog>