<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.261_nm.4350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4350" rank="species">Desulfotomaculum thermocisternum</organism><reference id="rid.261"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nilsen</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torsvik</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lien</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfotomaculum thermocisternum sp. nov., a sulfate reducer isolated from a hot North Sea oil reservoir.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>397</fpage><lpage>402</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-397</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfotomaculum thermocisternum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfotomaculum thermocisternum</i> (ther.mo.cis.ter'num. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; L. fem. n. <i>cisterna</i>, reservoir; N. L. adj. <i>thermocisternum</i>, hot reservoir, referring to the original habitat of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods that occur singly and in chains and are 0.7 to 1.0 μm in diameter and 2.0 to 5.2 μm long.</s><s>Cells of different sizes can occur in the same chain.</s><s>Cells have peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Spores are spherical and central and distend the cells.</s><s>No gas vacuoles are observed.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as carbon and energy sources in the presence of sulfate: H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, lactate, pyruvate, propionate, butyrate, pentanoate, hexanoate, heptanoate, octanoate, nonanoate, decanoate, tetradecanoate, pentadecanoate, hexadecanoate, heptadecanoate, ethanol, propanol, and butanol.</s><s>Lactate is incompletely oxidized to acetate.</s><s>The organism grows fermentatively on pyruvate.</s><s>In the absence of sulfate it also grows on propionate in coculture with a hydrogenotrophic methanogen.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, and thiosulfate are utilized as electron acceptors.</s><s>Biotin is required as a growth factor.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 41 to 75°C; the optimum temperature is 62°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.2 to 8.9; the optimum pH is 6.7.</s><s>The NaCl concentration range for growth is 17 pM to 800 mM; the NaCl optimum concentration is 50 to 200 mM.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 56 mol% as determined by HPLC and 57 mol% as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from pure formation water that originated from the subterranean Brent Group oil formation 2.6 km below the sea floor in the Norwegian sector of the North Sea.</s><s>The type strain is strain ST90 (= DSM 10259).</s></p></content></protolog>