<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1513_nm.1066" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1066" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1066" rank="species">Hyphomonas jannaschiana</organism><reference id="rid.1513"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiner</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devine</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Powell</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dagasan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hyphomonas oceanitis sp. nov., Hyphomonas hirschiana sp.nov., and Hyphomonas jannaschiana sp.nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>237</fpage><lpage>243</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hyphomonas jannaschiana</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyphomonas jannaschiana</i> (jan' nasch. i. an. a. L. fem. adj. <i>jannaschiana</i> named for Holger Jannasch for his contributions to marine microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mature mother cells are 0.5 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm, and the main body of the cell tends to be elongated and bullet or spindle shaped.</s><s>Young swarmer cells are motile and pear shaped and resemble those of other members of the genus.</s><s>On blood agar, colonies are small, dull grey, dry, and circular to irregular with dimpled elevations and lobate margins (strains VP1 and VP3) or grey, circular, convex, entire, glistening, and mucoid (strains VP2<sup>T</sup> and VP4), resembling <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i> colonies, which have a similar shape and are white.</s><s>In broth, growth appears granular, and a film of tan cells covers the sides and bottom of the culture vessel (strains VP1 and VP3), or growth may appear ropy and produce only a slight film (strains VP2<sup>T</sup> and VP4).</s><s>Strains VP1 and VP3 tend to form rosette-like cell aggregates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A brown pigment with chemical properties characteristic of melanins (1,7) is produced in type 2216 marine broth at 31 to 37°C.</s><s>A mixture containing glutamic acid, aspartic acid, and serine as substrates and the cofactor biotin is required for chemoorganotrophic growth.</s><s>The temperature for optimum growth is 37°C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration for optimum growth is 3.5 to 7.5%.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Produces α-hemolysis on Zobell marine medium supplemented with 5% sheep blood.</s><s>Susceptible to NP-40 (0.01%), novobiocin, penicillin, ampicillin, and streptomycin.</s><s>Resistant to Tween 80 (1.0%).</s><s>Very resistant to breakage by sonication.</s><s>Other nutritional and biochemical test results are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses some surface antigens in common with <i>Hyphomonas hirschiana</i>, but none in common with <i>Hyphomonas oceanitis</i>, <i>Hyphomonas polymorpha</i>, or <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i> (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Four strains, strains ATCC 33882 (= VP1), ATCC 33883<i>T</i> (= VP2<i>T</i>), ATCC 33884 (= VP3), and ATCC 33885 (= VP4) of <i>Hyphomonas jannaschiana</i> were isolated in 1979 (8) from shellfish beds near hydrothermal vents on the floor of the mid-Pacific Ocean.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fine structure of the vent strains is shown in Fig. 2.</s><s>The appearance is typical of gram-negative bacteria.</s><s>The only notable difference among the strains is the consistent presence of large dark granules in strains VP1 and VP3.</s><s>The occurrence of these granules is independent of the medium used for culturing.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of strains VP1, VP2<sup>T</sup>, VP3, and VP4 are 60 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Low levels of DNA homology occur between all four isolates and <i>Hyphomonas polymorpha</i> PS728<sup>T</sup> (Gebers et al., in press) (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains cannot be differentiated on the basis of morphological, serological, nutritional, or biochemical tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain VP2 (= ATCC 33883).</s></p></content></protolog>