<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.342_nm.6763" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6763" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6763" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora spinosa</organism><reference id="rid.342"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora spinosa sp. nov. isolated from soil collected in a sugar mill rum still.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>34</fpage><lpage>39</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharopolyspora spinosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora spinosa</i> (spi no' sa. L. adj. <i>spinosa</i>, spiny, referring to the spiny spore sheath surface)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, gram positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile, filamentous, and differentiated into substrate and aerial hyphae.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is yellowish pink, and the vegetative mycelium is yellow to yellowish brown.</s><s>A soluble brown pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>Spore chains have a distinctive beadlike appearance.</s><s>A spore sheath is present and is covered with short spines.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-fructose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-ribose, and trehalose; no acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, cellulose, dextrin, dulcitol, ethanol, D-galactose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, alpha-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, xylitol, and D-xylose.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, butyrate citrate, formate, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, and succinate; does not assimilate benzoate, mucate, oxalate, and tartrate.</s><s>Allantoin, malate, casein, elastin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, testosterone, tyrosine, and urea are hydrolyzed or degraded; adenine, esculin, guanine, starch, and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Catalase, H<sub>2</sub>S, phosphatase, and urease are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not produced.</s><s>Sensitive to lysozyme.</s><s>Unable to survive a temperature of 50°C for 8 h.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 11% NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15 to 37°C.</s><s>Cell wall chemotype IV, type A sugar pattern, phospholipid type PIII, and menaquinone MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>No mycolic acids are present.</s><s>Saturated and branched fatty acids are present.</s><s>Resistant to cephalothin, kasugamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, oligomycin, oxytetracycline, penicillin, polymixin B, rifampin, and trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A83543.1<sup>T</sup> resembles <i>S. erythraea</i> in morphological characteristics, but differs from it and all of the other species in physiological characteristics (Table 2) and in fatty acid composition (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain A83543.1 (= NRRL 18395).</s><s>This strain was isolated from soil collected from a sugar mill rum still in the Virgin Islands.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and thus serves as the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>