<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1393_nm.4824" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4824" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4824" rank="species">Acholeplasma morum</organism><reference id="rid.1393"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Del Giudice</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acholeplasma morum, a new non-sterol-requiring species.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>647</fpage><lpage>654</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-4-647</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acholeplasma morum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acholeplasma morum</i> (L. noun <i>morum</i>, mulberry)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological and cultural properties.</s><s>Broth cultures of strains 72-043 and S2 examined by dark-field microscopy showed predominately round and coccobacillary forms, with some beaded filaments and star forms in older cultures.</s><s>Cells stained by the Gram technique revealed gram-negative pleomorphic structures similar to those observed in dark-field preparations.</s><s>Electron microscopic examination of thin sections of cell pellets showed a pleomorphic organism with a unit membrane and no evidence of cell wall material outside the membrane (Fig. 1).</s><s>Broth cultures became turbid in 18 h at 37°C and in 48 h at 23°C.</s><s>The organisms grew well in medium containing 1% bovine serum fraction or in broth supplemented with 20% concentrations of fetal bovine serum or agamma horse serum (Table 2).</s><s>However, very poor growth, or no growth, occurred in broth medium containing 20% horse serum, 20% newborn calf serum, or 20% agamma calf serum.</s><s>Decreasing the quantity of horse serum in the broth to 5 or 10%, or reducing the newborn calf serum to 5%, removed the inhibition expressed at the higher serum levels.</s><s>Adequate growth could be maintained in a serum-free medium only when it was supplemented with albumin and palmitic acid.</s><s>Colonies on serum-free agar were small (60 to 100 μm) and very rough or irregular (Fig. 2A).</s><s>Colonies on the bovine serum fraction agar were slightly larger (100 to 150 μm) and also displayed the rough mulberry-like appearance seen on serum-free agar (Fig. 2B).</s><s>Optimum growth on agar occurred after 48 h at 37°C under anaerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reversion studies.</s><s>Cultures maintained in antibiotic-free broth medium for seven passages showed no reversion to bacterial forms, either when examined by Gram-staining techniques or when plated to bacteriological agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration studies.</s><s>A cloned broth culture of strain 72-043 contained 1.5 X 10<sup>7</sup> colony-forming units/ml before filtration through a series of membrane filters.</s><s>The number of colony-forming units per milliliter after filtration through membrane filters of 450-, 300-, and 220-nm average pore size were 4.5 X 10<sup>6</sup>, 6.0 X 10<sup>4</sup>, and 5.5 x 10 <sup>2</sup>, respectively.</s><s>Cells did not pass through the 100-nm filter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and biological properties.</s><s>The results of the biochemical and biological tests performed on strains 72-043 and S2 are summarized in Table 3.</s><s>Both strains fermented glucose but not mannose.</s><s>They hydrolyzed esculin and arbutin, but gave a weak (1+) reaction in the latter test.</s><s>Neither strain produced carotenoid pigments under the test conditions used.</s><s>The growth response of strain 72-043 to cholesterol is shown in Table 4.</s><s>None of the levels of cholesterol tested showed any stimulation of growth, and Tween 80 appeared to exert some inhibitory activity against this strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological tests.</s><s>Growth inhibition and plate immunofluorescence tests, with antisera or onjugates prepared to the mycoplasmas listed in Table 1, indicated that these strains were serologically unrelated to previously established <i>Acholeplasma</i> species or to other glucose-fermenting <i>Mycoplasma</i> species.</s><s>The two strains under examination showed complete serological cross-reactions with each other by both test procedures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Polyacrylamide gel patterns.</s><s>A comparison of the cell proteins of strains 72-043 and S2 by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis is shown in Fig. 3.</s><s>The patterns of the two strains are similar to each other but appeared to be distinct from those of other <i>Acholeplasma</i> species represented in a collection in the National Institutes of Health laboratory.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA characteristics.</s><s>The melting temperature of the DNA of both acholeplasmas was found to be 79.4°C, whereas that obtained with <i>S. citri</i> was recorded as 76.O°C.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content for strains 72-043 and S2 was calculated to be 34.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 72-043 is designated as the type strain.</s><s>A cloned line of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 33211.</s></p></content></protolog>