<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6616_nm.3844" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3844" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3844" rank="species">Helicobacter hepaticus</organism><reference id="rid.6616"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorelick</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter hepaticus sp. nov., a microaerophilic bacterium isolated from livers and intestinal mucosal scrapings from mice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>1238</fpage><lpage>1245</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8051250</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter hepaticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter hepaticus</i> (he.pa'ti.cus. Gr. adj. <i>hepatikos</i>, relating to the liver)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slender curved-to-spiral rods (0.2 to 0.3 μm by 1.5 to 5.0 μm) which form one to three spiral turns.</s><s>They are gram negative and nonsporulating and are motile by means of sheathed, single, bipolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies are pinpoint, but cultures often appear as a thin spreading layer on agar media.</s><s>Cells exhibit microaerophilic or anaerobic growth, but there is no growth aerobically.</s><s>There is growth at 37°C but not at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>There is growth in 1.5% NaCl, 1% glycine, 0.4% triphenyltetrazolium chloride, and 0.1% trimethylamine N-oxide (anaerobically). <i>H. hepaticus</i> produces urease, catalase, and oxidase activity.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is detected on lead acetate discs.</s><s>Indoxyl acetate is hydrolyzed, whereas hippurate is not.</s><s>Cells are resistant to cephalothin and nalidixic acid but sensitive to metronidazole.</s><s>Cells have been isolated from the colons and ceca of mice, as well as from the livers of mice with active, chronic hepatitis.</s><s>The type strain Hh-2 was isolated from the liver of a mouse with active, chronic hepatitis.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 51448.</s><s>The essentially complete 16S rRNA sequence of the type strain is available for electronic retrieval from the GenBank, EMBL, and DDBJ data bases under accession no. U07574.</s></p></content></protolog>