<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1928_nm.3072" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3072" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3072" rank="species">Aeromonas veronii</organism><reference id="rid.1928"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>MacDonald</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas veronii, a new ornithine decarboxylase-positive species that may cause diarrhea.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>900</fpage><lpage>906</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3584425</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas veronii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas veronii</i> (pronounced vehr-rhoń-ee-eye) is derived from the surname of M. M. Véron, a French microbiologist who has contributed greatly to our knowledge of the genera <i>Vibrio</i> and <i>Aeromonas</i> (13, 20, 21) and who coined the family name <i>Vibrionaceae</i> in 1965.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose the name <i>Aeromonas veronii</i> for the nine strains that are listed in Tables 1 and 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species name is treated as a modern (neo) Latin genitive noun meaning "of Véron." The type strain of the species is designated as CDC 1169-83 (ATCC 35604).</s><s>A complete description of <i>A. veronii</i> is given in Tables 2 through 6.</s><s>The complete biochemical reactions of <i>A. veronii</i> are given in Table 2.</s><s>The unique feature of <i>A. veronii</i> compared with other <i>Aeromonas</i> strains was its positive reaction for ornithine decarboxylase and negative reaction for arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>The <i>A. veronii</i> strains were string test<sub>-</sub>, produced gas from D-glucose, were resistant to 0/129 (7), and did not require added NaCl for growth.</s><s>This is a pattern typical of <i>Aeromonas</i> species. <i>A. veronii</i> had an antibiogram typical of other <i>Aeromonas</i> strains: resistance to penicillin, ampicillin, and carbenicillin but susceptibility to chloramphenicol, colistin, gentamicin, and tetracycline (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Practical identification of <i>A. veronii</i>.</s><s>When strain 1169-83 was compared biochemically with all other strains of the <i>Vibrionaceae</i> and <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> in our computer data base, the ones that were the closest matches were <i>V. cholerae</i> strains rather than <i>Aeromonas</i> strains.</s><s>The nine <i>A. veronii</i> strains had seven different API 20E profiles (Table 7).</s><s>Two of the profiles, 5 346 125 (strains 0935-84 and 1068-84) and 5 347 125 (strain 0265-84), were identified as <i>V. cholerae</i> profiles.</s><s>Therefore, it is important to distinguish strains of <i>A. veronii</i> and <i>V. cholerae</i>.</s><s>In contrast to <i>V. cholerae</i> strains, <i>A. veronii</i> strains produced gas during fermentation and were string test<sup>-</sup> (Table 6).</s><s>The nine <i>A. veronii</i> strains were beta-hemolytic on sheep blood within 24 h, and colonies were 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>The <i>A. veronii</i> strains grew well on MacConkey agar as lactose-negative colonies approximately 2 mm in diameter (24 h).</s><s>Only one (1170-83) of eight strains tested grew on thiosulfate-citrate-bile salts-sucrose agar.</s><s>The growth was light (plating efficiency less than 10-3), and the colonies were sucrose<sup>+</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>