<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6246_nm.3098" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3098" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3098" rank="species">Escherichia hermannii</organism><reference id="rid.6246"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riddle</surname><given-names>C.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McWhorter</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saitoh</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Atypical biogroups of Escherichia coli found in clinical specimens and description of Escherichia hermannii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>703</fpage><lpage>713</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7040466</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Escherichia hermannii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Escherichia hermannii</i> (modem Latin noun hermannii, her.man' ni.i pronounced her.mahn'nee.eye, of Hermann; in honor of George J. Hermann, former chief of the Enteric Section at the CDC, for his many contributions to enteric bacteriology and for Lloyd G. Herman, formerly of the Environmental Services Branch, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Md., for his contributions to the study of yellow-pigmented bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>f is a gramnegative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, nonsporeforming rod, motile with lophotrichous (two or more flagella at one or both poles) or degenerately peritrichous (flagella distributed unevenly over much of the cell periphery) flagella (Fig. 1), that reduces nitrate to nitrite, ferments D-glucose and other carbohydrates with the production of acid and gas, has 53 to 58 mol% (thermal denaturation) G+C in its DNA, and is isolated from food and a variety of human clinical specimens.</s><s>It is positive in reactions for maltose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-mannitol, mucate, indole, methyl red, and ornithine decarboxylase, negative in reactions for adonitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, Voges-Proskauer, Simmons citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S, urea, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, and gelatin, negative or delayed for lysine decarboxylase, and variable in reactions for lactose and sucrose.</s><s>A further description of <i>E. hermannii</i> is found in the tables and figure, as well as below.</s><s>The type strain (holotype) ATCC 33650 (CDC 980-72) was isolated from an infected toe of a 17-year-old female in Louisiana.</s></p></content></protolog>