<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1380_nm.5588" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5588" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5588" rank="species">Leuconostoc pseudomesenteroides</organism><reference id="rid.1380"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nucleic acid homologies of some vancomycin-resistant leuconostocs and description of Leuconostoc citreum sp. nov. and Leuconostoc pseudomesenteroides sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>279</fpage><lpage>283</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leuconostoc pseudomesenteroides</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leuconostoc pseudomesenteroides</i> (pseu.do.me.sen.ter.oi´des. Gr.adj. <i>pseudes</i>, false; Gr.n. <i>mesenterium</i>, the mesentery; Gr.n. <i>oides</i>, form, shape; M.L.adj. <i>pseudomesenteroides</i>, not the true <i>mesenteroides</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spherical or lenticular cells (ca. 0.5 to 0.7 by 0.7 to 1.2 μm) that occur usually in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Most strains are nonpigmented.</s><s>Grows at 10 and 37°C.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, D-fructose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, ribose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from L-arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, galactose, pgentiobiose, lactose, sucrose, and D-turanose.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from amygdalin, arbutin, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, and mannitol (after 7 days).</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, sorbitol, D-tagatose, L-xylose, or xylitol.</s><s>Arginine dehydrolase, urease, L-isoleucine arylamidase, and L-proline arylamidase negative.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 38.1 to 40.8 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from dairy sources, food, and clinical sources.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 768.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from L-arabinose, cellobiose, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, galactose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, and lactose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arbutin, mannitol (after 7 days), salicin, or starch.</s></p></content></protolog>