<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6858_nm.1284" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1284" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1284" rank="species">Rhizobium galegae</organism><reference id="rid.6858"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lindström</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium galegae, a new species of legume root nodule bacteria.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>367</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-365</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium galegae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium galegae</i> (ga.le'gae. M.L. fem. gen. n. <i>galegae</i>, of Galega)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods which are motile by means of one or two polar or subpolar flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>In nitrogen-fixing nodules the cells are elongated bacteroids, and some are branched (6, 9a).</s><s>Colonies on Vincent yeast-mannitol agar (14) are more than 1.0 mm in diameter after 7 days at 28°C.</s><s>The maximum growth temperature is 33 to 37°C.</s><s>The cells grow in the presence of 0.5% NaCl but not in the presence of 2.0% NaCl.</s><s>A majority of the strains studied form a serum zone and give an alkaline reaction in litmus milk.</s><s>They hydrolyze urea but do not precipitate calcium glycerophosphate, nor do they reduce nitrate.</s><s>They require calcium panthotenate but not thiamine for growth.</s><s>The following carbon sources are readily utilized in defined medium (def 9 medium [7]), with the formation of acidic end products: D-galactose, lactose, L-arabinose, dulcitol, raffinose, D-xylose, trehalose, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, maltose, D-glucose, D-fructose, and mannitol.</s><s>The response to sucrose and citrate is weaker.</s><s>The intrinsic antibiotic resistance patterns of <i>R. galegae</i> strains show fairly high resistance to trimethoprim and bacitracin and low resistance to neomycin and chloramphenicol (7).</s><s>Numerical taxonomy separates the <i>R. galegae</i> strains from the previously described rhizobial species (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of <i>R. galegae</i> is 63 mol% (7).</s><s>Data from DNA hybridizations in which DNAs from strains HAMBI 540<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain), HAMBI 1141, and galNW3 are used show that the <i>R. galegae</i> strains form a uniform DNA homology group, which is not closely related to other <i>Rhizobium</i> or <i>Bradyrhizobium</i> species (Table 1) (6, 15).</s><s>Thus, DNA homology can be used to distinguish <i>R. galegae</i> strains from other rhizobial species.</s><s>Ribosomal ribonucleic acid-DNA hybridization data place <i>R. galegae</i> in a separate group (group III) within the genus Rhizobium (3); <i>R. meliloti</i>, <i>R. fredii</i>, and <i>R. leguminosarum</i> form group I, and <i>R. loti</i> forms group II.</s><s>All of the <i>R. galegae</i> strains tested contain at least one very large plasmid, and some strains also contain additional smaller plasmids (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce extracellular polysaccharide (unpublished data).</s><s>The soluble protein and lipopolysaccharide patterns of <i>R. galegae</i> strains differ from those of other rhizobia.</s><s>Antiserum raised against strain HAMBI 540<sup>T</sup> (isolated from <i>G. orientalis</i>) reacts with lipopolysaccharides from all of the <i>R. galegae</i> strains tested.</s><s>Immunoblotting of whole-cell soluble proteins reveals two protein bands which are unique to <i>R. galegae</i> strains (9b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells can be infected by bacteriophages which are host range specific.</s><s>Susceptibility to phage gal 1/R can be used to distinguish <i>R. galegae</i> strains from other fast- and slow-growing root nodule bacteria (6, 7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen-fixing (effective) nodules are formed by strains isolated from <i>G. orientalis</i> on that plant and by strains isolated from <i>G. officinalis</i> on their original host.</s><s>Strains isolated from <i>G. orientalis</i> form ineffective nodules on <i>G. officinalis</i> and vice versa. <i>R. galegae</i> strains do not infect the other leguminous plants tested.</s><s>Plants of <i>Galega</i> spp. are only occasionally infected by other rhizobia, but when infection does take place, no nitrogen fixation occurs (6, 9, 9a).</s><s>Thus, in addition to typing with phage gal 1/R, effective nodulation of <i>G. orientalis</i> or <i>G. officinalis</i> phenotypically distinguishes <i>R. galegae</i> from other Rhizobium species.</s><s>The strains which presently can be included in the species <i>R. galegae</i> are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>R. galegae</i> is strain HAMBI 540 (isolated from <i>G. orientalis</i>), a culture of which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 43677.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above for the species with respect to morphology, physiology, guanine-plus-cytosine content, DNA and ribosomal ribonucleic acid homology, serology, and cross-nodulation.</s><s>It is a Finnish field isolate derived from strain HAMBI 1155 (=galE), which was originally isolated by Debora Gurfel in Estonia.</s><s>It is used as an inoculant in field experiments with goat's rue (5).</s><s>It is lysed by phages gal 1/R, gal 1/OW, gal 3/R, and gal 3/OW (6) and is the isolation host of phages gal 1261/M and gal 12611V (7; J.</s><s>J.</s><s>Patel and K.</s><s>Lindstrom, Abstr.</s><s>Global Impacts Appl.</s><s>Microbiol.</s><s>VII, abstr. no. B16, p. 86, 1985).</s><s>It is not lysed by bacteriophages which lyse <i>R. leguminosarum</i>, <i>R. meliloti</i>, and <i>R. loti</i> (6, 7)</s></p></content></protolog>