<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.250_nm.5710" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5710" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5710" rank="species">Syntrophococcus sucromutans</organism><reference id="rid.250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophococcus sucromutans gen. nov., sp. nov. uses carbohydrates as electron donors and formate, methoxymonobenzenoids or Methanobrevibacter as electron acceptor systems</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>143</volume><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00412795</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophococcus sucromutans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophococcus sucromutans</i> (su.cro.mu'tans. <i>sucro</i> modern chemical combined form referring to all sugars; part. adj. <i>mutans</i> changing or converting; M. L. adj. <i>sucromutans</i> converting sugar)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccus-shaped cells. 1.0 to 1.3 μm in diameter, with rounded to flattened plane of division, in short chains.</s><s>Non motile.</s><s>Non-sporing.</s><s>Gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Electron donor and acceptor are required for energy and growth.</s><s>Donors include pyruvate, glucose, fructose, galactose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, arabinose, maltose, ribose, xylose, salicin, and esculin.</s><s>The major organic product of these carbohydrates is acetate.</s><s>Compounds not used as electron donors include hydrocaffeate, gallate, protocatechuate, citrate, mannitol, fumarate, succinate, malate, aspartate, glutamate, glycine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valine, serine, isoleucine; butyrate, pectin and starch.</s><s>Electron acceptors with the major organic products in parentheses are as follows: formate (acetate), caffeate (hydrocaffeate), ferulate (caffeate, hydrocaffeate, acetate) syringate and 3,4,5-trimethoxybenzoate (gallate and acetate), vanillin (protocatechuic aldehyde, protocatechuate and acetate) and vanillate (protocatechuate and acetate).</s><s>The following compounds were not used as electron acceptors or as single energy sources: methanol, formaldehyde, CO, ethanol, fumarate, malate, crotonate, lactate, aspartate, glutamate, glycine, valine, serine, isoleucine, 1-methoxybenzene, 4-methoxybenzoate, cinnamate, 4-hydroxycinnamate, 4:1 H<sub>2</sub>:CO<sub>2</sub>; and 4:1 H<sub>2</sub>:CO<sub>2</sub> plus fumarate, crotonate or caffeate.</s><s>Growth occurs with an electron donor such as fructose when an H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>-using methanogen is the electron acceptor system.</s></p><p class="description"><s>ood growth occurs in an anaerobic medium containing 4:1 N<sub>2</sub>:CO<sub>2</sub> gas phase, minerals, 40-raM NaHCO<sub>3</sub>, 2-mM cysteine, 6-mM sodium formate, 6-mM fructose or xylose, 0.5% Casitone and 30% (v/v) rumen fluid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 6.0-7.6, optimum at 6.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range: 30.5-44.0°C optimum at 35-42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 52% G+C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: A numerous microbe catabolizing ferulate and syringate in the rumen of hay-fed cattle.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: S195, (=DSM 3224), DSM Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>