<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2490_nm.9732" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9732" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9732" rank="species">Thalassobius mediterraneus</organism><reference id="rid.2490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassobius mediterraneus gen. nov., sp. nov., and reclassification of Ruegeria gelatinovorans as Thalassobius gelatinovorus comb. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2371</fpage><lpage>2376</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63842-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280499</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassobius mediterraneus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassobius mediterraneus</em> (me.di.ter.ra′ne.us. L. masc. adj. <em>mediterraneus</em> pertaining to the Mediterranean Sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are usually 0·5–0·8 μm wide by 0·5–2 μm long.</s><s>Unable to reduce nitrate to nitrite or gas.</s><s>Requires at least 1·4 % (w/v) marine salts and tolerates up to 8 % (w/v) salts but fails to grow at 9 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive growth from 13 to 37 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>No hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, lecithin, alginate or agar.</s><s>It does not grow on Tween 80.</s><s>Tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulfate, indole production from tryptophan and sulfite oxidation are negative.</s><s>Enzyme activity in API ZYM is positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Provided that the medium is supplemented with 0·01 % yeast extract (an indication that undetermined growth factors are required), strain XSM19<sup>T</sup> utilizes the following compounds as carbon and energy sources after 7 days incubation: d-ribose, d-glucose, salicin, glycerol, propionate, pyruvate, citrate, succinate, fumarate, malate, acetate, lactate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-glutamate, l-alanine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and l-ornithine.</s><s>Slight growth is detected after 14 days incubation on d-fructose, maltose, d-sucrose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerate, 2-oxoglutarate, l-leucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-arginine, l-aspartate and putrescine.</s><s>Growth is negative on d-arabinose, d-xylose, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, glycine, l-tyrosine and l-histidine.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are, in order of abundance, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 12 : 1 3-OH, ECL 11·798, 16 : 0, 10 : 0 3-OH and 18 : 0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XSM19<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5383<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108400<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49438<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from water from the Mediterranean Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>