<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6287_nm.9956" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9956" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9956" rank="species">Prevotella bergensis</organism><reference id="rid.6287"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutcliffe</surname><given-names>I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hofstad</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella bergensis sp. nov., isolated from human infections.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>609</fpage><lpage>612</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63888-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514036</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella bergensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella bergensis</em> (berg.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bergensis</em> referring to Bergen, the Norwegian city where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on eight strains isolated from human skin and soft-tissue abscesses.</s><s>Biochemical results were identical for all strains studied.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, Gram-negative bacilli (0·7–0·8 μm×0·8–6 μm).</s><s>After 4 days incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 0·6–0·8 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, opaque and grey to off-white in colour.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces a moderate turbidity which is enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are saccharolytic and ferment arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, salicin and xylose; mannitol and trehalose are fermented variably; melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol and sucrose are not fermented.</s><s>Major amounts of acetic and succinic acids and a trace of isovaleric acid are produced as end products of metabolism in PYG broth.</s><s>The non-hydroxylated fatty acid profile is predominately iso-C14 : 0, iso-C15 : 0 and anteiso-C15 : 0.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed; arginine, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 48 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 94067913<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17361<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 51224<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type and other strains reported here were isolated from infections of the skin and soft-tissue abscesses.</s></p></content></protolog>