<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2680_nm.8882" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8882" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8882" rank="species">Thalassobacter stenotrophicus</organism><reference id="rid.2680"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassobacter stenotrophicus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel marine alpha-proteobacterium isolated from Mediterranean sea water.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63275-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653862</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassobacter stenotrophicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassobacter stenotrophicus</em> (ste.no.tro′phi.cus. Gr. adj. <em>stenos</em> narrow; Gr. adj. <em>trophikos</em> nursing, tending or feeding; N.L. masc. adj. <em>stenotrophicus</em> feeding on a narrow range of compounds).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, the type species has the following characteristics.</s><s>Growth on MA leads to regular, salmon-pink colonies that do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Pigment formation starts at the edges of the colonies or agar growing masses.</s><s>Does not swarm or luminesce.</s><s>Requires at least 0·85 % (w/v) marine salts and tolerates up to 7 % (w/v) salts, failing to grow at 8 %.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 13–37 °C and is optimum at 22–26 °C.</s><s>No growth is detected at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59·1 mol%.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Also negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulfate, indole production from tryptophan and sulfite oxidation (González <em>et al.</em>, 1999).</s><s>No growth is observed on TCBS agar.</s><s>Utilizes the following compounds as carbon and energy source: pyruvate, acetate, 2-ketoglutarate, succinate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-glutamate, l-ornithine, citrulline, sarcosine and putrescine, provided that the medium is supplemented with a small amount of yeast extract (an indication that undetermined growth factors are required).</s><s>Under the same conditions, the following substrates are not utilized: d-ribose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-trehalose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, salicin, amygdalin, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glucosamine, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, glycerate, fumarate, propionate, citrate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, malate, lactate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, d-saccharic acid, glycine, l-leucine, l-serine, l-arginine, l-alanine, l-threonine, l-aspartate, l-lysine, l-tyrosine and l-histidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5SM22<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5294<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16310<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Mediterranean sea water.</s></p></content></protolog>