<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1839_nm.8575" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8575" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8575" rank="species">Enterococcus hermanniensis</organism><reference id="rid.1839"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Koort</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sukura</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Björkroth</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus hermanniensis sp. nov., from modified-atmosphere-packaged broiler meat and canine tonsils</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1823</fpage><lpage>1827</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63112-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388750</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus hermanniensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus hermanniensis</em> (her.man.ni.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>hermanniensis</em> pertaining to Hermanni, a locality in Helsinki, Finland).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are Gram-positive, catalase-negative, spherical to semispherical cocci growing in pairs (Supplementary Fig. C).</s><s>Cells vary between 0·62 and 0·78 μm in width and 0·91 and 1·0 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies on blood or MRS agar are 1–2 mm in diameter after 5 days of incubation, white to light grey and translucent.</s><s>On bovine blood agar there is <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Strains grow slowly on azide-containing enterococcal selective media as typical, maroon colonies and cause blackening of bile-aesculin agar.</s><s>Strains grow well at 10 and 37 °C but no growth is observed at 45 °C.</s><s>All strains grow well in the presence of 2 or 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Some strains (not strains 302, 377 and 379) grow in the presence of 6·5 % NaCl but none of the strains grows in the presence of 10 % NaCl.</s><s>All strains react positively in Voges–Proskauer, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and leucine arylamidase tests.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis may be weak or delayed.</s><s>Strains are negative in tests for Lancefield D antigen, hippurate hydrolysis and <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>As is typical for enterococci, acid is produced from arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, ribose and salicin but not from erythritol, l-xylose, glycogen or fucose.</s><s>Unlike most of the other enterococci, no acid is produced from lactose, galactose and amygdalin, although there may sometimes be a weak positive reaction with the latter two.</s><s>All strains produce acid from mannitol.</s><s>Acid production from d-arabitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose and trehalose may be weak or delayed.</s><s>No acid production from adonitol, starch, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, dulcitol, ketogluconate, gluconate, glycerol, inositol, inulin, lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, d-raffinose, sucrose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol or d-xylose is detected.</s><s>Acid production from rhamnose and d-arabinose is weak or absent.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 36·6–37·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 12317<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 48100<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from dog tonsils.</s><s>Strains LMG 13617 and 334 (=LMG 21990) have also been deposited in the Belgian Co-ordinated Collections of Microorganisms (BCCM<sup>TM</sup>/LMG).</s></p></content></protolog>