<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7193_nm.6451" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6451" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6451" rank="species">Nocardia paucivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7193"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brzezinka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mauch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia paucivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>803</fpage><lpage>809</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758891</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia paucivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia paucivorans</i> (pau.ci.vo'rans. L. adj. <i>paucus</i> little; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to eat, to devour; L. pres. part. <i>vorans</i> eating; M.L. adj. <i>paucivorans</i> eating little, referring to the few compounds that are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The hyphae are Gram-positive and slightly acid-and alcohol-fast.</s><s>The vegetative hyphae are well developed with irregular branches penetrating the agar and bear white aerial hyphae.</s><s>At a late stage of growth the hyphae fragment into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>The organism contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e. the cell wall chemotype is chemotype IV).</s><s>It has mycolic acids with 48±54 carbon atoms and 2±4 double bonds (C<sub>48:3</sub>, C<sub>50:4</sub>, C<sub>52:2</sub>, C<sub>52:4</sub>, C<sub>54:2</sub> and C<sub>54:3</sub>) that are cleaved upon pyrolysis to release fatty acids with C<sub>14:0</sub> and C<sub>16:0</sub> carbon atoms, with C<sub>16:0</sub> as the major cleavage product; this <i>N. paucivorans</i> has a cellular fatty acid profile that comprises saturated, unsaturated and 10-methylbranched fatty acids.</s><s>It possesses type PII phospholipids with significant amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The menaquinone system consists of partially saturated menaquinones with eight isoprene units in which the two terminal isoprene moieties are cyclized; MK-8(H<sub>6</sub>) is the major menaquinone and minor amounts of 2,3-epoxy-MK-8(H<sub>8</sub>) are also present.</s><s>It hydrolyses urea but not adenine, aesculin, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, keratin, testosterone, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>It assimilates acetate, trehalose and paraffin as carbon sources but does not assimilate adipate, benzoate, citrate, gluconate, lactate, arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, myoinositol, mannitol, sorbitol, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butanediol, 1,2-propanediol, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate or <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>It does not utilize acetamide, alanine, gelatin, proline or serine as simultaneous carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 65.9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardia paucivorans</i> is strain IMMIB D-1632<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44386<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>