<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.181_nm.6777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6777" rank="subspecies">Actinosynnema pretiosum pretiosum</organism><reference id="rid.181"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanida</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatsano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higashide</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoneda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Motile actinomycetes: Actinosynnema pretiosum subsp. pretiosum sp. nov., subsp. nov. and Actinosynnema pretiosum subsp. auranticum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>314</fpage><lpage>320</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-314</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinosynnema pretiosum</i> subsp. <i>pretiosum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinosynnema pretiosum</i> subsp. <i>pretiosum</i> (pre. ti. o śum, L. adj. <i>pretiosum</i> precious)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology.</s><s>Branched vegetative hyphae are formed on various agar media.</s><s>Some of the branched mycelia that are formed at a later stage of growth in liquid culture break up into motile elements with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Long, straight, helical, or, rarely, branching hyphae are white to pale yellow and about 0.5 to 1.2 μm in diameter.</s><s>Hyphae are formed with tufts at the tips of the coremia on the surfaces of domelike or other extremely variable bodies.</s><s>Aerial mycelia have a bamboo-like appearance, and septa are set down along these hyphae and give rise to chains of spores that are capable of moving with peritrichous flagella in an aqueous environment.</s><s>The spore surface is smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony morphology.</s><s>Colonies on synthetic media are pale yellow to pale orange, convex, thin, slightly wrinkled, and spreading with a translucent edge; on organic media colonies are pale yellow to pale orange and wrinkled or leathery.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth conditions.</s><s>No growth takes place under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth occurs between 12 and 38°C and between pH 6 and pH 8.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell composition.</s><s><i>meso</i>-Diaminopimelic acid, glutamic acid, alanine, lysine, glycine, and galactose are present, but arabinose is not.</s><s>The cell walls are type III cell walls.</s><s>The major fatty acid component is a C<sub>17</sub> acid (margaric acid).</s><s>Mycolic acids have not been detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>Casein, tyrosine, starch, and esculin are hydrolyzed, but urea, xanthine, and hypoxanthine are not.</s><s>Milk is peptonized.</s><s>Nitrate reductase, alkaline phosphatase, and catalase are produced, but H<sub>2</sub>S is not.</s><s>Xylose, arabinose, glucose, galactose, mannose, sucrose, rhamnose, melibiose, trehalose, mannitol, and soluble starch are utilized as carbon sources for growth, but little or no growth is obtained with lactose, maltose, raffinose, sorbitol, inositol, and glycerol.</s><s>Growth occurs on 2% NaCl or in lysozyme broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptibilities.</s><s>This organism grows in the presence of 100 μg of amphotericin B per ml and 100 μg of sulbenicillin per ml.</s><s>Streptomycin, tetracycline and chloramphenicol at concentrations of 20 μg/ml completely inhibit growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from a blade of Carex species in Shiga Prefecture, Japan, in September 1975.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antagonistic products.</s><s>Produces ansamitocins (7, 24) and tomaymycin (23).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acids.</s><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid contains 71 ± 1 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain C-15003(N-1) (=IFO 13726 = FERM-P 3992 = ATCC 31281).</s><s>Another strain, strain C-l4919(N-2001) (=IFO 13723 = FERM-P 3991 = ATCC 31280), also has been deposited in culture collections.</s></p></content></protolog>