<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9699_nm.14845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14845" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14845" rank="species">Paracoccus chinensis</organism><reference id="rid.9699"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>H.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus chinensis sp. nov., isolated from sediment of a reservoir</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2670</fpage><lpage>2674</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004705-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625438</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus chinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus chinensis</em> (chi.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>chinensis</em> pertaining to China, where the type strain was isolated and studied).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile, ovoid- to coccus-shaped, 1.0×1.3–1.5–2.0 μm in size, and occur singly, in pairs, small clusters or short chains on R2A agar incubated for 3 days.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, smooth, moist, non-glossy, low-convex and colourless to orange.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–40 °C (optimum, 28–37 °C), pH 6.0–9.5 (optimum, pH 7.5–9.0) and with less than 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically using nitrate as electron acceptor.</s><s>A water-insoluble yellow pigment is produced on R2A agar, with a major absorbance peak at 470 nm.</s><s>A fluorescent pigment is also produced at a low rate on King's B medium.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, urease, lecithinase and hydrolysis of casein.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lipase activity (Tween 80), production of indole and hydrogen sulfide, and hydrolysis of starch, gelatin and carboxymethylcellulose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced but not nitrite.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-galactose, d-xylose, melibiose, melezitose, lactose, soluble starch, maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, l-fucose, d-glucose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, inositol, salicin, inulin, gluconate, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-proline, l-tyrosine, l-asparagine, pyruvate, citrate and acetate, but not raffinose, d-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbose, l-arabinose, malonate, mannitol, succinic acid, glycerol, lactate, succinate, l-glycine, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, methanol, ethanol or acetone.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/<em>ω</em>9<em>t</em>/<em>ω</em>12<em>t</em> (summed feature 7) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 69.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KS-11<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7655<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104937<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of the Guanting reservoir in China.</s></p></content></protolog>