<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4422_nm.4518" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4518" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4518" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacterium zeae</organism><reference id="rid.4422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cann</surname><given-names>I.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stroot</surname><given-names>P.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mackie</surname><given-names>K.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>White</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mackie</surname><given-names>R.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of two novel saccharolytic, anaerobic thermophiles, Thermoanaerobacterium polysaccharolyticum sp. nov. and Thermoanaerobacterium zeae sp. nov., and emendation of the genus Thermoanaerobacterium.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>293</fpage><lpage>302</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321073</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium zeae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacterium zeae</i> (ze.ae. Gr. n. <i>zeae</i> of corn, describing the use of corn as a substrate for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods and occur singly or sometimes in pairs.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Formation of spores has not been observed.</s><s>Peritrichous flagella are present.</s><s>Grows on solid media.</s><s>Anaerobic cultures are catalase-negative and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Thiosulfate, sulfate and sulfur are not reduced.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 65.70 °C.</s><s>The maximum temperature at which growth occurs is 72 °C and growth does not occur at 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range is 3.9-7.9.</s><s>The fastest doubling time observed for <i>Thermoanaerobacterium zeae</i> grown on glucose in a minimal media is 1.8 h for the optimum temperature range.</s><s>Growth is completely inhibited by tetracycline (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), rifampicin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), kanamycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and erythromycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of concentrations of 300 mM NaCl, 450 mM KCl and 150 mM NH%Cl.</s><s>The end products of fermentation on a minimal medium with 0.5% (w/v) glucose as the carbon source are ethanol (33 mM), formate (21 mM), acetate (14 mM) and lactate (7 mM).</s><s>Utilizes cracked corn, starch, xylan, glucose, arabinose, galactose, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, cellobiose, raffinose, melibiose, melizitose and pyruvate.</s><s>Cellulose, pectin, sorbose, mannitol, malate, fumarate, citrate, glycerol andH<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> are not utilized.</s><s>The G­C content is 42 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium zeae</i> is strain mel2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-16<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13642<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>