<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3739_nm.9522" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9522" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9522" rank="species">Aquimonas voraii</organism><reference id="rid.3739"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prasad</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bora</surname><given-names>T.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquimonas voraii gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel gammaproteobacterium isolated from a warm spring of Assam, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1491</fpage><lpage>1495</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63552-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014470</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquimonas voraii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquimonas voraii</em> (vo′ra.i.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>voraii</em> named after V. C. Vora, a distinguished biotechnologist and founder director of the Institute of Microbial Technology, Chandigarh, India).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the description of the genus, the species has the following characteristics.</s><s>Colonies on TSBA after 3 days of incubation at 30 °C appear circular, yellowish-brown, glistening and convex, with undulated margins.</s><s>Cells are 1·5–4·5 μm long and 0·3–0·4 μm wide.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–42 °C and pH 6·0–11·0, and NaCl concentrations of up to 2 % can be tolerated.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, starch, gelatin and Tweens 20, 40 and 80, but not urea, aesculin or <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl galactoside.</s><s>Cannot ferment lactose and cannot utilize l-arabinose, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-amygdalin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-xylose, acetate, citrate, fumerate, glutarate, malate, propionate or succinate as sole carbon sources, but weakly utilizes dulcitol, adonitol and d-arabinose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from any of the carbohydrates mentioned above, and also from inulin, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>Negative for indole formation, oxidation–fermentation reaction, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, nitrate reduction and utilization of xylan, cellulose and dextrin.</s><s>Negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, DNase and phenylalanine deaminase activities.</s><s>Grows on nutritionally poor medium such as TSBA100 (TSB, 100-fold diluted and solidified with agarose) and, therefore, may be considered as a facultative oligophile.</s><s>The genomic G+C content is 75 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GPTSA 20<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 6713<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12896<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a warm spring water sample collected from Assam, India.</s></p></content></protolog>