<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7158_nm.1204" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1204" rank="genus">Blastomonas</organism><reference id="rid.7158"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cahill</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Blastobacter natatorius (Sly 1985) to the genus Blastomonas gen. nov. as Blastomonas natatoria comb. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>566</fpage><lpage>568</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-566</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103650</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Blastomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Blastomonas</i> (Blas. to. mo'nas. Gr. n. <i>blastos</i>, bud shoot; Gr. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; M.L. fem. n. <i>Blastomonas</i>, a budding monad)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative and rod shaped or wedge shaped with a straight or slightly curved axis.</s><s>Cells are usually 0.5 to 0.8 by 1 to 3 μm.</s><s>Older cells may become elongated and reach lengths of 10 μm or more.</s><s>Some cells may have a swollen or bloated appearance.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and may form rosettes.</s><s>Each rosette-forming cell has a simple mucilaginous holdfast at its nonreproductive pole by which it attaches to other cells or to solid surfaces.</s><s>No stalks, prosthecae, or other holdfast structures are present.</s><s>Reproduction occurs by asymmetric division (budding) of the mother cell to produce a shorter daughter cell.</s><s>Buds may be spherical or ovoid and are usually 0.5 to 0.8 by 0.5 to 1 μm.</s><s>The free bud cells are motile with a single polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Good growth occurs on peptone-yeast extract agar or peptone-yeast extract-glucose agar.</s><s>Growth occurs on glucose-ammonium sulfate agar.</s><s>No vitamin requirement.</s><s>Colony pigmentation is yellow.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Contains ubiquinone Q10.</s><s>Contains 2-hydroxymyristic acid as a major component of the cellular fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of genomic DNA is 65 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Member of the alpha-4 group of the alpha subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in freshwater.</s><s>The type species is <i>Blastomonas natatoria</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>