<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.452_nm.2432" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2432" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2432" rank="species">Methylomonas pelagica</organism><reference id="rid.452"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sieburth</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>P.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eberhardt</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sieracki</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lidstrom</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laux</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The first methane-oxidizing bacterium from the upper mixing layer of the deep ocean.: Methylomonas pelagica sp. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>285</fpage><lpage>293</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01568138</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylomonas pelagica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylomonas pelagica</i> (<i>pelagica</i> the first isolations were obtained from pelagic (open ocean) seawater in the Sargasso Sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ultrastructure, metabolism, and DNA base composition of this species agree with the description of the genus <i>Methylomonas</i> as presently consituted [37].</s><s>Although the practice has been to avoid new species descriptions until a better characterization of extant isolates has been made, the distinctive properties and serology of this species do permit it to be described at this time.</s><s>Short rods, 0.5 μm in width by 0.8-1.2 μm in length.</s><s>Motile by a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>On purified agarose-seawater gels with appropriate nutrients and an atmosphere containing methane, small white, uniform, regular convex, soft colonies form which achieve a diameter of 1-2 mm.</s><s>Cytomembranes occur as stacked lamellae with fiat plates.</s><s>Utilizes only methane and methanol for growth, with formaldehyde being copiously leaked to the medium on the latter substrate.</s><s>These one-carbon units are assimilated via the ribulose monophosphate pathway for formaldehyde fixation.</s><s>Unable to grow on other C<sub>1</sub> compounds or on C-C bonded organic matter.</s><s>Ammonia and nitrate, but not dinitrogen, serve as sources of nitrogen.</s><s>Requires NaCI for growth.</s><s>Able to grow at 20°C and 30°C but not at 10°C The mol % G+C content in the DNA is 49.</s><s>Habitat is uncertain.</s><s>Possibly associated with particles of algal debris, produced by grazing and senescence in the upper ocean, that become anoxic and ferment to produce methanol and methane in an otherwise oxygen-saturated water column.</s><s>Type strain AA-23 (NCMB 2265) has been deposited in the National Collections of Industrial and Marine Bacteria Ltd. (Torrey Research Station, PO Box 31, Aberdeen, Scotland, UK AB9 8OG).</s></p></content></protolog>