<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7505_nm.8353" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8353" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8353" rank="species">Fusobacterium alocis</organism><reference id="rid.7505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium alocis sp. nov. and Fusobacterium sulci sp. nov. from the human gingival sulcus.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>475</fpage><lpage>477</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium alocis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium alocis</i> (a'lo.kis. Gr. n. <i>alox</i> a furrow; N.L. gen. n. <i>alocis</i> of a furrow, referring to its isolation from a crevice of the gums)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gramnegative, nonsporeforming, obligately anaerobic rods, 0.4 to 0.7 by 1.5 to 7.0 μm, with rounded to tapered ends.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, or occasionally in short chains.</s><s>Of 117 strains, 6 have slow twitching or end-over-end type of motility, but flagella are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates are pinpoint to 1.0 mm, circular, entire, flat to low convex, translucent to transparent, shiny, smooth, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>No internal colony structure is visible.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C, at which growth is only moderate at best.</s><s>Slight growth occurs at 30 and 45°C; there is little or no growth at 25°C.</s><s>Growth can be stimulated by the addition of rabbit serum (Anal concentration, 10 to 15% [vol/vol]) and cocarboxylase (final concentration, 5 μg/ml).</s><s>Most strains grow better in an atmosphere of 10% CO<sub>2</sub>-90% N<sub>2</sub> than of 100% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in peptone-yeast extract-glucose (PYG) bruth have a fine granular sediment and no turbidity after incdbation for 5 to 7 days.</s><s>The final pH of cultures in PYG broth and in basal medium incubated in a CO<sub>2</sub>-N<sub>2</sub> atmosphere is 6.8 to 7.1; under 100% CO<sub>2</sub>, the final pH of each is 5.9 to 6.1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although little or no gas is formed in PYG deep agar cultures, abundant H<sub>2</sub> is detected in the headspaces of broth cultures when there is sufficient growth.</s><s>No H<sub>2</sub>S is detected in sulfide-indole-motility medium (BBL Microbiology Systems).</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, esculin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, indlin, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, D-(-)ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, catalase, lecithinase, lipase, urease, oxidase, and deoxyribonuclease are not produced.</s><s>Esculin, starch, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced; neither resazurin nor neutral red is reduced.</s><s>There is no reaction in milk and no digestion of gelatin or chopped meat.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products of fermentation in PYG broth are small to moderate amounts of butyrate and acetate.</s><s>Pyruvate, DL-lactate, D-gluconate, and DL-threonine are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All tested strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml); 1 of 20 strains tested is resistant to penicillin (2 U/ml).</s><s>The principal habitat of <i>F. alocis</i> is the human gingival sulcus.</s><s>It has been isolated from a submandibular abscess and from a mouth ulcer.</s><s>The type strain of <i>F. alocis</i> is VPI D40B-5 (=ATCC 35896).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of this strain is 34 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>