<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3149_nm.11838" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11838" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4261" rank="species">Eubacterium oxidoreducans</organism><reference id="rid.3149"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium oxidoreducens sp. nov. requiring H2 or formate to degrade gallate, pyrogallol, phloroglucinol and quercetin.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>144</volume><fpage>8</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00454948</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium oxidoreducens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium oxidoreducens</i> (ox.i.do.re.du' cens. <i>oxido</i> combining form of modern chemical term, oxide, L. part. adj. <i>reducens</i> reducing; N. L. adj. <i>oxidoreducens</i> reducing compounds (containing) oxygen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped curved cells, 0.45 by 1.5-2.2 μm in size, with rounded ends, singles, or in pairs or in small clumps.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>No spore formation (pasteurized cultures are not viable).</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Requires formate or hydrogen as electron donor to catabolize approximately equimotar gallate, pyrogallol, phloroglucinol, or quercetin to acetate, butyrate, and sometimes CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No exogenous electron donor is required for catabolism (fermentation) of crotonate (growth rate much faster with 60 mM than with 30 mM or less) to acetate and butyrate.</s><s>No other compounds are used as energy sources with or without formate present.</s><s>These include rutin, hesperidin, monobenzenoids with or without methoxyl groups, fatty acids, citrate, acrylate, lactate, pyruvate, dicarboxylic acids, alcohols, sugars, amino acids and peptides.</s><s>It also does not grow in co-culture with <i>Desulfovibrio</i> sp. (with sulfate and with or without formate) with butyrate, protocatechuate, 3,5-dihydroxybenzoate, benzoate, phenol, 4-hydroxybenzoate, hydroquinone or caffeate as substrate.</s><s>Sulfate does not serve as a dissimilatory electron acceptor with formate in the medium.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>It grows well in defined medium containing utilizable energy sources, minerals, including NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, CO<sub>2</sub>-bicarbonate (required), B-vitamins, sulfide and cysteine.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolyzed, ammonia is not produced from arginine or Casitone, but ammonia is essential as the main nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 6.9 to 7.8, optimum at 7.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range: 30 to 43°C optimum 39 to 41°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 35.7% G + C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: Rumen of cattle.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: G41 (= DSM 3217).</s><s>DSM Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>