<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5671_nm.5536" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5536" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5536" rank="species">Enterococcus flavescens</organism><reference id="rid.5671"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pompei</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berlutti</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thaller</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ingianni</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cortis</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dainelli</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus flavescens sp. nov., a new species of enterococci of clinical origin.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>369</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-365</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503970</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus flavescens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus flavescens</i> (fla. ve' scens. L. adj. <i>flavescens</i>, showing a yellow color)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid and occur mostly in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood or nutrient agar are circular and smooth with entire edges.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Yellow pigmented.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Antigenic extracts of all strains react with group D antiserum.</s><s>All strains hydrolize esculin, are Voges-Proskauer, arginine dehydrolase, β-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, and pyrrolidonylarylamidase positive, and produce acid from L-arabinose, D-xylose, galactose, D-fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, D-raffinose, inulin, gluconate, rhamnose, and β-gentiobiose.</s><s>All strains are amylase, protease, pyruvate, β-glucuronidase, and alkaline phosphatase negative and fail to produce acid from glycerol, erythritol, ribose, L-xylose, adonitol, α-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-mannoside, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D- and L-fucose, D- and L-arabitol, and 2- and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Variable results are obtained for growth at 10°C (one strain is able to grow), growth at 45°C (one strain is not able to grow), and the litmus milk test.</s><s>With regard to bacteriolytic activity patterns, the CA-WE strains fall into lyogroup EIII, just as <i>E. casseliflavus</i> does (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid and monounsaturated octadecenoic acid (Δ11); no unsaturated hexadecanoic fatty acids are detected (Table 4).</s><s>A minor, but not significant, difference in fatty acid composition occurs in strain CA 8. <i>E. flavescens</i> is distinguished from <i>E. casseliflavus</i> by being unable to ferment ribose and by lacking hemolysis on sheep blood.</s><s>Other tests for separating <i>E. flavescens</i> from <i>E. faecium</i>, <i>E. mundtii</i>, and <i>E. sulfureus</i> are shown in Table 5.</s><s>The type strain is strain CA 2 (=CCM 439).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as the description of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>