<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9113_nm.14310" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14310" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14310" rank="species">Hymenobacter daecheongensis</organism><reference id="rid.9113"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>F.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hymenobacter daecheongensis sp. nov., isolated from stream sediment.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1183</fpage><lpage>1187</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002444-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406816</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hymenobacter daecheongensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hymenobacter daecheongensis</em> (dae.che.ong.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>daecheongensis</em> referring to the Daecheong Dam, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Obligately aerobic and chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Cells are 0.6–1.0 μm wide and 2.0–5.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells become larger, around 10 μm in length, after 7 days incubation.</s><s>Cells grow on R2A agar, but not on trypticase soy agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, entire, smooth and red–pink.</s><s>No flexirubin-type pigments are formed.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C and pH 5.0–10.0, but not at 37 °C.</s><s>The presence of more than 1 % NaCl inhibits growth on R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic and denitrifying conditions.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, summed feature 5 (iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Hydrolyses skim milk, but not xylan, starch, cellulose, chitin or olive oil.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of the following substrates: d-galactose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, formate, acetate, propionate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, caprate, maleic acid, phenylacetate, benzoic acid, 3-hydroxybenzoate, salicin, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinic acid, glutaric acid, tartaric acid, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalic acid, lactose, raffinose, d-adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, amygdalin, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, histidine, proline and tyrosine.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of the following substrates: d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, pyruvic acid, fumaric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoate, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, gluconate, dulcitol, inositol and dextran.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease and tryptophan deaminase activities and production of hydrogen sulfide, acetoin and indole.</s><s>Gelatinase activity is positive (API 20E).</s><s>API 20NE tests for nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, urease and aesculin hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4) and leucine arylamidase and negative for cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, valine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Dae14<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22258<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24498<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of a stream near Daecheong Dam, South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>