<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.267_nm.4321" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4321" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4321" rank="species">Desulfitobacterium hafniense</organism><reference id="rid.267"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Christiansen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ahring</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfitobacterium hafniense sp. nov., an anaerobic, reductively dechlorinating bacterium.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>442</fpage><lpage>448</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-442</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfitobacterium hafniense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfitobacterium hafniense</i> (haf. ni. en' se. M. L. n. <i>Hafnia</i>, Copenhagen; L. suff. <i>-ensis</i>, native of; M. L. adj. <i>hafniense</i>, native of Copenhagen, referring to the place of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped and gram negative and occur singly, in pairs, and in short chains; they are approximately 3.3 to 6 μm long and 0.6 to 0.7 μm wide and motile and have one or two terminal flagella.</s><s>Spores are formed, and the spores are terminal.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>At pH 7 the optimum growth temperature is near 37°C.</s><s>Only pyruvate and tryptophan support growth.</s><s>Acetate, CO<sub>2</sub>, 2,4-dichlorophenol, and 4-chlorophenol are formed during growth with pyruvate and 2,4,6-trichlorophenol.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, cellobiose, xylose, lactose, maltose, mannose, sucrose, raffinose, trehalose, D-mannitol, benzoate, lactate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, formate, fumarate, sorbitol, salicin, inulin, starch, glycerol, esculin, L-histidine, L-(+)-glutamhe, L-threonine, and L-phenylalanine do not support growth.</s><s>There is no sulfate reduction or growth in the presence of sulfate with the following carbon sources: formate, benzoate, lactate, glycerol, maltose, lactose, mannitol, acetate, glucose, propionate, butyrate, rhamnose, ribose, arabinose, galactose, mannose, and fucose.</s><s>There is no growth when thiosulfate is added as an electron acceptor with following carbon sources: L-arabinose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, fucose, mannose, raffinose, D-mannitol, lactate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, and formate.</s><s>There is no growth when 2,4,6-trichlorophenol is added as an electron acceptor with following carbon sources: L-arabinose, D-glucose, D-galactose, D-ribose, lactose, maltose, glycerol, benzoate, lactate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, and formate.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to ammonia and nitrite.</s><s>Thiosulfate, sulfite, and Fe(III) are also reduced in the presence of pyruvate.</s><s>Does not reduce Mn(IV) or sulfate in the presence of pyruvate.</s><s>Reductively dechlorinates pentachlorophenol, 2,4,5-trichlorophenol, 2,4,6-trichlorophenol, 2,4-dichlorophenol, 3,5-dichlorophenol, and 3-Cl-4OHPA.</s><s>Does not dechlorinate 3,4,5-trichlorophenol, 3,4-dichlorophenol, 2-chlorophenol, 3-chlorophenol, and 4-chlorophenol.</s><s>Conserves energy from reductive dechlorination of 3-Cl-4OHPA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Contains cytochrome <i>c</i> but no desulfoviridin.</s><s>Indole positive and catalase negative.</s><s>Does not liquify gelatin.</s><s>The cellular DNA G+C content is 47 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from municipal sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Desulfitobacterium hafniense</i> DCB-2<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH.</s></p></content></protolog>