<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.665_nm.8782" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8782" rank="species">Planococcus stackebrandtii</organism><reference id="rid.665"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prasad</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suresh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saini</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planococcus stackebrandtii sp. nov., isolated from a cold desert of the Himalayas, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63290-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653859</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Planococcus stackebrandtii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Planococcus stackebrandtii</em> (sta.cke.brand.ti′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>stackebrandtii</em> of Stackebrandt, to honour Erko Stackebrandt, a German microbiologist, for his valuable contributions to microbial taxonomy and molecular systematics).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile and coccoid, occurring in pairs and in groups.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are orange, opaque, smooth, convex, circular, entire and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–30 °C (optimum 25 °C) and at pH 5·6–11·0.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for citrate utilization, Tween 20 hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, ornithine decarboxylase and catalase, but negative for oxidase, casein hydrolysis, starch hydrolysis, urease production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reaction, hydrogen sulfide production, nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase and lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose medium.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, fructose, lactose, raffinose and sucrose, but not from glucose, arabinose, mannitol, xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, rhamnose or salicin.</s><s>As sole nitrogen source, it is negative for histidine, phenylalanine, valine, cysteine, hydroxy proline, arginine and serine.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains l-lysine; cell-wall sugars are d-glucose and d-ribose.</s><s>MK-7 and MK-8 are the major menaquinones.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 40 mol%.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, with minor amounts of C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>.</s><s>Phospholipid is of type II, which has the predominant polar lipids phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K22-03<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 6226<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16419<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12481<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil, 0·45 m below an ice glacier, at 4200 m elevation, Kibber village, Spiti valley, Himachal Pradesh, India.</s></p></content></protolog>