<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4384_nm.8143" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8143" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8143" rank="species">Cellulophaga algicola</organism><reference id="rid.4384"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Cellulophaga algicola sp. nov., isolated from the surfaces of Antarctic algae, and reclassification of Cytophaga uliginosa (ZoBell and Upham 1944) Reichenbach 1989 as Cellulophaga uliginosa comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1861</fpage><lpage>1868</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034497</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellulophaga algicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellulophaga algicola</i> (al.gi.co'la. M.L. n. <i>algae</i> algae; L. n. <i>incola</i> inhabitant, dweller; M.L. fem. n. <i>algicola</i> algae-dweller)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped with either rounded or tapered ends and with cells lengths and widths ranging from 1.5 to 4 and 0.4 to 0.5 μm, respectively.</s><s>Gliding motility present.</s><s>Colonies on marine 2216 agar have yellow-orange pigmentation and a compact centre, with a spreading edge possessing lighter pigmentation, are slimy in consistency and are slightly sunken into the agar.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not formed.</s><s>Agar around and beneath colonies is softened but not liquefied.</s><s>Strictly aerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Does not require elevated CO<sub>2</sub> levels for growth.</s><s>Strains grow between 0.5 and 10% NaCl, with best growth in the presence of about 2% NaCl.</s><s>Growth on nutrient agar is poor, while no growth occurs on R2A or Anacker-Ordal agar.</s><s>Grows between -2 and 28 °C, with most rapid growth at about 15-20 °C on agar media and at about 20-25 °C in liquid media.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is about 7±5.</s><s>Can hydrolyse agar, starch, CMC, casein, Tween 80, tributyrin and L-tyrosine but not urate, xanthine or dextran.</s><s>Forms a reddish-brown diffusible pigment when grown in the presence of 1% L-tyrosine.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, denitrification, H<sub>2</sub>S production and indole production are negative.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from D-galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, sucrose, cellobiose, lactose and mannitol.</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>G+­C content of the DNA ranges from 36 to 38 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>Isolated from the surfaces of algal species from the Antarctic marine coast and sea ice.</s><s>The type strain is IC166<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 630<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>