<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.370_nm.366" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.366" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.366" rank="species">Picrophilus oshimae</organism><reference id="rid.370"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleper</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pühler</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zillig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Picrophilus oshimae and Picrophilus torridus fam. nov., gen. nov., sp. nov., two species of hyperacidophilic, thermophilic, heterotrophic, aerobic archaea.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>814</fpage><lpage>816</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Picrophilus oshimae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Picrophilus oshimae</i> (o.shi'mae. M.L. gen. n. <i>oshimae</i>, of Oshima, referring to Japanese biochemist Tairo Oshima, who furnished invaluable help in organizing our collecting trip)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shape, size, and growth characteristics are as described above for the genus.</s><s>Large cavities, apparently not separated from the cytoplasm by a membrane, often are observed in sections.</s><s>The lattice constant of the S layer is 20 nm (6).</s><s>No pili or flagellae are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bis-phytanyl tetraetherlipids are dominated by a single phosphoglycolipid component (1).</s><s>The cytochromes resemble those of the genus <i>Thermoplasma</i> and are type b cytochromes.</s><s>The 16s rRNA sequence (accession number X84901) is 9.5% different from the sequence of <i>T. acidophilum</i> and about 3% different from the sequence of <i>P. torridus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36 mol%.</s><s>The EcoRI restriction pattern of the DNA is similar to, but characteristically different from, that of <i>P. torridus</i>.</s><s>Two different but partially homologous plasmids, one about 8.3 kbp long and the other about 8.8 kbp long, occur in some but not all strains.</s><s>One strain contains both plasmids.</s><s>The type strain is strain DSM 9789.</s></p></content></protolog>