<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4479_nm.8656" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8656" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8656" rank="species">Lactobacillus antri</organism><reference id="rid.4479"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roos</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engstrand</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jonsson</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus gastricus sp. nov., Lactobacillus antri sp. nov., Lactobacillus kalixensis sp. nov. and Lactobacillus ultunensis sp. nov., isolated from human stomach mucosa.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>82</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63083-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus antri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus antri</em> [an′tri. L. gen. n. <em>antri</em> of a cave (the antrum region of the stomach)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, catalase-negative rods, 1×1·2–2 μm in size and occurring as single cells or in pairs.</s><s>After anaerobic growth at 37 °C for 48 h, colonies on MRS agar are 2–3·5 mm in diameter; they are white, smooth and slightly convex.</s><s>Growth on MRS agar under aerobic conditions is very weak.</s><s>In MRS broth, growth occurs at 25 and 45 °C, but not 20 °C.</s><s>Both d- and l-lactate are produced.</s><s>Gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose (one of two strains), galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, mannitol (weak reaction), methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside (weak reaction), maltose, melibiose, sucrose, d-raffinose, d-turanose (weak reaction), d-arabitol and gluconate (weak reaction).</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed (weak reaction).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain Kx146A4<sup>T</sup> is 44·9 mol% and the peptidoglycan type is A4<em>α</em> l-lys–d-Asp.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence places the species in the <em>L. reuteri</em> subgroup of lactobacilli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Kx146A4<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22111<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16041<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 48456<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a biopsy of the healthy human gastric mucosa.</s></p></content></protolog>