<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12459_nm.21288" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21288" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21288" rank="species">Amycolatopsis thailandensis</organism><reference id="rid.12459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chomchoei</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pathom-aree</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanongnuch</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lumyong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis thailandensis sp. nov., a poly(L-lactic acid)-degrading actinomycete, isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>839</fpage><lpage>843</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023564-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis thailandensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis thailandensis</em> (thai.land.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>thailandensis</em> pertaining to Thailand, the source of the soil from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, non-motile and non-acid-fast actinomycete, which forms white colonies on ISP 2.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white to pale yellow with long fragmented strands of smooth-surfaced conidia.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is yellowish brown.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>On ISP 2, grows at pH 5.0–11.0 (optimum pH 6.0–10.0), at 10–37 °C (optimum 25–37 °C), but not at 45 °C, and with 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cell-wall hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-DAP, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylmethylethylethanolamine.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Arabinose, fructose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, raffinose and xylose are utilized as sole carbon sources, but not cellulose, rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and gelatin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, trehalose and d-xylose, but not from l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or l-sorbose.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, starch, l-tyrosine and urea are degraded, but not adenine.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, alkaline phosphatase, catalase, esterase, esterase lipase (C8), α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, urease and valine arylamidase, weakly positive for α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase and trypsin, but negative for α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and α-mannosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CMU-PLA07<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16380<sup>T</sup> = BCC 38279<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in northern Thailand and is able to degrade poly(l-lactic acid).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>