<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5241_nm.5284" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5284" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5284" rank="species">Gemella bergeri</organism><reference id="rid.5241"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjöden</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gemella bergeriae sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>1290</fpage><lpage>1293</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9574693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gemella bergeriae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gemella bergeriae</i> (ber.ger.iae L. n., named after Ulrich Berger in recognition of his contributions to the microbiology of gemellae)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci that occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>Cocci are sometimes elongated.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar plates after 48 h are small, circular, entire, low convex, translucent to opaque, and smooth.</s><s>Nonpigmented.</s><s>Some strains (three of six) are hemolytic on horse blood agar.</s><s>Growth does not occur in broth containing 6.5% NaCl, at 10 or 45°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Gas is not produced from Mann, Rogosa, or Sharpe broth.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid (weak reaction) from maltose and mannitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Using the API system, phosphoamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, and ester lipase C8 are detected; esterase C4 and phosphatase acid activity is detected in some strains.</s><s>Leucine aminopeptidase is positive, as is pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, by disk test methodology, but tests incorporated into dehydrated commercial identification systems (API) using these substrates give variable results.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacuronidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, lipase C14, β-mannosidase, trypsin, urease, and valine arylamidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Esculin, gelatin, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer and indole tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The G1C content of the DNA is 32.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Gemella bergeriae</i> is strain 617-93 (=CCUG 37817).</s><s>The type strain produces acid from mannitol and is pyroglutamic acid arylamidase negative.</s><s>Isolated from clinical specimens.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>