<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.105_nm.4751" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4751" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4751" rank="species">Ureaplasma gallorale</organism><reference id="rid.105"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Koshimizu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harasawa</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kotani</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ogata</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stephens</surname><given-names>E.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barile</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ureaplasma gallorale sp. nov. from the oropharynx of chickens.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>333</fpage><lpage>338</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-333</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ureaplasma gallorale</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ureaplasma gallorule</i> (gal. lo. ra'le. L. n. <i>gallus</i>, a barnyard fowl; <i>orale</i>, relating to the mouth; N. L. neut. adj. <i>galforale</i>, relating to mouth of barnyard fowl)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In this report we summarize the morphological, biological, biochemical, serological, and genomic properties of seven ureaplasma strains isolated from the oropharynx of chickens.</s><s>These strains showed no evidence of a cell wall by electron microscopy, were filterable through 450-nm filters, were resistant to solutions containing 1,000 U of penicillin per ml and 0.025% thallium acetate, and required cholesterol for growth.</s><s>They hydrolyzed urea but not arginine, did not ferment glucose, showed optimal growth at pH 6.0 to 7.0, and produced tiny typical colonies on agar medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth of strains D6-1<sup>T</sup> and T9-1 was determined by inoculating 10<sup>2</sup> to 10<sup>3</sup> CCU into broth media with the pH adjusted to values varying by 0.5 pH unit from pH 5.0 to 8.0.</s><s>Growth was observed within 1 day in broth media at pH 6.0 to 7.0.</s><s>No growth was observed in broth media at pH 5.0 or 8.0.</s><s>Colonies grown on agar medium had a fried egg appearance and measured about 15 to 60 μm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology and ultrastructure.</s><s>Smears prepared from sedimented broth cultures of strain D6-1<sup>T</sup> and stained with Gram stain showed gram-negative round or coccobacillary organisms.</s><s>Electron microscopic examination of thin sections of the cell pellets revealed pleomorphic organisms with a unit membrane and no evidence of a cell wall outside the membrane.</s><s>At higher magnifications, the membrane appeared to be a three-layer unit structure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reversion studies.</s><s>None of the avian strains showed reversion to the bacterial form when they were serially subcultured in antimicrobial agent-free broth and agar media.</s><s>Filtration studies.</s><s>Avian strains D6-I<sup>T</sup> and T9-1 passed through Millipore membrane filters with pore sizes of 450 nm or greater but failed to pass through filters with pore sizes of 200 nm or less.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>The growth responses of strain D6-1<sup>T</sup> to cholesterol and to various supplements added to the base medium are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Little growth was apparent in the serum-free base medium, in base medium containing supplements of albumin fraction and palmitic acid, or in base medium containing various levels of cholesterol only, but marginal growth occurred when both cholesterol and the other supplements were incorporated into the base medium.</s><s>However, significantly increased multiplication was observed when 1% PPLO serum fraction or 15% horse serum was added to the base medium, thus confirming the requirement for serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on agar medium of all seven avian ureaplasma strains used was inhibited by 1.5% digitonin when the disk test procedure was used (18).</s><s>The inhibition zones around the disks with digitonin ranged from 5 to 10 mm.</s><s>No inhibition of growth was seen adjacent to disks lacking digitonin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics.</s><s>All seven avian ureaplasma strains produced a slight alkaline color change with a corresponding rise in pH from 6.3 to 6.7 in broth medium without added urea.</s><s>In broth medium containing 0.05% urea, there was a marked alkaline color change and a rise in pH from 6.3 to 7.8, indicating that the urea was hydrolyzed.</s><s>There was no evidence for arginine hydrolysis or glucose fermentation in broth medium without added urea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological properties.</s><s>The seven avian ureaplasma strains did not react with the hyperimmune sera prepared against the three bovine <i>U. diversum</i> serovars or the eight human <i>U. urealyticum</i> serovars in either the MI tests or the GI tests.</s><s>Conversely, the hyperimmune sera prepared against the three representative avian ureaplasma strains (strains D6-<sup>1</sup>, Y8-1, and T9-1) reacted with the seven avian strains in high titers (range, 320 to 10,240) but not with the 3 bovine and 14 human ureaplasma serotype strains in the MI test.</s><s>Similar results were obtained in the GI test.</s><s>All of the avian strains were inhibited in growth (with inhibitory zones ranging from 3 to 5 mm) by immune sera prepared against the representative</s></p><p class="description"><s>avian strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell proteins and antigenic determinants.</s><s>The electrophoretic patterns of the six avian strains were similar to each other but distinct from the patterns of the three bovine strains and human strain T960<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The electrophoretic pattern of avian type strain D6-1 was distinct from the patterns of the 14 human serotype strains.</s><s>A common band at approximately 55 kilodaltons (kDa) was seen in the protein patterns of all avian, bovine, and human ureaplasmas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A cloned line of strain D6-1, the type strain of this species, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 43346 and in the National Collection of Type Cultures as strain NCTC 11707.</s></p></content></protolog>