<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7775" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7775" rank="species">Chlamydophila abortus</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> sp. nov., including abortion isolates previously belonging to <i>Chlamydia psittaci</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydia abortus</i> (a.bor'tus. L. masc. gen. n. <i>abortus</i> of miscarriage, referring to the principal symptom of infection)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Chlamydia abortus</i> strains are endemic among ruminants and efficiently colonize the placenta (Rodolakis et al., 1989).</s><s>They have a distinctive serotype and nearly 100 % conservation of ribosomal and ompA sequences.</s><s>The <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> 16s rRNA genes that have been sequenced to date differ by &#x003C; 0.07%.</s><s>Analyses of signature sequences (Figs 3 and 4) or other gene sequences readily identify this species.</s><s>An extrachromosomal plasmid has not been identified in any strain of <i>Chlamydia abortus</i>. <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> has been primarily associated with cases of abortion and weak neonates.</s><s>Typical isolates include strains B577, EBA, OSP, S26/3 and A22 and have been obtained from cases of abortion in sheep, cattle and goats worldwide (Andersen, 1991; Denamur et al., 1991 ; Storz et al., 1960). <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> isolates have also been characterized by serology and sequence analysis from cases of abortion in a horse, a rabbit, guinea pigs and mice (J.</s><s>Storz, K.</s><s>D.</s><s>E.</s><s>Everett, A.</s><s>A.</s><s>Andersen, unpublished data) and by PCR from a pig (Kaltenbock et al., 1997).</s><s>Sporadic zoonotic abortion due to <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> has been confirmed by genetic analysis of isolates from women who work with sheep (Herring et al., 1987; Jorgensen, 1997).</s><s>The type strain for <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> is B577<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC VR 656<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>B577<sup>T</sup> has a slightly divergent rDNA sequence compared to other <i>Chlamydia abortus</i> strains.</s></p></content></protolog>