<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1546_nm.512" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.512" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.512" rank="species">Deinococcus indicus</organism><reference id="rid.1546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suresh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sengupta</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deinococcus indicus sp. nov., an arsenic-resistant bacterium from an aquifer in West Bengal, India.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>457</fpage><lpage>461</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02758-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023960</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Deinococcus indicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Deinococcus indicus</em> (in′di.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>indicus</em> pertaining to India, Indian).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar medium are red-pigmented, smooth, convex, circular, uniform-edged and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C; growth occurs at 20–37 °C and pH 6–7.</s><s>Tolerates up to 1·0 % NaCl and is resistant to UV radiation (5·87 J cm<sup>−2</sup>).</s><s>Strictly aerobic and positive for catalase, gelatinase, amylase, arginine dihydrolase, aesculin and casein hydrolysis and reduction of nitrate to nitrite, but negative for oxidase, lipase, urease, indole production, Voges–Proskauer test and citrate utilization.</s><s>A number of compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources (Table 1), including d-maltose, sucrose, d-ribose and l-tyrosine, but not acetate, cellulose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, pyruvate, d-sorbose, l-glycine, creatinine, l-alanine or l-cysteine.</s><s>Sensitive to the antibiotics bacitracin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin, rifampicin, rifamycin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but resistant to ampicillin and amoxycillin.</s><s>Fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2; there are seven unknown polar lipids.</s><s>Major respiratory quinone is MK-8 and cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ornithine as the diamino acid.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 65·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Wt/1a<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4913<sup>T</sup>=DSMZ 1537<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>