<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1994_nm.10847" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10847" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10847" rank="species">Marinobacter salsuginis</organism><reference id="rid.1994"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Antunes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>França</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter salsuginis sp. nov., isolated from the brine-seawater interface of the Shaban Deep, Red Sea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1035</fpage><lpage>1040</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64862-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473254</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter salsuginis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter salsuginis</em> (sal.su′gi.nis. L. gen. n. <em>salsuginis</em> from salt water, brine, pertaining to the environment from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, rod-shaped cells (1 μm in width and 2–4 μm in length).</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Marine agar are round and whitish (2–3 mm).</s><s>NaCl is required for growth; the NaCl range for growth is 1–20 % (w/v), with optimum growth occurring at about 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C (optimum, 35–37 °C).</s><s>pH range for growth is about 6.5–9.5 (optimum, pH 7.5–8.0).</s><s>Heterotrophic and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows without yeast extract or growth factors.</s><s>Produces acid from glycerol, d-glucose, d-fructose and 5-ketogluconate; acid is not produced from d-melibiose, d-lactose, maltose or mannitol or any of the other substrates tested.</s><s>Denitrifies in medium supplemented with pyruvate or d-glucose.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Gelatin, casein and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Arbutin, DNA, aesculin, hippurate, starch and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acetate, glucose, lactate, malate, fumarate, glycerol, l-alanine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-phenylalanine, proline, pyruvate, succinic acid and 2-oxoglutarate are assimilated.</s><s>Fructose, galactose, mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, ribose, xylose, l-arabinose, maltose, lactose, cellobiose, melezitose, raffinose, sucrose, ribitol, sorbitol, arabitol, mannitol, erythritol, xylitol, glucuronate, citrate, formic acid, glycine, aspartate, arginine, asparagine, histidine, lysine, methionine, serine, tryptophan, ethanol, benzoate and methanol are not used.</s><s>Aliphatic hydrocarbons used include n-decane, n-hexadecane, heptane, hexane and petroleum ether, but l-chlorobutane, dodecane and toluene are not used.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are detected.</s><s>Weak reactions are also detected for valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Ubiquinone 9 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains SD-14B<sup>T</sup> and SD-14C were isolated from the brine–seawater interface of the Shaban Deep, Red Sea.</s><s>The type strain is SD-14B<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18347<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23697<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>