<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1937_nm.8944" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8944" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8944" rank="species">Chromohalobacter sarecensis</organism><reference id="rid.1937"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Quillaguamán</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Delgado</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mattiasson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatti-Kaul</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromohalobacter sarecensis sp. nov., a psychrotolerant moderate halophile isolated from the saline Andean region of Bolivia</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1921</fpage><lpage>1926</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63153-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545411</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chromohalobacter sarecensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chromohalobacter sarecensis</em> (sa.re.cen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. relating to Sida/SAREC, the institution that supports scientific research in Bolivia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative and motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 56·1 mol%.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped and 0·5×0·8 to 0·8×6·1 μm in size.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and show a wide distribution of sizes during the exponential phase of growth.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire margins, convex, smooth with a glistening surface and have a translucent to brown pigment, which is enhanced in old cultures.</s><s>Acid is produced in medium supplied with fructose, xylose, glucose, rhamnose, galactose or glycerol, but acidification is not detected with trehalose, sucrose, citrate or raffinose.</s><s>Heterotrophic and able to oxidize l-arabinose, d-arabitol, iso-erythritol, d-galactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, raffinose, rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, lactose, cellobiose, glucose, ribose, d-xylose, melibiose, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, d-alanine, l-alaninamide, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine and glycerol.</s><s>Cells are unable to metabolize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, adonitol, l-fucose, gentibiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol or 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Catalase-, oxidase- and tryptophan deaminase-positive.</s><s>Indole and sulfide are not produced, nitrate is not reduced, caseinase, DNase and urease are not present and gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Tests for hydrolysis of Tween 40, Tween 80, starch and aesculin are negative.</s><s>Moderately halophilic and psychrotolerant bacterium: grows at 0–25 % (w/v) NaCl in CAS medium, with the optimum at 8 % (w/v) NaCl; grows at 0–45 °C, with the optimum between 30 and 35 °C; grows at pH 5–10, with the optimum between pH 7·5 and 8·0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LV4<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 47987<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-761<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>