<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12910_nm.22731" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22731" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22731" rank="species">Aquisphaera giovannonii</organism><reference id="rid.12910"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bondoso</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lobo-da-Cunha</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lage</surname><given-names>O.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquisphaera giovannonii gen. nov., sp. nov., a planctomycete isolated from a freshwater aquarium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2844</fpage><lpage>2850</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027474-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21239565</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquisphaera giovannonii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquisphaera giovannonii</em> (gi.o.van.no′ni.i. N.L. masc. n. <em>giovannonii</em> of Giovannoni, in honour of the American microbiologist Stephen Giovannoni).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses the following characteristics in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are spherical, 1.6–2 µm in diameter, non-motile and occur singly or in aggregates held together by extracellular material.</s><s>Crateriform pits are distributed around the cell surface.</s><s>Colonies in PYGV are light pink, translucent and smooth.</s><s>NAG enhances colony pigmentation.</s><s>Growth does not occur in R2A or PYGV4 but a very large glycocalyx develops during growth, as observed by light and electron microscopy.</s><s>Extremely large visible cell aggregates are formed.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 30–35 °C (temperature range between 10 and 35 °C) and growth does not occur at 5 or 40 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH is 7.5–8.5 (pH range between 6.5 and 9.5) and growth does not occur at pH 5.5 or 10.5.</s><s>Does not grow in media containing more than 0.25 % NaCl.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Degrades starch, Tween 20, Tween 80 and gelatin, but not urea, casein, elastin, xylan, aesculin or arbutin.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-glucosidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucosidase and α-fucosidase (API ZYM); other activities are negative.</s><s>Produces acetoin but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are absent.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose d-fructose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, l-fucose, d-ribose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, cellobiose, trehalose, d-mannitol, α-ketoglutarate, acetate, pyruvate and d-glucoronate, but not l-sorbose, d-xylose, raffinose, glycerol, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, erythritol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, succinate, citrate, benzoate, fumarate, formate, aspartate, glutamate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-histidine, l-lysine, proline, l-glutamine, l-arginine, l-serine, valine, l-phenylalanine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-ornithine, methionine or l-threonine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, sucrose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose and potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50 CH), but not from any of the other carbon sources.</s><s>Oxidizes α-cyclodextrin, NAG, l-arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, formic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine and phenylethylamine (Biolog GN2), but not any of the other carbon compounds.</s><s>Peptone, yeast extract, Casamino acids, NAG, ammonia, asparagine, aspartate, cysteine, glutamine, ornithine, serine and threonine serve as sources of nitrogen.</s><s>Nitrate, nitrite and urea are not utilized.</s><s>Vitamin B12 is required for growth.</s><s>The mean DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.0±0.35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, OJF2<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7510<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22561<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the sediments of a freshwater aquarium.</s><s>OJF8, isolated from a similar source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>