<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.735_nm.9429" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9429" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9429" rank="species">Pusillimonas noertemannii</organism><reference id="rid.735"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stolz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bürger</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuhm</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pusillimonas noertemannii gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Alcaligenaceae that degrades substituted salicylates</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1077</fpage><lpage>1081</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63466-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879236</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pusillimonas noertemannii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pusillimonas noertemannii</em> (noer.te.mann′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>noertemannii</em> of Nörtemann, in honour of Bernd Nörtemann, who isolated this and various other bacterial strains that had extraordinary degradative abilities).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is as given for the genus above.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (1–1·5 μm in length and 0·5–0·8 μm in diameter).</s><s>They are motile by means of polarly inserted flagella.</s><s>On nutrient agar, colonies are brownish, circular and with an entire margin.</s><s>Grows at 30, 37 and 42 °C, but not at 4 °C. l-Alanine–<em>p</em>-nitroanilide is hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phenyl phosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl choline, l-aniline–<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate–<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline–<em>p</em>-nitroanilide.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole source of carbon: acetate, propionate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate and 4-hydroxybenzoate, on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>i</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, itaconate, l-malate, mesaconate, suberate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>No acids are produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s>Quinone system, polyamine pattern and polar lipid profile are identical to those listed under the genus description.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (trace), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (4·4 %), 2-OH C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (3·3 %), C<sub>13 : 1</sub> AT 12–13 (trace), summed feature 1 (C<sub>12 : 0</sub> alde?) (1·2 %), summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I and/or 3-OH C<sub>14 : 0</sub>) (8·0 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (trace), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (18·5 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (30·9 %), 2-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (trace), 3-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (trace), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (trace), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11 methyl (trace), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2·5 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> iso (0·9 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (26·8 %) and C<sub>20 : 2</sub><em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em> (trace).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (BN9<sup>T</sup>=DSM 10065<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 14020<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the River Elbe in Germany after enrichment of a mixed bacterial culture with 6-aminonaphthalene-2-sulphonate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 61·8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>