<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12163_nm.20154" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20154" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20154" rank="species">Paenibacillus residui</organism><reference id="rid.12163"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Figueira</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus residui sp. nov., isolated from urban
waste compost</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2415</fpage><lpage>2419</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014290-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19946057</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus residui</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus residui</em> (re.si′du.i. L. n. <em>residuum</em> leavings, scraps, residues; L. gen. n. <em>residui</em> of leavings, scraps, residues).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells may stain Gram-positive or Gram-negative and are motile rods (1.4–1.6 μm long and 0.5 μm wide).</s><s>Polar flagella may be observed and oval spores are positioned centrally in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are translucent and irregular on PCA after 48 h of incubation.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–50 °C, at pH 7–9 and in up to 2 % NaCl, with optimal growth at about 37 °C, pH 7 and 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur in an anaerobic atmosphere and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Citrate is not used, and H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Urease activity is variable.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid and alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, leucine and valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, lipase C14, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are not produced.</s><s>The sole carbon sources assimilated are d-glucose, maltose, d-ribose, d-fructose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, trehalose, gentiobiose, turanose and d-tagatose.</s><s>The following are not assimilated: l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-fructose, d-ribose, dulcitol, amygdalin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Variable for the assimilation of d-mannitol, erythritol, adonitol, dulcitol, sucrose and d-arabitol, and for acid production from d-xylose, adonitol, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, lactose, turanose, d-tagatose and d-arabitol.</s><s>Resistant to cephalothin (30 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), colistin sulfate (50 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Susceptible to meropenem (10 μg), amoxicillin (25 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), SXT (sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim, 23.75/1.25 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), ticarcillin (75 μg) and sulfamethoxazole (25 μg).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and the major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is of the A1<em>γ</em> type (directly cross-linked <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 49 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MC-246<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22072<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 57263<sup>T</sup>), isolated from municipal urban waste compost.</s></p></content></protolog>