<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4056_nm.6231" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6231" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6231" rank="species">Corynebacterium iranicum</organism><reference id="rid.4056"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carlson</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Corynebacterium plant pathogens, including a new pathogen of wheat, based on polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of cellular proteins.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>315</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium iranicum</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, pleomorphic rods, with a temperature maximum of 30°C. Colonies are circular (diameter, 2 to 4 mm), convex, and yellow pigmented on NBY medium. Produces acid from xylose, glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, melezitose, and glycerol but not from rhamnose, ribose, melibiose, raffinose, adonitol, mannitol, sorbitol, dulcitol, inositol, salicin, α-methyl glucoside, β-methyl glucoside, or esculin. Utilizes citrate, fumarate, malate, and succinate but not acetate or lactate. Does not hydrolyze starch and has a maximum NaCl tolerance of 2%. Distinguished from other <i>Corynebacterium</i> spp. by the presence of diaminobutyric acid in its peptidoglycan, its characteristic menaquinones (MK10 and MK8), and its distinct pattern of protein bands in polyacrylamide gels. Isolated from wheat (<i>T. aestivum</i> L.) showing a gumming disease of the seedheads. The type strain is strain NCPPB 2253, the reference strain of Dye and Kemp (14). As the preceding description is based on a single strain, the type strain, the species description also serves as a description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>