<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5089_nm.7491" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7491" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7491" rank="species">Microtetraspora tyrrhenii</organism><reference id="rid.5089"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tomita</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oda</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohkusa</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chikazawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fluvirucins A1, A2, B1, B2, B3, B4 and B5, new antibiotics active against influenza A virus. IV. Taxonomy on the producing organisms</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>940</fpage><lpage>948</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1938616</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microtetraspora tyrrhenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microtetraspora tyrrhenii</i> (tyrrhenii, tyr-re'-ni-i, L. adj. referring to the Tyrrhenian Sea in Mediterranean Sea, which the soil source site of this organism faces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Q464-31 (Fluvirucin A<sub>1</sub> Producer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hook or spiral spore-chains were formed monopodially on the tip of aerial hyphae.</s><s>The spores were big and had vertical folds on the surface (Fig. 1).</s><s>White aerial mycelium was formed on ISP media Nos. 2, 3 and 4.</s><s>The colony on ISP mediumNo. 2 was rigid, convex or crateriform and brownish.</s><s>Melanin and other distinct pigments were not produced.</s><s>Growth occurred between 17°C and 40°C, or in NaCl at 3% or less.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology and cell chemistry of strain Q464-31 indicated that the strain should be placed in the <i>Actinomadura pusilla</i> group which was proposed to be separated from the genus <i>Actinomadura</i> and reclassified in the genus <i>Microtetraspora</i>.</s><s>Based on the direct or descriptive comparisons of the strain to the known species of the <i>A. pusilla</i> group, strain Q464-31 was differentiated from the known species by its spores with vertical ridges and some physiological characteristics including the decomposition of adenine, the presence of urease and the absence of gelatinase.</s><s>Thus, strain Q464-31 is classified as a new species of the genus <i>Microtetraspora</i>.</s><s>The proposed designation is <i>Microtetraspora tyrrhenii</i> sp. nov.</s><s>The type strain is No. Q464-31 (ATCC 53931), which is single isolate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The source of strain Q464-31 was a soil sample collected in the river side of Tevere (Tiber) River, Rome, Italy.</s></p></content></protolog>