<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2542_nm.1797" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1797" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1797" rank="species">Brachymonas denitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.2542"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>Y.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sugiyama</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachymonas denitrificans gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic chemoorganotrophic bacterium which contains rhodoquinones, and evolutionary retionships of rhodoquinone producers to bacterial species with various quinone classes.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachymonas denitrificans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachymonas denitrificans</i> (de.ni.tri'fi.cans. M. L. part. adj. <i>denitrificans</i> denitrifying)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are the same as those described for the genus.</s><s>Additional characteristics are as follows.</s><s>Colonies on ordinary nutrient agar are smooth, convex, opaque, with entire margin, cream or pale yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs in a temperature range of 10 to 40°C (optimum, 30-35°C) and in a pH range of 5 to 9 (optimum, pH 7.0-7.5).</s><s>NaCI is not required for optimal growth, and multiplication occurs up to 3 % NaCI.</s><s>The following properties are negative: indole production, Voges-Proskauer reaction, urease, phenylalanine deaminase, carboxylation of arginine, lysine, and ornithine, hydrolysis of starch, alginate, chitin, gelatin, casein, tributyrin, and Tween 80, and acid production from sugars including L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, melibiose, adonitol, glycerol, mannitol, and sorbitol.</s><s>Good carbon and energy sources are acetate, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, succinate, alanine, glutamate, leucine, phenylalanine, and proline.</s><s>Other usable carbon sources are: butyrate, malate, glutarate, benzoate, ethanol, and polypropylene glycol.</s><s>Not utilized are: formate, caproate, caprylate, peragonate, citrate, gluconate, malonate, tartrate, xylose, arabinose, rhamnose, fructose, glucose, mannose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, adonitol, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, methanol, aminobutyrate, glycine, arginine, ornithine, lysine, tryptophan, and histidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Activated sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: AS-P 1, which has been deposited with the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, RIKEN (Wako, Japan) as <i>Brachymonas denitrificans</i> JCM 9216.</s></p></content></protolog>