<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1412_nm.83" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.83" rank="genus">Stygiolobus</organism><reference id="rid.1412"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segerer</surname><given-names>A.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trincone</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gahrtz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stetter</surname><given-names>K.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stygiolobus azoricus gen. nov., sp. nov. represents a novel genus of anaerobic, extremely thermoacidophilic archaebacteria of the order Sulfolobales.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>501</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stygiolobus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stygiolobus</i> (Sty.gi. o.lo’bus. L. masc. adj. <i>stygius</i>, stygian, from hell; Gr. masc. n. <i>lobos</i>, lobe; M.L. masc. n. <i>Stygiolobus</i>, lobed organism from Hades, referring to its biotope, in which the gate to hell was located in Dante’s <i>Divina Commedia</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, coccoid, and highly irregular in shape (Fig. 2 and 3).</s><s>They are strongly lobed or have sharp edges and bends.</s><s>Thin sections reveal a surrounding envelope covering the cell membrane (Fig. 4), which is composed of subunits in a hexagonal array (42).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, chemolithotrophic thermoacidophiles that thrive by means of S<sup>0</sup> reduction with H<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Neither muramic acid nor <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid is present, indicating the absence of murein (30).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Elongation factor EF-G is sensitive to adenosine diphosphate ribosylation by diphtheria toxin (32, 33).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain glycerol-dibisphytanyl-nonitol tetraether lipids and sulfolobusquinone.</s><s>No caldariellaquinone (11) has been detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms are resistant to vancomycin, ampicillin, and kanamycin at concentrations of 150 μg/ml.</s><s>Protein fractions produce incomplete immunochemical cross-reactions with polyclonal antibodies against the native DNA- dependent RNA polymerase from <i>Sulfolobus acidocaldarius</i> DSM 639<sup>T</sup> (Fig. 5a) and the native (NiFe) hydrogen uptake hydrogenase from <i>A. brierleyi</i> DSM 6334 (53) (Fig. 5b), and fractions enriched for acid-soluble proteins produce complete immunochemical cross-reactions with polyclonal antibodies against histone-like proteins HSNP c' and DBNP B from <i>Sulfolobus acidocaldarius</i> DSM 639<sup>T</sup> (36, 43).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The purified DNA has a G+C content of about 38 mol%.</s><s>There is no significant DNA homology with other members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms occur in acidic solfataric fields.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Stygiolobus azoricus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new organisms described above are archaebacteria on the basis of the occurrence of isopranyl ether lipids in their cells (12, 37), their resistance to cell wall and protein synthesis antibiotics (17), their lack of murein (30), and the presence of elongation factor EF-G which is sensitive to diphtheria toxin (32).</s><s>They resemble chemolithotrophic members of the <i>Thermoproteales</i> (24, 70) in that they grow by means of H<sub>2</sub>-S<sup>0</sup> lithography, but strongly differ from these organisms (and from all other members of the <i>Thermoproteales</i> [for details see reference 22]) in their shape, their extreme acidophily, and their much lower G+C contents.</s><s>Although they are strict anaerobes that are incapable of S<sup>0</sup> oxidation, they are members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> (29, 59), as indicated by their morphology, their extreme thermoacidophily, their relatively low G+C contents, the presence of characteristic lipid compounds (10-12), their strongly acidic biotope, and the immunochemical cross-reactions of their DNA-dependent RNA polymerases, hydrogenases (53), and histonelike proteins with antibodies against the respective enzymes and proteins from members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i>.</s><s>None of those cross-reactions occurs with representative type species belonging to the <i>Thermoproteales, Pyrobaculum islandicum</i> DSM 4184<sup>T</sup> (21, 27), and <i>Pyrodictium occultum</i> DSM 2709<sup>T</sup> (25, 60) (Fig. 5) (36).</s><s>Usually, DNA- dependent RNA polymerases reveal immunochemical cross-reactions only within members of the same family (61).</s><s>On the basis of this criterion, isolate FC6<sup>T</sup> belongs to the family <i>Sulfolobaceae</i> (29, 59).</s><s>On the basis of their strictly anaerobic mode of life, the lack of significant DNA homology with other members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> (Table 2), and their G + C contents of about 38 mol%, the new organisms are distinct from the four previously described genera in this order.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The distribution of the genus <i>Stygiolobus</i> is unknown.</s><s>Strains have been obtained only from solfataras on São Miguel Island.</s><s>We were unable to isolate it from solfataric samp!es obtained from Yellowstone National Park (United States), Iceland, Southern Italy (Naples and Vulcano Island), Indonesia, the Southern Kurils (USSR), and Hokkaido (Japan) (51).</s><s>This could be explained by the presence of <i>Acidianus</i> strains in the samples, which may have overgrown <i>Stygiolobus</i> strains in the enrichment cultures.</s><s>On the other hand, it may be that the genus <i>Stygiolobus</i> is a very rare and possibly even endemic genus in the Azores.</s><s>Other possibly endemic archaebacteria are the anaerobic <i>Methanothermus</i> spp., which have been found so far only in distinct Icelandic solafatara fields (39, 61), and the genetically unrelated strains of <i>Thermoplasma volcanium</i> (28), which occur only on Vulcano Island and Java (Indonesia) (46,50).</s><s>A final decision about the distribution of the genus <i>Stygiolobus</i> has to await further ecological studies.</s></p></content></protolog>