<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1202_nm.3214" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3214" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3214" rank="species">Klebsiella trevisanii</organism><reference id="rid.1202"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ferragut</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gavini</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>DeLey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Klebsiella trevisanii: a new species from water and soil.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>133</fpage><lpage>142</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-133</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of KZebsielZu trevisanii sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Klebsiella trevisanii</i> (tre.vi.san'ii, L. adj. after V. Trevisan, who originally named and described the genus Klebsiella)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on 17 strains belonging to group K of Gavini et al. and two strains belonging to group L (CUETM 77-177 and CUETM 78-134), all of which belong in this new species, as explained above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell characteristics.</s><s>Cells are gram negative, nonmotile, 0.3 to 1.5 by 0.6 to 6.0 μm, nonsporeforming, straight, and rod-shaped, resembling the cells of other members of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial characteristics.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, more or less dome-shaped, and of varying degrees of stickiness.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Relationship to oxygen.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and physiological characteristics.</s><s>As described by Gavini et al., all 19 <i>K. trevisanii</i> strains are positive for citrate (Simmons, at 30 and 37°C), β-galactosidase, growth at 41°C, growth on KCN, lysine decarboxylase, malonate, the methyl red test (at 30 and 37°C),mucate (KauEmann), nitrate reduction to nitrite, tartrate (Jordan), urease, the Voges-Proskauer reaction (at 30 and 37°C), and fermentation of adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose (acid and gas), dextrin, esculin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose (gas), glycerol (gas), <i>meso</i>-inositol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, rafhose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are negative for arginine dihydrolase, deoxyribonuclease, gelatinase (at 20°C), growth at 44.5°C, hydrolysis of chitin, starch, and Tween 80, motility (at 30 and 37°C), ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, production of H<sub>2</sub>S, tetrathionate reductase, and fermentation of <i>mess</i>-erythritol, glycogen, and melezitose.</s><s>Additional characteristics are given in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutritional characteristics.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized by 80 to 100% of the strains (15): L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, gluconate, mucate, salicin, glycerol, adonitol, D-mannitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, sorbitol, acetate, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate, D-malate, L-malate, pyruvate, citrate, malonate, succinate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-quinate, L-α-alanine, D-α-alanine, L-glutamate, L-proline, histamine, and putrescine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized by 80 to 100% of the strains within 5 days: D-arabinose, D-fucose, inulin, ethanol, methanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, isopropanol, geraniol, 2,3-butyleneglycol, <i>mess</i>-erythritol, dulcitol, ethylene glycol, propylene glycol, propionate, D-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, citraconate, itaconate, oxalate, pimelate, azelate, suberate, levulinate, mesaconate, glutarate, sebacate, salicylate, adipatebutyrate, isobutyrate, <i>n</i>-valerate, isovalerate, <i>n</i>-caproate, heptanoate, caprylate, pelargonate, caprate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate , L-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, terephthalate, phenol, benzylformate, glycine, β-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-valine, L-citrulline, L-threonine, L-cysteine, L-methionine,DL-2aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, 2-aminobenzoate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, L-tryptophan, D-tryptophan, spermine, amylamine, ethanolamine, butylamine, diphenylamine, urea, urate, sarcosin, betaine, creatin, pantothenate, trigonelline, nicotinate, acetamide, naphthalene, dodecane, and hexadecane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genetic data.</s><s>The mean guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of the type strain, CIP 81-36, is 56.9 mol%.</s><s>DNA-DNA hybridization values for the most related species are as follows: <i>K. terrigena</i>, 50 to 71% (20 strains tested); <i>K. oxytoca</i>, 50 to 65% (10 strains tested); <i>K. pneumoniae</i>, 45 to 61% (14 strains tested); and <i>K. mobiles</i>, 40 to 54% (11 strains tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Found in unpolluted soils and water (drinking water, surface water, sewage).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Gavini K70 = CUETM 78-120 = CIP 81-36.</s><s>Isolated from drinking water.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are those given above for the species, and the biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>