<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4443_nm.5119" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5119" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5119" rank="species">Paenibacillus borealis</organism><reference id="rid.4443"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Elo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suominen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Juhanoja</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haahtela</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus borealis sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing species isolated from spruce forest humus in Finland.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>535</fpage><lpage>545</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321100</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus borealis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus borealis</i> (bo.re.a'lis. M.L. adj. <i>borealis</i> pertaining to the north (wind), boreal)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, motile rods (0.75-1.0 μm in width, 3.0-5.0 μm in length).</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores formed in swollen sporangia in the subterminal or terminal region of the cell.</s><s>The mature spores of the type strain have a motif of stripes on the surface.</s><s>Flat, smooth, opaque and entire colonies on nutrient agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5-37 °C; optimum is 28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.6-8.0; optimum is pH 7.</s><s>Does not tolerate 5% NaCl, 0.001% lysozyme or 0.02% sodium azide.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase-negative.</s><s>Litmus milk reaction acidic.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Nitrogen is fixed.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, indole or dihydroxyacetone are not produced.</s><s>Casein, carboxymethyl cellulose, chitin, pectin and egg yolk lecithin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, D-xylose, methyl β-xyloside, N-acetylglucosamine, lactose, inulin, melezitose and D-arabitol.</s><s>D-Arabinose, ribose, rhamnose, inositol, methyl α-D-mannoside, D-fucose, L-fucose and gluconate are not fermented.</s><s>Aesculin and bis-p-nitrophenyl-phosphate are hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated: N-acetyl-dglucosamine, L-arabinose, p-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-maltose, D-sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucuronide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phenyl-phosphonate, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline and 2-deoxythymidine-5'-p-nitrophenyl phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: L-rhamnose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, acetate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-alanine, L-aspartate, L-leucine, 3-hydroxybenzoate and 4-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>The G+­C content of the type strain is 53.6 mol%.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, C<sub>14:0</sub> and C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>The relative amounts of straight-chain C<sub>14:0</sub> and C<sub>16:0</sub> are nearly equal for cells grown at 28 °C.</s><s>Isolated from acid humus in Norway spruce forest in Finland and from rhizoplane of birch and red fescue.</s><s>KK19<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13188<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 43137<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>