<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5700_nm.6562" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6562" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6562" rank="species">Actinoplanes palleronii</organism><reference id="rid.5700"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical and chemical classification of Actinoplanes and some related actinomycetes</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinoplanes palleronii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinoplanes palleronii</i> (pall.er.on'ii. ML gen. n. <i>palleronii</i>, of Palleroni ; named after Norberto Palleroni, a distinguished taxonomist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Light to yellow-brown substrate mycelium formed on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Sporangia spherical, spores motile and formed irregularly within sporangia.</s><s>Melanin produced on ISP7 medium.</s><s>Degrades arbutin, casein, lecithin, pectin and starch; utilizes D-fructose, D-glucose, D-maltose, D-mannose and D-xylose as sole carbon sources but not D-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, erythritol, D-galactose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, catechol, coumarin, m-, o- or p-hydroxybenzoic acid, sodium acetate, sodium fumarate, sodium succinate, syringaldehyde, syringic acid or vanillin.</s><s>Neither hydrogen sulphide nor urease is formed.</s><s>The organism is sensitive to a range of antibiotics and chemical inhibitors (Table 6).</s><s>It grows at 4 and 30 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>- and hydroxydiaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The principal wall sugars are arabinose, galactose, glucose, rhamnose, ribose and xylose.</s><s>The organism also contains complex mixtures of straight- and branched-chain fatty acids, with 12- methyltetradecanoic acid predominating, tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenologue, and major amounts of dip hosphatidylglycerol, p hosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from river sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Actinoplanes palleronii LA83 (IF) 14916, NCIB 20021).</s></p></content></protolog>