<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12630_nm.22166" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22166" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22166" rank="species">Burkholderia bannensis</organism><reference id="rid.12630"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aizawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vijarnsorn</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sunairi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia bannensis sp. nov., an acid-neutralizing bacterium isolated from torpedo grass (Panicum repens) growing in highly acidic swamps</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1645</fpage><lpage>1650</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026278-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20709915</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia bannensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia bannensis</em> (ban.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bannensis</em> pertaining to the Banna region of Nakhon Nayok Province, Thailand, where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods (0.6–0.8×1.6–2.1 µm).</s><s>Colonies are smooth, round, convex and pale yellow with entire margins after 3 days of cultivation at 32 °C on 1/10 TS agar plates (pH 4.0).</s><s>Growth occurs at 17–37 °C, with optimum growth at 28–32 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 3–8, with optimum growth at pH 4–6.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and reduction of nitrate to nitrite, but negative for hydrolysis of DNA and gelatin, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, proteinase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, indole production and reduction of nitrate to N<sub>2</sub> (API ZYM, API 20E and API 20NE).</s><s>Positive for acid production from glycerol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, arbutin, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d- and l-fucose and d-arabitol; negative for acid production from methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen and turanose (API 50CH).</s><s>Positive for utilization of Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, inositol, l-rhamnose, trehalose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-threonine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, thymidine, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon sources; negative for utilization of α-cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, xylitol, α-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, putrescine and 2,3-butanediol (Biolog GN2).</s><s>Resistant to (µg ml<sup>−1</sup>) penicillin (0.25), amoxicillin (4), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (4/2), oxacillin (2), cephalothin (8), cefoperazone (4), erythromycin (1), lincomycin (2), pristinamycin (2), tylosin (2), colistin (4), sulfamethizole (100), nitrofurantoin (25), fusidic acid (2) and metronidazole (4); sensitive to (µg ml<sup>−1</sup>) streptomycin (8), spectinomycin (64), kanamycin (8), gentamicin (4), apramycin (16), tetracycline (4), doxycycline (4), co-trimoxazole (2/38), flumequin (4), oxolinic acid (2), enrofloxacin (0.5) and rifampicin (4) (ATB VET).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the two known strains is 65 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, E25<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 103871<sup>T</sup>  = BCC 36998<sup>T</sup>), and a second strain, E21, were isolated from a root and an aerial stem, respectively, of <em>Panicum repens</em>, an aquatic plant growing luxuriantly in a highly acidic swamp (pH 2.9) in an AASS area in Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>