<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1358_nm.6702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6702" rank="genus">Amycolatopsis</organism><reference id="rid.1358"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prauser</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two new genera of nocardioform actinomycetes; Amycolata gen. nov. and Amycolatopsis gen. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>29</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-1-29</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolatopsis</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolatopsis</i> (A.my.co.la.top'sis. M.L. fem. n. <i>Amycolata</i> genus belonging to the order <i>Actinomycetales</i>; Gr. n. <i>opsis</i> appearance; M.L. fem. n. <i>Amycolatopsis</i> that which appears similar to <i>Amycolata</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Actinomycetes forming branching vegetative hyphae with a diameter of 0.5 to 2.0 μm, which tend to break down into squarish subunits.</s><s>Aerial mycelium may or may not be present.</s><s>Aerial hyphae, when formed, may be sterile or break down into chains of squarish to oval fragments or sporelike structures.</s><s>No endospores, sheaths, synnemata, sporangia, or sclerotia are present.</s><s>Gram positive, non-acidfast.</s><s>Mesophilic, aerobic, catalase positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Not susceptible to phages specific for the <i>Nocardia-Rhodococcus</i> complex, <i>Saccharomonospora</i>, and <i>Faenia</i>.</s><s>Type IV cell wall composition (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glutamic acid, alanine, muramic acid, glucosamine, galactose, and arabinose); type A whole-cell sugar pattern (galactose and arabinose present; no madurose, fucose or xylose; rhamnose variably present).</s><s>Mycolates absent.</s><s>Menaquinones predominantly MK-9 (H<sub>2</sub>, H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Type PII phospholipid pattern (phosphatidylethanolamine present with or without phosphatidylmethylethanolamine) in addition to (variably) phosphatidylinositol mannosides, phosphatidylinositol, and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Phosphatidylcholine and glucosamine-containing phospholipids absent.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 66 to 69 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Amycolatopsis orientalis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>