<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8500_nm.13331" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13331" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13331" rank="species">Glaciecola lipolytica</organism><reference id="rid.8500"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>S.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>H.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glaciecola lipolytica sp. nov., isolated from seawater near Tianjin city, China</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>76</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000489-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126727</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glaciecola lipolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glaciecola lipolytica</em> (li.po.ly′ti.ca. Gr. n. <em>lipos</em> fat; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lytica</em> from Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> -<em>ê</em> -<em>on</em> able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lipolytica</em> fat-dissolving, referring to the property of being able to hydrolyse lipid).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in Table 1.</s><s>Aerobic and heterotrophic.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 1.0–2.5 μm long, motile with a polar flagellum.</s><s>Forms non-pigmented colonies with a butyrous–mucoid consistency, about 2–4 mm in diameter on LOSWM plates after incubation at 30 °C for 2 days.</s><s>Grows at 4–36 °C (optimum 30 °C) but not at 0 or 40 °C, at pH 7.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.6) but not at pH 6.5 or 9.5 and at 0.5–9.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2 %).</s><s>NaCl is required for growth.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, amylase, urease, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, arginine dihydrolase and hydrolysis of starch and lipid.</s><s>Negative for indole production.</s><s>Forms acid from d- and l-arabinose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, gentiobiose and d- and l-fucose.</s><s>Does not form acid from glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α-</em>d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Positive in tests for alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; tests negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, gentiobiose, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate.</s><s>No growth observed on erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, capric acid, phenylacetic acid, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Resistant to (μg per disc) carbenicillin (100), polymyxin B (300) and benzylpenicillin (10).</s><s>Sensitive to neomycin (30), streptomycin (10), ampicillin (10), vancomycin (30), ciprofloxacin (5), rifampicin (5), chloramphenicol (30), kanamycin (30), erythromycin (15), norfloxacin (10), tetracycline (30), gentamicin (10) and novobiocin (5).</s><s>Cells contain C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) as the major fatty acids and phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol as major polar lipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, E3<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7001<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15139<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal surface seawater near Tianjin city, China.</s></p></content></protolog>