<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1451_nm.10712" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10712" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10712" rank="species">Erwinia tasmaniensis</organism><reference id="rid.1451"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Geider</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Auling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jakovljevic</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jock</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Völksch</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia tasmaniensis sp. nov., a non-phytopathogenic bacterium from apple and pear trees.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2937</fpage><lpage>2943</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64032-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17159002</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Erwinia tasmaniensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Erwinia tasmaniensis</em> (tas.ma.ni.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>tasmaniensis</em> pertaining to Tasmania, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, motile, straight rods, measuring 0.5–1 by 1.5–2 μm.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>The species has all of the characteristics of the genus <em>Erwinia</em>.</s><s>Colonies on Standard I agar (StI; Merck) are light-beige, circular, smooth, translucent, flat to slightly convex and about 3 mm in diameter after 24–48 h at 28 °C.</s><s>No diffusible or fluorescent pigment is observed.</s><s>Strains grow well on StI agar and nutrient agar at 28 °C, but not at 36 °C.</s><s>They are able to grow in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Glucose is fermented without gas production.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, gelatinase and tryptophan deaminase are not produced, but <em>β</em>-galactosidase is present.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>There is acetoin production.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C within 3 days: l-arabinose, ribose, glucose, fructose, galactose (except strain Et4/99), mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose, trehalose, melibiose (weak) and citrate.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 28 °C within 3 days: sorbitol, rhamnose, amygdalin, glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, mannose, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol (except strain Et2/99), methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol (except strain Et2/99), gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C contents of strains Et1/99<sup>T</sup>, Et2/99 and Et4/99 are 50.5–52.4 mol% as determined by the <em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method.</s><s>The known strains were isolated from the phyllosphere, in particular apple flowers, pear flowers and bark of apple trees.</s><s>The species may also occur on other plant surfaces and may also be found outside Australia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Et1/99<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17950<sup>T</sup>=NCPPB 4357<sup>T</sup>), was collected in Tasmania from apple flowers.</s><s>Strain Et2/99 (=DSM 17949=NCPPB 4358) was isolated from pear flowers in Victoria and strain Et4/99 was isolated from apple bark in Queensland.</s></p></content></protolog>