<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6772_nm.5452" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5452" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5452" rank="species">Pediococcus claussenii</organism><reference id="rid.6772"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dobson</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Deneer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hemmingsen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glaze</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ziola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of the genus Pediococcus, including Pediococcus claussenii sp. nov., a novel lactic acid bacterium isolated from beer.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2003</fpage><lpage>2010</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02191-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508860</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pediococcus claussenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pediococcus claussenii</i> (claus'sen.i.i. N.L. n. <i>claussenii</i> in honour of N. H. Claussen, who first used the genus name <i>Pediococcus</i> in 1903 for isolates of beer-spoilage bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The proposal of the name <i>Pediococcus claussenii</i> avoids any confusion that may have arisen with the revival of obsolete names such as `<i>Pediococcus cerevisiae</i>', `<i>Pediococcus flavus</i>', `<i>Pediococcus gadidarum</i>', `<i>Pediococcus odoris</i>' or `<i>Pediococcus tetrus</i>'.</s><s>Cells are cocci, 0.6-1 μm in diameter.</s><s>They are Gram-positive, non-motile, do not form spores and occur singly, in pairs or in tetrads.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, smooth, circular and opaque if exopolysaccharide is not present.</s><s>When exopolysaccharide is produced, colonies are grey, convex, circular, smooth, glistening, opaque and sticky.</s><s>In broth, growth causes turbidity.</s><s>The broth clears in a few days if the cells are non-ropy.</s><s>For ropy cells, the turbidity remains much longer, as the cells settle slowly.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, aesculin, D-fructose, β-gentiobiose, D-glucose, D-mannose, ribose, salicin and trehalose.</s><s>Most strains ferment mannitol and maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, starch, L-arabinose, D- or L-arabitol, D-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, galactose, gluconate, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, methyl α-D-glucoside, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, D-xylose, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, melezitose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, D- or L-xylose, methyl β-xyloside or xylitol.</s><s>Fermentation patterns for ropy and nonropy variants are identical.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All isolates reported here were brewery isolates.</s><s>The G+C content is 40.0-41.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is isolate P06<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-344<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14800<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description of the type isolate corresponds to that of the species.</s><s>This isolate can be obtained in an exopolysaccharide-producing form; however, this characteristic can be lost upon repeated broth culture.</s><s>Colonies showing a ropy phenotype should be used frequently to initiate broth cultures to maintain the ropy phenotype in liquid medium.</s></p></content></protolog>