<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.233_nm.6087" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6087" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6087" rank="species">Agromyces mediolanus</organism><reference id="rid.233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uramoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakase</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces mediolanus sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov., a species for Corynebacterium mediolanum Mamoli 1939 and for some aniline-assimilating bacteria which contain 2,4-diaminobutyric acid in the cell wall peptidoglycan.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>88</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-23</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573525</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agromyces mediolanus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agromyces mediolanus</i> (basonym, “<i>Colynebacterium mediolanum</i>” Mamoli 1939). Cells are gram-positive, irregular rods that are 0.3 to 0.6 by 1.4 to 3.0 μm and are nonmotile in 2-day-old cultures on R agar. A rudimentary mycelium may be formed. Colonies are circular, opaque, and yellow to white on R agar plates. DAB is the principal amino acid of the cell wall peptidoglycan. The molar ratio of glycine to glutamic acid to alanine to DAB in peptidoglycan hydrolysate is 1:1:1:2. The acyl type of the cell wall is an acetyl type. The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-12. The predominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> acids. The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and glycolipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics mentioned above are common in <i>Agromyces</i> species.</s><s>The following characteristics differentiate this species.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>DNase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, galactose, glycerol, and esculin.</s><s>Urate is utilized, but succinate is not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72.3 to 73.3 mol%.</s><s>The most abundant menaquinones other than MK-12 are MK-11 and MK-10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Agromyces mediolanus</i> is strain JCM 3346 (= ATCC 14004 = DSM 20152).</s><s>The other strains which we examined are strains JCM 1376, CNF183 (= JCM 9631), CNF186 (= JCM 9632), and CNF208 (= JCM 9633).</s></p></content></protolog>