<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6296_nm.3801" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3801" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3801" rank="subspecies">Campylobacter hyointestinalis lawsonii</organism><reference id="rid.6296"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>On</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bloch</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter hyointestinalis subsp. lawsonii subsp. nov., isolated from the porcine stomach, and an emended description of Campylobacter hyointestinalis.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>767</fpage><lpage>774</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-767</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547297</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter hyointestinalis</i> subsp. <i>lawsonii</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter hyointestinalis</i> subsp. <i>lawsonii</i> (law.son'ni.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>lawsonii</i>, of Lawson, in honor of Gordon H. K. Lawson, a bacteriologist at Edinburgh University whose studies on enteric disease in pigs led to the delineation of <i>Campylobacter mucosalis</i> and the unculturable bacterium Ileal symbiont intracellularis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of the seven isolates studied are gram-negative, slightly curved rods or spirals (0.2 μm wide and 1.4 to 2.0 μm long) as determined by light microscopy.</s><s>Motile in wet preparations by means of one or two polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies after 3 days of microaerobic growth on 5% calf blood agar are pinpoint to 1 mm in diameter, round, smooth, and slightly raised.</s><s>All strains produce oxidase, catalase, and hydrogen sulfide in triple sugar iron agar; most (six of seven) strains give strong reactions in triple sugar iron agar under the conditions which we used.</s><s>Both nitrate and selenite are reduced.</s><s>All strains grow at 37 and 42°C on 5% blood agar under microaerobic conditions and grow weakly at 37°C anaerobically.</s><s>All strains grow on unsupplemented nutrient agar and on <i>Campylobacter charcoaldeoxycholate</i> (i.e., unsupplemented "Preston" base) medium All strains grow in the presence of 1% bile, 0.032% methyl orange, and 32 mg of nalidixic acid per liter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Not able to hydrolyze hippurate, indoxyl acetate, and urea.</s><s>Triphenyltetrazolium chloride is not reduced.</s><s>Does not grow at room temperature (18 to 22°C), at 25°C, or under aerobic conditions on unsupplemented 5% blood agar.</s><s>Does not grow on media containing 1.5 or 2.0% bile, 2.O<sub>2</sub> 3.5, or 4.0% NaCl, 0.1% potassium permanganate, 0.05% sodium fluoride, or 0.04% triphenyltetrazolium chloride.</s><s>Pitting of agar media does not occur.</s><s>All isolates are asaccharolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the seven strains tested, CHY 8 and CHY 9 are alphahemolytic and the growth is a greenish color.</s><s>CHY 6 produces alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Tolerance to 1% glycine medium is exhibited by CHY 5<sup>T</sup> and CHY 9, while CHY 3, CHY 4, CHY 6, and CHY 7 are tolerant to 0.0005% crystal violet.</s><s>Although all strains initially grew on potato starch medium, CHY 3 and CHY 7 gave negative results when they were retested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 31 to 33 mol%.</s><s>So far, strains have been isolated only from the stomachs of pigs.</s><s>Pathogenicity is not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CHY 5 (= LMG 14432 = NCTC 12901 = CCUG 34538); its characteristics are the same as the characteristics given in the description above, and the G+C content of its DNA is 32 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>