<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8527_nm.13691" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13691" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13691" rank="species">Amphritea atlantica</organism><reference id="rid.8527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gärtner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiese</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amphritea atlantica gen. nov., sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium from the Logatchev hydrothermal vent field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>34</fpage><lpage>39</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65234-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175678</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amphritea atlantica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amphritea atlantica</em> (at.lan′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>atlantica</em> of or pertaining to the Atlantic Ocean).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>The mean cell size is 0.5×0.5–2.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on MB agar are circular beige with entire whitish edges.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 31–34 °C with 3 % salinity and pH 8.</s><s>The sodium ion of NaCl is required for growth.</s><s>Tests for luminescence are negative.</s><s>The main fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>.</s><s>Hydroxy fatty acids are represented by C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Carbon sources oxidized (Biolog GN2) are: Tween 80, Tween 40, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, sucrose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid and <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid.</s><s>Enzyme activities are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for esterase lipase, lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The API 20NE test system shows strong activities for arginine dehydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease.</s><s>Positive in tests for acetoin production and citrate utilization.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, tryptophan deaminase and gelatinase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 52.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M41<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18887<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24143<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from warm sediment samples at 3000 m depth from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge.</s></p></content></protolog>