<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.644_nm.7964" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7964" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7964" rank="subspecies">Bacteroides melaninogenicus macacae</organism><reference id="rid.644"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slots</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Genco</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides melaninogenicus subsp. macacae, a new subspecies from monkey periodontopathic indigenous microflora.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>82</fpage><lpage>85</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>macacae</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>macacae</i> (<i>macacae</i>. M. L. fem. n. <i>Macaca</i> generic name of macaque; M. L. gen. n. <i>macacae</i> of macaque)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this subspecies is 7728-L6C (= American Type Collection strain 33141).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The six monkey isolates examined were nonsporulating, gram-negative, anaerobic rods which produced black colonies, characteristics typical of the <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i>-<i>B. melaninogenicus</i> group (2).</s><s>The finding that the monkey strains did ferment galactose, glucose, lactose, and mannose, although weakly, suggests that they are members of <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> (2).</s><s>The monkey strains differ from B. asaccharo-lyticus not only in their fermentation of carbohydrates but also by producing catalase and forming relatively large amounts of acetic and propionic acids in glucose broth cultures.</s><s>Furthermore, the monkey isolates exhibit no hemagglutination of sheep erythrocytes, in contrast to oral strains of <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i> (6).</s><s>In addition, serological examinations revealed distinct antigenic differences between the monkey strains and the oral and nonoral strains of <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When compared with the three currently recognized subspecies of <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> (3), the monkey strains exhibited several phenotypic properties similar to those of <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>levii</i>.</s><s>They both fail to ferment most carbohydrates and only weakly ferment glucose and lactose.</s><s>They produce the same acid end products from glucose fermentation, although in differing quantities.</s><s>Butyric acid and isovaleric acid constitute less than 1 meq/100 ml of glucose fermentation medium for the monkey strains and more than 1 meq/100 ml for <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>levii</i> (3).</s><s>The monkey strains also differ from <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>levii</i> by being catalase positive and indole positive and by their antigenic composition.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Major differences exist between the monkey strains and <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>intermedius</i> and <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>melaninogenicus</i>.</s><s>For example, strains of these two subspecies fail to produce significant amounts of propionic acid and butyric acid in glucose broth cultures, and they ferment several carbohydrates (3) not fermented by the tested monkey isolates.</s><s>Distinct antigenic differences also exist between the monkey strains and <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>intermedius</i> and <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>melaninogenicus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>