<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1482_nm.5437" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5437" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5437" rank="species">Lactobacillus uli</organism><reference id="rid.1482"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus uli sp. nov. and Lactobacillus rimae sp. nov. from the human gingival crevice and emended descriptions of lactobacillus minutus and Streptococcus parvulus.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>266</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-261</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus uli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus uli</i> (u'li. Gr. n. <i>oulon</i>, the gum; N.L. gen. n. <i>uli</i>, of the gum) (formerly oral strains of <i>L. minutus</i> or <i>Lactobacillus</i> D01)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small, elliptical, nonmotile, gram-positive rods that occur singly, in pairs, and in short chains.</s><s>Central swellings may occur, particularly in cells grown on solid medium.</s><s>Strains are strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies on brain heart blood agar are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, raised or low convex, entire, and translucent to transparent after 5 days of anaerobic incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by 0.02% (vol/vol) Tween 80 and may be stimulated (18 of 48 strains) by 10% rabbit serum added to culture media.</s><s>Of 28 strains tested, 18 grow at 45°C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 6.5% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation products from glucose are lactic acid (0.6 to 8.1 meq/100 ml of culture; mean for 48 strains, 3.7 meq/100 ml), acetic acid (0 to 0.3 meq/100 ml; mean for the 41 of 48 strains in which it was detected, 0.1 meq/100 ml), formic acid (0 to 0.7 meq/100 ml; mean for the 29 of 48 strains in which it was detected, 0.2 meq/100 ml), and occasionally trace amounts of succinic acid.</s><s>Little or no gas is detected in agar deeps.</s><s>Hydrogen is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The terminal pH in PYG-Tween 80 broth cultures ranges from 4.0 to 5.5; the mean terminal pH for 48 strains is 4.6.</s><s>Glycogen, trehalose, and starch are fermented, and starch is hydrolyzed only when serum (which contains amylase) is added to the medium.</s><s>Amygdalin, erythritol, esculin, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is not liquefied, meat is not digested, indole is not produced, and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Reactions are negative for bile-esculin, DNase, and hippurate hydrolysis.</s><s>Catalase activity is not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The susceptibility to antibiotics varies among strains; 1 of 48 strains tested is resistant to 12 μg of chloramphenicol per ml or 1.6 μg of clindamycin per ml, 4 of 48 strains are resistant to 3 μg of erythromycin per ml, and 2 of 48 strains are resistant to 2 U of penicillin G per ml or 6 μg of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid derivatives are C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>cis</i>-9 fatty acid methyl ester and C<sub>18:1</sub> dimethylacetyl (Table 2).</s><s>Isolated from human gingival crevices, especially in patients with periodontitis (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VPI D76D-27C (= ATCC 49627).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 53 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>For each variable reaction described above, the reaction of the type strain is that of the majority of the strains.</s></p></content></protolog>