<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1205_nm.3278" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3278" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3278" rank="species">Providencia friedericiana</organism><reference id="rid.1205"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Providencia friedericiana, a new species isolated from penguins</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>709</fpage><lpage>715</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Providencia friedericiana</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Providencia friedericiana</i> sp. nov. (frie.de.ri.ci.a'na. M.L. adj. <i>friedericiana</i>, derived from the German names Friederike and Friederich [most of the technical work of this study was done by Friederike Heimbach]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology. <i>P. friedericiana</i> cells were gram negative, nonsporeforming, and rod shaped (about 0.5 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm).</s><s>The organisms grown at 25°C showed many peritrichously flagellated forms with five to eight flagella.</s><s>However, when strains were grown at 36°C, they produced no or only a few flagellated cells; the flagellar morphology was poor, and the number of flagella was one or two.</s><s>Capsules of slime layers were not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on media.</s><s>Colonies of <i>P. friedericiana</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>grown overnight on blood agar plates at 36°C were about 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter, glossy, semitranslucent, and smooth.</s><s>Hemolysis did not occur.</s><s>The strains grew poorly at 4 and 44°C, moderately between 10 and 22°C, and well at 30, 36, and 40°C.</s><s>There was also good growth on differential plating media that are selective for <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>, with some exceptions. <i>P. friedericiana</i> produced a brownish pigment like other <i>Providencia</i> species and some <i>Legionella</i> species.</s><s>Previously, Buttiaux, et al. noted that this pigmentation is produced only by members of the genus <i>Providencia</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and description of <i>P. friedericiana</i>.</s><s>The results of biochemical tests for 61 <i>P. friedericiana</i> strains and type strain 1/33 (= DSM 2620) are shown in Table 3.</s><s>All strains were oxidase negative and catalase positive and reduced nitrate to nitrite; they showed the characteristics of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>Furthermore, these strains were negative in tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, and ornithine decarboxylase and positive for phenylalanine deaminase.</s><s>They did not produce H<sub>2</sub>S, hydrolyze urea, or utilize malonate.</s><s>The strains gave weak reactions for Simmons citrate utilization.</s><s>They produced indole after growth in tryptone broth, but the production of indole in lysine-indole motility medium or ornithine-indole motility medium was very weak.</s><s>About one-half of the strains were nonmotile at 36°C; the others showed insignificant motility.</s><s>Most strains were moderately motile at 25°C, as determined in semisolid motility medium containing 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium chloride. <i>P. friedericiana</i> fermented glucose with the production of acid; gas was produced, but only in small amounts (often about a pinhead-sized gas bubble in Durham tubes) by most strains.</s><s>All strains fermented galactose, fructose, and mannose after 24 h and glycerol and sucrose after 48 h, but not adonitol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, trehalose, xylose, or some other carbohydrates.</s><s>They gave negative Voges-ProsProskauer reactions and were positive in the methyl red test.</s><s>Tyrosine clearing was positive.</s><s>These organisms did not utilize acetate or Jordan tartrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the deoxyribonucleic acids of strains 1/1 and 1/33<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) were determined spectrophotometrically by thermal denaturation.</s><s>The ratios obtained were 39±1.5 mol%, corresponding well to the values determined previously for the genus Providencia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antimicrobial susceptibility.</s><s>Eight strains and a total of 18 cultures were tested for susceptibility to amikacin, ampicillin, azlocillin, cefalotin, cefazolin, cefotaxim, cefoxitin, cefuroxim, chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, fosfomycin (plus glucose 6-phosphate) , fusidic acid, gentamicin, mezlocillin, nitrofurantoin, oxacillin, penicillin G, pipemidic acid, piperacillin, tetracycline, tobramycin, and trimethoprimsulfamethoxazole.</s><s>All strains were resistant to clindamycin, fusidic acid, penicillin G, and oxacillin and showed intermediate susceptibility to nitrofurantion.</s><s>Seven strains were resistant to erythromycin, and one showed intermediate susceptibility.</s><s>Six strains were susceptible to ampicillin, one was resistant, and one showed intermediate susceptibility.</s><s>Seven strains were susceptible to cephalotin and chloramphenicol, and one was intermediately susceptible.</s><s>Full susceptibility to all other substances was observed.</s><s>There was no clear distinction between <i>P. friedericiana</i> and the strains of <i>P. alcalifaciens</i> and <i>P . stuartii</i> tested</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 1/33 (=DSM 2620) is the type strain of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile by peritrichous flagella at 25°C; motility mostly absent at 36°C.</s><s>Not encapsulated.</s><s>Brownish pigment produced under special conditions.</s></p></content></protolog>