<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5986_nm.10122" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10122" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10122" rank="species">Costertonia aggregata</organism><reference id="rid.5986"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Costertonia aggregata gen. nov., sp. nov., a mesophilic marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from a mature biofilm</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1349</fpage><lpage>1353</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64168-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738113</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Costertonia aggregata</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Costertonia aggregata</em> (ag.gre.ga′ta. L. fem. adj. <em>aggregata</em> joined together, referring to the formation of aggregates during cultivation in liquid medium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.50–0.57 μm in length and 0.35–0.41 μm in diameter.</s><s>However, rods can sometimes be longer than 4 μm.</s><s>Properties are as described for the genus in addition to the following.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C, pH 6.5–9.0 and with 1.5–12.0 % sea salts.</s><s>Cells form irregular aggregates during growth in liquid medium.</s><s>Obligately requires NaCl, Ca<sup>2+</sup> and K<sup>+</sup> for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at pH 7.5–8.0 and 26–32 °C and requires the presence of 3 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrogen gas in API 20 E test strip.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and protease.</s><s>Degrades dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, l-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl–glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The dominant fatty acids are i-15 : 0 (39.7 %), i-15 : 1<em>ω</em>10 (22.4 %), 15 : 0 (7.8 %) and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>9 (4.6 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KOPRI 13342<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42265<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13411<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a mature marine biofilm formed on a rock-bed in Jungdongjin, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>