<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12519_nm.21371" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21371" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21371" rank="species">Halostagnicola alkaliphila</organism><reference id="rid.12519"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nagaoka</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minegishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Echigo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimane</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Usami</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halostagnicola alkaliphila sp. nov., an alkaliphilic haloarchaeon from commercial rock salt</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1149</fpage><lpage>1152</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023119-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543148</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halostagnicola alkaliphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halostagnicola alkaliphila</em> [al.ka.li.phi′la. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> (from Arabic <em>al-qalyi</em> the ashes of saltwort) alkali; N.L. adj. <em>philus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> -<em>ê</em> -<em>on</em>) friend to, loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>alkaliphila</em> loving alkaline conditions].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, pleomorphic and rod-shaped (approx. 0.8–1.0×2.0–2.5 µm).</s><s>Stains Gram-negative.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium are white/pink and circular, 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 25 %, w/v), 20–55 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and pH 8.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 8.5–9.0).</s><s>Cells lyse in water.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from sodium sulfite.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Nitrite is not reduced and no dinitrogen gas is formed.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur with DMSO and arginine, but does occur with nitrate.</s><s>Tests for oxidase activity are positive, but catalase activity is absent.</s><s>Starch, Tween 80, casein and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Tests positive for urease activity, but negative for β-galactosidase activity.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, pyruvate, propionate, dl-lactate and fumarate.</s><s>No growth occurs on l-arabinose, cellobiose, citrate, lactose, d-mannitol, ribitol, ribose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, starch, acetate, succinate, l-malate or l-glutamate.</s><s>Sensitive to anisomycin (50 mg), bacitracin (10 U), erythromycin (15 mg), novobiocin (30 mg), pravastatin (50 mg) and rifampicin (5 mg).</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10 mg), chloramphenicol (30 mg), gentamicin (120 mg), kanamycin (30 mg), nalidixic acid (30 mg), neomycin (30 mg), penicillin G (10 U), streptomycin (300 mg), tetracycline (30 mg) and vancomycin (30 mg).</s><s>Polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> and C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>25</sub> archaeol derivatives of PG and PGP-Me.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 60.7 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 167-74<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16592<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7631<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from commercial rock salt imported into Japan from Hubei Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>