<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12877_nm.22687" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22687" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22687" rank="species">Paenibacillus wooponensis</organism><reference id="rid.12877"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choe</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus wooponensis sp. nov., isolated from wetland freshwater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2763</fpage><lpage>2768</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028308-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216920</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus wooponensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus wooponensis</em> (woo.po.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>wooponensis</em> of or belonging to Woopo wetland, Republic of Korea, the geographical origin of the type strain of the species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive, strictly aerobic, motile rods (0.7–1.0×2.0–5.0 µm) with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Produces ellipsoidal endospores that lie in a subterminal position in cells and usually cause the sporangia to swell.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, opaque, cream-coloured and convex with entire margins and are usually 2 mm in diameter within 48 h of growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2 % NaCl, at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 6–8) and at 10–37 °C (optimum 30–35 °C).</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>DNA, casein and Tween 20 are hydrolysed but CM-cellulose, egg yolk, gelatin, Tween 80, l-tyrosine and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API 20 NE system, positive for aesculin hydrolysis (β-glucosidase), β-galactosidase and assimilation of d-glucose and maltose but negative for nitrate reduction, fermentation of d-glucose, indole production, production of arginine dihydrolase and urease and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, l-arabinose, capric acid, d-mannitol, d-mannose, malate, phenylacetic acid and trisodium citrate.</s><s>In the API 50 CHB system, acids are produced from amygdalin, cellobiose, dulcitol (weakly), aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl-α-d-glucopyranoside (weakly), methyl-α-d-mannopyranoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose; acids are not produced from other substrates.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, acid phosphatase, leucine arylamidase (weakly), esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α- and β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase activities are present; but alkaline phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the Biolog GP2 Microplate system the following substrates are assimilated: amygdalin, cellobiose, dextrin, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, α-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-β-d-galactoside, raffinose, palatinose, trehalose, stachyose, sucrose and turanose; other substrates are not assimilated.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), streptomycin (10) tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (32.2 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (20.1 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (18.1 %).</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and unknown aminophospholipids.</s><s>The diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso-</em>diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WPCB018<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 13280<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16350<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from freshwater collected from Woopo wetland.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 56.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>