<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7014_nm.2628" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2628" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2628" rank="species">Pseudomonas koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.7014"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas koreensis sp. nov., Pseudomonas umsongensis sp. nov. and Pseudomonas jinjuensis sp. nov., novel species from farm soils in Korea.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>21</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02326-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656147</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas koreensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. adj. <em>koreensis</em> pertaining to Korea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, approximately 1×2 μm in size, motile by more than one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are circular and white-yellow on Luria–Bertani (LB) agar and become mucoid after 2 days when cultured on TSA.</s><s>Cells produce a fluorescent pigment on King B and PAF media.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive and shows hydrolysis of arginine and Tween 80.</s><s>Most strains liquefy gelatin, but do not show hydrolysis of starch and show no acidification of glucose.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite is negative.</s><s>Most strains show positive lecithinase reaction.</s><s>Urease reaction is variable among strains.</s><s>Indole is not produced on tryptophan.</s><s>Strains grow at 4 °C but not at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in media supplemented with 5 % NaCl, but not at a salinity higher than 7 %.</s><s>Results obtained with Biolog GN2 microplates indicate that strains utilize Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, α-d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol.</s><s>Utilization of d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-ketobutyric acid and l-pyroglutamic acid is variable among strains.</s><s>The other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>The test using the API 20 NE strip shows that strains assimilate glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, malate and citrate.</s><s>Strains do not assimilate maltose, adipate or phenylacetate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain Ps 9-14<sup>T</sup> is 60·7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain Ps 9-14<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 10848<sup>T</sup> =LMG 21318<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>