<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3838_nm.3117" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3117" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3117" rank="species">Buttiauxella agrestis</organism><reference id="rid.3838"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Buttiauxella agrestis with recognition of six new species of Buttiauxella and two new species of Kluyvera: Buttiauxella ferragutiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella gaviniae sp. nov., Buttiauxella brennerae sp. nov., Buttiauxella izardii sp. nov., Buttiauxella noackiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella warmboldiae sp. nov., Kluyvera cochleae sp. nov., and Kluyvera georgiana sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>50</fpage><lpage>63</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-50</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11534554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Buttiauxella</i> agrestis Ferragut, Izard, Gavini, Lefebvre, and Leclerc 1981.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>B. agrestis</i> was called DNA hybridization group 1 in this study. The original description (13), which was based on the 17 strains originally described by Gavini et al. (15), stated that 60% of <i>B. agrestis</i> strains were malonate positive; we found (Table 2) that 96% of the strains were malonate positive. The biochemical tests that are useful for differentiating <i>B. agrestis</i> from other <i>Buttiamella</i> species are the arginine dihydrolase, fucose, glycerol, lactose, melibiose, ornithine decarboxylase, palatinose, and D-sorbitol tests. This species has been isolated from mollusks, as well as water, soil, and humans.</s></p></content></protolog>