<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3939_nm.5632" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5632" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5632" rank="subspecies">Streptococcus equi zooepidemicus</organism><reference id="rid.3939"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on streptococci of serological groups C, G and L and possibly related taxa</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>483</fpage><lpage>493</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus equi</i> subsp. <i>zooepidemicus</i> nom. rev., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(zo. ö. e. pi. démi. cus. Gr. noun <i>zoon</i> an animal; Gr. adj. <i>epidemius</i> among people; prevalent, epidemic; M. L. adj. <i>zooepidemicus</i> prevalent among animals)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive spherical or ovoid cells, occurring in pairs or chains.</s><s>Capsules may be formed.</s><s>On blood agar plates colonies are surrounded by a wide zone of β-haemolysis.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is ca. 37°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 or 45°C, in 6.5 % NaCl, in 10 % bile, in 0.1 % methylene blue milk, or at pH 9.6.</s><s>Cells do not survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Growth occurs only on complex media; minimal nutritional requirements are unknown.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Chemo-organotroph: metabolism fermentative Final pH in glucose broth ca. 4.6 to 5.0.</s><s>Acid produced from glucose, glycogen, lactose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose and starch.</s><s>Acid not produced from arabinose, glycerol, inulin, mannitol, raffinose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Most strains hydrolyse aesculin.</s><s>Gelatin not liquefied; most strains do not hydrolyse hippurate.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine dehydrolase, β-glucuronidase and leucine arylamidase positive.</s><s>α-Galactosidase and pyrrolidonylarylamidase negative.</s><s>Most strains are β-galactosidase negative.</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield group C antisera.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is based upon lysine (type: Lys-Ala<sub>2-3</sub>).</s><s>Major non-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are hexadecanoic (C<sub>16:0</sub>) and octadecenoic (C<sub>18:1</sub>) acids; cyclopropane-ring containing fatty acids are absent.</s><s>Menaquinones are absent.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of DNA ranges from 41.3 to 42.7 mol % as determined by melting temperature (Tm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: blood stream, inflammatory exudates and lesions of diseased animals.</s><s>The type strain is NCDO 1358.</s><s>This strain is β-galactosidase negative and does not hydrolyse aesculin or hippurate.</s><s>Other characteristics are as given above.</s><s>The mol % G+C content of NCDO 1358 is 41.3 (Tm).</s></p></content></protolog>