<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3434_nm.6324" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6324" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6324" rank="species">Mycobacterium bohemicum</organism><reference id="rid.3434"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reischl</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Emler</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horak</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaustova</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lehn</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naumann</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium bohemicum sp. nov., a new slow-growing scotochromogenic mycobacterium</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1349</fpage><lpage>1355</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1349</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium bohemicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium bohemicum</i> (bo.he'mi.cum. M.L. adj. <i>bohemicum</i> referring to the Czech Republic where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells show acid-alcohol fastness.</s><s>Colonies grown on LJ medium are scotochromogenic and 1-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 25 and 40 °C and does not grow on NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to cycloserine, gentamicin, amikacin, prothionamide and clarithromycin, but resistant to isoniazid (1 mg l<sup>-1</sup>), rifampin (32 mg l<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin (8 mg l<sup>-1</sup>), ethambutol (2 mg l<sup>-1</sup>) and ciprofloxacin (4 mg l<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Positive reactions for heat-stable catalase (68 °C) and urease.</s><s>Urease activity is weak.</s><s>Negative reactions for niacin, nitrate reductase, arylsulfatase (10 d), acid phosphatase, hydrolysis of Tween 80, acetamidase, benzamidase, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, succinamidase and allantoinamidase.</s><s>Strain does not show α-esterase, β-esterase or β-galactosidase activities.</s><s>Cell wall contains arabinose and galactose as major sugars and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid is the only diamino acid.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone and small amounts of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>) are also found.</s><s>Analysis of the fatty acids from the whole cells reveals a pattern of straight-chain, saturated and unsaturated fatty acids along with significant amounts of tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>The strain cannot be precisely identified on the basis of its fatty acid pattern by using the MIDI mycobacterial database, but resembles species of the MAIS complex.</s><s>TLC of mycolic acid methanolysates indicates the presence of α-mycolates and wax esters.</s><s>Only α-mycolates and alcohols are detected by two-dimensional TLC.</s><s>Combined results from HPLC and conventional biochemical testing are supportive of a novel species.</s><s>Conclusive genetic evidence of a novel species has been demonstrated with 16s rDNA analysis.</s><s>The unique sequence has molecular signatures of slow-growing mycobacteria and <i>Mycobacterium bohemicum</i> seems to be phylogenetically near to the slow-growing <i>Mycobacterium kansasii</i>, <i>Mycobacterium gastri</i>, <i>Mycobacterium szulgai</i> and <i>Mycobacterium avium-intracellulare</i> complex.</s><s>Type strain is DSM 44277<sup>T</sup> (deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>