<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.103_nm.7770" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7770" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7770" rank="species">Chlamydia pneumoniae</organism><reference id="rid.103"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grayston</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chlamydia pneumoniae sp. nov. for Chlamydia sp. strain TWAR.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>88</fpage><lpage>90</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-1-88</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chlamydia pneumoniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydia pneumoniae</i> (Pneu.mo'ni.ae. Gr. n. <i>pneumonia</i>, pneumonia, inflammation of the lungs; M.L. gen. n. <i>pneumoniae</i>, of pneumonia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on 10 strains.</s><s>The species has a chlamydial developmental cycle and in cultured cells has intracytoplasmic inclusions which are round and dense in appearance in Giemsa stain.</s><s>The inclusions are iodine stain negative (they contain no glycogen).</s><s>The elementary body is pleomorphic but typically pear shaped.</s><s>The average size is 0.38 μm, with a long axis of 0.44 μm, a short axis of 0.31 μm, and a ratio of the long axis to the short axis of 1.42.</s><s>The cytoplasmic mass is round, with an average diameter of 0.24 μm.</s><s>There is a large periplasmic space.</s><s>Small, round electron-dense bodies (diameter, 0.05 μm), which are attached to the cytoplasm by a stringlike structure, are present in the periplasmic space.</s><s>The reticulate body is circular and has an average diameter of 0.51 μm.</s><s>It shares the <i>Chlamydia</i> genus-specific antigen, as demonstrated by staining inclusions by immunofluorescence using genus-specific monoclonal antibodies.</s><s>Serologically, it can be identified by the monoclonal antibody specific to <i>C. pneumonia.</i> The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 40 mol%, which is within the range for chlamydiae.</s><s>No extrachromosomal DNA (plasmid) has been found.</s><s>The organisms grow better at 35°C than at 37°C in cell cultures.</s><s>Cell culture growth is enhanced by pretreatment of host cells with diethylaminoethyl-dextran before inoculation, centrifugation of inoculum onto cell monolayers, and incorporation of antimetabolites, such as cycloheximide, in Eagle minimum essential medium containing 10% fetal calf serum. <i>C. pneumoniae</i> shows low virulence to chicken embryos as determined by yolk sac inoculation and to mice as determined by intracerebral, intranasal, and intravenous inoculations and does not cause follicular conjunctivitis in monkeys as determined by conjunctival inoculation.</s><s>The spectrum of antibiotic susceptibility is similar to that of other chlamydiae, except that, like most <i>C. psittaci</i> strains, <i>C . pneurnoniae</i> is resistant to sulfadrugs.</s><s>The organism has been isolated from human throats and conjunctivas.</s><s>Differentiation characteristics for the species are listed in Tables 1 and 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the isolates which have been studied are similar as determined by ultrastructural, DNA, and serological analyses and thus are a single strain.</s><s>This strain is known as the TWAR strain of <i>C. pneurnoniae</i>.</s><s>So far, only one serovar has been identified.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is the first isolate, TW-183, which came from the conjunctiva of a child in Taiwan.</s><s>As with nine subsequent throat isolates from humans, it has all of the properties described above for the species.</s><s>The type strain has been made available to investigators by the Washington Research Foundation, Seattle, Wash.</s><s>Strain TW-183<sup>T</sup> has already been distributed to more than 50 investigators throughout the world.</s></p></content></protolog>