<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5875_nm.10066" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10066" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10066" rank="species">Terrimonas lutea</organism><reference id="rid.5875"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of [Flavobacterium] ferrugineum as Terrimonas ferruginea gen. nov., comb. nov., and description of Terrimonas lutea sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1117</fpage><lpage>1121</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64115-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627664</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Terrimonas lutea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Terrimonas lutea</em> (lu.te′a. L. fem. adj. <em>lutea</em> golden-yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are single rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in width and 1–3 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies are circular, about 1 mm in diameter and non-spreading.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, with optimum growth at 25–32 °C.</s><s>Colonies are yellow on nutrient agar and IAM medium 802.</s><s>Grows well on TSA and nitrogen-free medium.</s><s>Chitin and chitosan are not degraded on conventional media.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, fructose, galactose, raffinose and sucrose, but not from dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, xylose or sorbitol.</s><s>Glucose, mannose, aesculin, maltose, lactose, 5-ketogluconate, arabinose, galactose, fructose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, cellobiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose, raffinose, gentiobiose and melibiose are assimilated, but starch, d-xylose, glycogen, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, rhamnose and dulcitol are not.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol phosphohydrolase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are strongly positive; C14 lipase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase and trypsin activities are weakly positive; <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is only slightly different from that of the type species.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DY<sup>T</sup>(=IAM 15284<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB205006<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from garden soil in Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>