<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12851_nm.22658" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22658" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22658" rank="species">Rhizobium vallis</organism><reference id="rid.12851"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sui</surname><given-names>X.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium vallis sp. nov., isolated from nodules of three leguminous species</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2582</fpage><lpage>2588</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026484-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21131504</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium vallis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium vallis</em> (val′lis. L. gen. n. <em>vallis</em> of a valley, referring to the fact that the strains were isolated from the Valley of Red River in Yunnan province, China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods, 1.0–1.5 µm×2.0–3.5 µm.</s><s>Colonies on YMA are circular, convex, pearl-white, translucent and usually 2–3 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Strains can grow at pH 6.0–9.0 and cannot grow with up to 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 28 °C; cells can grow after exposure to 60 °C for 10 min and cannot grow at 10 °C or 37 °C.</s><s>Tests for catalase, urease, oxidase and litmus milk acid production, acid coagulation and peptonization are positive.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reductase, cellulose hydrolase, l-phenylalanine deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S production and hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, DNA and Tween 80 are negative.</s><s>Reduces litmus milk, but methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>d-Arabinose, galactitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, sodium malate, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, and dl-proline can be used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Strains grow weakly on media with adipate, melezitose, d-amygdalin, calcium gluconate, calcium malonate, dextrin, <em>meso</em>-erythrose, inulin, sodium pyruvate, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium formate, sodium gluconate, sodium succinate, sodium hippurate, sorbose, starch, syringic acid, potassium sodium tartrate or vanillic acid as sole carbon source.</s><s>dl-Alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-cystine, l-glutamic acid, hypoxanthine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, l-methionine, d-valine and dl-proline are used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Resistant to (µg ml<sup>−1</sup>) kanamycin (5) and neomycin (5); and sensitive to ampicillin (50), kanamycin (50), neomycin (50), erythromycin (5), gentamicin sulfate (5) and streptomycin sulfate (5).</s><s>The pattern of cellular fatty acids of the type strain is given in Supplementary Table S2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCBAU 65647<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25295<sup>T</sup>  = HAMBI 3073<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from root nodules of <em>Phaseolus vulgaris</em> and its DNA G+C content is 60.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>