<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6441_nm.7769" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7769" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7769" rank="species">Chlamydia pecorum</organism><reference id="rid.6441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fukushi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirai</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Chlamydia pecorum sp. nov. for Chlamydia strains derived from ruminants.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>306</fpage><lpage>308</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1581191</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chlamydia pecorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydia pecorum</i> (pe.co'rum. M. L. gen. pl. <i>pecorum</i>, flocks of sheep or herds of cattle)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the results obtained with the following strains: strains Bo/E58<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC VR628<sup>T</sup>) and Bo/Shizuoka, which were isolated from cattle that had encephalomyelitis; strain Bo/ Maeda, which was isolated from cattle that had pneumonia; strain Boflokohama, which was isolated from cattle that had diarrhea; and strain Ov/IPA (= ATCC VR629), which was isolated from sheep that had polyarthritis. <i>C. pecorum</i> has many phenotypic characteristics that are similar to those described previously for <i>C. psittaci</i>, including the developmental cycle, the ultrastructural morphology of the elementary body and the reticulate body, the inclusion morphology, the absence of glycogen in inclusions, and sulfadiazine resistance.</s><s>It contains the Chlamydia genus-specific lipopolysaccharide antigen, as demonstrated by the complement fixation test.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 39.3 mol%. <i>C. pecorum</i> can be isolated by inoculating chicken embryo yolk sacs and cell cultures containing Madin-Derby bovine kidney and HeLa cells.</s><s>Cell culture growth is enhanced by pretreating cells with DEAE-dextran before inoculation and incubating infected cells with media containing cycloheximide (20). <i>C. pecorum</i> has been isolated from brains, lungs, joints, embryonic kidneys, feces, and other parts of cattle and sheep.</s><s>The diseases caused by <i>C. pecorum</i> include encephalomyelitis, polyarthritis, pneumonia, and enteritis.</s><s>Three serovars are distinguished by the results of immunoblot analyses of the major outer membrane protein.</s><s>The type strain is strain BoE58 (=ATCC VR628), which is the first strain of this species that was isolated.</s><s>Strain Bo/E58<sup>T</sup> can be propagated in Madin-Derby bovine kidney cells and has characteristics typical of <i>C. pecorum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>