<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8889_nm.14221" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14221" rank="genus">Afifella</organism><reference id="rid.8889"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urdiain</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>López-López</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gonzalo</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Langer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosseló-Móra</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Rhodobium marinum and Rhodobium pfennigii as Afifella marina gen. nov. comb. nov. and Afifella pfennigii comb. nov., a new genus of photoheterotrophic Alphaproteobacteria and emended descriptions of Rhodobium, Rhodobium orientis and Rhodobium gokarnense.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>31</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>351</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2008.07.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18774253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Afifella</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Afifella</em> (A.fi.fel’la. N.L. fem. dim. n. <em>Afifella</em> named after S. Afif, British philosopher and painter in recognition of his expertise and guidance in the subject of the philosophical tendency of structuralism, essential for the development and understanding of taxonomy as a science).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus affiliate with the genera <em>Rhodobium</em> and <em>Anderseniella</em> within the <em>Alphaproteobacteria</em> subclass.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells with asymmetric division, motile by means of one to various polar, sub-polar or randomly distributed flagella.</s><s>Phototrophic grown cells contain intracytoplasmic membranes of the lamellar type together with bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids belonging to the spirilloxanthin series.</s><s>Colonies are pink coloured due to the synthesis of photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic growth in the dark can occur aero- or microaerobically, and in some cases fermentatively.</s><s>C<sub>18:1</sub> and C<sub>18:0</sub> are the major fatty acids with the former being predominant.</s><s>When grown aerobically in the dark, species of this genus exhibit a quinone system with ubiquinone Q-10 predominating and significant amounts of menaquinone MK-10 (ratio 2–8:1).</s><s>Species of this genus show a polyamine profile with <em>sym</em>-homospermidine predominating.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, an unknown glycolipid (GL1), moderate amounts of phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine and minor amounts of an unknown lipid L3.</s><s>Other unknown lipids present in minor amounts may be detected.</s><s>Mesophilic, marine bacteria that require NaCl for growth, and grow at seawater salinity and higher concentrations.</s><s>Can be found associated with photosynthetic microbial mats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C mol% of the DNA is 62.1–67.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: <em>Afifella marina</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>