<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8768_nm.13350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13350" rank="species">Halomonas cerina</organism><reference id="rid.8768"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González-Domenech</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas cerina sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, denitrifying, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>803</fpage><lpage>809</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65322-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398173</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas cerina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas cerina</em> (cer.i′na. L. fem. adj. <em>cerina</em> the colour of beeswax, describing the colour of the mature colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, Gram-negative rods, 1.9–2.8×0.7–0.9 μm, appearing either singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cells are capsulated and non-motile.</s><s>Cells accumulate PHA and do not form endospores.</s><s>Cell colonies are wax coloured, circular, convex and mucoid.</s><s>The growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>Moderate halophile, capable of growing in mixed-sea salt concentrations of 3–25 % (w/v), with optimum growth occurring between 7.5 and 10 %.</s><s>Requires NaCl and can grow within a range of 7.5–20 % (w/v), the optimum being 7.5–10 %.</s><s>Grows within a temperature range of 4–45 °C at pH values of between 5 and 10, the optimum values being 20–32 °C and pH 7–8.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory with oxygen, nitrate and nitrite as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Respiration with fumarate is negative.</s><s>Under aerobic conditions, selenite and nitrate are reduced.</s><s>Acids are not produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, O/F and ONPG tests give a negative result.</s><s>Does not produce pyocyanin, fluorescein or pigment in tyrosine medium.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, casein, lecithin or aesculin.</s><s>Produces urease, phosphatase and DNase but not phenylalanine deaminase.</s><s>Gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar but not on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Blood is not lysed.</s><s>The following compounds serve as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, fumarate, d-gluconate, succinate, d-glucose, maltose and d-mannose, whilst aesculin, galactose, formate, malonate and sorbitol do not.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-isoleucine, l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-methionine and l-valine cannot be used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>Susceptible to (amounts per disc): amoxicillin+clavulanic acid (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), aztreonam (30 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), ceftazidine (30 μg), doxycycline (30 U), gentamicin (10 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (30 μg), sulphamide (250 μg) and trimetroprim+sulphametoxazol (1.25−23.75 μg).</s><s>Resistant to tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>Principal fatty acids are 16 : 0, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant respiratory lipoquinone is ubiquinone with nine isoprene units (Q-9).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is between 62.7 and 66.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SP4<sup>T</sup>, grows in a medium containing only 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>It hydrolyses tyrosine and Tween 80 but not gelatin.</s><s>It does not survive for 10 min at 80 °C.</s><s>Salicin, ethanol and serine serve as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>It does not utilize arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, lactose, starch, trehalose, lactate, adonitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol or histidine.</s><s>The principal fatty acids of the type strain are: 16 : 0 (33.9 %); 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (18.72 %); 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (16.08 %); 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (14.46 %) and 12 : 0 3-OH (6.22 %).</s><s>The predominant respiratory lipoquinone is ubiquinone with nine isoprene units (Q-9).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.2 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SP4<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7282<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24145<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil.</s></p></content></protolog>