<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9571_nm.14748" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14748" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14748" rank="species">Bhargavaea cecembensis</organism><reference id="rid.9571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Manorama</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pindi</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G. S. N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bhargavaea cecembensis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the Chagos–Laccadive ridge system in the Indian Ocean</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2618</fpage><lpage>2623</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002691-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625444</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bhargavaea cecembensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bhargavaea cecembensis</em> [ce.cem.ben′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>cecembensis</em> pertaining to CCMB, arbitrary adjective formed from the acronym of the Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CCMB), where the taxonomic studies on this novel species were performed].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus above.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and rod-shaped (2.0 μm in length×6.0 μm in width) and occur singly, in pairs or in groups (Fig. 2).</s><s>Colonies on TSA medium are convex, 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, regular and opaque.</s><s>Cells grow from 15 to 55 °C with an optimum temperature of 37 °C and tolerate up to 6.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs over a pH range of 7–7.5.</s><s>The doubling time is 5 h.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase and urease activities are positive, but tests for phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>Tyrosine is not degraded, indole is not produced, The methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Tween 60 is hydrolysed but Tween 80, starch, aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and H<sub>2</sub>S gas is produced.</s><s>Cells do not produce either acid or gas from adonitol, d- arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, d-sorbitol, trehalose or xylose even after incubation at an optimum temperature for 1 week.</s><s>Assimilates adonitol, d-fructose, melezitose and maltose, but not <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, citric acid, dulcitol, galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, glyoxylic acid, inositol, inulin, lactose, d-mannose, mannitol, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, polyethylene glycol, acetate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, gluconate, sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Cells utilize l-arginine and l-proline but not the remaining eighteen amino acids, including l-ornithine and l-creatinine.</s><s>Cells are resistant to (μg disc<sup>−1</sup>) cefazolin (30), colistin (10), co-trimoxazole (25), lincomycin (2), nalidixic acid (30) and polymixin-B (50 U) but susceptible to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), bacitracin (10), carbenicillin (100 ), cefotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), gentamicin-G (30), kanamycin (30), lomefloxacin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), norfloxacin (10), novobiocin (30), oleandomycin (15), penicillin-G (10), rifampicin (30), spectinomycin (100), tetracycline (30), tobramycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains diaminopimelic acid, glutamic acid and alanine.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The isoprenoid quinones are MK-6 (8 %) and MK-8 (92 %).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>TEM images of negatively stained cells (a) and thin sectioned cells (b) of strain DSE10<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Bars, 0.5 μm (a) and 200 nm (b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSE10<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24411<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14375<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a deep-sea sediment sample collected from the Chagos–Laccadive ridge system (111060 S, 721310 E), Indian Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>