<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9488_nm.14633" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14633" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14633" rank="species">Acidisoma tundrae</organism><reference id="rid.9488"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Belova</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Detkova</surname><given-names>E.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaparullina</surname><given-names>E.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidisoma tundrae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Acidisoma sibiricum sp. nov., two acidophilic, psychrotolerant members of the Alphaproteobacteria from acidic northern wetlands</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2283</fpage><lpage>2290</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009209-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acidisoma tundrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acidisoma tundrae</em> (tun′drae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>tundrae</em> from the tundra, of the northern zone of Eurasia and North America).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus but with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.8–1.5 μm wide and 1.9–4.1 μm long.</s><s>Colony colour is white or ivory.</s><s>Able to utilize the following carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v): sorbose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, gluconate, lactate, pyruvate, galacturonic acid, yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone, asparagine, butyrate, glycerol, arabinose, mannose, glucose, trehalose, dulcitol, ethanol, sorbitol, xylose, fructose, malate, galactose and mannitol.</s><s>Unable to utilize acetate, propionate, capronate, formate, citrate, benzoate, succinate, methanol, butanol, glucuronic acid, alanine, leucine, maltose, raffinose, fumarate, lactose, oxalate, cellobiose, sucrose or aspartate.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing fucoidan and pectin, but not laminarin, pullulan, alginate, carboxymethylcellulose or chondroitin sulfate.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are present: acid phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM test).</s><s>Able to utilize the following nitrogen sources (0.05 %, w/v): ammonia, urea, Bacto yeast extract, histidine HCl, proline, alanine, methionine, glutamine and nitrate.</s><s>Contains phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown aminolipid as predominant polar lipids.</s><s>Phosphatidylserine, phosphatidic acid and several unknown polar lipids are present in minor amounts.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin and lincomycin, but susceptible to kanamycin, novobiocin, gentamicin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol and neomycin.</s><s>Capable of growth at pH 3.0–7.5 (optimum, pH 4.5–5.7) and at 2–30 °C (optimum, 15–22 °C).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 1.5 % (w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WM1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19999<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2488<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an acidic oligotrophic <em>Sphagnum</em>-dominated wetland in the Vorkuta region of northern Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>