<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2206_nm.2363" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2363" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2363" rank="species">Legionella jordanis</organism><reference id="rid.2206"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cherry</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorman</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Orrison</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilkinson</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKinney</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella jordanis: a new species of Legionella isolated from water and sewage.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>297</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7040449</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella jordanis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella jordanis</i> (jore.da'nis, L. gen. n. <i>Jordanis</i> of the Jordan river in Bloomington, Ind., where the organism was first isolated.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Legionella jordanis</i> is proposed as the name for the species represented by strains BL-540 and ABB-9.</s><s>The type strain of <i>L. jordanis</i> is BL-540 (ATCC 33623).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DFA tests of isolates with conjugates for recognized serogroups and species of <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>When BL-540 and ABB-9 cells were tested with the diagnostic dilutions of polyvalent and monovalent conjugates for the six species, including all six serogroups of <i>L. pneumophila</i> and both serogroups of <i>L. longbeachae</i> listed in Materials and Methods, only very slight cellular fluorescence was observed, with one exception.</s><s>The conjugate for <i>L. bozemanii</i> (WIGA) gave significant cellular staining (1 + to 3+), with visibly stained flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibody absorption studies with DFA conjugates.</s><s>The results of homologous and heterologous DFA staining tests with absorbed and unabsorbed conjugates for BL-540, ABB-9, and <i>L. bozemanii</i> (WIGA) are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The ABB-9 conjugate had a titer of 1,024 for both BL-540 and ABB-9 cells.</s><s>Against the BL-540 conjugate, the homologous antigen titer was 1,024, and against ABB-9 it was 512. <i>L. bozemanii</i> WIGA and GA-PH were the only other cultures among those tested that were stained appreciably by either conjugate.</s><s>The GA-PH strain (3) and the MI-15 strain (8) are presumed to be identical because they were isolated from the same patient and have the same characteristics.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When conjugates for BL-540 and ABB-9 were cross-absorbed and tested against their homologous and heterologous antigens, no cellular fluorescence was seen at the 1:4 dilutions (Table 1).</s><s>These results show that the two isolates were serologically identical, as determined by DFA tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The relationship of BL-540 and ABB-9 to <i>L. bozemanii</i> was explored by absorbing WIGA conjugate with BL-540 and BL-540 and ABB-9 conjugates with WIGA antigen.</s><s>These results indicate a partial relationship between WIGA and cultures of the new species (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>IFA with human sera.</s><s>Of 444 serum pairs from cases of suspected Legionnaires disease that were tested against multiple <i>Legionella antigens</i> in a seroprevalence survey, 5 showed evidence of specific antibody titers against the ABB-9 and BL-540 antigens (i.e., titers against <i>L. jordanis</i> that were fourfold or greater than those against any other antigen tested [H.</s><s>W.</s><s>Wilkinson, A.</s><s>L.</s><s>Reingold, B.</s><s>J.</s><s>Fikes, D.</s><s>L.</s><s>McGiboney, T.</s><s>A.</s><s>Thompson, C.</s><s>V.</s><s>Broome, and G.</s><s>W.</s><s>Gorman, manuscript in preparation]).</s><s>In all cases, titers against the two cultures of <i>L. jordanis</i> agreed within the acceptable twofold dilution factor, although there was a tendency for any discrepant titers to be one tube dilution factor higher against the ABB-9 antigen.</s><s>A greater than fourfold rise in titer (seroconversion) occurred for two cases within 25 days after onset of illness: one from 64 to 2,048 and the other from 64 to 8,192.</s><s>Two additional cases had both acute-phase (within 2 days) and convalescentphase (21 ± 1 day) titers that were 1,024, presumptive evidence of infection at an unknown time.</s><s>The remaining case showed a greater than fourfold decrease in IFA titer, from the first serum titer of 1,024 to the second one of 128, over a 2-month period.</s><s>The date of onset was unknown for the latter case.</s><s>The five sera came from four states: Florida, Indiana, Missouri, and Oklahoma.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological, staining, and physiological characteristics of the species.</s><s>Cultures of BL-540 and ABB-9 are thin, gram-negative rods consistent in size with members of <i>Legionella</i>, i.e., 0.3 to 0.9 μm wide by 2 to 20 μm long (6).</s><s>Motile by polar flagella, they are non-spore-forming, nonencapsulated, and non-acid-fast organisms.</s><s>When stained with Sudan black B, very few cells contained fat deposits.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cultures failed to grow on either blood agar or Trypticase soy agar but gave growth typical of legionellae on CYE agar slants and plates.</s><s>Colonies appeared about the third day of incubation and continued to increase in size for several days.</s><s>They were grey, with a smooth but textured surface (ground glass appearance), and raised, with an entire edge.</s><s>In Table 2, the important phenotypic characteristics of BL-540 and ABB-9 are compared with those of the six other species of <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>In addition, an esterase produced by cultures of <i>L. jordanis</i> readily hydrolyzed 4-methylumbelliferyl propionate and 4-methylumbelliferyl nonanoate to produce the intensely blue fluorescent 4-methylumbelliferone (25, 30).</s><s>Diacetylfluorescein was hydrolyzed, resulting in the production of a brownish-green color different from that seen in tests with other <i>Legionella</i> spp. (25).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase activity was not demonstrated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characterization of the cellular fatty acids by GLC-mass spectrometry.</s><s>Previous studies have established that all known species of <i>Legionella</i> characteristically contain relatively large amounts of branched-chain cellular fatty acids (14, 17, 22, 24).</s><s>The data in Table 3 show that the fatty acids of strains BL-540 and ABB-9 were qualitatively similar to those of other legionellae.</s><s>The single most abundant acid in each strain of the new species was a saturated, branched-chain, 15-carbon acid (a-15:0)-the methyl branch was at the <i>anteiso</i> (antipenultimate) carbon atom-and the second most abundant was an a-17:0 acid.</s><s>The next most abundant acids were a saturated, branched-chain, 16-carbon acid (i-16:0)-the methyl branch was at the iso (penultimate) carbon atom-a mono-unsaturated, 16-carbon, straight-chain acid (16:1), and a normal saturated, straight-chain, 16-carbon acid (16:0).</s><s>Thus, the overall composition of the fatty acids of the new species is quantitatively similar to the composition of the acids of <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffli</i>, <i>L. gormanii</i>, and <i>L. micdadei</i> but is distinct from the composition of the acids of <i>L. pneumophila</i>, which contains i-16:0 as the major acid (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA relatedness.</s><s>Legionella-like organisms received by our laboratory are first tested for DNA relatedness to the type strains of existing species.</s><s>Unlabeled DNA from BL-540, therefore, was tested against labeled DNAs from the six recognized Legionella species.</s><s>Relatedness of BL-540 to the other legionellae was between 4 and 20% when reactions were done at a 60°C incubation temperature and from 0 to 10% when reactions were done at the more stringent 75°C incubation temperature (Table 4).</s><s>These data indicated that BL-540 was a new species of <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>Because the phenotypic characteristics of ABB-9 were extremely similar to those of BL-540, DNA from ABB-9 was labeled and tested against BL-540 DNA.</s><s>The two strains were almost identical on the basis of relatedness at both 60 and 75°C, as well as on the basis of the lack of appreciable divergence within related sequences (Table 4).</s><s>ABB-9 was less than 10% related to DNAs from other <i>Legionella</i> species (Table 4).</s><s>Thus, BL-540 and ABB-9 belonged to the same new species. (Table 4).</s><s>Thus, BL-540 and ABB-9 belonged to the same new species.</s></p></content></protolog>