<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10091_nm.15043" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15043" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15043" rank="species">Basfia succiniciproducens</organism><reference id="rid.10091"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kuhnert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scholten</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haefner</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayor</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Basfia succiniciproducens gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Pasteurellaceae isolated from bovine rumen</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>44</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011809-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Basfia succiniciproducens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Basfia succiniciproducens</em> (suc.ci.ni.ci.pro.du′cens. N.L. n. <em>acidum succinicum</em> succinic acid; L. part. adj. <em>producens</em> producing; N.L. part. adj. <em>succiniciproducens</em> succinic acid producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows on blood agar under facultatively anaerobic conditions at 37 °C.</s><s>Capnophilic.</s><s>Colonies are 0.1–0.5 mm in diameter, shiny and greyish after 24 h.</s><s>Cells are coccoid to rod-shaped.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>Produces succinic acid under anaerobic conditions in the presence of a substrate such as glucose.</s><s>Glucose is fermented without production of gas.</s><s>In conventional test tube assays, acid is produced from dextrin, maltose and d-fructose, whereas no acid is produced from adonitol, d-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, melezitose, d-sorbitol and d-salicin.</s><s>Acid production from melibiose and d-rhamnose is variable.</s><s>On the Vitek2 GN and NH cards the following results are obtained.</s><s>Positive reactions for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>β</em>-galactopyranosidase, phosphorylcholine, d-mannitol, maltotriose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-malate, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, phosphatase and phenylphosphonate.</s><s>Negative reactions for adonitol, l-arabitol, Ala–Phe–Pro arylamidase, l-pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>γ</em>-glutamyl transferase, glutamyl arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-xylosidase, alanine arylamidase, l-proline arylamidase, lipase, palatinose, citrate, l-malate, urease, maltose, H<sub>2</sub>S, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, d-xylose, malonate, l-lactate alkalinization, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, starch (glycogen), succinate alkalinization, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-galactosaminidase, glycine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, l-histidine, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, Glu–Gly–Arg arylamidase, l-lysine arylamidase, pyruvate and l-glutamine.</s><s>Variable reactions were observed with cellobiose, 5-keto-d-gluconate, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, coumarate and Ellman's reagent.</s><s>No toxicity towards lymphoid bovine and human cells or fish cells, and no RTX toxin genes observed.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.5 mol%.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from bovine rumen as part of the normal flora.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JF4016<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22022<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 57335<sup>T</sup>) isolated from the rumen of a Simmental cow in Switzerland.</s></p></content></protolog>