<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6795_nm.10879" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10879" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6321" rank="species">Mycobacterium avium</organism><reference id="rid.6795"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thorel</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krichevsky</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lévy-Frébault</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical taxonomy of mycobactin-dependent mycobacteria, emended description of Mycobacterium avium, and description of Mycobacterium avium subsp. avium subsp. nov., Mycobacterium avium subsp. paratuberculosis subsp. nov., and Mycobacterium avium subsp. silvaticum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>254</fpage><lpage>260</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-254</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397193</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Mycobacterium avium</i> Chester 1901.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are short to long rods with no cord formation. Colonies may be smooth or rough. The colony type may change after first isolation from pathological material through subsequent subcultures. Most strains are nonphotochromogenic and may become yellow on aging. However, some strains are scotochromogenic and have bright yellow pigment. Growth occurs after more than 7 days at 37°C, which is the optimal temperature , and may require mycobactin and/or special media other than egg-based media. Growth may be stimulated by pH 5.5 or pyruvate. Strains do not produce niacin, peroxidase, nitrate reductase, urease, arylsulfatase, penicillinase, or β-glucosidase and do not hydrolyze Tween 80 in 10 days. Strains produce small amounts of thermoresistant catalase. All strains have the same mycolic acid pattern, namely, mycolate I (α-mycolate), mycolate IV (keto-mycolate), and mycolate VI (dicarboxymycolate) (12, 26). All strains are resistant to thiophene-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide and isoniazid. Strains may be susceptible to <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoate, ethambutol, pyrazinamide, rifampin, and streptomycin. Most strains are susceptible to ansamycin. The validity of the species has been demonstrated by the results of numerous DNA-DNA hybridization studies and by determinations of the thermal stabilities of the hybrids (1, 2, 23, 31, 52, 53). The type strain is strain ATCC 25291. The guanine-plus-cytosine content is 70 mol% (3). The species includes both potential and obligate parasites and is divided into subspecies on the basis of pathogenicity and host range.</s></p></content></protolog>