<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1381_nm.10809" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10809" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5411" rank="species">Lactobacillus paracasei</organism><reference id="rid.1381"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zanoni</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deoxyribonucleic acid homology studies of Lactobacillus casei, Lactobacillus paracasei sp. nov., subsp. paracasei and subsp. tolerans, and Lactobacillus rhamnosus sp. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>108</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-105</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus paracasei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus paracasei</i> (pa.ra.ca´se.i. Gr.prep. <i>para</i>, resembling; L.gen.n. <i>casei</i>, a specific epithet; M.L.adj. <i>paracasei</i>, resembling <i>L . casei</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped (ca. 0.8 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 4.0 μm), often with square ends, and occur singly or in chains.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Grows at 10 and 40°C; some strains grow at 5 and 45°C.</s><s>Facultatively heterofermentative.</s><s>L-(+)-Lactic acid is produced; a few strains produce inactive lactic acid due to the activity of L-lactic acid racemase.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, maltose, mannitol, and D-mannose, melezitose, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, D-tagatose, and trehalose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from β-gentiobiose, gluconate, lactose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, and D-turanose.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from adonitol, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, dulcitol, D-fucose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, ribitol, L-sorbose, and starch.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, L-arabitol, erythritol, L-fucose, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, α-methyl-mannoside, β-methyl-xyloside, rhamnose, xylitol, D-xylose, and L-xylose.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>Murein type Lys-D-Asp.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 45 to 47 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from dairy products, sewage, silage, humans, and clinical sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 151.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the subspecies.</s><s>The type strain does not grow at 45°C.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from β-gentiobiose, gluconate, lactose, and sucrose; acid is not produced from D-arabinose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, α-methyl- D-glucoside, sorbitol, and L-sorbose.</s></p></content></protolog>