<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6990_nm.8316" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8316" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8316" rank="species">Runella zeae</organism><reference id="rid.6990"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chelius</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henn</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Triplett</surname><given-names>E.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Runella zeae sp. nov., a novel gram-negative bacterium from the stems of surface-sterilized Zea mays</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2061</fpage><lpage>2063</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02203-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508869</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Runella zeae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Runella zeae</i> (ze'ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>Zeae</i> of <i>Zea</i>, named because the organism was isolated from maize, <i>Zea mays</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most of the phenotypic data presented below were first published in Chelius &#x0026; Triplett (2000).</s><s>Cells are Gramnegative, straight to slightly bent rods that form chains of irregular shapes.</s><s>Colonies are round, smooth and salmon in colour when grown on R2A at 28 °C.</s><s>This strain ferments, and produces acid from, glucose and sucrose.</s><s>In contrast with Runella slithyformis, no acid produced from ribose.</s><s>Weakly catalase-positive and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15-37 °C and highest NaCl concentration tolerated is less than 1.5%.</s><s>This strain will grow on peptone water and weakly on Ayer's agar.</s><s>It will not grow on litmus milk.</s><s>This strain will grow on the following sole sources of carbon: acetate, amidon, fumarate, D-lyxose, malate, malonate, sucrose, tartrate, erythritol, D- and L-arabinose, β-methylxyloside, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, mannose, rhamnose, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetyμglucosamine, amygdaline, arbutine, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-tagatose and D- and L-fucose.</s><s>This strain grew weakly on dulcitol, inositol, 5-ketogluconate, sorbitol and sorbose.</s><s>This strain did not grow on D- and L-arabitol, glycerol, mannitol, methanol or formate.</s><s>This strain cannot hydrolyse agar, cellulose or starch.</s><s>In contrast to <i>R. slithyformis</i>, this strain will not grow on D-arabitol, L-arabitol, glycerol or mannitol.</s><s>Unlike <i>R. slithyformis</i>, this strain will grow on glycogen.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>This strain is resistant to ampicillin (25 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>), kanamycin (50 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>) and spectinomycin (10 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>) but sensitive to rifampicin (25 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>) and tetracycline (10 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>).</s><s>Unlike <i>R. slithyformis</i>, this strain is also sensitive to chloramphenicol (25 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>), streptomycin (10 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>) and trimethoprim (25 μg ml<sub>-1</sub>).</s><s>The level of DNA-DNA homology between NS12<sup>T</sup> and <i>R. slithyformis</i> was 19%.</s><s>The principal fatty acids are 36.9% 15:0 iso 2-OH/16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 17.8% 16:1<i>ω</i>5<i>c</i> and 16.1% 15:0 iso.</s><s>The G+C content is 49 mol%.</s><s>This strain was isolated from surface-sterilized <i>Zea mays</i> (cv. Mo17) stem and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC BAA-293<sup>T</sup> and the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection as LMG 21438<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>