<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4859_nm.1339" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1339" rank="genus">Sinorhizobium</organism><reference id="rid.4859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maestrojuan</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neyra</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dreyfus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomy of Rhizobia: emendation of the genus Sinorhizobium and description of Sinorhizobium meliloti comb. nov., Sinorhizobium saheli sp. nov., and Sinorhizobium teranga sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>715</fpage><lpage>733</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Sinorhizobium</i> (Chen, Yan and Li 1988)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Rods that are 0.5 to 1 by 1.2 to 3 μm. Commonly pleiomorphic under adverse growth conditions. Cells usually contain poly-P-hydroxybutyrate granules which are refractile as determined by phase-contrast microscopy. Non-spore forming. Gram negative. Motile by means of one polar or subpolar flagellum or two to six peritrichous flagella. Fimbriae occur in a few strains. Aerobic, having a respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor. Often able to grow well under oxygen tensions less than 1.0 Pa. Optimum temperature, 25 to 33°C. Optimum pH, 6 to 7. Colonies are circular, convex, semitranslucent, raised, and mucilaginous and usually are 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 3 to 5 days on yeast-mannitol-mineral salts agar. Pronounced turbidity develops after 2 to 3 days in agitated broth media. Chemoorganotrophic, utilizing a wide range of carbohydrates (but not cellulose and starch) and salts of organic acids as carbon sources (5) (Table 2). Cells produce an acid reaction in mineral salts media containing several carbohydrates. Peptone is poorly utilized. 3-Ketolactose is not produced from lactose. Growth on carbohydrate media is usually accompanied by copious extracellular polysaccharide slime production. The organisms are typically able to invade the root hairs of temperate zone and tropical zone leguminous plants (family Leguminosae) and incite the production of root nodules, where the bacteria occur as intracellular symbionts. All strains exhibit host range activities (“host specificity”). The bacteria are present in root nodules as pleiomorphic forms (bacteriods) which are normally involved in fixing atmospheric nitrogen into a combined form (ammonia) that can be utilized by the host plant. The G+C content of the DNA is 57 to 66 mol% (as determined by the melting method). The type species is Sinorhizobium fredii. At the molecular level the genus can be recognized by the sequence of the 16s rRNA genes.</s></p></content></protolog>