<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1796_nm.3842" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3842" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3842" rank="species">Helicobacter felis</organism><reference id="rid.1796"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tordoff</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fraser</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Rourke</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferrero</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny of Helicobacter felis sp. nov., Helicobacter mustelae, and related bacteria.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>38</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-31</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1704791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter felis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter felis</i> (fe' lis. L. gen. n. <i>felis</i>, of a cat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rigid, spiral-shaped, gram-negative cells that are 0.4 μm wide and 5 to 7.5 μm long and have five to seven spirals per cell.</s><s>Spherical forms (diameter, 2 to 4 μm) are present in older cultures.</s><s>No endospores are produced.</s><s>Cells are motile with a rapid corkscrewlike motion.</s><s>Cells have tufts of 10 to 17 polar sheathed flagella (thickness, 25 nm) that are positioned slightly off center at the end of the cell.</s><s>Cells are surrounded by periplasmic fibers which appear as concentric helical ridges, either in pairs, threes, or singly on the surfaces of the cells.</s><s>Microaerophilic, but can grow anaerobically.</s><s>Grows at 37 and 42°C but not at 25°C.</s><s>One strain does not grow at 42°C.</s><s>Nutritionally fastidious, growing only on media enriched with blood or serum.</s><s>Asaccharolytic.</s><s>No acid is produced from maltose, sucrose, lactose, fructose, xylose, sorbitol, arabinose, raffinose, glucose, and galactose.</s><s>Urease, oxidase, and catalase positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine aminopeptidase, leucine aminopeptidase, and γ-glutamyl transpeptidase activities are detected.</s><s>Most strains have histidine and leucine aminopeptidase activity.</s><s>No production of N-acetylglucosaminidase , α-glucosidase , α-arabinosidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, indoxylacetate, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid amylamidase, tyrosine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase, glycine aminopeptidase, and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub> are not produced.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 1% glycine and 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to cephalothin, ampicillin, erythromycin, metronidazole, and bismuth compounds, but resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>Isolated from the gastric mucosa of cats and dogs.</s><s>Strain CS1 (= ATCC 49179), which was isolated from the gastric mucosa of a cat, is the type strain; its G+C content is 42.5 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>