<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7159_nm.5273" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5273" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5273" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus sciuri carnaticus</organism><reference id="rid.7159"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ballard</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Webster</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubner</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tomasz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Couto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sloan</surname><given-names>G.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dehart</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Lencastre</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sanches</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heath</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leblanc</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ljungh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ribotype delineation and description of Staphylococcus sciuri subspecies and their potential as reservoirs of methicillin resistance and staphylolytic enzyme genes.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>323</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103615</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus sciuri</i> subsp. <i>carnaticus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus sciuri</i> subsp. <i>carnaticus</i> (car.na'ti.cus. Med. L. adj. <i>carnaticus</i>, pertaining to meat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics of 14 strains isolated in 1991 and 1992.</s><s>Colonies grow to 5 5 2 mm in diameter on P agar and to 9 ± 1 mm in diameter on TSA.</s><s>Many strains (50% of the strains) produce small (diameter, 3 to 4 mm) colonies on P agar.</s><s>Growth in the anaerobic portion of semisolid thioglycolate medium ranges from no detectable growth to weak, delayed growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperatures are 35°C on P agar and 35 to 40°C on TSA.</s><s>Growth is absent or very poor at 45°C.</s><s>Culture growth produces hemolysis (greening) of bovine and horse blood.</s><s>All strains produce acid aerobically from D-xylose, D-fucose, D-trehalose, and maltose.</s><s>Acid production from maltose is weak to moderate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-melezitose and α-L-rhamnose.</s><s>Other characteristics of <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>carnaticus</i> that are uniformly positive or negative for the species are listed above.</s><s>The variable characteristics for this subspecies are listed in Table 3.</s><s>The major API STAPH-IDENT profiles are 4710 (50%), 4000 (21%), and 5710 (21%); the major STAPH Trac profiles are 6736550 (36%) and 6336550 (29%).</s><s>The major ribotype pattern type is dd 0791 (63%).</s><s>Five different ribotype patterns have been described (Fig. 1).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36 mol%.</s><s>This subspecies is found mainly living on bovine (artiodactyl) hosts and their meat products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>carnaticus</i> DD 791 (= ATCC 700058), which was isolated from a sliced veal leg.</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies described above and, in addition, has the properties listed below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spherical cells (diameter, 0.7 to 1.2 μm) occur singly, in pairs, and in tetrads.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular P-agar colonies are 5 to 6 mm in diameter, have moderately undulate edges, have raised edges with depressed centers, are smooth with glistening surfaces, are translucent to opaque, and have sectors that are unpigmented to slightly cream tinted.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are 8 to 9 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Delayed weak growth occurs in the anaerobic portion of thioglycolate medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Partial hemolysis (greening) of bovine and horse blood occurs.</s><s>No hemolysis of sheep blood occurs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate alkaline phosphatase activity and weak staphylolytic enzyme activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Clumping factor and protein A are not detected by latex agglutination.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate amounts of acid are produced aerobically from D-xylose, D-sorbitol, D-mannose, α-lactose, salicin, D-mannitol, D-tehalose, and maltose.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-cellobiose and L-arabinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to erythromycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type dd 0791 ribotype pattern.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is L-Lys-L-Ala-Gly,; the teichoic acid is polyglycerolphosphate-N-acetylglucosamine( polyglycerolphosphate substituted by N-acetylglucosamine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>