<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7285_nm.2971" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2971" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2971" rank="species">Vibrio halioticoli</organism><reference id="rid.7285"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sugimura</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohtsuka</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio halioticoli sp. nov., a non-motile alginolytic marine bacterium isolated from the gut of the abalone Haliotis discus hannai.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>573</fpage><lpage>580</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-573</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731299</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio halioticoli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio halioticoli</i> (hal.i.o.ti'co.li. M.L. n. <i>Haliotis</i> systematic name of an abalone genus. Gr. n. colon gut. M.L. gen. n. <i>halioticoli</i> the <i>Haliotis</i> gut, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, non-mo tile, non-flagellated rod.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, with rounded ends, and are 0.6-0.4 μm in diameter and 1.7-2.0 μm long when the organism is grown in ZoBell 2216E broth, but cells are spherical shaped 0.7-1.0 μm in diameter and 1.0-1.6 μm long when the organism is grown in ZoBell 2216E broth containing alginate; the cells occur singly in the broth, or in irregular clusters, or chained in the broth containing alginate.</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solidified media and/or in liquid media.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are beige, circular, smooth and convex with entire edge.</s><s>Sodium ion is essential for growth.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph which grows at 15-30°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 40°C.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose; reduces nitrate; hydrolyses alginate; indole-, oxidase- and catalase-positive; assimilates D-fructose, maltose, D-glucosamine, N-acetylglucosamine, D-mannitol, fumarate, succinate, glycerol, D-glucose and alginate.</s><s>Nonmotile; does not produce gas from glucose; does not produce acetoin; negative for lysine decarboxylase, arginine dehydrolase and ornithine decarboxylase; no luminescence or pigmentation; does not require organic growth factors; does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin, chitin, Tween 80 or agar; does not accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate; does not assimilate D-mannose, sucrose, D-gluconate, D-sorbitol, citrate, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, DL-malate, α-ketoglutarate, D-galactose, cellobiose, melibiose, lactose, D-glucronate, D-xylose, trehalose, putrescine, δ-aminovarate, 𝛾-aminobutyrate, acetate, pyruvate, L-tyrosine, propionate, aconitate, L-glutamate or L-arabinose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41.6-43.1 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the gut of the abalone <i>Huliotis discus hannai</i>.</s><s>The type strain is IAM 14596<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>