<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11598_nm.18636" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18636" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18636" rank="species">Thalassospira xianhensis</organism><reference id="rid.11598"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassospira xianhensis sp. nov., a polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-degrading marine bacterium</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1125</fpage><lpage>1129</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013201-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666802</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassospira xianhensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassospira xianhensis</em> (xian.hen′sis. <em>xianhensis</em> pertaining to Xianhe of Shangdong Province, China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative-staining, curved to spiral rods (0.3–0.6×1.0–1.6 μm).</s><s>Colonies on 5 % SSDMY agar are cream–yellow, circular, smooth, opaque and approximately 1.5–2 mm in diameter after incubation at 30 °C for 2 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 °C and 42 °C (optimum 30 °C), with saline concentrations between 0.1 and 17.0 % (optimum 3.0–6.0 %) and at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum pH 7.2).</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase and urease and hydrolysis of Tween 80, but negative for DNase and hydrolysis of starch.</s><s>Facultative anaerobic growth with nitrate and nitrite as electron acceptors.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, cephalothin, clarithromycin, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin and vancomycin, but resistant to ceftriaxone, cefotaxime, ciprofloxacin, gentamicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Among the 95 carbon sources in the Biolog system, the following are utilized: adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, turanose, xylitol, pyruvate methyl ester, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, urocanic acid and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose, mannose and sucrose, but not from lactose or arabinose.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is Q-9.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, with smaller amounts of C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.2±1.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P-4<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6849<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14850<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from a saline soil contaminated by crude oil, collected from Xianhe, Shangdong Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>