<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2309_nm.9743" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9743" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9743" rank="species">Sphingomonas abaci</organism><reference id="rid.2309"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hauser</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of two novel species, Sphingomonas abaci sp. nov. and Sphingomonas panni sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2565</fpage><lpage>2569</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63872-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280528</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas abaci</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas abaci</em> (a′ba.ci. L. gen. n. <em>abaci</em> of/from a table, referring to the fact that the type strain was isolated from a treatment table).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative (by staining and in the KOH test), non-spore-forming rods with rounded poles and are 0·4–0·5×1·5–3·0 μm in size.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs (rarely).</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive; growth occurs under aerobic and microaerobic conditions but not under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>No motility is observed under the light microscope.</s><s>Good growth occurs on PYE agar, TSA, 1 % (w/v) NaCl and at temperatures between 15 and 28 °C on PYE agar.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar or at 4, 37 and 42 °C on PYE agar.</s><s>On PYE agar, orange, shiny, circular, leathery, dry colonies approximately 0·5 mm in diameter form within 48 h.</s><s>After 5 days incubation, colonies on PYE agar reach diameters of approximately 2 mm.</s><s>The quinone system of the type strain consists of Q-10 (86 %), Q-9 (9 %) and Q-8 (5 %).</s><s>The polyamine pattern primarily consists of <em>sym</em>-homospermidine [48·1 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>] with moderate amounts of spermidine [12·0 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>].</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and sphingoglycolipid.</s><s>Additionally, moderate amounts of phosphatidylcholine, three unidentified glycolipids and an unknown polar lipid, small amounts of phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine and three unknown phospholipids are present.</s><s>The fatty acids comprise C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (64·8 %), 2-OH C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (12·9 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (12·4 %), summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 2-OH C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso) (8·3 %) and C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1·6 %).</s><s>Acid production from sugars, carbon-source utilization and hydrolysis of chromogenic substrates are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, C42<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21978<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15867<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the treatment table in the Medical Clinic for Small Animals, University for Veterinary Medicine, Vienna, Austria.</s></p></content></protolog>