<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10764_nm.17859" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17859" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17859" rank="species">Brevibacterium sandarakinum</organism><reference id="rid.10764"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schäfer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium sandarakinum sp. nov., isolated from a wall of an indoor environment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>909</fpage><lpage>913</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014100-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661519</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium sandarakinum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium sandarakinum</em> (san.da.ra.ki′num. N.L. neut. adj. <em>sandarakinum</em> from Gr. neut. adj. <em>sandarakinos</em> of light-red colour).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>On nutrient agar, no clear rod–coccus cycle is observed.</s><s>After 12 h of growth, cells are coccoid and occur singly (0.8 and 1.2 μm in diameter, respectively); after 24 h, cells are coccoid to oval.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 3 days of incubation on nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed between 4 °C (weak) and 36 °C (but not above that temperature), at initial pH between 5.5 and 12.5 (optimum pH 7.5–9.5) and at 1–10 % NaCl.</s><s>The quinone system consists of the major compound menaquinone MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), moderate amounts of MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and minor amounts of MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major lipids diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified glycolipid, moderate amounts of an unidentified aminophospholipid and minor amounts of three unidentified phospholipids and an unidentified polar lipid.</s><s>The characteristic cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The polyamine pattern shows the major compound putrescine and cadaverine.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-branched fatty acids.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, ribose, d-sorbitol, acetate (weak), propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate (weak), glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate and histidine are utilized as sole sources of carbon. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, maltose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-maltitol, d-mannitol, putrescine, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, itaconate, 2-oxoglutarate and mesaconate are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 01-Je-003<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22082<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7649<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in Jena, Germany, from a sample from the wall of a house colonized with moulds.</s></p></content></protolog>