<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1351_nm.5407" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5407" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5407" rank="species">Lactobacillus oris</organism><reference id="rid.1351"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus oris sp. nov. from human oral cavity.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>118</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-116</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus oris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus oris</i> (or'is. L. gen. n. <i>oris</i>, of the mouth). Cells are rod shaped (0.8 to 1.0 by 2 to 4 μm) and occur singly or in pairs or short chains. Colonies are small, raised, semirough, or rough. Gram positive. Nonmotile. Grows at 30 and 40°C but not at 22 or 48°C; some strains grow at 45°C. Facultatively anaerobic. Catalase negative. Heterofermentative, producing D and L-lactic acid. Gas is produced from glucose. Acid is produced from amygdalin, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, D-fructose, D-galactose, β-gentiobiose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose, and D-xylose. Acid is not produced from L-arabitol, D-arabinose, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, D-lyxose, mannitol, melezitose, a-methyl-D-mannoside, rhamnose, L-sorbose, sorbitol, starch, D-tagatose, L-xylose, and xylitol. Some strains produce acid from arbutin, cellobiose, gluconate, inulin, D-mannose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl xyloside, N-acetylglucosamine, salicin, trehalose, and D-turanose. Some strains hydrolyze esculin and hippurate. Some strains produce urease. Arginine dihydrolase negative. H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced. Grows in 4% NaCl. Nitrate is not reduced. G+C content of DNA ranges from 49.3 to 50.7 mol% (<sub>m</sub>,). Isolated from human saliva.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCDO 2160<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from gluconate; acid is not produced from arbutin, cellobiose, inulin, D-mannose, <i>a</i>-methyl-D-glucoside, <i>β</i>-methyl xyloside, trehalose, and D-turanose.</s><s>The type strain does not hydrolyze esculin.</s></p></content></protolog>