<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5993_nm.8543" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8543" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8543" rank="species">Chryseobacterium formosense</organism><reference id="rid.5993"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium formosense sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of Lactuca sativa L. (garden lettuce)</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>423</fpage><lpage>426</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63331-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653912</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium formosense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium formosense</em> [for.mo.sen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>formosense</em> pertaining to Formosa (Taiwan)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (about 2 μm in length and 1 μm wide).</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-positive, with good growth after 48 h on trypticase soy agar, brain heart infusion agar and nutrient agar at 25–32 °C, but unable to grow on MacConkey's agar.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges; they become mucoid and cannot be identified as single entities after prolonged incubation.</s><s>Yellow pigmentation is non-diffusible, non-fluorescent of flexirubin type.</s><s>Unable to grow at 5 °C or above 37 °C.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Positive for indole and acetoin production, gelatinase and cytochrome oxidase activity, but negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and oxidation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: dextrin, d-arabitol, lactulose, acetic acid, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, citric acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-pyroglutamic acid (all weakly positive), cellobiose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose, monomethyl succinate, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glucose 1-phophate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following are not utilized as sole carbon sources: methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, propionic acid, cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-psicose, methylpyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, hydroxyproline, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Positive enzyme activities are seen for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for myristate lipase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-H3-2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 49271<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108367<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of <em>Lactuca sativa</em> L. (garden lettuce).</s></p></content></protolog>