<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5219_nm.6577" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6577" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6577" rank="species">Catenuloplanes japonicus</organism><reference id="rid.5219"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catenuloplanes japonicus gen. nov., sp. nov., nom. rev., a genus of the order Actinomycetales.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>805</fpage><lpage>812</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Catenuloplanes japonicus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Catenuloplanes japonicus</i> (ja.pon'i-cus. M. L. neut. adj. <i>japonicus</i>, pertaining to Japan)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is the same as the description of the genus.</s><s>Spores are motile when they are suspended in a nutrient broth and are peritrichous.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Good growth occurs at temperatures between 21 and 28°C.</s><s>The organism grows well on yeast extract-malt extract agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, gelatin agar, starch agar, Czapek-sucrose agar, glucose- aspargine agar, and casein agar.</s><s>In general, the vegetative mycelia of the strains are pale orange to orange yellow, and the aerial mycelia are white to pale yellow.</s><s>They produce a pale yellowish soluble pigment on Czapek-sucrose agar, glucose-aspargine agar, and calcium malate agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, succinate, L-arabinose cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, α-methyl- D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose are utilized as carbon sources, but benzoate, citrate, mucate, oxalate, propionate, dextrin, phenol, ribitol, galactitol, erythritol, sorbitol, and L-sorbose are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from ribitol, galactitol, erythritol, sorbitol, and L-sorbose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contains D-glutamate, D- and L-serine, glycine, D-alanine, and L-lysine (molar ratio, ca. 1:1:1:1:1) and a small amount of L-ornithine.</s><s>The cell wall type is type VI as defined by Lechevalier and Lechevalier (16).</s><s>Mannose, xylose, and glucose are present as cell wall sugars.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are Octadecenoic acid (18:1) and hexadecanoic acid (16:0) or anteiso-heptadecanoic acid (a17:0).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71.0 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>); in addition, small amounts of MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) are also present.</s><s>The diagnostic phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylcholine, and phosphatidylethanolamine (type PIII).</s><s>Habitat: soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain N381-16, which has been deposited in the IFO as strain IFO 14176 and in the ATCC as strain ATCC 31637.</s></p></content></protolog>