<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7506_nm.4828" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4828" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4828" rank="species">Acholeplasma parvum</organism><reference id="rid.7506"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Atobe</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ogata</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acholeplasma parvum, a new species from horses.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>344</fpage><lpage>349</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-344</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acholeplasma parvum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acholeplasma parvum</i> (par'vum. L. adj. <i>parvus</i> small, intended to refer to the poor biochemical activities and tiny colonies of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and cultural characteristics.</s><s>Colonies of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> on media with and without horse serum after 5 days at 30 and 37°C are shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>Colonies on serum-supplemented and serum-free media at 30°C exhibited a "fried-egg" shape, although colonies on serum-free medium were usually smaller; the colonies on media incubated at 37°C were of the rough type and had no peripheral zone.</s><s>Strain H23M<sup>T</sup> produced only slight turbidity in liquid medium.</s><s>When they were examined by electron microscopy, cells from a 24-h-old broth culture of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> exhibited coccobacillary forms (Fig. 2).</s><s>The cells were bounded by a single, triple-layered plasma membrane.</s><s>A serum-free broth culture of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> containing 7 x 10<sup>7</sup> CFU/ml was passed through filters with pore diameters of 800, 450, 220, and 100 nm, yielding 2 x 10<sup>7</sup>, 5 x 10<sup>6</sup>, 3.5 x 10<sup>6</sup>, and 0 CFU/ml, respectively.</s><s>Similar results were obtained with strain H7M.</s><s>When each strain was subcultured serially five times on a medium without bacterial inhibitors, there was no colonial or cultural evidence of reversion to bacterial forms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>All of the isolates grew on the basal medium, and they grew almost equally well on all of the media tested.</s><s>They did not exhibit any growth response to increasing cholesterol concentrations in the medium.</s><s>All of the isolates were resistant to 1.5% digitonin and 20% sodium polyanethol sulfonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth conditions.</s><s>On media with and without serum, all of the isolates grew almost as rapidly at 22 as at 37°C.</s><s>They failed to grow at 45°C.</s><s>All of the isolates grew under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical properties.</s><s>None of the four strains fermented carbohydrates (including glucose, salicin, and esculin), hydrolyzed arginine or urea, or reduced tetrazolium chloride or methylene blue.</s><s>All four strains reduced potassium tellurite and weakly hemolyzed horse, sheep, and guinea pig erythrocytes.</s><s>After 14 days of incubation in the medium containing glucose, the pH did not differ by more than 0.5 U from the pH of the inoculated control in medium without glucose.</s><s>In this test, the growth of the strains was confirmed by plate counts, and usually 10<sup>7</sup> to 10<sup>8</sup> CFU/ml was present in a 5-day-old culture.</s><s>No strain produced any appreciable pH change in the glucose-containing medium when the inoculum was increased 100-fold or when the organism was serially subcultured up to 15 times in the glucose-containing medium.</s><s>The type strains of eight currently recognized <i>Acholeplasma</i> species fermented glucose in the same test medium.</s><s>In addition, the utilization of glucose was examined by determining hexokinase activity, which demonstrates the presence of the glycolytic pathway.</s><s>The type strains of two glucose-fermenting <i>Acholeplasma</i> species, <i>A. laidlawii</i> and <i>A. granularum</i>, showed high hexokinase activity and phosphorylation of glucose, whereas the glucose-nonfermenting <i>M. arthritidis</i> and <i>M. bovigenitalium</i> strains tested had only low activities; the hexokinase activity of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> was almost the same as the activities of the latter group (Table 1 and Fig. 3).</s><s>Our results indicated that strain H23M<sup>T</sup> does not ferment glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Strain H23M<sup>T</sup> and the type strains of <i>A. axanthum</i>, <i>A. modicum</i>, <i>A. equifetale</i>, and <i>A. hippikon</i> failed to produce carotenoid pigments, as determined by the method described above.</s><s>The optical densities at 438 nm of the carotenoid pigments of <i>A. laidlawii</i>, <i>A. granularum</i>, and <i>A. oculi</i> were 57.3 x 10<sup>-3</sup>, 36.9 x 10<sup>-3</sup> and 6.8 x 10<sup>-3</sup> per mg of protein, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptone requirement.</s><s>The isolates grew best in Phytone- and Soytone-containing media, although the <i>Acholeplasma</i> type strains grew equally well in all of the peptone-containing media tested.</s><s>With strain H23M<sup>T</sup>, the number of CFU obtained per milliliter from cultures grown in the Phytone- and Soytone-containing media were usually 3 logs higher than the values obtained with the other peptone-containing media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electrophoretic patterns of cell proteins.</s><s>The electrophoretic pattern of the cell proteins of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> differed from the patterns of the type strains of <i>Acholeplasma</i> species (Fig. 4).</s><s>Furthermore, the patterns of the type strains of the <i>Acholeplasma</i> species were distinct from one another.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Deoxyribonucleic acid base composition.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of strain H23M<sup>T</sup> was 29.1 mol%, as determined by the thermal melting point method, whereas the values obtained for <i>A. luidlawii</i> PG8<sup>T</sup> and <i>A. granularum</i> BTS39<sup>T</sup> were 30.4 and 29.8 mol%, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological properties.</s><s>The four strains isolated from horses and the type strains of the <i>Acholeplasma</i> species were examined for antigenic relationships by reciprocal growth inhibition tests.</s><s>None of the isolates showed a zone of growth inhibition around disks of antisera against the type strains of <i>A. laidlawii</i>, A<i>. granularum</i>, <i>A. axanthum</i>, <i>A. modicum</i>, <i>A. oculi</i>, <i>A. equifetale</i>, <i>A. hippikon</i>, and <i>A. morum</i>, and antiserum against strain H23M<sup>T</sup> inhibited only the four new isolates.</s><s>However, there was slight inhibition of both <i>A. modicum</i> and <i>A. morum</i> by <i>A. hippikon</i> antiserum and of <i>A. equifetale</i> by both <i>A. modicum</i> and <i>A. ocidi</i> antisera.</s><s>In each of these instances, the zone of inhibition was less than one-half the size of the zone produced by the homologous antiserum.</s><s>Stain H23M<sup>T</sup> also differed from the type strains of the <i>Acholeplasma</i> species when it was tested by the indirect immunofluorescence method (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain H23M is the type strain of <i>A. parvum</i>, and a culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 29892.</s></p></content></protolog>