<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7399_nm.1359" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1359" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1359" rank="species">Bartonella alsatica</organism><reference id="rid.7399"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heller</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kubina</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mariet</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Delacour</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dehio</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lamarque</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasten</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boulouis</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chomel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Piémont</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bartonella alsatica sp. nov., a new Bartonella species isolated from the blood of wild rabbits.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>283</fpage><lpage>288</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-283</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028274</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bartonella alsatica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bartonella alsatica</i> (al.sa'ti.ca. L. adj. <i>alsaticus</i> from Alsace, the region in the eastern part of France near the Rhine river where the wild rabbits were trapped and where the strains were isolated and identified)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown on blood agar appeared after 10 d as small, white, smooth, regular colonies (diameter of about 1 mm).</s><s>Electron microscopic examination showed small bacilli without flagella and with a size of approximately 1-2 μm in length by 0.5-0.8 μm in width. <i>B. alsatica</i> is a Gram-negative rod, aerobic, oxidase-negative.</s><s>It grows best on blood-enriched media in a moist atmosphere containing 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The three strains tested were all catalase-negative, produced negative Voges-Proskauer reaction, had negative pyrazinamidase and urease activities and did not acidify trehalose.</s><s>They did not hydrolyse bis-<i>p</i>-nitrophenylphosphate or <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, and had amino acid arylamidase activity with the following amino acids: leucine, methionine, lysine (alkaline as well as acid), glycine, proline, arginine and tryptophan.</s><s>They had glycylglycylarylamidase and trypsin-like activity but no pyrrolidonylarylamidase activity.</s><s>The new species is distinguished from the other <i>Bartonella</i> species by its 16s rRNA gene sequence and by the whole DNA hybridization.</s><s>The type strain is IBS 382<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from the blood of a wild rabbit and deposited in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur under the number CIP 105477<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Its G + C DNA content is 37 mol% (as determined by the capillary electrophoresis method).</s><s>Its 16s rRNA gene sequence has been deposited in the EMBL database under the number AJ002139.</s></p></content></protolog>