<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3878_nm.9497" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9497" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9497" rank="species">Staphylococcus pseudintermedius</organism><reference id="rid.3878"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Graef</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dawyndt</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Decostere</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus pseudintermedius sp. nov., a coagulase-positive species from animals</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1569</fpage><lpage>1573</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63413-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Staphylococcus pseudintermedius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Staphylococcus pseudintermedius</em> [Gr. adj. <em>pseudes</em> or <em>pseudos</em> false; L. masc. adj. <em>intermedius</em> intermediate, and also a specific epithet; N.L. masc. adj. <em>pseudintermedius</em> a false (<em>Staphylococcus</em>) <em>intermedius</em>, because of the high phenotypic similarity to <em>S. intermedius</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Consists of Gram-positive cocci predominantly arranged in groups.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia sheep blood agar are non-pigmented and surrounded by double zone haemolysis.</s><s>The outer band, which is incompletely haemolytic, turns into complete haemolysis after being put at 4 °C (hot–cold haemolysis), and is typical of staphylococcal <em>β</em>-haemolysin (a sphingomyelinase).</s><s>The strains are catalase-positive and coagulate rabbit plasma, but they are clumping-factor-negative in the so-called slide or rapid coagulase test.</s><s>A strong DNase is produced.</s><s>Positive in tests for acetoin, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, urease, nitrate reduction, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and ONPG (<em>β</em>-galactosidase).</s><s>Does not produce <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Susceptible to 8 μg acriflavine ml<sup>−1</sup> and to novobiocin.</s><s>Resistant to deferoxamine.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol (weakly and delayed), ribose, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, mannitol (weakly and delayed), <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose and d-turanose (weakly and delayed).</s><s>No acid is produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-xyloside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 22219<sup>T</sup> (=ON 86<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49543<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from lesions in different animal host species, but the habitat and pathogenic activity are unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>