<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6281_nm.3786" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3786" rank="genus">Campylobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6281"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rossau</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tytgat</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revision of Campylobacter, Helicobacter, and Wolinella taxonomy: emendation of generic descriptions and proposal of Arcobacter gen. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>88</fpage><lpage>103</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1704793</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Campylobacter</i> Sebald and Veron 1963.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Slender, spirally curved, gram-negative rods that are 0.2 to 0.5 μm wide and 0.5 to 5 μm long. The rods may have one or more spirals and can be as long as 8 μm. They also appear to be S shaped and gull winged when two cells form short chains. Nonsporeforming. Cells in old cultures may form spherical or coccoid bodies. Motile (with a characteristic corkscrewlike, darting motion) by means of a single polar unsheathed flagellum at one or both ends of the cell. Microaerophilic to anaerobic with a respiratory type of metabolism. Growth at 37°C; no growth at 15°C. An O<sub>2</sub> concentration of 3 to 15% is required for the preferentially microaerophilic species, while most strains (<i>Campylobacter curvus</i> and <i>Campylobacter rectus</i>) which prefer to grow under anaerobic conditions can also grow in the presence of 1 to 5% O<sub>2</sub>. Hydrogen is required or stimulates growth under both microaerophilic and anaerobic conditions. Occasionally a few strains may grow slightly under aerobic conditions (20% O<sub>2</sub>). Chemoorganotrophs. Carbohydrates are neither oxidized nor fermented. Does not require serum or blood for growth. Energy is obtained from amino acids or tricarboxylic acid cycle intermediates and not from carbohydrates. Urea (except for a group of atypical <i>Campylobacter lari</i> strains [4]) and gelatin are not hydrolyzed. Oxidase activity, but no lipase activity. No pigment production, except for <i>Campylobacter mucosalis</i> and <i>Campylobacter hyointestinalis</i>, which produce a dirty yellow pigment. Menaquinone 6 and methyl-substituted menaquinone 6 are the major respiratory quinones ; tetradecanoic acid, hexadecanoic acid, hexadecenoic acid, and octadecenoic acid are the major fatty acids. The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 30 to 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Several species are pathogenic for humans and animals.</s><s>Found in the reproductive organs, intestinal tracts, and oral cavities of humans and animals.</s><s>The type species is <i>Campylobacter fetus</i> (Smith and Taylor 1919) Sebald and Veron 1963.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This emended genus contains the following species: <i>Campylobacter fetus</i>, <i>Campylobacter hyointestinalis</i>, <i>Campylobacter mucosalis</i>, <i>Campylobacter concisus</i>, <i>Campylobacter sputorum</i>, <i>Campylobacter jejuni</i>, Campylobacter co li, <i>Campylobacter lari</i>, "<i>Campylobacter upsaliensis</i>", <i>Campylobacter curvus</i>, and <i>Campylobacter rectus</i>.</s><s>All other <i>Campylobacter</i> species are generically misnamed.</s></p></content></protolog>