<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7222_nm.490" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.490" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.490" rank="species">Thermosipho melanesiensis</organism><reference id="rid.7222"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Antoine</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cilia</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meunier</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guezennec</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lesongeur</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermosipho melanesiensis sp. nov., a new thermophilic anaerobic bacterium belonging to the order Thermotogales, isolated from deep-sea hydrothermal vents in the southwestern Pacific Ocean.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1118</fpage><lpage>1123</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1118</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336917</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of  <i>Thermosipho melaniensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermosipho melaniensis</i> (me. la. ne. si. en'sis. L. gen. n. <i>melanesiensis</i>, originating from Melanesia, describing its site of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative rods with a length of 1 to 3.5 μm and a width of 0.4 to 0.6 μm.</s><s>The rods are surrounded by a sheathlike structure, ballooning over the ends.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, or, rarely, in chains with a maximum of five rods.</s><s>They are anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs between 45 and 80°C, with an optimum at 70°C; between pH 3.5 and 9.5, with an optimum at pH 6.5 to 7.5; and at NaCl concentrations between 5 and 60 g/liter, with an optimum at 30 g/liter (doubling time at optimum temperature and salinity and at pH 6.5, 100 min).</s><s>For heterotrophic growth under anaerobic conditions, complex organic material, such as yeast extract or brain heart infusion, is necessary.</s><s>Growth is supported by yeast extract or brain heart infusion alone or by malt extract, tryptone, and carbohydrates supplemented by yeast extract.</s><s>For carbohydrates, decreasing yields of growth are obtained with sucrose and starch, glucose and maltose, lactose, cellobiose, and galactose.</s><s>Meat extract, xylose, fructose, ethanol, mannitol, sorbitol, glycine, glycogen, formate, acetate and Casamino Acids do not support growth, even combined with yeast extract.</s><s>Hydrogen inhibits growth, but this inhibition is overcome by the reduction of elemental sulfur.</s><s>Under this condition, hydrogen sulfide is produced and the growth yield and more precisely the growth rate are in creased.</s><s>Neither thiosulfate nor sulfate can be used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Shifting metabolism to alanine production in the absence of elemental sulfur.</s><s>Completely inhibited by rifampin, chloramphenicol, and streptomycin, each at a final concentration of 100 μg/ml.</s><s>Slight growth with the same concentration of vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition (G+C content) is 30.5 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis based on the 16s rRNA sequence affiliates the strain with the <i>Thermotogules</i> and, more specifically, with the genus <i>Thermosipho</i>, but genomic DNA-DNA similarity analysis and physological properties offer clear evidence for significant divergence from the species <i>Thermosipho africanus</i>.</s><s>Isolated from the gills of a deep-sea hydrothermal mussel (<i>B. brevior</i>) collected at the bottom of a black smoker in the Lau Basin (latitude, 22°32's; longitude, 176°43'W; depth, 1,832 to 1,887 m), Southwest Pacific Ocean.</s><s>Type strain is <i>Thermosipho melanesiensis</i> B1429<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 104789<sup>T</sup> [Collection de Bactéries de l'Institut Pasteur, Paris, France]).</s></p></content></protolog>