<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8525_nm.13280" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13280" rank="species">Chryseobacterium pallidum</organism><reference id="rid.8525"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Herzog</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winkler</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolking</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium ureilyticum sp. nov., Chryseobacterium gambrini sp. nov., Chryseobacterium pallidum sp. nov. and Chryseobacterium molle sp. nov., isolated from beer-bottling plants.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>26</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65362-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175677</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium pallidum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium pallidum</em> (pal′li.dum. L. neut. adj. <em>pallidum</em> pale).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods, approximately 1.3 μm (sd 0.3 μm) in length and 0.8 μm (sd 0.1 μm) in width.</s><s>After growth for 2 days at 30 °C on trypticase soy agar, colonies are circular and pale-cream-coloured with a diameter of approximately 1 mm.</s><s>Gram-negative and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not produce flexirubin-type pigments.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25 and 37 °C but not at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>Grows on plain nutrient agar and on nutrient agar containing up to 1 % NaCl, but not on nutrient agar containing 2 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs on Cetrimide, MacConkey or Simmons' citrate agars.</s><s>Positive for gelatinase, lecithinase and haemolytic activities; production of indole; nitrate reduction; and hydrolysis of aesculin and Tweens 20 and 80.</s><s>Negative for starch hydrolysis; oxidation of gluconate; fluorescence on King B agar; production of acetoin; urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities; production of H<sub>2</sub>S; and acid formation from glucose, lactose, sucrose, arabinose, rhamnose, mannitol, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, dulcitol, melibiose and amygdalin.</s><s>Glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, adipate and malate are utilized as sole carbon sources, but <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, phenylacetate, citrate and caprate are not.</s><s>Susceptible to kanamycin, streptomycin, erythromycin, tetracycline, gentamicin, novobiocin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, furazolidone and fusidic acid and resistant to ampicillin.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 15 : 0 iso, 16 : 1 <em>cis</em>9 and 17 : 0 iso 3-OH.</s><s>Predominant respiratory quinone type is MK-6.</s><s>Polar lipids are composed of phosphatidylethanolamine, several aminolipids and other polar lipids.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 38.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 26-3St2b<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18015<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52548<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a steel surface of a beer-bottling plant in Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>