<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11573_nm.18609" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18609" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18609" rank="species">Amycolatopsis halophila</organism><reference id="rid.11573"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>T.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis halophila sp. nov., a halophilic actinomycete isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1073</fpage><lpage>1078</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012427-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666809</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis halophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis halophila</em> (ha.lo.phi′la. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> <em>halos</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>halophila</em> salt-loving, referring to the ability of the type strain to grow at high NaCl concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, halophilic, filamentous actinomycete.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are well developed and fragment into squarish, rod-like elements.</s><s>Aerial mycelia differentiate into long chains of spore-like structure at maturity.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–45 °C, at pH 6.0–8.0 and in the presence of 1–15 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C, pH 7.0 and 5 % NaCl; no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are degraded, but aesculin, casein, starch, cellulose, chitin, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Positive for gelatin liquefaction, but negative for nitrate reduction, milk peptonization and coagulation, H<sub>2</sub>S, and melanin production.</s><s>Utilizes d-galactose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, inositol, xylitol, erythritol, sodium acetate, glycerol and trisodium citrate as sole carbon source, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-ribose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-xylose, maltose, lactose, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol or sodium propionate.</s><s>Utilizes l-threonine, l-arginine, glycine, l-serine, l-histidine, l-proline, l-tyrosine, alanine, l-methionine, hypoxanthine, l-asparagine and xanthine as sole nitrogen source, but not l-lysine, l-phenylalanine or adenine.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible (per disc) to ciprofloxacin (5 μg), amoxicillin (10 μg), novobiocin (5 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and erythromycin (15 μg), but resistant to netilmicin (10 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), penicillin (10 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), tobramycin (10 μg), sulfamethoxazole (23.75 μg), amikacin (30 μg) and clindamycin.</s><s>Contains <em>meso</em>-DAP, glutamic acid and alanine as cell-wall diamino acids, and glucose and galactose as major whole-cell sugars.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>Phospholipids present are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxy-phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositolmannosides and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 93223<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45216<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19403<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>