<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12343_nm.20375" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20375" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20375" rank="species">Litoreibacter janthinus</organism><reference id="rid.12343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Litoreibacter albidus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Litoreibacter janthinus sp. nov., members of the class Alphaproteobacteria isolated from the seashore</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>154</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019513-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173002</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Litoreibacter janthinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Litoreibacter janthinus</em> (jan′thi.nus. L. masc. adj. <em>janthinus</em> violet–blue).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter and 1.8–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Produces greyish-violet-pigmented colonies with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter, on MA.</s><s>Bchl <em>a</em> is not produced.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs at 0.5–6 % NaCl (w/v) and is optimal in 2–3 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Grows in/on basal medium containing NaCl alone without any of the sea salts components MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub>, NaNO<sub>3</sub>, K<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>, KCl, NaSO<sub>4</sub>, NaHCO<sub>3</sub>, NaF and FeSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Psychrotolerant; temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C, with an optimum at 25–28 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed above 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–10.0, with an optimum at pH 7.0–8.5.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production and hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, DNA, Tween 80, chitin, starch and l-tyrosine.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, melanin-like pigments and clearance zones are not produced.</s><s>No acid production from d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or d-mannitol.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (PNPG test) and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification under anaerobic conditions, arginine dihydrolase, urease production, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In ID32 GN tests, does not assimilate l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-proline.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, weakly positive for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc unless indicated) ampicillin (10), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100), gentamicin (10), lincomycin (15), oleandomycin (15), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (30), vancomycin (30), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), neomycin (30), ofloxacin (5), polymyxin (300 U), erythromycin (15), cephazolin (30), cephalexin (30), chloramphenicol (30), oxacillin (10) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Detailed fatty acid and polar lipid compositions are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.5 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3842<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0772<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16492<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a shallow sediment sample collected from the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>