<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8492_nm.13285" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13285" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13285" rank="species">Colwellia polaris</organism><reference id="rid.8492"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Colwellia polaris sp. nov., a psychrotolerant bacterium isolated from Arctic sea ice.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1931</fpage><lpage>1934</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65596-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Colwellia polaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Colwellia polaris</em> (po.la′ris. N.L. fem. adj. <em>polaris</em> polar, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the Arctic Ocean).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, psychrotolerant, curved rods, 0.6–0.9×0.9–4 μm.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, convex, circular and smooth with entire edges.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–26 °C and pH 5.0–10.0; optimum growth occurs at 20–21 °C and approximately pH 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Grows aerobically and produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1–6 % (w/v) NaCl and no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Negative for indole production and in the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction and the production of hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, urease, agarase, chitinase, lecithinase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Positive for gelatinase, caseinase, amylase, alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: glucose, mannitol, d-mannose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, maltose, fructose, d-galactose, melibiose, glycerol and pyruvate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: cellobiose, xylose, melezitose, galactitol, erythritol, salicin, lysine, valine, glycine, cysteine, citrate, hippurate, malate, succinate and tartrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannitol, maltose, melibiose, d-galactose and glycerol.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (22.95 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (17.64 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (13.74 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (7.55 %), iso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6.45 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (5.69 %).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 537<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6132<sup>T</sup> =JCM 13952<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sea ice collected from the Canadian Basin in the Arctic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>