<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8222_nm.14698" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14698" rank="species">Neoehrlichia lotoris</organism><reference id="rid.8222"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yabsley</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Murphy</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luttrell</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilcox</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Howerth</surname><given-names>E.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Munderloh</surname><given-names>U.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of 'Candidatus Neoehrlichia lotoris' (family Anaplasmataceae) from raccoons (Procyon lotor).</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2794</fpage><lpage>2798</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65836-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060060</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Neoehrlichia lotoris’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Neoehrlichia lotoris’ [lo.tor′is. L. gen. n. <em>lotoris</em> of a clothes-washer, of <em>Procyon lotor</em> (a raccoon)]. The reference strain is RAC413<sup>R</sup>. Isolated from a captive raccoon experimentally infected with ‘<em>Candidatus</em> N. lotoris’ by blood inoculation from a naturally infected raccoon from Clarke Co., Georgia, USA (Munderloh <em>et al.</em>, 2007). Not infectious to two strains of laboratory mice (<em>Mus musculus</em>, strains BALB/c and C3H), laboratory rats (<em>Rattus norvegicus</em>, Wistar strain) or laboratory rabbits (<em>Oryctolagus cuniculus</em>, New Zealand White) in limited inoculation trials (Yabsley <em>et al.</em>, 2008a). Host cells within raccoons are not known. Morphology of organisms in ISE6 tick cells is similar to that of other members of the family <em>Anaplasmataceae</em>. Member of the family <em>Anaplasmataceae</em> based on 16S rRNA gene, <em>groESL</em> and <em>gltA</em> sequences and growth within membrane-bound cytoplasmic vacuoles. Organisms are Gram-negative, highly pleomorphic (compact coccus-like and elongated, wavy forms; 0.5–4 μm), stain light to dark purple with Giemsa and tend to cluster on the side of the endosome nearest the host cell nucleus. Ultrastructurally, the organism has an outer unit membrane separated from the inner cell wall by a thin periplasmic space, characteristic of the family <em>Anaplasmataceae</em>. In some cases, individual bacteria are wrapped in two sets of membranes. Analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence revealed a novel 2 bp insertion compared with members of the genus <em>Ehrlichia</em> (AT at base 784 of <em>E. chaffeensis</em> Arkansas<sup>T</sup>; GenBank accession no. AF416764). Analysis of <em>gltA</em> sequence revealed a novel deletion compared with members of the genera <em>Ehrlichia</em> and <em>Anaplasma</em> (6 bp deletion at base 1011 of <em>E. chaffeensis</em> Arkansas<sup>T</sup>; GenBank accession no. AF304142) and a 2 bp insertion compared with other members of the family <em>Anaplasmataceae</em> (TTG at base 744 of <em>E. chaffeensis</em> Arkansas<sup>T</sup>; AF304142). The G+C content of four sequenced genes of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> N. lotoris’ RAC413<sup>R</sup> is 38.1 mol%. Can be differentiated from ‘<em>Candidatus</em> N. mikurensis’ on the basis of unique 16S rRNA gene, <em>groESL</em> and <em>gltA</em> sequences.</s></p></content></protolog>