<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9250_nm.14385" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14385" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14385" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.9250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter oryzae sp. nov., isolated from soil of a rice paddy</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1451</fpage><lpage>1454</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007138-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502333</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter oryzae</em> (o.ry′zae. L. gen. fem. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice, referring to the rice paddy fields where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, non-motile, aerobic rods, 0.5–0.8 μm wide and 1.5–2.8 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are pale pink, convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–35 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH 5.0–8.0 (optimum pH 6.5–7.5).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Cells produce large amounts of EPS.</s><s>Casein, urea, pectin, xylan, laminarin, CM-cellulose, aesculin, gelatin and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but starch and Tweens 20 and 80 are not.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from raffinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, l-arabinose, melibiose, d-fructose, salicin, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, sucrose, but not from arbutin.</s><s>Positive for Voges–Proskauer test, but negative for indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, citrate utilization and lysine decarboxylase (API 20E).</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannose, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities, but not trypsin or <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak activities are observed for lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for oxidization of Biolog GN2 MicroPlate substrates <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, acetic acid, d-gluconic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in the Biolog GN2 MicroPlate are not oxidized.</s><s>Resistant to polymyxin B, gentamicin, kanamycin, oleandomycin, ampicillin, streptomycin, penicillin G, lincomycin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, carbenicillin and novobiocin.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.4 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B9<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12816<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19975<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from rice paddy soil associated with the roots of <em>Oryza sativa</em> in Jinju, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>