<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3399_nm.6761" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6761" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6761" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora hordei</organism><reference id="rid.3399"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lacey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Athalye</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Embley</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowen</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora gregorii and Saccharopolyspora hordei: Two new actinomycete species from fodder.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>2125</fpage><lpage>2139</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharopolyspora hordei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora hordei</i> (hor'.de.i. L neut. n. <i>hordeum</i>, barley; ML n. <i>Hordeum</i>, a genus of grass.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies colourless to light buff, conical, rounded or wrinkled.</s><s>Substrate mycelium well developed, sometimes fragmenting into coccoid elements.</s><s>Aerial mycelium lacking or sparse white with short flexuous, hooked or spiral spore chains often with a beaded appearance.</s><s>Transmission electron micrographs show the spores to be characteristically covered by a smooth sheath, with adjacent spores often separated by a short length of empty hypha.</s><s>Degrades aesculin, arbutin, DNA, guanine, RNA, starch, testosterone, Tweens 20 and 80, L-tyrosine and xanthine ; utilizes L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glycogen, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, starch, sucrose and xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Neither allantoin nor urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>Tolerant to a range of antibiotics and chemical inhibitors (see Table 2).</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 20-30°C up to 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The wall peptidoglycan contains alanine, glutamic acid and glycine with <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid.</s><s>The principal wall sugars are arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The organism is rich in <i>iso</i>- and <i>anteiso</i>- fatty acids, with 14-methylhexadecanoic acid and 14- and 15-methylpentadecanoic acids predominating.</s><s>It also contains tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the major isoprenologue and major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and uncharacterized phospho- and glycolipids.</s><s>The mol % G + C content of the DNA of the type strain is 72 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from barley and oat grains, grass hay, straw and sugar cane bagasse.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain : <i>Saccharopolyspora hordei</i> NCIB 12824 (A54).</s></p></content></protolog>