<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.14763" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14763" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11872" rank="species">Rivibacter subsaxonicus</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rivibacter subsaxonicus</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rivibacter subsaxonicus</em> (sub.sa.xo′ni.cus. L. prep. <em>sub</em> low/below/under, L. masc. adj. <em>saxonicus</em> pertaining to Saxony, N.L. masc. adj. <em>subsaxonicus</em> pertaining to Lower Saxony, a state of the Federal Republic of Germany). The etymology has been changed from the original description (N.L. masc. adj. <em>subsaxonicus</em> a bacterium originating from the German state of Lower Saxony).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Methylibium subsaxonicum</em> Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em> 2008.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on that given for <em>Methylibium subsaxonicum</em> (Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em>, 2008).</s><s>In addition to the properties of the genus, the following properties characterize the species.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are 1 mm in diameter and whitish.</s><s>Assimilation of d-glucose, methylpyruvate, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid is weak.</s><s>The sugars and polysaccharides provided by the API 20NE and API 20 E substrate panels are not fermented.</s><s>Of the substrates provided by the Biolog GN microplate, d-glucose, dl-lactic acid, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, l-proline, uraconic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid are assimilated.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch is strong, while that of beechwood xylan and wheat arabinoxylan is weak; negative for cellulose hydrolysis.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile of the type strain is listed in Supplementary Table S1.</s><s>Sensitive (inhibition zones &#x003E;30 mm) to (per disc) penicillin G (10 IU), ampicillin (10 μg), ticarcillin (75 μg), mezlocillin (30 μg), cefatolin (30 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), imipenem (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), ofloxaxin (5 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg) and doxycycline (30 μg).</s><s>Inhibition zones of 10–30 mm are observed for polymyxin B (300 IU), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), vancomycin (30 μg) and pipemidic acid (10 μg).</s><s>Resistant to oxacillin (5 μg), aztreonam (30 μg), lincomycin (15 μg) and bacitracin (10 IE).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BF49<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19570<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109700<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a biofilm of a tufa deposit in the Westerhöfer rivulet, near Westerhof, Lower Saxony, Germany (5 ° 45′ 49″ N 1 ° 05′ 31.7″ E).</s></p></content></protolog>