<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1212_nm.1895" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1895" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1895" rank="species">Thiobacillus versutus</organism><reference id="rid.1212"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genomic and physiological comparisons between heterotrophic thiobacilli and Acidiphilium cryptum, Thiobacillus versutus sp. nov., and Thiobacillus acidophilus nom. rev.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>211</fpage><lpage>217</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-211</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus versutus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(ver.su'tus. L. adj. <i>versutus</i> versatile)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. versutus</i> is an aerobic, mesophilic, gram-negative, nonsporulating, nonmotile, rod-shaped, non-acidophilic mixotroph.</s><s>The G +C content of its DNA is approximately 68 mol%.</s><s>It grows well in mineral salts medium with thiosulfate as the sole energy source, and it grows optimally between pH 7 and 9.</s><s>This organism grows anaerobically in the presence of nitrate as an electron acceptor and produces copious N<sub>2</sub> with organic substrates, but not with thiosulfate in mineral salts medium.</s><s>In yeast extract-glucose medium the growth rate is optimum between pH 7 and 9; growth is less rapid between pH 5.5 and 6.5, and the cells may become bloated; growth does not occur in this medium at pH &#x003C;5. <i>T. versutus</i> can be differentiated from other non-acidophilic mixotrophic thiobacilli by its rapid rate of growth and cell yield in thiosulfate and organic media, by its denitrifying activity with organic substrates, and by its versatility in utilizing various organic compounds as sole sources of energy.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized by <i>T. versutus</i> but not by <i>T. novellus</i> as sole energy sources: sucrose, butyrate, <i>n</i>-butylalcohol, L-leucine, L-isoleucine , L-tryptophan, DL-serine, L-glutamate, L-asparate, malate, succinate, citrate, benzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-aminobenzoate, and cyclohexane carboxylate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A2 (= ATCC 25364) is designated the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>