<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7196_nm.7257" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7257" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7257" rank="species">Streptomyces sannanensis</organism><reference id="rid.7196"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Iwasaki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mori</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces sannanensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>280</fpage><lpage>284</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-280</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces sannanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces sannanensis</i> (san.nan.en'sis. M. L. adj. <i>sannanensis</i> of Sannan; named for Sannan Town, Hikami District, Hyogo Prefecture, Japan, the source of the soil from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore chain morphology: Section <i>Spirales</i>.</s><s>Mature spore chains generally moderately short, often with 20 or more spores per chain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore surface: Smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Color of colony: Aerial mass color in the Gray color-series on sucrose-nitrate agar, glucose-asparagine agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, and oatmeal agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reverse side of colony: No distinctive pigments (colorless to buff in color) on all media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Diffusible pigment: Melanoid pigments are not formed in peptone-yeast extract-iron agar, tyrosine agar, or tryptone-yeast extract broth.</s><s>No pigment other than a trace of yellow is produced in the media used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics: Mesophilic (growth range is from 17 to 37OC; temperature for optimum growth is between 27 and 34°C).</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed and gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Does not grow in skim milk medium.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbon utilization: No growth or only a trace of growth with L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-fructose, sucrose, i-inositol, L-rhamnose, raffinose, or D-mannitol with Pridham and Gottlieb's basal mineral salts agar.</s><s>On CuSO<sub>4</sub>-free Pridham and Gottlieb's basal mineral salts agar and Czapek solution agar, D-xylose and D-glucose are utilized for growth; D-glUCOSe gives only faint growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall composition: LL-diaminopimelic acid occurs in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The cell wall composition is believed to be of Type I.</s><s>Antagonistic properties: Produces sannamycins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: Soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Strain KC-7038.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., where it has been assigned the number 31530.</s><s>Because the description given above for the species is based on a single strain, the type strain, the species description also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>