<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2005_nm.10837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10837" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10837" rank="species">Lysobacter defluvii</organism><reference id="rid.2005"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siering</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter defluvii sp. nov., isolated from municipal solid waste</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1131</fpage><lpage>1136</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64966-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter defluvii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter defluvii</em> [de.flu′vi.i. L. gen. neut. n. <em>defluvii</em> from outflow (sewage)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (approximately 1–2 μm in length).</s><s>Gram-negative and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies are mucoid and yellow in colour.</s><s>Produces a brown pigment that becomes more marked in older cultures.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures in the range 22–37 °C.</s><s>Salt concentrations in the range 0.0–6.0 % (w/v) NaCl are tolerated.</s><s>Growth occurs on tryptone soya agar and nutrient agar but the micro-organism grows preferentially on BHI agar.</s><s>Has the ability to swarm and spread on the surface of agar plates by means of gliding.</s><s>Shows the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of members of the genus <em>Lysobacter</em>.</s><s>Fatty acids mainly comprise saturated and unsaturated fatty acids with straight and branched chains of the iso/anteiso type.</s><s>The main hydroxylated fatty acid is iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, elastin, gelatin and hippurate, but not adenine, chitin, aesculin, guanine, hypoxanthine, keratin, starch, testosterone, tyrosine, Tween 80 or xanthine.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, starch, amygdalin, d-glucose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-sucrose, d-trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Shows alkaline phosphatase activity, but is negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine aminopeptidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, nitrate reductase and urease activities.</s><s>Negative for acetoin, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Assimilates trisodium citrate but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB APB-9<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53152<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18482<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample taken from a municipal landfill site in Udupi, Karnataka State, India.</s></p></content></protolog>