<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5626_nm.4011" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4011" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4011" rank="species">Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum</organism><reference id="rid.5626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Keis</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shaheen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Clostridium acetobutylicum and Clostridium beijerinckii, and descriptions of Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum sp. nov. and Clostridium saccharobutylicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760952</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum</i> (sac.cha.ro.per.bu.tyl.a.ce.to'ni.cum. Gr. n. <i>saccharon</i> sugar juice ; Gr. pron. <i>per</i> throughout; N.L. n. <i>butylum</i> butanol; N.L. adj. <i>acetonicus</i> acetonic; N.L. adj. <i>saccharoperbutylacetonicum</i> denoting the production of a large amount of butanol and acetone from sugar)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. saccharoperbutylacetonicum</i> was first named and described by Hongo (1960) in US patent no. 2945786.</s><s>The species status of <i>C. saccharoperbutylacetonicum</i> has now been firmly established by 16S rRNA genesequence analysis (Keis et al., 1995) and DNA-DNA reassociation (Johnson et al., 1997), and, since this name is in widespread use in the scientific literature, we recommend that it be validated.</s><s>The original description by Hongo (1960) has been incorporated in the description provided below.</s><s>Strain N1-4 was deposited by Hongo &#x0026; Murata in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 13564, along with its derivatives N1-4 (HMT) (ATCC 27021<sup>T</sup>) and N1-504 (ATCC 27022).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in most broth cultures consist of straight, short and long rods with rounded ends, measuring 0.4-0.8 μm x3.1-6.2 μm.</s><s>Rods occur singly, or occasionally in pairs, and are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>They are initially phase-dark and Gram-positive, becoming Gram-negative in older cultures.</s><s>Towards the end of exponential growth, the rod-shaped cells usually begin to accumulate granulose.</s><s>These morphological changes are typically associated with the metabolic shift from acid production to solvent production.</s><s>Endospores are oval, measuring 0.8-1.5 μm x 1.6-2.2 μm.</s><s>Existing strains sporulate poorly on most common laboratory culture media.</s><s>Colonies on CBMagar are 2-3 mm in diameter, domed, white and have smooth surfaces and entire}undulated margins.</s><s>The species is mesophilic, optimum growth for solvent production occurring between 25 and 35 °C; the optimum pH range is between pH 5.6 and pH 6.7.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase and indole are not produced.</s><s>The strains are resistant to rifampicin (100 ng).</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrohydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from nitrite.</s><s>The results for the production of hydrogen sulphide are as follows: negative from peptone-containing medium; negative or weakly positive from the reduction of sulphites ; and positive from the reduction of thiosulphates.</s><s>Digestion of coagulated albumin is very weak or negative.</s><s>Strains ferment arabinose, xylose, glucose, mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, saccharose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, mannitol, melibiose, methyl-glucopyranoside, raffinose, salicin, trehalose, turanose, amygdalin, starch, glycogen, dextrin, pectin, melezitose and inulin.</s><s>The utilization of the latter two sugars is in contrast to the original description given in the patent by Hongo (1960).</s><s>The sugars ribose and glycerol were not utilized and weak fermentation was observed with rhamnose.</s><s>Strain N1-4 was able to ferment sorbitol, dulcitol and inositol, but strain N1-504 was unable to utilize these alcohol sugars.</s><s>No curd formation of milk occurs during the ®rst 48 h and no ribo¯avin is produced (Johnson et al., 1997).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) is 31 mol% (Hongo et al., 1966).</s><s>Fermentation products include acetic and butyric acids, acetone, butanol, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>These industrial strains were used in the applied fermentation process for the production of the solvents acetone, butanol and ethanol from a variety of sugar- and starchbased substrates.</s><s>Commercial production of solvents commonly used various types of molasses mash supplemented with nitrogen in the form of ammonium salts and organic nitrogen.</s><s>Typically, industrial fermentations utilized molasses containing 4-6% fermentable sugars at temperatures of 25-35 °C for 48-72 h, giving a final pH of 5.5-8.0, solvent yields of 27-34% and solvent concentrations of 15-17 g l<sup>-1</sup> (maximum 19 g l<sup>-1</sup>); the proportion of butanol ranged from 73 to 85%.</s><s>Corn mash typically required longer fermentation times and produced significantly lower yields and concentrations of solvents.</s><s>More detailed information on solvent ratios, concentrations and yields for both sugar-based and starch-based substrates with two strains belonging to this species is available in a recent publication by Shaheen et al. (2000).</s><s>Since the ATCC 13564 strain has been deaccessioned, it is recommended that the type strain for this species should be ATCC 27021<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>