<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12527_nm.21382" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21382" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21382" rank="species">Brachybacterium squillarum</organism><reference id="rid.12527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Par</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium squillarum sp. nov., isolated from salt-fermented seafood</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1118</fpage><lpage>1122</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022517-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543157</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brachybacterium squillarum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brachybacterium squillarum</em> (squil.la′rum. L. gen. pl. n. <em>squillarum</em> of/from shrimp).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 1.0–1.5 µm in diameter, coccoid-shaped, non-motile and Gram-positive.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on MA plates are camel yellow-coloured, circular in form and convex with regular edges.</s><s>Grows at 25–37 °C; no growth occurs at 45 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.0, with optimal growth at pH 7.0, under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimal growth in 5 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Does not grow under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Negative for catalase and oxidase activities.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse Tween 60, but not Tweens 20, 40 or 80.</s><s>Analysis using the API 20E system revealed that cells are positive for gelatinase and acid production from d-mannitol, inositol, l-rhamnose and sucrose, but negative for β-galactosidase (ONPG hydrolysis), l-arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer).</s><s>They are also negative for acid production from d-glucose, d-sorbitol, melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>In the Biolog GP2 test, dextrin, glycogen, d-arabitol, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, α-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, turanose, pyruvic acid, adenosine, inosine and uridine are oxidized, but not α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, methyl α-d-galactoside, methyl β-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl β-d-glucoside, methyl α-d-mannoside, palatinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-tagatose, trehalose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, 2′-deoxy adenosine, thymidine, AMP, TMP, UMP, d-fructose 6-phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate or dl-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The diagnostic cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and the peptidoglycan type is A4γ, containing amino acids <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, alanine, glycine, aspartic acid and glutamic acid.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and phospho- and glycolipids.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M-6-3<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14221<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16464<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt-fermented seafood.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>