<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2234_nm.5249" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5249" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5249" rank="species">Staphylococcus felis</organism><reference id="rid.2234"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Igimi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawamura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus felis, a new species from clinical specimens from cat.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>373</fpage><lpage>377</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-373</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus felis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus felis</i> (fe' lis. L. gen. n. <i>felis</i>, of a cat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. felis</i> below is based on 39 strains, unless otherwise noted.</s><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci (diameter, 0.8 to 1.2 μm) that occur singly, in pairs, and predominantly in irregular clusters.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Agar colonies are circular, entire, 5.0 to 8.0 mm in diameter, slightly convex, and opaque with smooth and glistening surfaces.</s><s>Most strains are unpigmented.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs in both the aerobic and anaerobic portions of thioglycolate medium.</s><s>These organisms grow in the presence of 10% (wt/vol) NaCl in P agar after 24 h and in the presence of 15% NaCl after 72 h.</s><s>They grow weakly at 45°C and very weakly at 15°C.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics are listed in Table 1.</s><s>All of the strains produce neither free coagulase nor fixed coagulase (clumping factor).</s><s>All strains fail to produce β-hemolysin (hemolysis on sheep blood agar and hot-cold reaction).</s><s>Typical α-hemolysin and δ-hemolysin are not detected, but most strains have very weak hemolytic activity.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to novobiocin (1.6 μg/ml), bacitracin (2 U/ml), and lysostaphin (200 μg/ml).</s><s>All strains produce acid from glucose, mannose, fructose, trehalose, lactose, and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is usually produced from mannitol (87% of the strains), galactose (77% of the strains), and sucrose (67% of the strains); some strains produce acid from ribose (21% of the strains).</s><s>No acid is produced from arabinose, xylose, maltose, cellobiose, raffinose, or xylitol by the 39 strains which we tested; no acid is produced from melibiose, rhamnose, melezitose, glycogen, sorbitol, erythritol, inositol, adonitol, dulcitol, dextrin, salicin, or amygdalin by 22 of the strains which we tested.</s><s>All six strains tested produce esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Most strains (four of five strains tested) weakly produce lipase and α-glucosidase.</s><s>The following enzymes are not detected: leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase, and β-fucosidase.</s><s>All 12 strains tested are highly susceptible to penicillin G (MIC, &#x003C;0.025to 0.1 μ/ml) and ampicillin (MIC, &#x003C;0.1 μg/ml).</s><s>All strains are susceptible to erythromycin (0.2 to 0.39 μg/ml) and chloramphenicol (3.13 to 6.25 μg/ml).</s><s>Most strains are susceptible to oxytetracycline (0.39 to 0.78 μg/ml); one strain which we tested is resistant to this antibiotic (MIC, 100 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Type strain GD521 was isolated from a mass on the auricle of a cat.</s><s>The characteristics of type strain GD521 are the same as those described above and listed in Table 1.</s><s>Strain GD521<sup>T</sup> produces only L-lactic acid from glucose.</s><s>The peptidoglycan structure is of the L-Lys-Gly,<sub>4.6</sub>-Ser<sub>4.6</sub> type.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of its DNA as determined by the melting temperature method is 35.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>