<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.498_nm.6256" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6256" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6256" rank="species">Corynebacterium propinquum</organism><reference id="rid.498"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Corynebacterium propinquum sp. nov. for Corynebacterium group ANF-3 strains</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>113</volume><fpage>229</fpage><lpage>234</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium propinquum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium. propinquum</i> (pro'. pin. qu. um L. adj. <i>propinquus</i> near, close)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacteria are nonmotile pleomorphic rods, nonspore forming, Gram-positive with occasionally metachromatic granules and arranged in palisades or V-shaped forms.</s><s>They are non-acid fast, and no rod-coccus cycle is present.</s><s>They are catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>They are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies (1 to 2 mm in diameter) on 5% sheep blood agar are nonhemolytic, grey-white with a matted surface.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is not produced from o-glucose, glycogen, lactose, sucrose, ribose, o-xylose, D-mannose, D-galactose, trehalose, and o-mannitol or on triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Tyrosine is degraded but not gelatin, starch and urea.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The methyl red test is negative and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Growth is visible in 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of hippurate is variable.</s><s>Production of pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase is variable, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are not produced.</s><s>Cells utilize acetate, lactate, glyconate and malate.</s><s>Utilization of adipate and phenyl acetate is variable.</s><s>Propionate, glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, N-acetyl glucosamine, maltose, caprate and citrate are not utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The predominant types of mycolic acids are C<sub>30:1</sub>, C<sub>30:2</sub>, C<sub>32:1</sub>, C<sub>32:2</sub>, C<sub>34:1</sub>, C<sub>34:2</sub> and C<sub>36:2</sub>.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 57 to 59 mol% G + C (HPLC). <i>C. propinquum</i> strains were isolated from human sources, mainly respiratory tract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B 77159 (= Collection of the Institut Pasteur CIP 103792).</s><s>It was isolated by a tracheal aspiration of a patient.</s><s>This strain has all of the above properties for the species.</s><s>Adipate is utilized but not phenyl acetate.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and alkaline phosphatase are not produced.</s><s>The mol% G + C content of DNA is 57.</s></p></content></protolog>