<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5162_nm.10655" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10655" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2724" rank="species">Cellvibrio mixtus</organism><reference id="rid.5162"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cellulolytic and dextranolytic Gram-negative bacteria: revival of the genus Cellvibrio.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>97</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.1985.tb01779.x</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellvibrio mixtus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellvibrio mixtus</i> (mix.tus, M.L. masc. adj. <i>mixtus</i> mixed, referring to the type of flagellation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description: Growth on PYEA is poor or non-existent but on SPA colonies have either of the following descriptions: white to cream, convex to low convex, translucent, mucoid and circular with an entire edge, smooth surface and diameter of 1-3 mm or orange-yellow, flat, translucent, circular, irregular edge, dull surface and diameter of 1-3 mm.</s><s>All strains on defined mineral salts medium with added cellulose are white, circular, with an entire edge, smooth consistency and surrounded by a small zone of clearing in the semi-opaque medium.</s><s>Motile cells exhibit mixed flagellation, with a single polar flagellum and up to 11 lateral flagella of a different thickness and wavelength.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, dextrin, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose and xylose but not adonitol, arabitol, D-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, ribose, sorbitol or sorbose.</s><s>Starch, chitin, neutral pH and alkaline pH pectate gels and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>The enzymes α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and β-xylosidase are produced but not urease, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, arylsulphatase, acylamidase or phenylalanine deaminase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin, casein, DNA, Tween 80 and acid pH pectate gel cannot be hydrolysed.</s><s>All strains produce curdlan polysaccharide from glucose and grow on GYEA, PYEA plus 5% sucrose and glucose ammonium sulphate agar.</s><s>Growth does not occur on cetrimide agar, in an anaerobic environment, at 42°C, on glucose nitrogen free medium, in alkylamine mineral salts medium or in phenol mineral salts medium.</s><s>Further tests found to be negative are: utilization of organic acids as sole sources of carbon, acid from ethanol, 3-ketolactose from lactose, dihydroxyacetone from glycerol, oxidation of gluconate, indole production from tryptophan, gas from nitrate, H<sub>2</sub>S from cystine, methyl red test, Voges-Proskauer reaction and tolerance of 0.0075% KCN.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UQM 2601.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two subspecies are proposed, and these may be differentiated by the characteristics described below.</s></p></content></protolog>