<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.239_nm.4545" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4545" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4545" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus</organism><reference id="rid.239"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ljungdahl</surname><given-names>L.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus gen. nov., spec. nov., a new, extreme thermophilic, anaerobic bacterium.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>128</volume><fpage>343</fpage><lpage>348</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00405910</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus</i> (e.tha.no.li.cus. IVS.n. ethanol, corresponding alcohol of ethane (ethane + ol) M. L. masc. adj. <i>ethanolicus</i>, indicating the production of ethanol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Rods, 0.3-0.8μm by 4-8μm in the early logarithmic growth phase; in later growth phases, cell shape varies from chains of coccoid cells (0.8 - 1.5 μm in diameter) to long filamentous cells (up to 100μm in length) which often divide by constriction to form chains of bacteria with differing cell lengths.</s><s>Uneven division is common.</s><s>Cells in the late logarithmic growth phase frequently form protuberances, blebs, or spheroplast-like forms; no heat-stable endospores observed.</s><s>One to twelve peritrichous flagella (up to 50 μm in length and 150-170 Å thick) which are commonly lost during the late logarithmic stage of growth; 4-8pili (about 50Å thick).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony Morphology.</s><s>Deep agar (2%; 60° colonies, 0.5-1 mm in diameter, lenticular, and white which can become dark brown in older cultures; no extractable pigment observed.</s><s>Surface colonies, 2-4 mm in diameter, smooth, white, round to irregular and flat after 50 h growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Chemoorganotroph, anaerobe.</s><s>Growth occurs between 37 and 78°C and from pH 4.4-9.9.</s><s>Utilizes various hexoses, ribose, xylose, cellobiose, sucrose, starch;inhibited by chloramphenicol, and Polymycin B.</s><s>Fermentation end products: From hexoses and starch mainly ethanol and CO<sub>2</sub> with a minor production of lactate and acetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G + C Guanine Plus Cytosine Content of the DNA.</s><s>Between 37 and 39 mol%, determined by buoyant density measurements and around 32 mol% by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Alkaline and slightly acidic hot springs in Yellowstone National Park, WY, USA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type Strain. <i>Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus</i> JW 200 (ATCC 31550).</s></p></content></protolog>