<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2124_nm.4975" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4975" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4975" rank="species">Bacillus salexigens</organism><reference id="rid.2124"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Garabito</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mellado</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus salexigens sp. nov., a new moderately halophilic Bacillus species.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>741</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-735</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226905</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus salexigens</i> Garabito, Arahal, Mellado, Marquez, and Ventosa sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus salexigens</i> (sal.ex'i. gens. L. n. <i>sal</i>, salt; L. v. exigu, to demand; M. L. part. adj. <i>salexigens</i>, salt demanding)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive rods that are 0.3 to 0.6 by 1.5 to 3.5 μm and occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Oval endospores are produced at subterminal or central positions in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are nonpigmented, circular, smooth, convex, and entire.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 7 to 20% (wt/vol) total salts, and optimal growth occurs in the presence of 10% (wt/vol) total salts.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 15 and 45°C (optimal temperature, 37°C) and at pH values between 6.0 and 11.0 (optimal pH, 7.5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose, D-mannitol, glycerol, and D-mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from dulcitol, D-galactose, D-melibiose, lactose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, and Lrhamnose.</s><s>DNA is hydrolyzed; starch, Tween 80, and tyrosine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole, Voges-Proskauer, Simmons citrate, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: pyruvic acid, D-xylose, dextrin, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannose, D-psicose, D-ribose, salicin, turanose, L-lactic acid, N-acetyl-glutamate, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-alanyl-glycine, glycerol, adenosine, 2’-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, and uridine.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>p</i>-Hydroxyphenylacetic acid and succinic acid are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, carbenicillin, rifampin, novobiocin, cephalothin, penicillin G, and ampicillin.</s><s>Resistant to nalidixic acid and polymyxin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other phenotypic features are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 36.3 to 39.5 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitats are solar salterns and saline soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain C-20Mo (= ATCC 700290 = DSM 11483 = CCM 4646).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same of that of the species, except that the type strain grows in the presence of 10 to 20% (wt/vol) total salt and does not produce acid from D-mannitol.</s><s>The base composition of its DNA is 39.5 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Other characteristics of this strain are shown in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>