<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5677_nm.9926" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9926" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9926" rank="species">Dietzia cinnamea</organism><reference id="rid.5677"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dietzia cinnamea sp. nov., a novel species isolated from a perianal swab of a patient with a bone marrow transplant</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>641</fpage><lpage>645</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63863-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514042</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dietzia cinnamea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dietzia cinnamea</em> (cin.na.me′a. L. fem. adj. <em>cinnamea</em> of/from cinnamon referring to the colour of the cellular biomass).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms smooth, yellow-pigmented colonies on agar media.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, exhibit snapping division and produce V-forms.</s><s>Gram-positive and not acid-fast.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows at temperatures of 22–45 °C.</s><s>Has the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of the genus <em>Dietzia</em>.</s><s>The glycan moiety of the cell walls contains <em>N</em>-acetyl residues (<em>N</em>-acetylmuramic acid).</s><s>Cleavage of mycolic acids by pyrolysis releases fatty acids of C14 : 0, C15 : 0, C16 : 0, C17 : 0, C18 : 1 and C18 : 0 as the major products.</s><s>The fatty acid profile mainly consists of straight-chain saturated, unsaturated and 10-methyl branched fatty acids.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) is the major menaquinone component and MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) is the minor one.</s><s>The phospholipid type is PII, with phosphatidylethanolamine as diagnostic phospholipid.</s><s>Hydrolyses testosterone and urea, but not adenine, casein, elastin, aesculin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, d-glucose, maltose and 1,2-propanediol as carbon sources, but not adonitol, adipate, iso-amylalcohol, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, cellobiose, citrate, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-galactose, gluconate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactate, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Unable to utilize acetamide, l-alanine, arginine, gelatin, ornithine, proline or serine as simultaneous carbon and nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <em>Dietzia cinnamea</em>, IMMIB RIV-399<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44904<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 50875<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a perianal swab of a patient with a bone marrow transplant.</s></p></content></protolog>