<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7976_nm.8051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8051" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4404" rank="species">Prevotella dentalis</organism><reference id="rid.7976"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>16S rRNA gene similarities indicate that Hallella seregens (Moore and Moore) and Mitsuokella dentalis (Haapasalo et al.) are genealogically highly related and are members of the genus Prevotella: emended description of the genus Prevotella (Shah and Collins) and description of Prevotella dentalis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>832</fpage><lpage>836</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prevotella dentalis</i> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are nonmotile, non-spore-forming, gram-negative, blunt-ended, oval rods that are 0.7 by 1 to 2 μ,m. They occur singly. Peritrichous fimbrae and a thick capsulelike structure are present. Obligately anaerobic. Poor growth occurs in liquid media; better growth occurs on blood agar media supplemented with hemolyzed blood. No growth occurs on kanamycin-vancomycin laked blood agar. After 3 days, colonies on enriched horse blood agar (containing hemolyzed blood) are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, convex, irregular, translucent, wet, and mucoid; they have a characteristic water drop appearance. Alpha-hemolysis on horse and sheep blood agar usually occurs after 7 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ferments arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, and raffinose in prereduced anaerobically sterilized peptone-yeast extract broth.</s><s>Melibiose and sucrose are weakly fermented (pH 5.5 to 5.7).</s><s>Erythritol, mannitol, melezitose, rhamnose, salicin, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Fermentation reactions are negative as determined by API 20A systems.</s><s>No hydrolysis of gelatin and starch occurs.</s><s>Esculin hydrolysis is negative in esculin broth for anaerobes, but positive when a chromogenic substrate for the detection of a constitutive enzyme is used with cells grown on an agar plate.</s><s>The major metabolic end products are acetate and succinate.</s><s>Malate dehydrogenase is present, and glutamate dehydrogenase is present in minor amounts.</s><s>α-Arabinosidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, and alanine aminopepticiase are present.</s><s>Hydrolyzes indoxylacetate.</s><s>α-Fucosidase, α-mannosidase, and β-glucosidase are absent.</s><s>Does not produce leucine, proline, tyrosine, arginine, histidine, phenylalanine, and glycine aminopeptidases or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>Arginine is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to kanamycin and colistin.</s><s>Vancomycin is inhibitory at concentrations higher than 5 μg/ml.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, penicillin, rifampin, and metronidazole and to oxgall and brilliant green.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the dibasic amino acid and glycine, alanine, glutamic acid, and aspartic acid.</s><s>Hydroxylated and nonhydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present; 3-OH-C<sub>16:0</sub> is the main hydroxylated fatty acid, and C<sub>16:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14:0</sub> are the major fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 56 to 60 mol% (as determined by thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from dental root canals.</s><s>The type strain is strain DSM 3688.</s></p></content></protolog>