<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12890_nm.22708" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22708" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22708" rank="species">Actinophytocola xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.12890"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinophytocola xinjiangensis sp. nov., isolated from virgin forest soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2928</fpage><lpage>2932</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027722-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257681</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinophytocola xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinophytocola xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, a province of north-west China, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Good growth occurs on ISP 3, ISP 4, modified Bennett’s agar and N-Z-amine medium, on which beige to yellowish brown colonies and a non-fragmented substrate mycelium with occasional septa are formed.</s><s>Scant aerial hyphae are produced on ISP 3, ISP 4, ISP 5 and ISP 9.</s><s>The aerial mycelium fragments into short spore chains with cylindrical spores.</s><s>Greyish-black diffusion pigments are produced on ISP 7.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 8.0) and at 10–30 °C (optimum 25–30 °C).</s><s>The maximum NaCl concentration for growth is 4 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive for catalase, reduction of nitrate, liquefaction of gelatin, peptonization of milk and decomposition of casein, hypoxanthine, starch and urea, but negative for production of H<sub>2</sub>S and decomposition of adenine, guanine, l-tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>Utilizes adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, galactose, d-glucose, glycogen, glycerol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose as sole carbon sources, but not inositol, lactose, melezitose, raffinose, salicin or turanose.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-glucose, maltose, l-rhamnose and ribose, but not from adonitol, d-fructose, galactose, inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose, glucose, ribose and rhamnose (trace).</s><s>The diagnostic phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxyphosphatidylethanolamine and ninhydrin-positive phosphoglycolipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H and C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, QAIII60<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 4.4663<sup>T</sup>  = NBRC 106673<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from virgin forest soil of Kanas Nature Reserve, Xinjiang, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>