<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5183_nm.2563" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2563" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2563" rank="species">Pseudomonas antimicrobica</organism><reference id="rid.5183"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Attafuah</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bradbury</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas antimicrobica, a new species strongly antagonistic to plant pathogenes.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>67</volume><fpage>567</fpage><lpage>573</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas antimicrobica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The cells were straight, non-spore-forming rods, 0.5 x 0.8-1.5 μm, Occurring singly, in groups, and occasionally in pairs, Gram-negative, aerobic, heterotrophic and motile with one to two polar flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two colony types were observed on nutrient agar.</s><s>Those of one variant (NCIB 9897) were circular, raised, creamy-white and opaque, rugose: and butyrous with raised, microundulate margins at 5 d, while the other (NCIB 9898) was moist, smooth, glistening and slightly viscid with· entire margins and occasionally an orange tinge.</s><s>Nutrient broth cultures at 4 d showed turbidity and thin to membranous pellicles which broke easily when disturbed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A yellowish-orange, water-soluble, nonfluorescent pigment was produced in medium A and B of King et al. (1954), tyrosine medium, and various others.</s><s>An orange weakly diffusible pigment was produced in Czapek Dox, nutrient, and some other common laboratory agar media, but not in PDA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurred between 15° and 37°C, with a broad optimum around 30°C; there was no growth at 41°C.</s><s>Growth occurred in the presence of up to 4% sodium chloride, but weakened to a trace at 6%.</s><s>Levan type colonies were not produced; poly-β-hydroxybutyrate was not stored in the cells; no pectolytic activity or rotting of vegetable tissue was found.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but not gas was produced from arabinose, dulcitol, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, lactose, mannitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, sorbitol, and xylose, but not from maltose, raffinose, salicin or sucrose.</s><s>Utilization tests showed that N-acetylglucosamine, D-alanine, L-arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glucose, glutamate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, DL-hydroxybenzoate, <i>meso</i>-inositol, α-ketoglutarate, malonate, mannitol, Dmannose, phenylacetate, L-proline, propionate, and raffinose were used as sole carbon sources, but not adipate, D-<i>iso</i>-ascorbate, malate, or <i>meso</i>-tartrate.</s><s>Starch and ethanol were not assimilated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In litmus milk the dye was slowly reduced and a whitish sediment formed without curd; the final pH was slightly alkaline.</s><s>Positive results were observed for nitrate reductase, lecithinase, lipolysis, 2-ketogluconate production, aesculin hydrolysis, Simmons citrate and Leifson's malonate, and negative results for indole and hydrogen sulphide production, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate, denitrification, and hydrolysis of gelatin and cellulose.</s><s>L-Asparagine, ammonium and nitrate were all used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Vitamins and growth factors were not required.</s><s>A wide spectrum of antibiotic activity was present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The two variants showed only minor differences, mainly in colony morphology and were considered to belong to one species.</s></p></content></protolog>