<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.494_nm.5397" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5397" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5397" rank="species">Lactobacillus malefermentans</organism><reference id="rid.494"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nucleic acid studies on some heterofermentative lactobacilli: description of Lactobacillus malefermentans sp. nov. and Lactobacillus parabuchneri sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>55</volume><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Lactobacillus malefermentans sp.nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.8-1.0 × 1.5-2.5 μm), occurring singly, in pairs or chains. Cells and Gram-positive and non-motile; grow at 15 and 30°C; some strains grow at 10°C but not at 37°C; facultatively anaerobic; catalase negative; heterofermentative; gas is produced from glucose; acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, D-glucose, maltose, α-methyl-D-glucoside and ribose. Some strains produce acid from gluconate. Acid is not produced from adonitol, amidon, amygdaline, o-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fructose, D-fucose, L-fucose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, inositol, inulin, lactose, D-lyxose, D-mannose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, β-methylxyloside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, D-raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, L-sorbose, sorbitol, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, trehalose, D-xylose, L-xylose and xylitol; aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed; arginine dihydrolase positive; urease and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced; nitrate is not reduced to nitrite; Voges-Proskauer negative; the mol% G + C content of DNA ranges from 41 to 42; isolated from beer; the type strain is NCDO 1410. The description of the type strain corresponds with that of the species except acid is produced from gluconate.</s></p></content></protolog>