<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2477_nm.11412" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11412" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11412" rank="species">Vibrio rhizosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.2477"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ramesh Kumar</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nair</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio rhizosphaerae sp. nov., a red-pigmented bacterium that antagonizes phytopathogenic bacteria</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2241</fpage><lpage>2246</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65017-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio rhizosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio rhizosphaerae</em> (rhi.zo′sp.hae.rae. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhiza</em> root; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> -<em>ae</em> ball, any globe, sphere; N.L. gen. n. <em>rhizosphaerae</em> of the rhizosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods (approx. 1.8–3.2 μm long and 0.4–0.5 μm wide) and motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on agar media are red–pink, non-luminescent and circular, with entire margins.</s><s>Swarming is not detected.</s><s>Can inhibit a range of bacterial phytopathogens.</s><s>Facultative anaerobe capable of both aerobic and anaerobic fermentative growth.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from fermentation of glucose.</s><s>Other carbohydrates such as cellobiose, galactose, lactose, mannose, sucrose, xylose, mannitol and salicin are also fermented.</s><s>Trehalose, dulcitol, sorbitol and inositol are not fermented.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer, amylase, gelatinase, caseinase and lipase tests are positive, but arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25–30 °C and pH 7 and in 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 42 °C, but not at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0.1–10 % NaCl; no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows in mineral medium containing glucose and NH<sub>4</sub>Cl.</s><s>Cellobiose, galactose, glucose, lactose, mannose, melibiose, sucrose, xylose, mannitol, acetate, citrate, fumarate, pyruvate, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-serine and l-cysteine are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Utilizes trehalose, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, proline, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-threonine and l-glycine as sole sources of carbon and energy, only when grown on minimal salt agar medium, not in liquid medium.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSSRF3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23790<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18581<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of mangrove-associated wild rice (<em>Porteresia coarctata</em> Takeoka).</s></p></content></protolog>