<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5702_nm.9973" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9973" rank="genus">Millisia</organism><reference id="rid.5702"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Soddell</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stainsby</surname><given-names>F.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eales</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Millisia brevis gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from activated sludge foam.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>739</fpage><lpage>744</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63855-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Millisia</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Millisia</em> (Mil.li′si.a. N.L. fem. n. <em>Millisia</em> named after Professor Emeritus Nancy F. Millis AC, MBE, a celebrated Australian microbiologist who promoted wastewater microbiology in Australia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and previous studies (Soddell &#x0026; Seviour, 1998; Soddell <em>et al.</em>, 1998).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive to Gram-variable, acid–alcohol-fast, non-motile, catalase-positive actinomycetes that form non-spore-forming rods showing rudimentary right-angled branching and which contain polyphosphate storage granules.</s><s>Form salmon-pink, irregular colonies with filamentous margins and sparse, unbranched aerial hyphae on glucose/yeast extract agar.</s><s>Colonies are matt and dry in appearance, soft in texture and easy to emulsify.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Whole-organism hydrolysates are rich in <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>Contain <em>N</em>-glycolated muramic acid residues.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone has eight isoprene units, one of which is hydrogenated.</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides are the major polar lipids.</s><s>The mycolic acids present have 44–52 carbons (principal components C<sub>48</sub>, C<sub>50</sub> and C<sub>52</sub>).</s><s>Oleic, palmitic and palmitoleic acids are the predominant fatty acids, and there are relatively small proportions of myristic, stearic and tuberculostearic acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain of the type species is 64·7 mol%.</s><s>The genus forms a distinct lineage in the <em>Corynebacterineae</em> 16S rRNA gene tree.</s><s>The type species is <em>Millisia brevis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>