<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.23_nm.3387" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3387" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3387" rank="species">Pasteurella lymphangitidis</organism><reference id="rid.23"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stevens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus rossii sp. nov., Actinobacillus seminis sp. nov., nom. rev., Pasteurella bettii sp. nov., Pasteurella lymphangitidis sp. nov., Pasteurella mairi sp. nov., and Pasteurella trehalosi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella lymphangitidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella lymphangitidis</i> (lymph.ang.it'id.is. M.L. gen. n. <i>lymphangitidis</i>, pertaining to lymphangitis, inflammation of the lymph nodes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The BL (bovine lymphangitis) bacterium of Jayaraman and Sethumadavan (18); phenon 4 of Sneath and Stevens (46).</s><s>Cells are nonmotile bacilli, with some coccobacilli.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic and facultatively anaerobic, mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on sheep blood agar are round, greyish, semitransparent, about 2.5 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C, and nonhemolytic but sometimes showing greening of the erythrocytes.</s><s>Notable for not reducing nitrate, in being sensitive to azide, for acidifying arbutin, and for giving a negative oxidase reaction (46).</s><s>In our hands galactose and mannose were acidified, although both of these reactions were recorded as negative by Jayaraman and Sethumadavan (18).</s><s>Other properties are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from lymphangitis in <i>Bos indicus</i> in Southern India (18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Weak serological cross-reactions have been reported with <i>A. lignieresii</i> and <i>Yersinia pseudotuberculosis</i> (18).</s><s>Phenotypically, this organism has some weak affinities with members of the genus <i>Yersinia</i> (46), but is evidently allied to the <i>Actinobacillus-Pasteurella</i> complex (46).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA pairing tests show low values (less than 30%) to <i>P. multocida</i>, <i>P. pneumotropica</i>, <i>P. ureae</i>, <i>A. lignieresii</i>, <i>A. equuli</i>, and <i>A. suis</i> (13, 28).</s><s>In our hands this organism was variable for the tests marked d in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 49.7 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method) (28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 10547 (= Jayaraman strain I = A82 = 71) (28, 46).</s><s>In our hands this strain was negative for the tests marked d in Table 2, except for late reactions in the tests for acid production from maltose and salicin.</s></p></content></protolog>