<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9262_nm.14540" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14540" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14540" rank="species">Corynebacterium freiburgense</organism><reference id="rid.9262"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frodl</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Englert</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium freiburgense sp. nov., isolated from a wound obtained from a dog bite</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2054</fpage><lpage>2057</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008672-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605716</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium freiburgense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium freiburgense</em> (frei.bur.gen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>freiburgense</em> from Freiburg/Breisgau, Germany, named after the city where the bacterium was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>They are typically club-shaped rods that occur as single cells, in pairs or in small clusters.</s><s>Colonies are beige–whitish, dryish, convoluted with irregular edges, strongly adherent to sheep blood agar plates and up to 1–2 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation.</s><s>In 5-day-old colonies, a ‘spoke-wheel’ macroscopic morphology may be observed.</s><s>Weak anaerobic growth is observed.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, galactose, glucose, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, maltose, mannose, ribose, sucrose and tagatose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, lyxose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>The following enzyme activities can be detected: nitrate reductase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, urease, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, gelatinase, lipase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>The CAMP (Christie–Atkins–Munch-Petersen) reaction is negative.</s><s>The cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and mycolic acids are also present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 1045<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 56874<sup>T</sup> =DSM 45254<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a patient's wound obtained from a dog bite.</s></p></content></protolog>