<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6896_nm.3399" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3399" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3399" rank="species">Actinobacillus arthritidis</organism><reference id="rid.6896"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Angen</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Final classification of Bisgaard taxon 9 as Actinobacillus arthritidis sp. nov. and recognition of a novel genomospecies for equine strains of Actinobacillus lignieresii.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1239</fpage><lpage>1246</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02043-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinobacillus arthritidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinobacillus arthritidis</i> (ar.thri'ti.dis. N.L. fem. gen. n. <i>arthritidis</i> of arthritis, from Gr. n. <i>árthron</i> joint ; L. suffix -<i>itis</i> used in names of inflammations)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species is positive in the following tests : catalase, oxidase, fermentative reaction in Hugh-Leifson medium with (­+)D-glucose, porphyrin test, nitrate reduction, urease, alanine aminopeptidase, phosphatase, ONPG, α-galactosidase and production of acid from (-)D-ribose, (+­)D-xylose, (-)D-mannitol, (-)D-sorbitol, (-)D-fructose, (­+)D-galactose, (­+)D-glucose, (­+)D-mannose, lactose, sucrose and raffinose.</s><s>Negative results are obtained in the following tests: Gram-staining (pleomorphic without distinctive morphology), motility at 22 and 37°C, symbiotic growth, β-haemolysis, Simmons citrate, mucate-acid, malonate-base, H<sub>2</sub>S/TSI, growth in the presence of KCN, methyl red and Voges-Proskauer at 37°C, production of gas from nitrate, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, indole production, gelatinase, hydrolysis of Tweens 20 and 80, pigment production, α-glucosidase (PNPG), β-glucosidase (NPG), α-fucosidase (ONPF), α-glucuronidase (PGUA), α-mannosidase, β-xylosidase, production of acid from <i>m</i>-erythritol, adonitol, (+)D-arabitol, xylitol, (-)L-xylose, dulcitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, (+)D-fucose, (+)L-rhamnose, (-)L-sorbose, cellobiose, trehalose, (+)D-melezitose, (+)D-glycogen, inulin, aesculin, amygdalin, arbutin, gentiobiose, salicin, (+)D-turanose and β-N-CH<sub>3</sub>-glucosamid and formation of gas from (+)D-glucose.</s><s>Characteristics that show variation are listed in Table 2.</s><s>On bovineblood agar, the colonies are non-haemolytic, circular, raised and regular with entire margins.</s><s>The surface of the colonies is generally smooth, shiny, greyish and non-transparent.</s><s>Mucoid or watery cultures also exist.</s><s>A diameter of 2-3 mm is often observed after 24 h aerobic incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from the oral cavities of apparently healthy horses, as well as from diseased foals or horses (mainly those with septicaemia and arthritis) (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 24862<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 13376<sup>T</sup>= Wetmore 1706<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a joint of a horse.</s></p></content></protolog>