<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9285_nm.14571" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14571" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14571" rank="species">Novosphingobium indicum</organism><reference id="rid.9285"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novosphingobium indicum sp. nov., a polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-degrading bacterium isolated from a deep-sea environment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2084</fpage><lpage>2088</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002873-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Novosphingobium indicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Novosphingobium indicum</em> (in′di.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>indicum</em> Indian, referring to the Indian Ocean, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile rods without polar flagella, 1.1–1.4 μm long and 0.6–0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Positive for catalase, gelatinase and utilization of d-glucose, d-mannose and maltose using API 20NE, but negative for Gram-staining, oxidase, lipase (Tween 80 hydrolysis), urease, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, indole production and utilization of adipic acid, N-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, d-mannitol, l-arabinose, malic acid, phenylacetic acid, potassium gluconate and trisodium citrate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine aminopeptidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphoamidase, valine aminopeptidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, weakly positive for cystine aminopeptidase, lipase (C14) and <em>α</em>-glucosidase and negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–41 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), but not at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose.</s><s>Able to reduce nitrate to nitrite, but incapable of denitrification.</s><s>On 216L agar plates, produces smooth, round, yellow colonies with regular edges, slightly raised in the centre, 1–2 mm in diameter after 72 h incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Principal fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Of 95 substrates in the Biolog GN2 system, positive for utilization of <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-mannose, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, Tweens 40 and 80, maltose, methyl pyruvate and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>Sensitive to (per disc) ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cefazolin (30 μg), cefobid (30 μg), cephradin (30 μg), chloromycetin (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), co-trimoxazole (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), minomycin (30 μg), neomycin (10 μg), ofloxacin (5 μg), penicillin G (10 μg), piperacillin (100 μg), rocephin (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg); resistant to cefalexin (30 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), furazolidone (15 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), metronidazole (5 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), oxacillin (1 μg), polymyxin B (30 U), streptomycin (10 μg) and vibramycin (30 μg).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 62 mol%.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone 10 and the major polyamine is spermidine.</s><s>Table 1 shows characteristics used to distinguish the type strain from type strains of related species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, H25<sup>T</sup> (=MCCC 1A01080<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.6784<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24713<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from deep-sea water in December 2005.</s></p></content></protolog>