<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10588_nm.17840" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17840" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17840" rank="species">Epilithonimonas lactis</organism><reference id="rid.10588"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shakéd</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hantsis-Zacharov</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halpern</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Epilithonimonas lactis sp. nov., isolated from raw cow'smilk</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>675</fpage><lpage>679</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012575-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656919</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Epilithonimonas lactis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Epilithonimonas lactis</em> (<em>lac′tis</em>. L. gen. n. <em>lactis</em> of milk, referring to the isolation of the type strain from raw milk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative rods, 0.7–0.9 μm in width and 1.1–2.2 μm in length, devoid of flagellar motility.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation on standard plate count agar at 30 °C in the dark, colonies are circular with entire edges, opaque, smooth and orange-coloured.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Good growth occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth is not observed after five days under anaerobic conditions on LB agar supplemented with 0.1 % (w/v) potassium nitrate or 0.5 % glucose.</s><s>Grows at 5–33 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C), with 0–2.0 % NaCl (optimum, 0–0.5 % NaCl) and at pH 4.0–8.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–8.0).</s><s>Growth is observed on standard plate count, nutrient and trypticase-soy agars but not on MacConkey and cetrimide agars.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>The following results were obtained from API 20NE strips after 48 h of incubation at 25 °C: indole is produced; <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity is present; aesculin is hydrolysed; glucose and maltose are assimilated.</s><s>The following results were obtained from API 20E strips after 24 h of incubation at 25 °C: acetoin and indole are produced; H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced; gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed; citrate is not utilized; <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity is present; arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>In API 50CH strips incubated for 48 h at 25 °C, oxidative acid production occurs for glucose, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose, while oxidative acid production does not occur for glycerol, erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API ZYM strips incubated for 4.5 h at 25 °C, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine and valine arylamidases, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities are present; lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities are weakly present.</s><s>Trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The dominant (&#x003E;10 %) cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid composition of strain H1<sup>T</sup> is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is H1<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24401<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19921<sup>T</sup>), isolated from raw cow'smilk in Israel.</s></p></content></protolog>