<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1354_nm.8270" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8270" rank="genus">Cytophaga</organism><reference id="rid.1354"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the genus Cytophaga and transfer of Cytophaga agarovorans and Cytophaga salmonicolor to Marinilabilia gen. nov.: phylogenetic analysis of the Flavobacterium-Cytophaga complex.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>599</fpage><lpage>603</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Cytophaga</i> Winogradsky 1929,577<sup>AL</sup>, emend.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are short to moderately long flexible rods that are 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide and 2 to 10 μm long and have slightly tapered ends. Resting stages are absent. Motile by gliding. Gram negative. The cell mass is usually pigmented yellow to orange because of cell-bound carotenoids, flexirubin type pigments, or both. When covered with alkali (e.g., a 20% KOH solution [flexirubin reaction]), colonies may reversibly change color from yellow to purple- or red-brown. Oxidase positive and catalase negative. Strict aerobes. Chemoorganotrophs. Metabolism is respiratory. Organic acids may also be produced during growth. All strains decompose crystalline cellulose (filter paper). The optimum temperature is 20 to 30°C. The optimum pH is around 7. Common in soil. The major polyamine is homospermidine. The quinone is MK-7. The G+C content of the DNA is 39 to 42 mol%. The type species is <i>Cytophaga hutchinsonii</i>. The other species in the genus is <i>Cytophaga aurantiaca</i>. These two species can be differentiated by the color of the cell mass, the flexirubin reaction, and the optimum temperature (17).</s></p></content></protolog>