<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.58_nm.10650" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10650" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3809" rank="species">Campylobacter pylori</organism><reference id="rid.58"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Edmonds</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter pylori subsp. mustelae subsp. nov. isolated from the gastric mucosa of ferrets, Mustela putorius furo, and an emended description of Campylobacter pylori.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>367</fpage><lpage>370</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-367</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Campylobacter pylori</i> (Marshall, Royce, Annear, Goodwin, Pearman, Warren, and Armstrong 1984) Marshall and Goodwin 1987.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Fastidious, gram-negative microaerophilic, nonencapsulated, curved rods. Cells are 3 to 5 μm long and 0.5 to 1 μm wide with a spiral periodicity (14). Darting motility by means of multiple sheathed polar flagella or lateral flagella with terminal bulbs or both. Poor growth in most liquid media; grows in 2 to 5 days on brain heart infusion broth or agar, blood agar, and chocolate agar. Colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, and 1 mm in diameter (1416). Optimal growth at 37°C, no growth at 25°C, growth at 30°C, and variable growth at 42°C. No growth in the presence of 3% NaCl. Variable growth in 0.04% triphenyltetrazolium chloride and 1% glycine. Catalase positive. H<sub>2</sub>S production is negative on triple sugar iron agar and is variable on lead acetate paper. Urea is rapidly hydrolyzed. Variable reactions for nitrate reduction and hippurate hydrolysis. Variable susceptibility to nalidixic acid, cephalothin, and metronidazole. Susceptible to ampicillin, amoxicillin, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, penicillin, rifampin, and tetracycline (11, 14). Resistant to vancomycin, lincomycin, and colistin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the gastric mucosa of humans and ferrets.</s><s>In humans, isolates found in cases of gastritis and gastric ulcers, but the role of the organism in these diseases, if any, has not been established.</s><s>In ferrets, strains are isolated from normal or inflamed gastric mucosa obtained from either laboratory-maintained animals or pets.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content in 36 to 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Royal Perth Hospital Isolate 13487 (= NCTC 11637 = ATCC 43504).</s><s>It has a G+C content of 37 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>