<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7142_nm.4475" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4475" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4475" rank="species">Anaerobaculum thermoterrenum</organism><reference id="rid.7142"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rees</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grassia</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheehy</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerobaculum thermoterrenum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel, thermophilic bacterium which ferments citrate.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>150</fpage><lpage>154</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-150</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995817</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerobaculum thermoterrenum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerobaculum thermoterrenum</i> (ther.mo.ter.re'num. Gr. adj. <i>thermus</i>, warm, hot; L. adj. <i>terrenum</i>, earthen, belonging to the earth; M. L. adj. <i>thermoterrenum</i>, from hot earth, describing the site of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.75 by 2 μm and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Grows very slowly at 28°C, and the maximum temperature for growth is 60°C; the optimum temperature is 55°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium containing 0 to 20 g of NaCl per liter; the optimum salinity is about 10 g/liter.</s><s>Growth occurs at pHs ranging from 5.5 to 8.6, and the optimum pH is between 7 and 7.6.</s><s>Ferments citrate, fumarate, malate, pyruvate, glutamate, α-ketoglutarate, tartrate, starch, pectin, glucose, fructose, mannose, inositol, glycerol, protein extracts, and Casamino Acids.</s><s>Compounds that are not used are xylose, galactose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, rhamnose, raffinose, cellulose, carboxymethyl cellulose, gum arabic, malonate, succinate, glutarate, and lactate.</s><s>Sulfide is produced when the organism is grown in the presence of elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, and cystine.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, and nitrate are not reduced.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 44 mol% G+C (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Cytochromes are not present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from production fluid of a petroleum reservoir.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is RWcit2, which has been deposited in the Australian Collection of Microorganisms (University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia) as strain ACM 5076.</s></p></content></protolog>