<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8720_nm.13677" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13677" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13677" rank="species">Virgibacillus kekensis</organism><reference id="rid.8720"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chai</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus kekensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake in China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>647</fpage><lpage>653</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65365-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus kekensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus kekensis</em> (ke.ken′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kekensis</em> pertaining to salt lake Keke in Qinghai Province, north-west China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, motile, Gram-positive rods (2.0–3.0×0.3–0.5 μm) that occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in terminally swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 3 days on MA supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl at 37 °C, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular to slightly irregular, raised, translucent, creamy grey-coloured and slightly transparent at the edges.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–25 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum, 10 % (w/v) NaCl] at 10–50 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 7.0).</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose, chitin, aesculin, gelatin, and Tweens 20 and 80 are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Cells are resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (20 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg), but susceptible to ampicillin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, glycogen, d-mannose, d-mannitol, salicin, starch and maltose, but not from amygdalin, inositol, potassium 5-ketogluconate, sucrose, d-sorbitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, aesculin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-malic acid, monomethylsuccinate, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, 2′-deoxyadenosine and inosine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are catalase, cytochrome oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase; lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7 (93 %), with significant amounts of MK-6 (6 %) and minor amounts of MK-8 (1 %) also present.</s><s>Polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and two unknown phospholipids.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids (making up 84.9 % of the total) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM kkny16<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17056<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6298<sup>T</sup>), which is the isolate on which the species description is based.</s><s>It was isolated from a saline mud sample collected from the Keke salt lake in the Qaidam basin in Qinghai Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>