<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3839_nm.5466" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5466" rank="genus">Abiotrophia</organism><reference id="rid.3839"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kawamura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>X.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sultana</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Streptococcus adjacens and Streptococcus defectivus to Abiotrophia gen. nov. as Abiotrophia adiacens comb. nov. and Abiotrophia defectiva comb. nov., respectively.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>798</fpage><lpage>803</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-798</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547302</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Abiotrophia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Abiotrophia</i> (Abi. o. tro'phi. a. G. prefix <i>a</i>-, negative (un-); G. n. <i>bios</i>, life; G. n. <i>trophe</i>, nutrition; M. L. n. <i>Abiotrophia</i>, life nutrition deficiency)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from this study and previously described studies (1, 3, 5, 10, 24).</s><s>Cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, and gram positive.</s><s>Cells are mainly cocci, but pleomorphic ovoid cells, coccobacilli, and rod-shaped cells may occur in THB or CBA supplemented with pyridoxal hydrochloride or L-cysteine.</s><s>Facultative anaerobes.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Lactic acid is the compound that is predominantly produced during glucose fermentation.</s><s>Does not produce gas from glucose.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 and 45°C or in the presence of 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Nutritionally fastidious.</s><s>No or slight growth occurs in THB or on CBA.</s><s>Sulfydryl compounds (0.01% L-cysteine is usually used) or vitamin B, (0.001% pyridoxal hydrochloride is usually used) is required for growth.</s><s>Grows as satellite colonies adjacent to <i>Staphylococcus epidermidis</i> on blood agar.</s><s>Alpha-hemolytic on sheep blood agar supplemented with 0.01% L-cysteine or 0.001% pyridoxal hydrochloride.</s><s>PYR positive.</s><s>Resistant to optochin and susceptible to vancomycin.</s><s>L-Lysine is the diamino acid at position 3, and alanine or alaninealanine is the peptide cross bridge, so the presumptive peptide type is type A3α.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36.6 to 46.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of the genus <i>Abiotrophia</i> is <i>Abiotrophia defectiva</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tests that are useful for distinguishing the genus <i>Abiotrophia</i> from other catalase-negative, gram-positive cocci are shown in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>