<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.14945" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14945" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4964" rank="species">Bacillus pseudalcalophilus</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus pseudalcalophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus pseudalcalophilus</i> (pseu.dal.ca.lo'phi.lus, Gr. adj. <i>pseudes</i> false; specific epithet <i>alcalophilus</i>; ML adj. <i>pseudalcalophilus</i>, false <i>alcalophilus</i> because it is phenotypically closely related to <i>B. alcalophilus</i> but phylogenetically distinct)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from this study for strains of DNA hybridization group 9.</s><s>Colonies are white and circular with an undulate margin.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped (0.5-0.6 x 2.0-4.0 μm) and produce ellipsoidal spores (0.5-0.7 x 0.8-1.3 μm) which swell the sporangium and are situated paracentrally to subterminally.</s><s>Strains of this species hydrolyse casein, gelatin, starch and pullulan, but hippurate, MUG and Tween 20 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Phenylalanine is not deaminated and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>No growth is obtained at pH 7.0 and the optimum is about pH 10.0.</s><s>All strains grow from 10-40 °C.</s><s>Strains tolerate up to 10% NaCl.</s><s>Carbohydrate utilization profiles show growth on L-arabinose or galactose, with some strains able to grow on tagatose or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>No growth is observed on inositol, xylitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, N-acetylglucosamine or mannose.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 38.2 and 39.0 mol % G +C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil samples.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-137 (= DSM 8725).</s></p></content></protolog>