<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4550_nm.2513" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2513" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2513" rank="species">Halomonas maura</organism><reference id="rid.4550"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouchotroch</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>del Moral</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bejar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas maura sp. nov., a novel moderately halophilic, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1625</fpage><lpage>1632</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594589</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas maura</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas maura</i> (mau'ra. L. adj. <i>maurus</i> northwest African)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 6.9¬0.5-0.7 μm, occurring either singly or in pairs, occasionally as long filaments.</s><s>Cells are capsulated, non-motile and accumulate PHA.</s><s>Does not form endospores.</s><s>Colonies on MY medium are circular, convex, mucoid and cream-coloured; they are 2-3 mm in diameter after 24 h, but reach more than 5 mm in diameter and are considerably mucoid after 72 h at 32 °C.</s><s>Moderate halophile, capable of growth in salt concentrations of between 1 and 15% (w/v).</s><s>Optimum growth occurs in 7.5-10.0% (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salts.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 10 and 40 °C (optimum growth at 32 °C) and at pH values between 6 and 9 (optimum growth at pH 7.2).</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is of the respiratory type, with oxygen as the terminal acceptor.</s><s>Capable of anaerobic growth in the presence of nitrate, but not in the presence of fumarate.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Does not produce acids from sugars.</s><s>Selenite is reduced and gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from peptones and Tween 20 is hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges-Proskauer are negative.</s><s>Aesculin, tyrosine, DNA, gelatin, casein, urea, lecithin and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Blood is not haemolysed.</s><s>Phenylalanine deamination, growth on MY medium using the anaerobic Gas Pack System and growth on cetrimide agar are all negative.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-gluconate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, DL-lactate, maltose, D-mannose, propionate, D-sorbitol and sucrose.</s><s>Formate, D-salicin and L-sorbose are not used.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: L-alanine, L-arginine, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-serine and L-valine.</s><s>Cysteine and L-tryptophan are not used.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin, ampicillin, cephalothin, cefoxitin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, polymixin, rifampicin and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole, but resistant to tetracycline and vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Isolated from soil samples from a solar saltern at Asilah (Morocco).</s><s>DNA G­+C content is 62.2-64.1 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>The type strain is strain S-31<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5298<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13445<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>Additionally, phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on KCN and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Starch hydrolysis and ONPG are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: citrate, ethanol, fumarate, D-fructose, glycerol, D-rhamnose and D-ribose; it does not use lactose or D-trehalose.</s><s>It is susceptible to gentamicin, penicillin, sulfonamide and tobramycin, but resistant to erythromycin.</s><s>Its DNA G­+C content is 64.1 mol% (Tm method).</s><s>It grows best in 9%(w/v) salts and has strict and specific requirements for Na<sup>+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup>.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration is 1.2 M; the optimum MgCl<sub>2</sub>⋄6H<sub>2</sub>O concentration is 0.2 M.</s><s>The major (up to 81%) fatty acids are 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>/2-OH i15:0 and 16:0.</s><s>This bacterium produces an exopolysaccharide, named EPS S-31, which is of potential industrial use as a viscosifier and emulsifier.</s><s>The physical and chemical properties of this polymer are described elsewhere (Bouchotroch et al., 2000).</s><s>Briefly, it is composed of the neutral sugars glucose, mannose and galactose at a ratio of 1:4:2.5.</s><s>The EPS aqueous solution (1%, w/v) attains a viscosity of 10.98 Pa s<sup>-1</sup> at 4.5 Pa shear rate.</s><s>EPS S-31 is able to emulsify crude oil more efficiently than some chemical surfactants such as Triton X-100 and Span 60.</s></p></content></protolog>