<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7768" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7768" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7768" rank="species">Chlamydia muridarum</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> sp. nov., including hamster and mouse isolates previously belonging to <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> (mu.ri.da'rum. M.L. pl. gen. fem. n. <i>muridarum</i> of the Muridae (i.e. the mouse/hamster family))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two strains of <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i>, MoPn and SFPD (Fox et al., 1993; Nigg, 1942; Stills et al., 1991), have been isolated from mice and hamsters.</s><s>The recently reconstructed family Muridae includes both mice and hamsters (Alderton, 1996).</s><s>The <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> 16s rRNA genes that have been sequenced to date differ by &#x003C; 0.13 % (using updated SFPD sequence data), and their 16s-23s intergenic spacers and 23s domain I segments are identical.</s><s>Analyses of other gene sequences can also identify this species.</s><s>Glycogen production by both strains has been demonstrated, although it is difficult to detect in MoPn (Moulder et al., 1984).</s><s>MoPn has an extrachromosomal plasmid, pMoPn. <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> MoPn binds mAbs recognizing <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> MOMP vs4 core epitope (T)LNPT(IA) (Peterson et al., 1991).</s><s>DNA sequence analysis indicates that these mAbs should recognize SFPD and that <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> B-serogroup mAbs specific for the vs4 epitope IAGAG should recognize SFPD (Batteiger et al., 1996).</s><s>MoPn was isolated in 1942 from the lungs of asymptomatic albino Swiss mice and was subsequently shown to be capable of producing disease in mice.</s><s>SFPD was obtained from a hamster, concurrent with a causative agent of proliferative ileitis.</s><s>MoPn has been shown to be sensitive to sulfadiazine.</s><s>The type strain for <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> is MoPn<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC VR 123<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>