<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7551_nm.8415" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8415" rank="genus">Xiphinematobacter</organism><reference id="rid.7551"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname><given-names>T.T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coomans</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Occurrence of novel verrucomicrobial species, endosymbiotic and associated with parthenogenesis in Xiphinema americanum-group species (Nematoda, Longidoridae)</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2197</fpage><lpage>2205</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155997</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of '<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter' gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Xiphinematobacter (Xi.phi.ne.ma.to.bac'ter. Gr. neut. n. <i>Xiphinema</i> the generic name of the host organism, gen. <i>Xiphinematos</i>, stem <i>Xiphinemat</i>-; Gr. connecting vowel o; N.L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i> the equivalent of Gr. n. neut. <i>baktron</i> a rod; N.L. masc. n. <i>Xiphinematobacter</i> the rod-shaped microbe associated with <i>Xiphinema</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-motile, non-sporulating, rod-shaped bacteria with rounded ends, belonging to subdivision 2 of the <i>Verrucomicrobia</i> on the basis of their 16S rDNA sequence, but lacking the characteristic prosthecae found in <i>Verrucomicrobium spinosum</i> and <i>Prosthecobacter fusiformis</i>.</s><s>The cell wall does not contain a TEM-discernible peptidoglycan layer, but a hexagonally arrayed monolayer of 10 nm protein units may be attached to the internal face of the outer membrane.</s><s>Cells are bounded by a two- or three-layered envelope, consisting of the bacterial plasma membrane, an intensely electron-dense outer membrane and the surrounding vacuolar membrane (sometimes absent) of the host.</s><s>The bacteria measure 0.7-1.0 μmx2.1-3.2 μm (TEM) and multiply by unipolar growth followed by constriction, daughter cells often occurring as serial pairs.</s><s>Nucleoid often concentrated into one or two polar chromatin-like clumps distinguishable by TEM or DAPI.</s><s>Bacteria live as obligate cytoplasmic symbionts with maternal transmission in nematodes of the <i>Xiphinema americanum</i> group (Nematoda, Longidoridae), where they first populate the gut epithelium and only later infect the ovaries in great numbers, especially the ovarial wall cells. <i>Xiphinematobacter</i> are presumed to induce thelytokous parthenogenesis in their hosts.</s><s>Type species is `<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter brevicolli' sp. nov.</s><s>The internal 16S rDNA distance between the endosymbiont species is approximately 7%, whereas the closest relative, clone WCHD3-88, is more than 13%distant, on average.</s><s>Fig. 1 in this paper may serve to illustrate morphological characters pertinent to the classification, in the genus `<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter' gen. nov., of the following three species: `<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter brevicolli ' sp. nov., `<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter americani' sp. nov. and `<i>Candidatus</i> Xiphinematobacter rivesi ' sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>