<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7213_nm.8295" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8295" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8295" rank="species">Dyadobacter fermentans</organism><reference id="rid.7213"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chelius</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Triplett</surname><given-names>E.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dyadobacter fermentans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel gram-negative bacterium isolated from surface-sterilized Zea mays stems.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>751</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758885</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dyadobacter fermentans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dyadobacter fermentans</i> (fer.men'tans. L. part. <i>fermentans</i> causing fermentation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those described for the genus.</s><s>This strain can grow on acetate, D- and L-arabitol, amidon, fumarate, 5-ketogluconate, glucose, glycerol, D-lyxose, malate, malonate, sucrose, tartrate, erythritol, D- and L-arabinose, D- and L-xylose, β-methylxyloside, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, mannose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdaline, arbutine, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, saccharose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-tagatose, and D- and L- fucose.</s><s>It can ferment glucose and sucrose and produce acid from ribose.</s><s>This strain cannot hydrolyse agar, cellulose, gelatin or starch.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C.</s><s>The principal fatty acids are 43∙5% 15:0iso 2-OH/16:1ω7c, 17∙5% 16:1ω5c and 16∙8% 15 : 0iso.</s><s>The type strain, NS114T, was isolated from surface-sterilized <i>Zea mays</i> (cv. Mo17) stem and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700827T.</s></p></content></protolog>