<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4044_nm.3239" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3239" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3239" rank="subspecies">Pantoea stewartii indologenes</organism><reference id="rid.4044"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verdonck</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Erwinia ananas, synonym, Erwinia uredovora and Erwinia stewartii to the genus Pantoea emend. as Pantoea ananas, Serrano 1928 comb. nov. and Pantoea stewartii, Smith 1898 comb. nov., respectively, and description of Pantoea stewartii subsp. indologenes subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>162</fpage><lpage>173</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-162</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> (in.do.lo'gen.es. M. L. n. <i>indolum</i>, indole; Gr. n. <i>gennao</i>, to produce; M. L. adj. <i>indologenes</i>, indole producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The subspecies has all of the characteristics of the species.</s><s>The description below is based on the data obtained for the 10 strains listed in Table 1.</s><s>Many strains grow at 4 and 37째C and some strains grow at 41째C, but few strains grow at 44째C.</s><s>The biochemical and nutritional characteristics at 30째C and characteristics that distinguish this subspecies from <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i> are shown in Tables 2 and 4.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Growth occurs on <i>cis</i>-aconitate and <i>meso</i>-tartrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, maltose, lactose, arbutin, salicin, and D-arabitol.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid composition is shown in Table 3.</s><s>The main fatty acids are (in order of decreasing relative content) hexadecanoic acid (C<sub>16:0</sub>), straight-chain octadecenoic acids <sub>18:1</sub>, and <i>cis</i>-9-hexadecenoic acid cis <sub>16:1 <i>cis</i> 9</sub>.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of three strains are 53.6 mol% (43), 54.5 mol%, and 56.4 mol% (this study).</s><s>Strains of <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> are thought to cause leaf spot on foxtail millet (Setaria italica) and pearl millet (<i>Pennisetum americanum</i>) and rot of <i>A. comosus</i>; one strain was isolated from cluster bean (<i>Cyamopsis tetragonolobus</i>).</s><s>The type strain is strain LMG 2632 (= NCPPB 2280 = ICMP 77); its characteristics are shown in Table 2, and the G+C content of its DNA is 56.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>