<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4692_nm.2808" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2808" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2808" rank="species">Alteromonas atlantica</organism><reference id="rid.4692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akagawa-Matsushita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alteromonas atlantica sp. nov. and Alteromonas carrageenovora sp. nov., bacteria that decompose algal polysaccharides.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>621</fpage><lpage>627</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-621</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas atlantica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas atlantica</i> (at.lan'.ti.ca. Gr.adj. <i>atlantica</i>, of the Atlantic [Ocean])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, polarly flagellated bacterium isolated from seaweeds.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped, with rounded ends, and are 0.5 to 0.8 μm in diameter and 1.5 to 2.3 μm long when the organism is grown on marine agar 2216 medium (catalog no. 0979; Difco); the cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Peritrichous flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solidified media.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 medium are beige to pale yellow orange, are smooth and convex with entire edge, and grow to a diameter of 7.0 to 10.0 mm in 5 days at 25°C.</s><s>The colonies on agar media were strongly depressed by agarase activity.</s><s>Sodium ion is essential for growth.</s><s>Are mesophilic and neutrophilic chemoorganotrophs which grow at temperatures between 5 and 35°C and at pHs between 5.5 and 8.5.</s><s>They never grow at 40°C and pH 5.0.</s><s>All strains except IAM 12927<sup>T</sup> grow at pH 9.0.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose and mannitol.</s><s>Are positive for hydrolyses of esculin, Tween 80, gelatin, casein, starch, DNA, alginate, and agar.</s><s>Chitinase is not produced.</s><s>Are positive for oxidase and catalase; in the <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside (ONPG) test; and for tyrosine decomposition, phosphatase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, litmus milk coagulation, and methylene blue reduction.</s><s>Are negative for nitrate reduction, denitrification, cell pigmentation, amidase, xanthine decomposition, indole production, 2-ketogluconate production from gluconate, 3-ketolactose production from lactose, citrate utilization, 0/129 sensitivity, growth on medium containing 0.4% phenethyl alcohol, and deaminases for tryptophan and phenylalanine; are negative in the methyl red test; and are negative for curdlan-like polysaccharide production.</s><s>Some strains produce carrageenase, urease, acetylmethylcarbinol, and melanin-like dark pigment on tyrosine-containing medium.</s><s>Luminescence is never observed.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, <i>n</i>-valerate, isovalerate, pelargonate, caprate, oxalate, succinate, aconitate, citrate, glycerol, galactose, glucose, fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, amygdalin, esculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, and L-glutamate are utilized by 67% or more of the strains as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized by at least 67% of the strains: <i>n</i>-caproate, caprylate, malonate, maleate, glutarate, adipate, pimerate, suberate, azerate, sebacate, glycolate, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, D-malate, L-malate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate , levulinate, 2-ketoglutarate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, tea-phthalate, glycine, D-α-alanine, L-α-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-norleucine, L-valine, DL-norvaline, DL-2-aminobutyrate, L-serine, L-threonine, L-cysteine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, L-histidine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, trigonelline, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-ornithine, L-lysine, L-citrulline, DL-kynurenine, L-proline, betaine, creatine, β-alanine, DL-3-aminobutyate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovarelate, 2-aminobenzoate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, urea, acetoamide, sarcosine, ethylamine, butylamine, amylamine, ethanolamine, benzylamine, 1,4-diaminobut ane, spermine, histamine, tryptamine, D-glucosamine, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methy-D-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, arbutin, salicine, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 40.6 to 41.7 mol%.</s><s>Isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from marine macroalgae collected from both the Atlantic and Pacific coastal areas.</s><s>The type strain is IAM 12927 (=NCIMB 301, =ATCC 19262).</s><s>Strains 512-M, 512-<sup>T</sup>, 512-W, 511-<sup>T</sup>, and T9 were deposited to the Institute of Applied Microbiology culture collection as IAM 14161, IAM 14162, IAM 14163, IAM 14164, and IAM 14165, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>