<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3397_nm.8089" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8089" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8089" rank="species">Flavobacterium gleum</organism><reference id="rid.3397"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Owen</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium gleum, a new species found in human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>21</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-1-21</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium gleum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium gleum</i> (gle'um. Gr. neu. adj. <i>gloion</i> slippery, sticky; M. L. neu. adj. <i>gleum</i> sticky)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics for which all 12 strains of <i>F. gleum</i> gave either positive results or negative results are listed below.</s><s>The characteristics for which the 12 strains gave different results are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods of regular shape with rounded ends.</s><s>Nonmotile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular, entire colonies that are viscid or butyrous in consistency develop on nutrient agar, becoming mucoid and translucent after incubation for 5 days.</s><s>Colonies nonhemolytic on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar.</s><s>On nutrient agar, a bright yellow pigment is produced, which is not fluorescent and turns red upon addition of 20% KOH.</s><s>A water-soluble brown pigment is produced on tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at room temperature and at 37°C but not at 5°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not tolerate KCN at a concentration of 0.0075% (wt/vol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 20.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of indole (Ehrlich reagent); no production of indole (Kovacs reagent).</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of hydrogen sulfide (lead acetate paper and triple sugar iron agar methods).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on MacConkey agar, but not on cetrimide agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Casein digested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of esculin and tributyrin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No utilization of citrate (Simmons medium) or malonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No oxidation of gluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of arginine deimidase, arginine deiminase, lysine decarboxylase, or ornithine decarbosylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of 3-ketolactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of selenite and no deamination of phenylalanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of phosphatase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, fructose, maltose, and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from adonitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, inostol, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, or sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose or 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of gas from glucose in peptone-water medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of the following substrates (using API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 8.5; L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide; L-valyl-2-naphthylamide; 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 5.4; naphthol-AS-B1-phosphodiamide; 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside; 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide; bis-(<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl)phosphate; 4-methylumbelliferylcellobiopyranoside; L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide; L-lysyl-β-naphthylamide; L- histidyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-aspartyl-β-naphthylamide; L-arginyl-β-naphthylamide; L-alanyl-β-naphthylamide; α-L-glutamyl-anaphthylamide; DL-methionyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide hydrobromide; gly-cyl-L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide; L-leucyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-seryl-L-tyrosyl-β-naphthylamide; L-glutamine-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; α-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide; L-isoleucyl-β-naphthylamide; L-ornithyl-β-naphthylamide; L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; L-seryl-β-naphthylamide; L-threonyl-β-naphthylamide; L-tryptophyl-β-naphthylamide; N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginine-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No hydrolysis of the following substrates (using API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl butyrate; 2-naphthyl myristate; L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide; N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide; N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside; 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside; naphthol-AS-B1-β-D-glucuronic acid; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside; 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-xylopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-fucopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-L-fucopyranoside; <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-lactoside; <i>p</i>-nitrocathechol-sulfate; 4-methylumbelliferylarabinopyranoside; L-hydroxyprolyl-β-naphthylamide; N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 37.6±1.0 mol%, and the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 37.0 mol%, as estimated by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following two additional strains of <i>F. gleum</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: group IIb strain 3531 (= NCTC 10795) and strain F129 (= NCTC 11433).</s></p></content></protolog>