<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1684_nm.11476" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11476" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11476" rank="species">Labedella gwakjiensis</organism><reference id="rid.1684"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Labedella gwakjiensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinomycete of the family Microbacteriaceae</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2498</fpage><lpage>2502</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64591-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978208</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Labedella gwakjiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Labedella gwakjiensis</em> (gwak.ji.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>gwakjiensis</em> pertaining to Gwakji Beach, Jeju, Republic of Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 1.0–4.4 μm in length and 0.30–0.38 μm in width.</s><s>On TSA, colonies are smooth, circular, convex, translucent and yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.1–10.1, with optimum growth at pH 7.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase but negative for urease.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, DNA and starch.</s><s>Casein and elastin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production is observed.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin, but negative for indole production, glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase (API 20NE).</s><s>d-Glucose, d-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources but utilization of maltose, gluconate, caproate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate is not observed (API 20NE).</s><s>Under aerobic conditions, acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, d-xylose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-arabinose, melibiose, l-ribose, l-sorbose, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-erythritol, 1,2-propanediol or d-xylitol.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from d-lactose, maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and trehalose.</s><s>In the tests with the API ZYM system, positive for leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8) but negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>α</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (49.4 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (20.5 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (11.4 %).</s><s>Tuberculostearic acid (10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>) is also present as a minor component.</s><s>Polar lipids contain phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KSW2-17<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14008<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19176<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a dried seaweed sample collected around Gwakji Beach in Jeju, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>