<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.207_nm.1296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1296" rank="species">Rhizobium mediterraneum</organism><reference id="rid.207"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nour</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleyet-Marel</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genomic heterogeneity of strains nodulating chickpeas (Cicer arietinum L.) and description of Rhizobium mediterraneum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>640</fpage><lpage>648</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-640</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium mediterraneum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium mediterraneum</i> (med.i.ter.ra'ne.um. L. adj. <i>mediterraneum</i>, of the Mediterranean, one of the primary centers of origin from which chickpea plants were disseminated throughout the world)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Colonies on yeast extract-mannitol agar are convex, opaque, and 2 mm in diameter within 4 to 5 days when cultures are incubated at 28°C. <i>R. mediterraneum</i> can be differentiated from other species belonging to the <i>Rhizobiaceae</i> by the following characteristics: total 16s rRNA sequence, DNA-DNA relatedness data, multilocus enzyme electrophoresis data (24), and polymorphism of the 16s IGS rDNA.</s><s>Two representative strains of the species, UPM-Ca36<sup>T</sup> and UPM-Ca142, which have been studied previously by performing different phenotypic tests and an isozyme polymorphism analysis (24), clearly group together and are separated from the other chickpea isolates.</s><s>These two strains have the following characteristics in common with the other group A strains (24): the maximum temperature for growth is 40°C, they are able to grow on minimal media, they tolerate 2% (wt/vol) NaCl, and they grow at pH 9.5.</s><s>The characteristics that differentiate UPM-Ca36<sup>T</sup> and UPM-Ca142 from <i>R. ciceri</i> are their inability to grow at pH 10 and 5, their susceptibility to carbenicillin, and their resistance to chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>Strain UPM-Ca36, which was isolated from nodulated chickpeas grown in Spain, is the type strain.</s><s>This strain has the characteristics described above for <i>R. mediterraneum</i> sp. nov.</s><s>Strain UPM-Ca36<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the American Type</s></p><p class="description"><s>Culture Collection.</s></p></content></protolog>