<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10585_nm.17837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17837" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17837" rank="species">Niastella populi</organism><reference id="rid.10585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rahman</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Niastella populi sp. nov., isolated from soil of Euphrates poplar (Populus euphratica) forest, and emended description of the genus Niastella</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>542</fpage><lpage>545</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012112-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Niastella populi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Niastella populi</em> (po′pu.li. L. gen. n. <em>populi</em> of a poplar, pertaining to <em>Populus</em>, the Latin name of the poplars that grow in the forest from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-staining-negative, filamentous rods approximately 0.2–0.5 μm wide and 6–30 μm long (see Supplementary Fig. S2 available in IJSEM Online) and are devoid of flagella and exhibit no gliding motility.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are rough, convex, irregular and yellow-coloured.</s><s>Growth occurs at 17–37 °C, at pH 5.0–8.0 and in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl (w/v); growth is optimal at 30 °C, at pH 7.0 and in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows on R2A, NA and TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-negative.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not produced and Congo red is not absorbed.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>Chitin, carboxymethylcellulose, starch, tyrosine, agar and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In API 20NE and API ID 32GN strips, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamine, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, maltose, sucrose and l-histidine are assimilated.</s><s>d-Mannitol, potassium glucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline are not assimilated.</s><s>In API 20NE and API ZYM strips, reactions are positive for aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis and for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities; weakly positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase activities, and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase, urease, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activities.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;17 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, THYL-44<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 208238<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22560<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the soil of a Euphrates poplar forest in Xinjiang, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>