<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3172_nm.3553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3553" rank="species">Desulfobacterium autotrophicum</organism><reference id="rid.3172"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brysch</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schneider</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuchs</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Widdel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lithoautotrophic growth of sulfate-reducing bacteria, and description of Desulfobacterium autotrophicum gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>148</volume><fpage>264</fpage><lpage>274</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00456703</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfobacterium autotrophicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfobacterium autotrophicum</i> (Au.to.tro'phi.cum. Gr. pronoun <i>autos</i> by itself. Gr.n. <i>trophe</i> nurishment. <i>Desulfobacterium autotrophicum</i> a rod-shaped sulfate reducer that nourishes itself from inorganic compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oval, usually motile cells, 1-1.5 μm in diameter and 1.5-2.5 μm in length, with single polar flagellum.</s><s>Good growth with a doubling trine of 15-25 h occurs in the presence of sulfate on H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>, formate, butyrate and higher fatty acids up to palmitate, ethanol and higher alcohols, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate and malate.</s><s>Acetate and propionate are slowly utilized.</s><s>Lactate, pyruvate, fumarate and malate can be fermented in the absence of sulfate.</s><s>Cell synthesis is possible with CO<sub>2</sub> as the only source of carbon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biotin, <i>p</i>-aminobenzoate and nicotinate, and 20 g NaCl and 3 g MgCl<sub>2</sub>⋄6 H<sub>2</sub>0 per liter are required for growth.</s><s>The temperature optimum is at 25 - 28°C.</s><s>At higher temperature, cells tend to lyse.</s><s>The pH optimum for autotrophic growth is around 6.7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain b- and c-type cytochromes, menaquinone-7 and high activity of carbon monoxide dehydrogenase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 47.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain has been isolated from a marine sediment.</s><s>Similar types with somewhat slower growth may occur in anaerobic freshwater habitats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: HRM2, DSM number 3382, deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, FRG.</s></p></content></protolog>