<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7320_nm.6048" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6048" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6048" rank="species">Microbacterium halophilum</organism><reference id="rid.7320"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of six new species in the genus Microbacterium and transfer of Flavobacterium marinotypicum ZoBell and Upham to the genus Microbacterium as Microbacterium maritypicum comb. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>973</fpage><lpage>982</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-973</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734054</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium halophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium halophilum</i> (ha.lo'phi.lum. Gr. n. <i>hals</i> salt; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; M.L. neut. adj. <i>halophilum</i> salt-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on solid media in air ;colonies are 2-4 mm in diameter, circular, low convex with entire margins, opaque and moist.</s><s>Yellowish white pigment is produced.</s><s>In young cultures, small, slender rods are formed.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at angles, forming V shapes; primary branching is uncommon.</s><s>In older cultures rods are shorter, but a marked rod-coccus growth cycle does not occur.</s><s>Gram-positive non-motile rods.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 28 °C, and growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs in the presence of 2, 5 and 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Maltose, mannose, mannitol and gluconate are assimilated, but arabinose, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, acetate, adipate, caprate, citrate, fumarate, lactate, malate, phenyl acetate and propionate are not assimilated.</s><s>Starch, Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, and gelatin and Tween 20 are hydrolysed weakly.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive and Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, mannose and rhamnose, but is not produced from L-arabinose, galactose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains ornithine, homoserine, glutamate plus hydroxyglutamate, glycine and alanine.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are mannose, galactose and glucose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15:0, anteiso-C17:0, iso-C15:0 and iso-C16:0.</s><s>Unsaturated menaquinones with 11, 12 and 13 isoprene units are present.</s><s>The DNA G + C content of the type strain is 67.2 mol %.</s><s>Source is soil in mangrove rhizosphere.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 16062<sup>T</sup> (= strain No. 76<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>