<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5659_nm.2928" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2928" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2928" rank="species">Shewanella livingstonensis</organism><reference id="rid.5659"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tudela</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiménez</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinea</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella frigidimarina and Shewanella livingstonensis sp. nov. isolated from Antarctic coastal areas.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>195</fpage><lpage>205</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837303</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Shewanella livingstonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Shewanella livingstonensis</i> (li.ving.sto.nen'sis. N.L. masc./fem. adj. <i>livingstonensis</i> pertaining to Livingston Island, Antarctica, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, rod-shaped cells that are 0.3-0.5 μm wide and 1-3 μm long when the organism is grown in TSB.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and after 24 h incubation in liquid medium filaments 10 μm long are observed.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures from 4 to 20 °C.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, smooth, convex, slightly mucoid and reD-brown in colour with a diameter of 1-2 mm after 5 d at 15 °C.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Positive in oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and β-galactosidase tests.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween, gelatin and casein.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Cells are able to reduce nitrate to nitrite and grow anaerobically by reducing TMAO and ferric compounds with lactate as electron donor.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs alternatively by fermentation of D-glucose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, D-galactose, D-xylose, N-acetylglucosamine and trehalose.</s><s>Growth occurs on D-glucose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, D-mannose, dmannitol, D-galactose, D-xylose, N-acetylglucosamine, trehalose, malonate, succinate, D-ribose and dllactate.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are monounsaturated acids (16:1 <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 17:1 <i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>) followed by straight-chain saturates and terminally branched saturates.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 41 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from water collected from Johnson's Dock (Livingston Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica).</s><s>Strain NF22<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection as LMG 19866<sup>T</sup> and in the Spanish Type Culture Collection as CECT 5933<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>