<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7081_nm.11059" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11059" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5639" rank="species">Streptococcus gallolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.7081"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schlegel</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ageron</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reappraisal of the taxonomy of the Streptococcus bovis/Streptococcus equinus complex and related species: description of Streptococcus gallolyticus subsp. gallolyticus subsp. nov., S. gallolyticus subsp. macedonicus subsp. nov. and S. gallolyticus subsp. pasteurianus subsp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>631</fpage><lpage>645</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02361-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807180</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Streptococcus gallolyticus</em> Osawa <em>et al.</em> 1996</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Colonies of about 1 mm in size, when grown on blood agar for 24 h at 37 °C, are circular, unpigmented, <em>α</em>-haemolytic or non-haemolytic.</s><s>They are catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic, but their growth is enhanced by 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Strains show homogeneous growth in buffered glucose broth and brain heart infusion broth.</s><s>They grow in MRS broth without gas production.</s><s>Growth in 6·5 % NaCl broth is variable.</s><s>Cells are coccoid, Gram-positive and mostly grouped in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>They are non-motile and non-sporulating.</s><s>They do not produce exopolysaccharide in 5 % sucrose medium.</s><s>All strains produce leucine aminopeptidase, alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer test is positive).</s><s>Most of them produce <em>α</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>They do not produce pyrrolidonyl arylamidase or alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Arginine, urea and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase is variable, as is the hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Strains produce acid from lactose, maltose and sucrose, but not from arabitol, tagatose, ribose, sorbitol or cyclodextrin.</s><s>Variable results are observed with glycogen, inulin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, trehalose and starch.</s><s>Some strains may produce tannase or gallate decarboxylase.</s><s>The presence of the Lancefield group D antigen is variable.</s><s>The type strain is ACM 3611<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 35224<sup>T</sup>=CIP 105428<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10005<sup>T</sup>=LMG 16802<sup>T</sup>=HDP 98035<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>