<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12884_nm.22698" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22698" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22698" rank="species">Brachybacterium saurashtrense</organism><reference id="rid.12884"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gontia</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kavita</surname><given-names>K. Schmid</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jha</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium saurashtrense sp. nov., a halotolerant root-associated bacterium with plant growth-promoting potential</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2799</fpage><lpage>2804</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023176-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216918</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brachybacterium saurashtrense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brachybacterium saurashtrense</em> (sau.rash.tren′se. N.L. neutr. adj. <em>saurashtrense</em> of or belonging to Saurashtra, the name of the Western coast in Gujarat State, India, where <em>Salicornia</em> plants grow and from where this strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, are coccoid to ovoid and have a diameter 0.3–0.75 µm.</s><s>Aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow, circular, have an entire margin and are opaque within 24 h with a diameter of approximately 2 mm.</s><s>Mesophilic, with an optimum growth temperature of 30 °C, but able to grow between 10 and 45 °C and at pH 6–11 (optimum pH 8).</s><s>Able to tolerate concentrations of NaCl up to 15 % (w/v) with optimal growth at 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tests for assimilation of maltose, mannose, fructose, galactose, xylose, sucrose, malic acid, glucose and lactose give positive results.</s><s>Ribose, arabinose, adonitol, sorbitol and citrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Positive in tests for catalase and methyl red, but negative for oxidase and urease activity and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Carbon source utilization and hydrolysis of substrates (including characteristics that differentiate the species from other members of the genus <em>Brachybacterium</em>) are indicated in Table 2.</s><s>Able to reduce nitrate, but does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, erythromycin, clindamycin, fusidic acid, nitrofurantoin and sulphamethoxazole.</s><s>Possesses several plant growth-promoting traits such as IAA production, siderophore production, ACC utilization, ACC deaminase activity and conversion of acetylene to ethylene.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is variant A4γ and the menaquinone is MK7 (100 %).</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of DPG, PG, MGDG, three unknown phospholipids and three unknown glycolipids.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> with significant amounts of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JG 06<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23186<sup>T</sup> = IMCC 252<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from roots of <em>Salicornia brachiata</em> from coastal marshy swamps, Bhavnagar district, Gujarat, India.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>