<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2155_nm.7883" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7883" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7883" rank="species">Serpulina intermedia</organism><reference id="rid.2155"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fournié-Amazouz</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Postic</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trott</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baranton</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hampson</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saint Girons</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Recognition of two new species of intestinal spirochetes: Serpulina intermedia sp. nov. and Serpulina murdochii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1007</fpage><lpage>1012</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336899</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serpulina intermedia</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serpulina intermedia</i> (in.ter.me'di.a. L. fem. adj. <i>intermedia</i>, in the middle, referring to the fact that the biochemical reactivities of this organism are intermediate between those characteristically possessed by <i>S. hyodysenteriae</i> and by <i>S. innocens</i> [20])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Also called "<i>Serpulina intermedius</i>" (20).</s><s>Some intestinal spirochetes referred to as "<i>Treponema hyodysenteriae</i> biotype 2" or "intermediate type" may be <i>S. intermedia</i> strains (2).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. intermedia</i> strains have been isolated from swine, including swine with diarrhea (7,11).</s><s>Evidence of pathogenicity after experimental infection of pigs with pure cultures has been inconclusive (15, 24). <i>S. intermedia</i> strains have been isolated from commercial poultry flocks exhibiting diarrhea and reduced production (23).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. intermedia</i> morphology and motility are typical of spirochetes (order <i>Spirochaetales</i>).</s><s>Helical cells are 0.35 to 0.45 by 7.5 to 10 μm, generally exhibit a regular coiling pattern, and have 24 to 28 periplasmic flagella per cell (12 to 14 inserted at each cell end).</s><s>Cells growing beneath an N<sub>2-</sub>O<sub>2</sub> (99:1) atmosphere in stirred BHIS broth have a population doubling time of 2 to 4 h and an optimum growth temperature of 39 to 42°C and reach population densities of approximately 10<sup>9</sup> cells/ml.</s><s>Colonies on Trypticase soy agar containing 10% defibrinated bovine blood are weakly hemolytic.</s><s>The spirochete does not grow aerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrates that support growth of <i>S. intermedia</i> PWS/A<sup>T</sup> in HS broth containing 7% fetal calf serum include glucose, fructose, sucrose, N-acetylglucosamine, pyruvate, L-fucose, tyehalose, galactose, and maltose.</s><s>Substrates that do not support growth are D-fucose, glucosamine, ribose, raffinose, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>In HS broth containing glucose beneath an N<sub>2-</sub>O<sub>2</sub> (99:1) atmosphere, growing cells consume oxygen and yield H<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>2</sub>, acetate, butyrate, and ethanol.</s><s>Hydrogen is produced in greater amounts than C<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Strain PWS/A<sup>T</sup> cells express NADH oxidase activity and contain the <i>nox</i> gene.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. intermedia</i> strains have been classified by MEE analysis (MEE group II [35]) and by biochemical tests (group II spirochetes [7, 81).</s><s>This spirochete has DNA homology levels of 57, 45,28, and 37% with <i>S. hyodysenteriae</i> B78<sup>T</sup>, <i>S. innocens</i> B256<sup>T</sup>, <i>S. pilosicoli</i> P43/6/7g<sup>T</sup>, and <i>S. murdochii</i> 56-150<sup>T</sup>, respectively. <i>S. intermedia</i> PWS/A<sup>T</sup> can be differentiated from other weakly hemolytic intestinal spirochetes (<i>S. innocens</i>, <i>S. pilosicoli</i>, <i>S. murdochii</i> sp. nov.) by RFLβ-PCR analysis of the 16s rDNA by using the enzymes <i>HinfI</i>, <i>Sau3A</i>, and <i>TaqI</i>.</s><s>The restriction patterns of the 558-bp amplicon of <i>rrs</i> contain 132- and 426-bp fragments (<i>HinfI</i>); 43-, 81-, 208-, and 226-bp fragments (<i>TaqI</i>); and uncut 558-bp fragment (<i>Sau3A</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram reaction negative and chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Produces indole and does not hydrolyze hippurate.</s><s>Aerotolerant and anaerobic.</s><s>Cells lack α-galactosidase and possess α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase activities.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 25 mol%.</s><s>Strain PWS/A<sup>T</sup> has all of the properties of the species and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51140<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>