<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2001_nm.10913" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10913" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10913" rank="species">Ochrobactrum pseudintermedium</organism><reference id="rid.2001"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Teyssier</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marchandin</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jean-Pierre</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Masnou</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dusart</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jumas-Bilak</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum pseudintermedium sp. nov., a novel member of the family Brucellaceae, isolated from human clinical samples</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1007</fpage><lpage>1013</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64416-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ochrobactrum pseudintermedium</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ochrobactrum pseudintermedium</em> (pseud.in′ter.med′i.um. Gr. adj. <em>pseudos</em> false; L. neut. adj. <em>intermedium</em> intermediate, and a specific epithet of the genus <em>Ochrobactrum</em>; N.L. neut. adj. <em>pseudintermedium</em> a false <em>Ochrobactrum intermedium</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore forming, short rods, and motile by subpolar flagella.</s><s>Cells are 0.65–0.75×1.5–1.7 μm in size.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–45 °C on tryptic soy agar.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar and R2A agar at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, mucoid and opaque.</s><s>Aerobic respiration, oxidative metabolism, nitrate reduction and catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>Positive for glycine arylamidase, l-proline arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase and l-pyrrolidonyl arylamidase activities, assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, malate, potassium gluconate, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose and capric acid, acidification of adonitol and d-tagatose, and alkalinization of l-lactate and succinate.</s><s>Negative for activities of DNase, urease, phenylalanine deaminase, tryptophan deaminase, Glu-Gly-Arg arylamidase and <em>β</em>-alanine arylamidase <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), arginine dihydrolase, Ala-Phe-Pro arylamidase, glutamyl arylamidase pNA, <em>β</em>-xylosidase, lipase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-galactosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, phosphatase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis).</s><s>Negative for acidification of d-glucose, d-mannose, l-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-mannitol, d-trehalose, malonate, 5-keto-d-gluconate and coumarate, production of indole, acetoin and H<sub>2</sub>S, hydrolysis of gelatin, assimilation of adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, l-histidine and l-lactate, and fermentation of carbohydrates.</s><s>Resistant to <em>β</em>-lactams except imipenem, and to chloramphenicol, tetracycline, fosfomycin and colistin.</s><s>Susceptible to aminoglycosides (gentamicin, tobramycin, netilmicin, isepamicin, amikacin), fluoroquinolones (pefloxacin, ofloxacin, ciprofloxacin), nalidixic acid, rifampicin and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 is the dominant respiratory lipoquinone.</s><s>Polar lipids mainly comprise phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>16S rRNA gene amplification is not obtained with primers F4 and R2 (Velasco <em>et al.</em>, 1998).</s><s>Genome is constituted of two chromosomes of about 2.8 and 1.8 Mb comprising four <em>rrn</em> copies with two <em>rrn</em> operons in divergent orientation on the small chromosome.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 54.5 mol%.</s><s>Can be differentiated from other species of the genus <em>Ochrobactrum</em> by 16S rRNA, <em>dnaK</em> and <em>rpoB</em> gene sequencing.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ADV31<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109116<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17490<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a human clinical sample.</s></p></content></protolog>