<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2596_nm.11549" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11549" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11549" rank="species">Lechevalieria xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.2596"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lechevalieria xinjiangensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from radiation-polluted soil in China.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2819</fpage><lpage>2822</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65134-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048731</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lechevalieria xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lechevalieria xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> referring to Xinjiang, north-western China, the source of the isolate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, non-motile actinomycete that forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium that fragments <em>in situ</em> into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Moderate amounts of white to yellow aerial hyphae are formed on modified Bennett's agar, Gauze's no. 1 agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, yeast extract-malt extract agar and yeast extract-starch agar.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not produced and melanin pigments are not produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar or tyrosine agar.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 10 and 45 °C and at pH 5.0–12.0.</s><s>Does not degrade elastin or Tween 80.</s><s>l-Arabinose, l-cellobiose, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose and sucrose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth (all at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Similarly, d-alanine, l-cysteine, d-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, dl-isoleucine, l-leucinamide, l-leucine, sodium acetate, sodium propionate and sodium suberate are used as sole carbon sources at 0.1 % (w/v).</s><s>l-Cysteine, l-phenylalanine and potassium nitrate are used as sole sources of nitrogen.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, glycerol, maltose and d-xylose, but not from d-raffinose, sodium acetate, sodium lactate, sodium malonate, sodium benzoate, sodium citrate, sodium oxalate or sodium tartrate.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic properties are typical of the genus <em>Lechevalieria</em>.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is composed mainly of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (10.7 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (9.8 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (19.9 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (13 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (4.0 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (7.4 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (4.5 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R24<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.3525<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45081<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a radiation-polluted soil sample collected in the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region of China.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and hence serves as a description of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>