<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6862_nm.9552" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9552" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9552" rank="species">Gelidibacter salicanalis</organism><reference id="rid.6862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae from Antarctic maritime habitats including Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii gen. nov., sp. nov., Subsaximicrobium saxinquilinus sp. nov., Subsaxibacter broadyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Lacinutrix copepodicola gen. nov., sp. nov., and novel species of the genera Bizionia, Gelidibacter and Gillisia</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gelidibacter salicanalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gelidibacter salicanalis</em> (sal.i.can.a.l′is. L. n. <em>sal</em> salt; L. n. <em>canalis</em> channel; N.L. gen. n. <em>salicanalis</em> of the salt channel).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped or filamentous, approximately 0·4–0·6×2–15 μm.</s><s>Small coccoid bodies (approximately 1–1·5 μm diameter) form in older cultures.</s><s>Motile by gliding (visible on very dilute growth media only).</s><s>Cell mass is golden yellow.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are circular and convex, with an entire edge and a butyrous consistency on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at −2 °C in marine broth.</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA at 1–25 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 30 °C or higher.</s><s>Non-halophilic.</s><s>Grows in 0–2·5 M NaCl, with optimal growth occurring at approximately 0·3–0·4 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows in media prepared with 2× strength sea salts, whereas poor growth occurs in 4× strength sea salts.</s><s>Grows on TSA containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl, TSA and NA.</s><s>Does not require yeast extract for growth, and can utilize inorganic nitrogen sources such as sodium nitrate and ammonium chloride.</s><s>In mineral salts growth media can utilize d-glucose, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, l-proline and l-serine as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates on Leifson's O–F medium is positive for d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-galactose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, lactose, cellobiose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, casein, l-tyrosine and aesculin, but not elastin, starch, Tween 80 or DNA.</s><s>Urea is weakly decomposed.</s><s>Produces 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Produces arginine dihydrolase, but does not produce lecithinase or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic data are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Mean DNA G+C content is 42 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IC162<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1053<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108532<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from sea-ice algae collected from pack-ice brine, Southern Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>