<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6053_nm.10150" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10150" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10150" rank="species">Enterococcus caccae</organism><reference id="rid.6053"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carvalho</surname><given-names>M.G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shewmaker</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morey</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sampson</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joyce</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barrett</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Teixeira</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus caccae sp. nov., isolated from human stools.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1505</fpage><lpage>1508</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64103-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825620</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus caccae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus caccae</em> (cac′cae. Gr. n. <em>kakke</em> faeces; N.L. gen. n<em>. caccae</em> of faeces)<em>.</em></s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of Gram-positive cocci occurring as short chains, in pairs and as single cells.</s><s>Non-pigmented, <em>α</em>-haemolytic, small colonies up to 0.5 mm in diameter are formed on sheep-blood agar at 37 °C and are unaffected by the absence or presence of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Strains are catalase-negative, non-motile and susceptible to vancomycin.</s><s>Growth occurs at 45 °C and in broth containing 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Strains are positive for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase activity, leucine aminopeptidase activity, hydrolysis of aesculin in the presence of bile, hippurate hydrolysis, pyruvate utilization and in the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, ribose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, inulin, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, sorbitol or sorbose.</s><s>Reactions are negative for production of gas in MRS broth, hydrolysis of arginine and tolerance of 0.04 % tellurite.</s><s>In the API Rapid ID 32 Strep system, acid is produced from maltose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, ribose, sucrose, tagatose and trehalose.</s><s>The enzymes <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (both substrates), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Acetoin is produced and hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, pullulan, raffinose or sorbitol.</s><s>The species is distinguished by whole-cell-protein profiling and 16S rRNA gene sequencing.</s><s>The AccuProbe <em>Enterococcus</em> genetic probe result is positive and Lancefield extracts react with Centers for Disease Control and Prevention group D antiserum.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 32.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 2215-02<sup>T</sup> (=SS-1777<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1240<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 51564<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human stool samples, in Portland, OR, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>