<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6865_nm.6601" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6601" rank="genus">Spirilliplanes</organism><reference id="rid.6865"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayakawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new genus of the order Actinomycetales, Spirilliplanes gen. nov., with description of Spirilliplanes yamanashiensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>97</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995810</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirilliplanes</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirilliplanes</i> (Spi.rill.li.plan'es. Gr. n. <i>speira</i>, coil; Gr. n. <i>planes</i>, a wanderer; M.L. fem.n. <i>Spirilliplanes</i>, an organism with wandering cells, in spirals)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, aerobic organisms with branching hyphae.</s><s>Nonfragmenting substrate mycelia are present.</s><s>The aerial hyphae aggregate into clusters resembling coils, but true sporangia are not observed; 14-day-old cultures grown on inorganic salts-starch agar have hyphae arranged in spirals of 5 to 10 turns with several spores per spore chain.</s><s>Spores are ovals or short rods (0.5 to 0.7 by 0.7 to 1.0 μm) with smooth surfaces and are motile when they are suspended in 0.01 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.0) containing 10% soil extract or distilled water.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Good growth occurs at temperatures between 25 and 30°C.</s><s>The organism shows good growth on oatmeal agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, and peptone-yeast extract- iron agar.</s><s>In general, the vegetative mycelia of the strain are yellow to orange, and aerial hyphae are white.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain glutamic acid, glucosamine, glycine, alanine, and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The wall chemotype is type II according to the scheme of Lechevalier and Lechevalier (14), and the peptidoglycan type is presumed to be type Alγ according to the classification of Schleifer and Kandler (23).</s><s>Mannose, 3-O-methylmannose, glucose, xylose, and galactose are detected in the whole-cell sugars.</s><s>C<sub>17:1</sub>, C<sub>17:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> are present as major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), and small amounts of MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol are diagnostic phospholipids (phospholipid pattern type PII).</s><s>The acyl type of the cell wall polysaccharides is glycolyl.</s><s>Habitat: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Spirilliplanes yamanashiensis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>