<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.192_nm.7276" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7276" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7276" rank="species">Streptomyces spinoverrucosus</organism><reference id="rid.192"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Diab</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Al-Gounaim</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces spinoverrucosus, a new species from the air of Kuwait.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>331</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-327</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces spinoverrucosus</i> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces spinoverrucosus</i> (spi.no.ve.ru.co'sus. L . adj. <i>spinosus</i> thorny; L. adj. <i>verrucossus</i> warty; M.L. adj. <i>spinoverrucosus</i> spiny and warty, referring to the spiny and warty spore surface)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A comparison of the description of strain 163MA with the descriptions of <i>Streptomyces</i> species in the above-mentioned keys for identification and with the ISP descriptions showed that no known <i>Streptomyces</i> species in the green series is melanin positive and has a spiny or warty spore surface.</s><s>All melanin-positive species in this series have hairy spore surfaces.</s><s>On the other hand, in the key of Küster none of the species with green aerial mycelia produces a water-soluble pigment.</s><s>In the key of Nonomura, two species produce water-soluble pigments, but these species are melanin negative and differ significantly from strain 163MA.</s><s>In the yellow series, no species is melanin positive, has a distinctive reverse pigment, and produces a water- soluble pigment, except "<i>Streptomyces flavofungini</i>", which has Rectiflexibiles spore chain morphology and smooth spore surfaces and is unable to utilize sucrose for growth.</s><s>In the gray series there are no melanin-positive species with warty spore surfaces.</s><s>Three species (<i>S. iakyrus</i>, <i>S. cyaneus</i>, and "<i>S. indigocolor</i>") have spiny spore surfaces, are melanin positive, and produce distinctive reverse pigments and watersoluble pigments.</s><s>However, these species differ from strain 163MA.</s><s>In the red series, only one species has a warty spore surface (<i>Streptomyces lateritius</i>); this species has Rectiflexibilis-Retinaculiaperti spore chain morphology, produces a blue or violet water-soluble pigment and a grayish yellow reverse side of colony modified by violet or blue, and is unable to utilize sucrose, mannitol, and raffinose.</s><s>On the other hand, the following species produce soluble pigments and have spiny spore surfaces: <i>S. purpurascens</i>, <i>S. roseoviolaceus</i>, <i>S. violaceus</i>, <i>S. violarus</i>, <i>S. violatus</i>, and <i>S. arenae</i>.</s><s>All of these species differ from strain 163MA in characters mentioned above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>According to the data given in the ISP descriptions, Szabo and Marton (12) reported that of the 426 strains identified, 54% fall within the range delineated by one Tresner-Backus color wheel, whereas 46% fall into two, three, and four different color series when they are examined on three different media.</s><s>Only two species fall into four color series: one is in the red, gray, yellow, and blue series, and the other in the yellow, gray, green, and red series.</s><s>According to the ISP descriptions, the latter (<i>Streptomyces olivaceoviridis</i>) has smooth spore surfaces and is melanin negative.</s><s>It produces no, or only a trace of, yellow water-soluble pigments and no distinctive reverse pigment.</s><s>Hence, it differs from strain 163MA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>To the best of our knowledge, there has not yet been reported a <i>Streptomyces</i> species with an aerial mass color which allows placement of the organism in the green, red, yellow, and gray color series along with the following characters: melanin positive; spiral spore chains; spiny spore surfaces; brownish red reverse sides of colonies; brown, red, or reddish brown watersoluble pigments; and utilization of D-glucose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, <i>i</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, fructose, rhamnose, sucrose, and raffinose for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 163MA (= NCIB 11666).</s><s>Since the description of the species is based on a single strain, the description given above for the type strain also serves for the present as the species description.</s></p></content></protolog>