<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6741_nm.1355" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1355" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1355" rank="species">Fulvimarina pelagi</organism><reference id="rid.6741"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fulvimarina pelagi gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium that forms a deep evolutionary lineage of descent in the order 'Rhizobiales'.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1853</fpage><lpage>1859</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02644-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fulvimarina pelagi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fulvimarina pelagi</em> (pe.la′gi. L. fem. adj. <em>pelagi</em> from the open sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of this species is the same as that given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0·7–1·4 μm wide and 0·4–1·0 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are 0·8–1·8 mm in diameter, uniformly circular, convex and opaque.</s><s>Tolerates 10·0 % NaCl and grows optimally at 2·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Absorption spectral peaks of the pigments are observed at 477, 453 and 419 nm.</s><s>Utilizes d-ribose, d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-mannitol, glycerol, pyruvic acid, formic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-lysine, l-proline, l-serine, l-isoleucine and l-arginine as sole carbon sources, but does not utilize dl-glyceraldehyde, <em>β</em>-lactose, d-melezitose, d-sorbitol, itaconic acid, citric acid, d-malic acid, malonic acid, myo-inositol, d-glucosamine, l-alanine or glycine (sole carbon source utilization tests by custom-made 48-well plate).</s><s>According to Biolog tests, the following substrates were oxidized by all strains: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine, uridine, thymidine and glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HTCC2506<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-666<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12091<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15513<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the western Sargasso Sea, Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>