<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.21_nm.8261" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8288" rank="species">Flexibacter psychrophilus</organism><reference id="rid.21"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bernardet</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deoxyribonucleic acid relatedness and phenotypic characterization of Flexibacter columnaris sp. nov., nom. rev., Flexibacter psychrophilus sp. nov., nom rev., and Flexibacter maritimus Wakabayashi, Hikida, and Masumura 1986.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>346</fpage><lpage>354</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flexibacter psychrophilus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flexibacter psychrophilus</i>  (psy.chro'phil.us Gr. adj. <i>psychros</i>, cold; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. adj. <i>psychrophilus</i>, cold loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(basionym, “<i>Cytophaga psychrophila</i>” ex Borg 1960)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on seven strains and also includes data from Borg (5), Pacha (23), and Holt (M.Sc. and Ph.D. theses).</s><s>Cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-negative rods that are 1 to 5 μm long by 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide in 48-h liquid cultures; a few longer cells (8 to 12 μm) may appear.</s><s>Some cells have an enlarged end.</s><s>In hanging-drop preparations, the gliding movement is frequently slow and weak and is noticed after prolonged observation.</s><s>Some strains exhibit faster gliding.</s><s>Good growth occurs in Anacker-Ordal broth (2) supplemented with 0 or 0.5% NaCl and at 10 to 20°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 15 to 18°C, and scant, slow growth occurs at 6 and 22 to 25°C.</s><s>No growth occurs in Trypticase soy broth.</s><s>Growth on Anacker-Ordal agar is enhanced by an enriched formula (0.5% tryptone instead of 0.05% tryptone).</s><s>Most colonies are smooth, glossy, and circular with regular edges, but most strains can also produce colonies with narrow and uneven spreading margins.</s><s>The colonies are bright yellow and do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Nondiffusible flexirubin type pigments are present.</s><s>Colonies do not absorb Congo red.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, and hydrogen sulfide is not produced. <i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cellulose, carboxymethyl cellulose, chitin, starch, esculin, and agar are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No acid is produced from carbohydrates in ammonium salt-sugar medium (API 50CH galleries).</s><s>Gelatin, casein (skim milk agar), and tyrosine are hydrolyzed.</s><s>No brown color is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Lysine, arginine, and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Tributyrin, lecithin (egg yolk), Tween 20, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Weak, slow DNA hydrolysis.</s><s>No inhibition zone is formed around the following types of disks (the concentration in each type of disk is indicated in parentheses): gentamicin (15 μg), neomycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg), and trimethoprim (5 μg).</s><s>Susceptible (inhibition zone, more than 9 mm) to vibriostatic compound Oh29 (500 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 IU), tetracycline (30 IU), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 IU), novobiocin (30 IU), and furans (300 μg).</s><s>Hydrolyzes the following substrates (API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl-phosphate (at pH 8.5 and 5.4), 2-naphthyl-butyrate, 2-naphthyl-caprylate, L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide, and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze the following substrates (API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl-myristate, L- cystyl-2-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide, N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, 6- Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronide, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, 6- Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, and 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The base composition is 32.5 to 34 mol% G+C (three strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains were isolated from freshwater fish suffering from cold-water disease in North America and France.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCMB 1947.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain NCMB 1947<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, it produces round colonies with regular edges.</s><s>Colonies with narrow spreading margins are sometimes produced.</s><s>The gliding movement is very slow.</s><s>Susceptible (inhibition zone, more than 9 mm) to kanamycin (30 μg), sulfonamides (200 μg), nalidixic acid (30 v), and actinomycin D (2.5 μg).</s><s>The base composition of the type strain is 32.5 mol% G+C.</s></p></content></protolog>