<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3941_nm.3178" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3178" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3178" rank="subspecies">Erwinia carotovora wasabiae</organism><reference id="rid.3941"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia carotovora subsp. wasabiae subsp. nov. isolated from diseased rhizomes and fibrous roots of Japanese horseradish (Eutrema wasabi Maxim.).</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>130</fpage><lpage>135</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-2-130</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Erwinia carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> (wa.sa.bi.a.e. wasabi species name of host plant; L. gen. n. <i>wasabiae</i> of wasabi)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonencapsulated, nonsporeforming rods with an average size of 1.8 by 0.5 μm and are motile by means of 2 to 15 peritrichous flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules do not accumulate.</s><s>Colonies on yeast extract-peptone agar plates at 28°C are white, transparent, circular with entire margins, convex, and 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter after 24 h.</s><s>Growth on yeast extractpeptone agar slants is moderate, white and butyrous, with high viability.</s><s>Abundant growth is obtained on yeast extractpeptone agar slants supplemented with glucose or on potato-glucose agar slants, although viability on these media is poor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic characteristics that differentiate the wasabi bacterium from <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i>, <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>atroseptica</i>, <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i>, <i>E. chrysanthemi</i> pv. <i>chrysanthemi</i>, <i>E. chrysanthemi</i> pv. <i>zeae</i>, and <i>E. rhapontici</i> are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The wasabi bacterium was identical to these bacteria in being positive for the following characteristics: rodshaped cells, with size ranging from 0.5 to 0.8 μm in diameter by 1.0 to 2.5 μm in length; anaerobic growth; fermentative metabolism of glucose; reduction of KNO<sub>3</sub>; catalase reaction; utilization of ribose, rhamnose, L-arabinose, mannose, fructose, glucose, cellobiose, sucrose, mannitol, esculin, salicin, acetate, fumarate, malate, succinate, and galacturonate; utilization of asparagine as a sole source of nitrogen and carbon; and the presence of ubiquinone Q8.</s><s>They were also identical in being negative in the following tests: capsule formation; Gram stain; poly-phydroxybutyrate accumulation; production of 2-ketogluconate, oxidase, amylase , arginine dihydrolase, amino acid decarboxylase, and urease; lipolysis of cottonseed oil; no pigmentation on King medium B; and utilization of glycogen, dextrin, sorbitol, dulcitol, adonitol, propionate, oxalate, and benzoate.</s><s>The properties shown in Table 2 indicate that the wasabi strains are more similar to <i>E. carotovora</i> subspecies than to <i>E. chrysanthemi</i> pathovars and <i>E. rhapontici</i>.</s><s>The characteristics which differentiate the wasabi strains from the three subspecies of <i>E. carotovora</i> are shown in Table 3. <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov. differs from some of these bacteria in growth inhibition by KCN, growth at 36°C, inability to ferment melibiose and raffinose, a 24-h lag in galactose catabolism, and rapid catabolism of trehalose (within several hours).</s><s>Although this bacterium lowered the pH of the lactose medium after incubation for 2 weeks, the growth was poor, and β-galactosidase activity could not be detected, even in cells adapted for lactose; the enzyme was not induced by the presence of isopropyl-β-D-thiogalactopyranoside (12, 13).</s><s>An oxidation mechanism seemed to be involved in this phenomenon.</s><s>Such pH change was not observed in media containing melibiose or raffinose during incubation for 3 weeks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ability to utilize lactose or the presence of β-galactosidase activity has been used as a major criterion in the classification of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>(1).</s><s>The different lactose metabolisms in enterobacteria originate in the nature of the lactose system, consisting of lactose permease, pgalactosidase, and transacetylase.</s><s>Some bacteria that do not utilize lactose have only part of the system, whereas others have none (7).</s><s>In this respect, the wasabi bacterium was distinct from other species of soft rot <i>Erwinia</i> spp., including <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavascularum</i>.</s><s>The lag found in galactose catabolism is another distinct property that differentiates <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov. from other members of soft rot <i>Erwinia</i> spp. (11).</s><s>Because the lag in galactose catabolism often became undetectable when the bacterium was repeatedly grown in galactose medium, the lag may be related to induction of galactose-metabolizing enzymes (8).</s><s>The adaptation of the bacterium to galactose, htowever, showed no effect on the inducibility of β-galactosidiase.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov. was distinct in its sensitivity to 0.075% KCN.</s><s>As long as the test medium was maintained anaerobically under liquid paraffin, the growth was completely depressed for 2 weeks, whereas the other subspecies of <i>E. carotovora</i>, except <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i>, showed normal growth.</s><s>The characteristics of the wasabi bacterium which are described above warranted the creation of a new subspecies of <i>E. carotovora</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains SR36 and SR91<sup>T</sup> of <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov. were shown to have some of the same antigens as strains sR35 and EC1 of <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i> (Fig. 2).</s><s>Similar reaction patterns were observed with other antisera; the number of precipitin bands formed with antigens of wasabi strains was always less than the number formed with antigens of <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i> and <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i>. <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov. and <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i> were indistinguishable in pathogenicity.</s><s>They caused soft rot on excised leaf petioles of wasabi, on sliced rhizomes, tubers, and roots of wasabi, potato, and carrot and radish, respectively, and on midribs of Chinese cabbage.</s><s>They were also pathogenic to wasabi, tomato, and tobacco seedlings, although the wasabi bactenium tended to be less virulent on the intact plants than <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i>.</s><s>These bacteria also exhibited weak virulence on succulent young stems of chrysanthemum but not on mature stems.</s><s>Although <i>E. rhapontici</i> had a similar pathogenic pattern, its virulence was much weaker than the virulence of these bacteria on all test plants. <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i> was not pathogenic to intact wasabi, tomato, or tobacco plants, although it induced soft rot of succulent tissues of vegetables in petri dishes. <i>E. chrysanthemi</i> pv. <i>zeae</i> and <i>E. chrysanthemi</i> pv. <i>chrysanthemi</i> were distinct from <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>wasabiae</i> subsp. nov., <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>carotovora</i>, <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>atroseptica</i>, and <i>E. carotovora</i> subsp. <i>betavasculorum</i> in exhibiting pathogenicity to rice, corn, and mature stems of chrysanthemum.</s><s>The subspecies of <i>E. carotovora</i> were erratic in inducing the typical hypersensitivity reaction on tobacco leaves within 12 h.</s><s>The response was sometimes negative and other times positive, ostensibly under the same experimental conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SR91 (=ATCC 43316 and PDDCC 9121) is designated the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>