<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4330_nm.2191" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2191" rank="genus">Halothiobacillus</organism><reference id="rid.4330"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sievert</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heidorn</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halothiobacillus kellyi sp. nov., a mesophilic, obligately chemolithoautotrophic, sulfur-oxidizing bacterium isolated from a shallow-water hydrothermal vent in the Aegean Sea, and emended description of the genus Halothiobacillus.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1229</fpage><lpage>1237</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843067</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Halothiobacillus</i> (Kelly and Wood 2000)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halothiobacillus</i> (Hal.o.thi.o.ba.cil'lus. Gr. n. <i>hals</i> sea, salt ; Gr. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; L. n. bacillus a small rod; L. masc. n. <i>Halothiobacillus</i> salt-loving sulfur rodlet)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.3.0.6 lm in diameter and 1.0-2.5 μm in length.</s><s>They are Gram-negative, occur singly or in pairs and are motile.</s><s>Spore formation is absent.</s><s>All members of the genus are strictly aerobic and grow chemolithoautotrophically with thiosulfate, tetrathionate, sulfur and sulfide, but not with thiocyanate, as electron donor, and with carbon dioxide as carbon source.</s><s>Heterotrophic growth is never observed.</s><s>Addition of acetate can increase the amount of biomass produced if a reduced sulfur compound is provided as electron donor.</s><s>Sulfate is the end product of sulfur compound oxidation, but sulfur, sulfite or polythionates may be accumulated, sometimes transiently, by most species.</s><s>During growth on reduced sulfur compounds, the pH decreases from neutrality to a pH as low as 2.5-3.0 depending on the species.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between pH 6.5 and 8.0 at temperatures of 30-42 °C.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 400-500 mMfor most strains, but many tolerate much higher concentrations.</s><s>A requirement for NaCl is found for some species.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed by means of ribulose-bisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>Nitrate can be reduced to nitrite, but is not reduced further.</s><s>On thiosulfate agar, cells produce small, white-yellowish, smooth, entire colonies (1.3 mm in diameter) in which sulfur is deposited and acid is produced.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of members of this genus varies between 56 and 67 mol%.</s><s>As determined by 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis, the genus <i>Halothiobacillus</i> belongs to the γ-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Members of the genus can be isolated from freshwater, soil and frequently from marine environments.</s><s>Traditional enrichment culture techniques seem to favour their isolation because of their higher acid tolerance compared to other marine, sulfur-oxidizing bacteria such as <i>Thiomicrospira</i> spp.</s><s>The type species is <i>Halothiobacillus neapolitanus</i> (formerly <i>Thiobacillus neapolitanus</i>) strain NCIMB 8539<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 581<sup>T</sup>=Parker strain X<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>