<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5591_nm.2315" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2315" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2315" rank="species">Cycloclasticus pugetii</organism><reference id="rid.5591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dyksterhouse</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gray</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herwig</surname><given-names>R.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lara</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cycloclasticus pugetii gen. nov., sp. nov., an aromatic hydrocarbon-degrading bacterium from marine sediments.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>123</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857792</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cycloclasticus pugetii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cycloclasticus pugetii</i> (pu.get'i.i. M. L. gen. n. <i>pugetii</i>, of Puget, named in honor of Peter Puget, a British naval officer who participated in the Vancouver Expedition and for whom Puget Sound was named; Puget Sound is a large, deep, marine body of water and associated estuaries which is located in western Washington and extends south of the Strait of Juan de Fuca)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods that are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Requires at least 10‰ salinity for growth.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Grows poorly on complex bacteriological media containing no aromatic compounds.</s><s>Aromatic compounds, including biphenyl, naphthalene, phenanthrene, anthracene, and toluene, are used as sole or principal carbon sources for growth.</s><s>In addition, strains utilize selected fatty acids and amino acids, including acetate, propionate, and glutamate.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Colonies are small, round, and entire with no pigmentation, and a yellow diffusible compound is produced during growth on biphenyl.</s><s>The principal fatty acids in whole cells are 16:1ω7<i>cis</i> and 16:O.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, <i>C. pugetii</i> PS-1, was isolated from the surface sediments of Sinclair Inlet, which is located on Puget Sound near the city of Bremerton, Wash.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. pugetii</i> PS-1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51542<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is significant that members of this genus of aerobic, gram-negative rods could not be identified without sequencing their 16s rRNAs.</s><s>On the basis of phenotypic test and DNA base composition results, these organisms would have been most logically placed in the genus <i>Alteromonas</i>.</s><s>Thus, the use of 16s rRNA sequencing was critical for the correct placement of this genus in its appropriate phylogenetic position.</s><s>It is also noteworthy that, if this bacterium had not been isolated but simply had had its sequence determined as a clone from natural samples collected from the marine environment, it may have been described as a lithotrophic bacterium most closely related to sulfur oxidizers or methane oxidizers.</s><s>Thus, an analysis of the 16s rRNA sequence alone would not have permitted meaningful characterization of the metabolic capabilities of the organism.</s></p></content></protolog>