<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7309_nm.1289" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1289" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1289" rank="species">Rhizobium huautlense</organism><reference id="rid.7309"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Berkum</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beyene</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sui</surname><given-names>X.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorado</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium huautlense sp. nov., a symbiont of Sesbania herbacea that has a close phylogenetic relationship with Rhizobium galegae.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>687</fpage><lpage>699</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-687</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734023</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium huautlense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium huautlense</i> (huau.tlen'se. N.L. gen. n. <i>huautlense</i> of Huautla, the region in Mexico where the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Grows on YMA and PY at temperatures up to 40 °C.</s><s>On YMA, the colonies are circular, cream-coloured, semi-translucent and mucilagenous within 2-4 d.</s><s>Older colonies have a white centre.</s><s>On PY medium, the colonies produce less polysaccharides than on YMA and acid is produced.</s><s>The generation time is 2.0-2.2 h.</s><s>Growth occurs on YMA supplemented with 1.0% NaCl and at pH 9.0.</s><s>Resistant to 300 µg lincomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 5 µg ml<sup>-1</sup> each of ampicillin, erythromycin, neomycin and kanamycin.</s><s>Sensitive to 50 µg ml<sup>-1</sup> each of ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin and neomycin, and 5 µg tetracycline ml<sup>-1</sup>, and 100 µg kanamycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Adenine, L-leucine, L-lysine, methionine, L-tryptophan, L-arginine, L-isoleucine, L-phenylalanine, glutamate and aspartic acid are used as sole nitrogen substrates for growth, but p-fluoro-DL-phenylalanine and anthranilic acid are not utilized.</s><s>Dulcitol, inositol, xylose, D-fructose, D-galactose, lactose, melibiose, D-arabinose, rhamnose, fumarate and succinate are used as sole carbon substrate for growth, but citrate and propionate are not utilized.</s><s>Thiamin is required for growth.</s><s>The species nodulates and forms nitrogen-fixing symbioses with <i>Sesbania herbacea</i> and <i>L. leucocephala</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level, <i>Rhizobium huautlense</i> is differentiated from related species by cellular plasmid content, the molecular size of the symbiotic plasmid, variation in electrophoretic mobilities of 12 enzyme loci, low estimates of DNA relatedness and by the nucleotide sequence of 16s rRNA gene.</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 57.0- 58.9 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>S02<sup>T</sup> is the type strain of <i>R. huautlense</i>, and it has the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>All 66 isolates of <i>R. huautlense</i> characterized in our study have been deposited in the USDA ARS National <i>Rhizobium</i> Resource Center collection, USA, and in the Culture Collection of Centro de Investigación sobre Fijación de Nitrógeno (CFN) at UNAM, Cuernavaca, Mexico.</s></p></content></protolog>