<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3776_nm.1465" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1465" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1465" rank="species">Afipia felis</organism><reference id="rid.3776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>English</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vincent</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Radosevic</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birkness</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibb</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quinn</surname><given-names>F.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Afipia gen. nov., with Afipia felis sp. nov. (formerly the cat scratch disease bacillus), Afipia clevelandensis sp. nov. (formerly the Cleveland Clinic Foundation strain), Afipia broomeae sp. nov., and three unnamed genospecies.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>2450</fpage><lpage>2460</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1774249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Afipia felis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Afipia felis</i> (fe'lis. L. gen. n. <i>felis</i>, of the cat, because a cat scratch or bite is the means by which this organism infects humans)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>A. felis</i> exhibits all of the characteristics of the genus.</s><s>It is 0.2 to 0.5 μm in diameter and 0.2 to 2.5 μm long (9).</s><s>Cells grown in brain heart infusion broth for 72 h at 32°C and then incubated at 37°C for 3 weeks form delicate pleomorphic forms (9). <i>A. felis</i> is catalase, citrate, and D-mannitol negative.</s><s>It reduces nitrates and produces acid oxidatively from D-xylose in a delayed, weak reaction.</s><s>The biochemical characteristics of use in differentiating <i>A. felis</i> from other <i>Afipia</i> species are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antimicrobial susceptibility data are given in Table 3. <i>A. felis</i> has previously been reported by English and colleagues (8, 9) to be resistant to ampicillin, cefamandole nafate, cefazolin sodium, cefoperazone sodium, cephalothin sodium, chloramphenicol, clindamycin hydrochloride, erythromycin, nitrofurantoin, penicillin G, and tetracycline hydrochloride; to have intermediate or moderately susceptible to piperacillin sodium, sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim, ticarcillin disodium, and vancomycin hydrochloride; and to be susceptible to amikacin sulfate, cefotaxime sodium, cefoxitin sodium, gentamicin sulfate, mezlocillin sodium, netilmicin sulfate, and tobramycin sulfate by the API UniSept microvolume broth dilution breakpoint procedure (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content in each of the four <i>A. felis</i> strains was 62.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>A. felis</i> is pathogenic for humans and is the causative agent of CSD.</s><s>The type strain is AFIP strain BV (= B-91-007352 = ATCC 53690), which was isolated by English and colleagues (8, 9) from a lymph node obtained from a person with CSD.</s></p></content></protolog>