<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1514_nm.17947" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17947" rank="order">Prochlorales</organism><reference id="rid.1514"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Florenzano</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balloni</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Materassi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nomenclature of Prochloron didemni (Lewin 1977) sp. nov., nom rev., Prochloron (Lewin 1976) gen. nov., nom. rev., Prochloraceae fam. nov., Prochlorales ord. nov., nom. rev. in the class Photobacteria Gibbons and Murray 1978.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>351</fpage><lpage>353</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the order <i>Prochlorales</i> ord. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prochlorales</i> (Pro.chlo.ra'les. M .L. fem. n. <i>Prochloraceae</i> type family of order; <i>ales</i> ending to denote an order; M.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Prochlorales</i> the Prochloraceae order)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are unicellular or multicellular gram-negative photosynthetic procaryotes, containing chlorophylls <i>a</i> and <i>b</i> and carotenoids.</s><s>Motile or nonmotile, Free living or symbionts on invertebrate animals (didemnid ascidians, sponges, or tectibranch molluscs).</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Perform oxygenic photosynthesis.</s><s>Photoautotrophic or myxotrophic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The photopigments are located on paired (not single) thylakoids without phycobilisomes.</s><s>The arrangement of DNA, scattered in the periphery of the cell (therefore the center appears hollow), is different from that of all the cyanobacteria (6).</s><s>The cells do not contain gas vacuoles or cyanophicin.</s><s>This broad definition of the ordinal rank is made not to restrict <i>Prochlorales</i> solely to the photosynthetic procaryotes having a proven symbiotic capacity in a given host, but to make possible the inclusion of free-living members, which can be cultivated away from the host.</s><s>Presently it is suggested that <i>Prochlorales</i> includes one</s></p><p class="description"><s>family with the following diagnosis.</s></p></content></protolog>