<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2823_nm.12175" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12175" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3489" rank="species">Desulfovibrio indonensis</organism><reference id="rid.2823"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Feio</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beech</surname><given-names>I.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carepo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cheung</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franco</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guezennec</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitchell</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moura</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lino</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterisation of a novel sulphate-reducing bacterium of the Desulfovibrio genus.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>117</fpage><lpage>130</lpage><source id="225">Anaerobe</source><issn>1075-9964</issn><essn>1095-8274</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/anae.1997.0142</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16887631</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfovibrio indonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cell morphology</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>Microscopy observations revealed that the cells of Ind 1 were rod-shaped, Gram-negative and occurred singly or, during certain stages of the growth, as chains containing two or more bacteria [Figures 1 and 2(a)].</s><s>Cells were 3–5 μm long and 0.5–1.2 μm wide.</s><s>The cells were motile, moving by means of a single polar flagellum [Figure 2(b)].</s><s>Sporulation was never observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Physiological properties</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>The ranges of temperature, pH and salinity that facilitated the growth of Ind 1 were from 10°C to 37°C, 6.5 to 8.5 and 0% to 10% (w/v) NaCl, respectively.</s><s>No growth was observed below or above these limits.</s><s>The cultures were able to reduce sulphate to sulphide using lactate and pyruvate as carbon sources.</s><s>Other tested compounds were not utilised.</s><s>From the growth curve obtained following the optical density measurements at 660 nm, a specific growth rate (μ<sub>max</sub>) of 0.07/h was determined.</s><s>Lactate consumption and acetate production curves of the culture growing in lactate/sulphate medium (Figure 3) demonstrate an incomplete lactate oxidation to acetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Lipid characterisation</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty acid profile of Ind 1 is shown in Table 1.</s><s>The analysis revealed large amounts of branched fatty acids which account for 53.1% of the total fatty acids with anteiso C<sub>15:0</sub> being the predominant species (52.86%).</s><s>With the exception of C<sub>18:1ω7c</sub> (which accounted for 1.34% of the total fatty acids), only traces of monounsaturated fatty acids were detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>16S rRNA sequence data analysis</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>The 16S rRNA sequence data analysis established that the isolated strain Ind 1 belongs to the genus <i>Desulfovibrio</i>.</s><s>The similarity levels between Ind 1 and some SRB strains of the <i>Desulfovibrio</i> genus were determined, revealing a high similarity with <i>D. desulfuricans</i>, <i>D. gigas</i> and <i>D. vulgaris</i>.</s><s>Recently, a second 16S rRNA sequence analysis was performed, which confirmed the DSM 16S rRNA sequence analysis and revealed a similarity level of 97% with <i>Desulfovibrio gabonensis</i> (Prof.</s><s>W.</s><s>A.</s><s>Hamilton, personal communication), a recently described strain [38].</s><s>Table 2 summarises the similarity values obtained for the isolated <i>Desulfovibrio</i> strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Molecular phylogeny of</i> Desulfovibrio <i>Ind 1</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>The 16S rRNA gene from Ind 1 was sequenced from positions 74 to 966 (<i>Escherichia coli</i> numbering [42]) and aligned with sequences from bacteria belonging to the α, β and δ subdivisions of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Phylogenetically uninformative information was removed from the alignment manually, leaving 500 nucleotides containing 92 informative sites.</s><s>Phylogenetic trees were constructed from distances calculated using the Kimura 2-parameter model [39] using the nearest-neighbour method [40].</s><s>Outgroups were chosen from the α and β subdivisions and included <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens</i>, <i>Neisseria polysaccharia</i>, <i>Pseudomonas cepacia</i> str.</s><s>G4, and <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i>.</s><s>The phylogenetic trees obtained presented a picture that was consistent with previous reports [41,42].</s><s>The two main branches of the mesophilic Gram-negative sulphate-reducing bacteria are shown in Figure 4.</s><s>The majority of <i>Desulfovibrio</i> species are placed within the first major branch with good support (93% bootstrap).</s><s>The second major branch contained the remaining genera of the sulphate-reducing bacteria and <i>Myxococcus xanthus</i>.</s><s>Support for these major branches was very strong (99% bootstrap).</s><s>Within the <i>Desulfovibrio</i> lineage, <i>Desulfomonas pigra</i>, <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> ATCC 27774, <i>Desulfovibrio vulgaris</i> and <i>Desulfovibrio longreachii</i> form a clade.</s><s>This observation is consistent with those of Devereux et al. who identified five major lineages within this group [42].</s><s>The organisms representing these lineages were (i) <i>Desulfovibrio salexigens</i> and <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> El Aghelia Z, (ii) <i>Desulfovibrio africanus</i>, (iii) <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> ATCC 27774, <i>Desulfomonas pigra</i> and <i>Desulfovibrio vulgaris</i>, (iv) <i>Desulfovibrio gigas</i> and (v) <i>Desulfovibrio baculatus</i> and <i>Desulfovibrio desulfuricans</i> Norway 4.</s><s>In Figure 4 only four of these lineages are implied: the organisms representing the fifth lineage were omitted from analysis.</s><s>The <i>Desulfovibrio gigas</i> lineage represents a deep branch within this group [42] and has been expanded to include <i>Desulfovibrio gabonensis</i> DGU31080, a marine isolate [38].</s><s>Strain Ind 1 joins this group pairing with <i>esulfovibrio gabonensis</i> (100% bootstrap).</s><s>Both of these species are marine but with enough sequence dissimilarity to suggest that <i>Desulfovibrio</i> Ind 1 is a new and separate species.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Whole cell, OM and extracellular polymers protein profiles</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>The protein profiles obtained for the whole cells of <i>Desulfovibrio</i> Ind 1 and <i>D. gabonensis</i> are presented in the electrophoretogram shown in Figure 5.</s><s>The patterns obtained for outer membranes and extracellular polymeric substances (EPS) are not shown.</s><s>In all cases, differences between the two strains are apparent both in the number of proteins and their ratios.</s><s>The main differences found are indicated by arrows.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Characterisation of the purified proteins</i></s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Cytochrome c<sub>3</sub></i>.</s><s>The UV/visible spectrum of cytochrome c<sub>3</sub> [Figure 6(a)], exhibits typical absorption bands for both the oxidised (530 nm and Soret band at 419 nm) and dithionite reduced forms (α band at 551 nm, β band at 522 nm and Soret band at 418 nm) [43].</s><s>The <sup>1</sup>H-NMR spectrum of the Ind 1 cytochrome c<sub>3</sub> (data not shown) presents numerous common features with the spectra from other tetrahemic cytochromes [44,45].</s><s>Downfield chemical shifted heme methyl groups are observed experiencing the low spin paramagnetism of the protein.</s><s>The Ind 1 cytochrome c<sub>3</sub> NMR spectrum is almost identical to the spectrum reported for the homologous protein from <i>D. gigas</i> [46].</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Hydrogenase</i>.</s><s>The UV/visible spectrum of the native, as isolated hydrogenase, shows typical Fe-S charge transfer bands in the 400 nm region with a broad shoulder centred at 440 nm [Figure 6(b)].</s><s>The isolated hydrogenase is a dimer of 92 kDa which contains subunits of molecular weights 32 and 60 kDa, as determined using SDS-PAGE.</s><s>The enzyme’s specific activity, as determined by H2 production, is 2.71U/mg protein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The EPR spectrum of the enzyme in the native state, at high temperature (100 K), shows a rhombic-type signal with g values of 2.32, 2.24, and 2.01 [Figure 7(a)].</s><s>This EPR signal, known as the Ni-A signal, is similar to the nickel signal observed at this temperature in the <i>D. gigas</i> hydrogenase (g values of 2.31, 2.23 and 2.01) [47].</s><s>The Ni-A signal has been related to an oxygenated, unsteady state of the enzyme, that can be reversibly activated.</s><s>In addition to the nickel EPR detectable species, an EPR active oxidised [3Fe-4S] cluster can be observed up to 40 K (inset of Figure 7), associated with an almost isotropic EPR signal centred at a g value of 2.02.</s><s>This signal is very similar to the one reported for the [3Fe-4S] cluster of <i>D. gigas</i> and <i>D. vulgaris</i> Miyazaki [NiFe] hydrogenases [48,49].</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Sulphite reductase (desulfoviridin)</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The purified <i>Desulfovibrio</i> Ind 1 sulphite reductase exhibited a dark-green colour.</s><s>The UV/vis spectrum presented in Figure 6(c) shows absorbance peaks with maxima at 631, 580, 409 and 394 nm, these peaks being  characteristic of the desulfoviridin-type sulphite reductases.</s><s>The nonhemic iron content determined colorimetrically following the TPTZ method was 18 ± 1 atoms of iron per molecule.</s><s>This value is similar to those reported previously for other dissimilatory sulphite reductases [50].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The molecular weight of the desulfoviridin in the native state (determined employing HPLC gel filtration), was found to be 218 kDa.</s><s>Oligomeric structure and subunity molecular weight determination using SDS-PAGE revealed two bands of molecular weights 54 and 47 kDa (12.5% T gels) and a third band at around 10 kDa (17.5% T gels).</s><s>Considering the molecular weight of the native protein, the presence of these three types of subunits indicates an α<sub>2</sub>β<sub>2</sub>γ<sub>2</sub> subunit structure.</s><s>These results are in agreement with previous reports on sulphite reductases of the desulfoviridin type [51].</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Ferredoxin</i>.</s><s>The purified ferredoxin was of an orange-brown colour and the UV/vis spectrum showed a broad maximum at 430 nm and a protein peak at 280 nm [Figure 6(d)].</s><s>The extinction coefficient at 430 nm is 15.2 mM/cm.</s><s>The low absorbance observed at 260 nm demonstrates the absence of nucleic acids contamination, indicating a highly pure ferredoxin preparation.</s><s>The purity of the ferredoxin sample was confirmed by obtaining a single NH<sub>2</sub>-terminal sequence (Figure 8).</s><s>The molecular weight of the ferredoxin in the native state, determined using HPLC gel filtration, was 18.4 kDa.</s><s>The iron content for the native protein determined colorimetrically following the TPTZ method was 10.8 ± 0.5 atoms of iron per molecule.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The EPR spectrum of the as-isolated ferredoxin recorded at 10 K is silent (data not shown), indicating that the protein is diamagnetic in its native form.</s><s>After addition of a few aliquots of sodium dithionite (1 mg/mL), the orange brown colour of the ferredoxin sample bleached, as expected for the reduced form of an [Fe-S] centre.</s><s>The EPR spectrum of the reduced protein could only be observed at low temperature (4.5 K) and showed a rhombic signal, with g values of 2.08, 1.93 and 1.86.</s><s>These EPR results are characteristic for a [4Fe-4S] centre [52].</s></p></content></protolog>