<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7511_nm.2402" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2402" rank="genus">Methylococcus</organism><reference id="rid.7511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the methanotrophs: Description of Methylobacter gen.nov., emendation of Methylococcus, validation of Methylosinus and Methylocystis species, and a proposal that the family Methylococcaceae includes only the Group I Methanotrophs.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>753</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-735</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Methylococcus</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are cocci, coccobacilli, or occasionally short rods, are 0.8 to 1.5 μm wide, 1.0 to 1.5 μm long, and occur singly or in pairs. When motile, the cells possess a single polar flagellum. Produces <i>Azotobacter</i> type cysts which do not confer desiccation resistance. Contains a partially functional Benson-Calvin cycle which allows incorporation of carbon dioxide for cellular carbon in the presence of methane, but no autotrophic growth occurs in the absence of methane. Fixes atmospheric nitrogen via an oxygen-sensitive nitrogenase. Not susceptible to lysis by 0.2% (wt/vol) SDS. Moderate thermophiles with an optimal temperature for growth between 37 and 50°C. The major PLFAs are 16:0 and 16:1ω7c. The major ubiquinone is 18-methyleneubiquinone 8(12). The G+C content is 59 to 66 mol%. The type species is <i>Methylomonas capsulatus</i>, which was originally described by Foster and Davis (20). The other species belonging to this genus is <i>Methylomonas thermophilus</i>, which was described by Malashenko et al. (35).</s></p></content></protolog>