<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12692_nm.22432" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22432" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22432" rank="species">Leifsonia psychrotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.12692"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ganzert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bajerski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mangelsdorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia psychrotolerans sp. nov., a psychrotolerant species of the family Microbacteriaceae from Livingston Island, Antarctica</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1938</fpage><lpage>1943</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021956-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833887</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leifsonia psychrotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leifsonia psychrotolerans</em> (psy.chro.to′le.rans. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>psychrotolerans</em> cold-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, motile, non-spore-forming short rods (0.3×0.9 µm).</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, translucent and yellow in colour.</s><s>Grows at −6 to 28 °C (optimum 16 °C) and at pH 4.5–9.5 (optimum pH 5.5–6.5).</s><s>Tolerates up to 5 % NaCl (optimum 1–2 % NaCl).</s><s>Positive for catalase, H<sub>2</sub>S production and methyl red test (weak), but negative for oxidase, urease and indole production.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch (weak), but not casein, Tween 20 or gelatin.</s><s>Grows on nutrient, LB and tryptic soy agar media, but not on mineral medium.</s><s>Unlike other members of the genus <em>Leifsonia</em>, can grow anaerobically with glucose as carbon source.</s><s>Produces acid from d-galactose, d-glucose, l-rhamnose, salicin (weak) and sucrose (weak), but not from lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, adonitol, l-arabinose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Can utilize l-arabitol (weak), cellobiose, dulcitol (weak), <em>m</em>-erythritol, d-fructose (weak), l-fucose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose (weak), d-salicin, sorbitol, d-xylose, acetate, l-asparagine, glycerol, glycogen (weak), pyruvate and succinate, but not adonitol, formate, glycine, lactate, melibiose, raffinose or trehalose as sole carbon source.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin, neomycin, streptomycin, oxytetracycline, novobiocin, rifampicin and kanamycin.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin and erythromycin.</s><s>Major menaquinone is MK-10.</s><s>Major fatty acid (&#x003E;20 % of total composition) is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LI1<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22824<sup>T</sup> = NCCB 100313<sup>T</sup>), isolated from moss-covered soil from Livingston Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of LI1<sup>T</sup> is 64.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>