<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3820_nm.12192" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12192" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.310" rank="species">Haloferax lucentensis</organism><reference id="rid.3820"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gutierrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dyall-Smith</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic characterization of Haloferax sp. ( H. alicantei) strain Aa 2.2: description of Haloferax lucentensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>479</fpage><lpage>483</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00792-002-0282-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12486456</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloferax lucentensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloferax lucentensis</i> (lu.cen.ten'sis L. adj., pertaining to the city of Lucentum, Alicante, Spain, where the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are pleomorphic rods (0.6 × 2.5 μm).</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Colonies are pink, circular, opaque convex with an entire margin.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing 10–30% NaCl, with an optimum at 25% NaCl.</s><s>Grows between 10 and 45°C (optimum at 37°C) and pH 5–9 (optimum at 7.5).</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, fructose, glucose, maltose, xylose and glycerol but not from galactose, lactose, sucrose or trehalose.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole is produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Starch, gelatin and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, fructose, glucose, glucosamine, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, dulcitol, glycerol, acetate, α-aminobutyrate, butyrate, fumarate or glycerate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: fucose, galactose, gluconolactone, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, adonitol, erythritol, ethanol, mannitol, meso-inositol, propanol, sorbitol, aconitate, α-aminovalerate, caprilate, α-ketoglutarate, citrate, glutamate, malate, malonate, oxalate, propionate, saccharate or tartrate.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: L-alanine, L-glutamine, L-methionine, L-proline, L-serine or L-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: L-arginine, L-asparagine, betaine, creatine, glycine, L-histidine, L-lysine, L-ornithine, putrescine, sarcosine or L-threonine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> derivatives of PG, PGP-Me, DGD-1 and S-DGD-1.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 64.5 mol% (<i>Tm</i> method).</s><s>Isolated from salterns in Alicante, Spain.</s><s>Type strain is Aa 2.2<sup>T</sup>. (= JCM 9276 = NCIMB 13854 = CIP 107410 = DSM 14919 = CECT 5871 = CCM 7023).</s></p></content></protolog>