<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12412_nm.21242" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21242" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21242" rank="species">Caloramator mitchellensis</organism><reference id="rid.12412"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ogg</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caloramator mitchellensis sp. nov., a thermoanaerobe isolated from the geothermal waters of the Great Artesian Basin of Australia, and emended description of the genus Caloramator</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>644</fpage><lpage>653</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023655-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20400665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Caloramator mitchellensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Caloramator mitchellensis</em> (mit.chell.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>mitchellensis</em> pertaining to the Mitchell bore in QLD, Australia, from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, thermophilic, slightly curved rods (1.5–3.5×0.4–0.8 μm) that stain Gram-negative but possess a Gram-positive cell-wall ultrastructure.</s><s>Cells possess peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Spores are not observed despite the detection of a <em>spo0A</em> gene homologue.</s><s>Growth occurs between 37 and 60 °C (optimum temperature 55 °C) and pH 6.0 to 9.0 (optimum pH 7).</s><s>Ferments glucose, fructose, xylose, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, cellobiose, ribose, pyruvate, yeast extract, tryptone, peptone, Casamino acids, amyl media and serine, but not galactose, mannose, mannitol, inositol, ethanol, glycerol, acetate, lactate, propionate, citrate, valine, arginine, alanine, glutamate, isoleucine or methionine.</s><s>End products from glucose fermentation are acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>In the presence of 0.2 % yeast extract, vanadium(V) is reduced, but not Fe(III), Mn(IV), elemental sulfur, sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, nitrate or nitrite.</s><s>Vanadium(V) is reduced in the presence of yeast extract, peptone, tryptone, glucose, sucrose and Casamino acids without an increase in growth yield or growth rate.</s><s>Vanadium(V) is not reduced in the presence of glycerol, ethanol, acetate, propionate, pyruvate, lactate or the aromatic compounds benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 2-methoxybenzoate and 3-chlorobenzoate.</s><s>Sensitive to chloramphenicol, streptomycin, tetracycline, penicillin, ampicillin and NaCl concentrations above 2 % (w/v).</s><s>Most closely related to <em>Caloramator australicus</em> (16S rRNA gene sequence similarity of 85.0 and 95.2 %) and <em>Caloramator fervidus</em> (16S rRNA gene sequence similarity of 86.1 and 94.0 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, VF08<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15828<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 5735<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample from the outflow of a GAB bore (the Mitchell Bore) in Queensland, Australia.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.4±0.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>