<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7278_nm.2995" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2995" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2995" rank="species">Vibrio pectenicida</organism><reference id="rid.7278"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nicolas</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cilia</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Corre</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio pectenicida sp. nov., a pathogen of scallop (Pecten maximus) larvae.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>481</fpage><lpage>487</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-481</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731288</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio pectenicida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio pectenicida</i> (pec.ten.i.ci'da. M.L. n. <i>Pecten</i> genus name of scallops; M.L. v. <i>caedo</i> to kill; <i>pectenicida</i> scallop-killer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, motile by means of a single polar flagellum in liquid and unsheathed lateral flagella on solid media.</s><s>Colonies develop within 24 h at 20°C, are circular and smooth, unpigmented and began swarming after 48 h. <i>V. pectenicida</i> strains are not luminescent.</s><s>No growth occurs on thiosulfate/citrate/ bile/sucrose (TCBS) agar.</s><s>No pigment is produced.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative. <i>V. pectenicida</i> strains are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from D-glucose and maltose.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, and nitrate reduction to nitrite are positive. <i>V. pectenicida</i> strains are susceptible to the vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>DNA, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed extracellularly.</s><s>Acetoin and indole are not produced. <i>V. pectenicida</i> uses the following substrates as sole carbon and energy source: maltose, succinate, glycerol, Lrhamnose, isovalerate, pyruvate, L-α-alanine, L-aspartate, L-lysine, L-histidine, betaine, fumarate, glucosamine.</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose and glucose, but not from sucrose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, Dmannose, D-sorbitol, D-xylose, D-galactose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, fructose and L-rhamnose.</s><s>The G + C content is 39-41 mol% as determined by thermal denaturation.</s><s>Regularly isolated from moribund scallop (<i>Pecten maximus</i>) larvae cultured on the Atlantic French coast (Brittany).</s><s>Strain A365<sup>T</sup> is the type strain (=CIP 105190<sup>T</sup>) and had all the properties of the species except for a positive growth response at 30°C (cf.</s><s>Table 2).</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 41 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>