<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1930_nm.8596" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8596" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8596" rank="species">Glycomyces lechevalierae</organism><reference id="rid.1930"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Glycomyces and description of Glycomyces algeriensis sp. nov., Glycomyces arizonensis sp. nov. and Glycomyces lechevalierae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2343</fpage><lpage>2346</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63089-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545481</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glycomyces lechevalierae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glycomyces lechevalierae</em> (le.che.val.i.er′ae. N.L. fem. n. <em>lechevalierae</em> named for Mary Lechevalier, an American microbiologist who isolated this strain and contributed substantially to the field of actinomycete biology during her career at the Waksman Institute of Microbiology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>White to yellowish white waxy growth on most media.</s><s>Light grey to yellow plicate growth on ATCC medium 172.</s><s>Sparse white aerial mycelia produced on several media.</s><s>Menaquinones present include MK-10, MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-11, MK-11(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-11(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Adenine, allantoin, casein, aesculin, hypoxanthine, starch and tyrosine are hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Gelatin, urea and xanthine are not hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, malate, mucate, oxalate and succinate are assimilated.</s><s>Benzoate, lactate, propionate and dl-tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from melibiose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside or raffinose.</s><s>Growth occurs on 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRRL B-16149<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44724<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil collected from a corn field in Greensburg, PA, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>