<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4482_nm.1432" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1432" rank="genus">Albibacter</organism><reference id="rid.4482"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuznetsov</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leisinger</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Albibacter methylovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel aerobic, facultatively autotrophic and methylotrophic bacterium that utilizes dichloromethane.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1051</fpage><lpage>1058</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411673</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Albibacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Albibacter</i> (Al.bi.bac'ter. L. adj. <i>albus</i> white; M.L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i> equivalent of Gr. neut. n. <i>baktron</i> a small rod; M.L. masc. n. <i>Albibacter</i> white rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, colourless rods that occur singly, in pairs or in clusters and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Colonies on methanol or PYG agar are circular, 1-2 mm in diameter, white, convex, translucent to opaque and mucoid.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Does not produce water-soluble fluorescent pigment.</s><s>Indole is produced from tryptophan on medium with nitrate as nitrogen source.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>No anaerobic growth in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>Produces acids from sugars oxidatively, but not fermentatively.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, but not gelatin or cellulose.</s><s>Chemolithoheterotrophic and facultatively methylotrophic, assimilating C<sub>1</sub> compounds by the RuBP pathway.</s><s>Able to grow on a wide spectrum of polycarbon substrates.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrate, urea, peptone, some amino acids and methylamine are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Strictly aerobic, with a respiratory type of metabolism.</s><s>Neutrophilic and mesophilic.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0-9.0 and at temperatures between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>No growth in the presence of 3% NaCl.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>Dominant phospholipids are phosphatidyl ethanolamine, phosphatidyl glycerol, phosphatidyl choline and phosphoserine.</s><s>The prevailing cellular fatty acids are <i>cis</i>-vaccenic (<i>c</i>18:1<i>ω</i>7) and palmitic (16:0) acids.</s><s>Levels of DNA-DNA hybridization with representatives of the genera <i>Paracoccus</i>, <i>Xanthobacter</i>, <i>Blastobacter</i>, <i>Angulomicrobium</i>, <i>Ralstonia</i> and <i>Methylopila</i> are less than 7%.</s><s>The genus <i>Albibacter</i> belongs to the α-2 subgroup of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, as revealed by comparative sequence analysis of the 16S rDNA.</s><s>The type species is <i>Albibacter methylovorans</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>