<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2310_nm.9808" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9808" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9808" rank="species">Nonlabens tegetincola</organism><reference id="rid.2310"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>S.C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plakhotnikova</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobretsov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawlik</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonlabens tegetincola gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from a microbial mat in a subtropical estuary</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2279</fpage><lpage>2283</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63810-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nonlabens tegetincola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nonlabens tegetincola</em> (te.get.in′col.a. L. n. <em>teges</em> -<em>etis</em> mat; L. n. <em>incola</em> an inhabitant; N.L. n. <em>tegetincola</em> mat-inhabitant, pertaining to its microbial mat habitat).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus plus the following.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are orange in colour, circular, 2·0–4·0 mm in diameter, convex with smooth surfaces and entire translucent margins.</s><s>No diffusible pigment.</s><s>Growth occurs between 12·0 and 44·0 °C (28·0–36·0 °C optimum), pH 5·0 and 10·0 and 2·0 and 4·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to kanamycin.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 33·6 mol% and the dominant fatty acids are i15 : 0, i15 : 0 3-OH, i16 : 0, i16 : 0 3-OH, i17 : 0 3-OH, summed feature 3 (comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) and an unknown fatty acid with a carbon chain length equivalent to 13·6 (altogether representing 78·3 % of the total).</s><s>Produces acetoin, but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80, but not agar, casein, cellulose or chitin.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are positive. <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease activities are negative.</s><s>Except for acid production from sucrose, no growth or acid production is observed from the carbon sources included in the API 50 CH, API 20 E and API 20 NE test systems.</s><s>Except for growth on complex media containing yeast extract and peptone, the carbon and nitrogen sources supporting the growth of <em>Nonlabens tegetincola</em> are hitherto not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UST030701-324<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-41136<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12886<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a microbial mat in an estuarine mangrove habitat in the Bahamas.</s></p></content></protolog>