<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7244_nm.5806" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5806" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5806" rank="species">Actinomyces urogenitalis</organism><reference id="rid.7244"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nikolaitchouk</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grainger</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Actinomyces isolates from samples from the human urogenital tract: description of Actinomyces urogenitalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1649</fpage><lpage>1654</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939672</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces urogenitalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces urogenitalis</i> (u.ro.ge.ni.ta'lis. M.L. adj. <i>urogenitalis</i> belonging to the urogenital tract)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods which stain Gram-positive, are non-acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose, darabitol (weak), maltose, melibiose, melezitose, lactose, D-raffinose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from cyclodextrin, glycogen, pullulan, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from L-arabinose, mannitol, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside and ribose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin and hippurate are not.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, valine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, acid phosphatase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, α-fucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophane arylamidase, β-mannosidase, pyrazinamidase, trypsin and urease are not produced.</s><s>Activities for alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase and a-mannosidase may or may not be detected.</s><s>Acetoin production is variable.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical sources.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 38702<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106421<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+­C content of the type strain is 61 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>