<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1331_nm.4426" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4426" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4426" rank="species">Selenomonas flueggei</organism><reference id="rid.1331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas noxia sp. nov., Selenomonas flueggei sp. nov., Selenomonas infelix sp. nov., Selenomonas dianae sp. nov., and Selenomonas artemidis sp. nov., from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas flueggei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas flueggei</i> (fluegge'i. N. L. gen. n. <i>flueggei</i> of Flugge [named for C. Flugge, an early German bacteriologist]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, motile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods.</s><s>Cells are curved, crescent shaped, and 1.0 to 1.3 by 3.8 to 13.9 μm.</s><s>With Leifson flagellum stain, cells appear to have one or more central-to-polar flagella arising from the concave side.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On rabbit blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h, discrete colonies are 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter, circular, entire to spreading, opaque, white, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Sometimes growth is as a spreading film over the entire plate.</s><s>Strains produce moderate turbidity in PY broth and abundant growth with clear broth and a smooth sediment in PYG broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 to 45°C; strains grow well at 30°C but poorly, if at all, at 25°C.</s><s>Neutral red is not reduced.</s><s>In PYG agar deep cultures, resazurin is reduced and moderate amounts of gas are produced.</s><s>A moderate amount of ammonia is detected in chopped meat broth cultures, but none is produced in PY or PYG cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation acids of the type strain, in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture, are 2.0 of acetic and 3.5 of propionic in PYG cultures; 0.3 of acetic, 0.5 of propionic, and 0.37 of lactic in PY cultures; 3.6 of acetic, 2.0 of propionic, and 1.1 of lactic in PY-pyruvate cultures; and 4.8 of acetic and 4.7 of</s></p><p class="description"><s>propionic in PYG-fumarate cultures.</s><s>Lactate is not used, and threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>No hydrogen, or only a trace amount, is detected in the headspace gas of PYG cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The PAGE protein patterns are shown in Fig. 2.</s><s>Cellular components of the species are given in Table 5.</s><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 56mol%.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the nine other</s></p><p class="description"><s>strains tested are 54 to 60 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 43531, isolated from the gingival crevice of a person in an experimental gingivitis trial.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although there are two DNA homology subgroups in this species, those with 86 to 88% homology with the type strain and those with 73 to 93% relatedness with strain D65C-23A and only 57 to 69% homology with the type strain, no phenotypic trait tested differentiated the two subgroups.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is isolated from the gingival crevice of persons with gingivitis or periodontitis and from the adjacent supragingival- plaque coronal to the sites affected with periodontitis.</s><s>This species has been referred to as <i>Selenomonas</i>d D-2 and D-10 and D-15 (in part) in previous publications.</s></p></content></protolog>