<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12732_nm.22503" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22503" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22503" rank="species">Tistrella bauzanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tistrella bauzanensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2227</fpage><lpage>2230</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026930-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952545</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tistrella bauzanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tistrella bauzanensis</em> [bau.zan.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bauzanensis</em> referring to Bauzanum (latin name of Bozen/Bolzano), a city in South Tyrol, Italy, from where the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, strictly aerobic and rod-shaped (1.0–1.2×1.5–12 µm after 5 days at 20 °C on R2A agar); they often occur in chains with a length of approximately 12 µm and are motile.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are white, round, convex and smooth with entire margin; colony diameter is about 1 mm after 5 days at 20 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A, nutrient agar and TSA.</s><s>Good growth on R2A plates and in liquid R2A medium occurs at 1–25 °C; growth is weak at 30 °C and absent at 37 °C.</s><s>In liquid culture, growth rate is highest at 25 °C but cell yields are highest at 10–20 °C.</s><s>On R2A agar plates, growth is observed at pH 7 and in the presence of 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Accumulates PHAs.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and production of indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Negative for hydrogen sulfide production and hydrolysis of urea, starch, aesculin and gelatin.</s><s>Positive for catalase, cytochrome <em>c</em> oxidase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities; weakly positive for alkaline phosphatase and valine arylamidase activities; negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase, ornithine dihydrolase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase and α-mannosidase activities.</s><s>Assimilates malic acid but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltose, potassium gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, capric acid or phenylacetic acid as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of all 49 organic substrates in the API 50 CH system.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin, amikacin, rifampicin and neomycin (each 30 µg) but resistant to chloramphenicol (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and erythromycin (15 µg).</s><s>Q-10 is the major ubiquinone.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> cyclo, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BZ78<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22817<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 1.10188<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 26047<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from hydrocarbon-contaminated soil in Bozen, South Tyrol, Italy.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>