<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12465_nm.21294" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21294" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21294" rank="species">Arthrobacter livingstonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12465"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ganzert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bajerski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mangelsdorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter livingstonensis sp. nov. and Arthrobacter cryotolerans sp. nov., salt-tolerant and psychrotolerant species from Antarctic soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>979</fpage><lpage>984</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021022-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511467</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter livingstonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter livingstonensis</em> (li.ving.sto.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>livingstonensis</em> pertaining to Livingston Island, Antarctica, the sampling location of the soil from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are off-white, opaque, round, slightly convex and glossy with entire margins.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, psychrotolerant, Gram-stain-positive, motile, non-spore-forming and exhibit a rod–coccus cycle.</s><s>Growth occurs from −6 to 28 °C, at pH 4.0–9.5 and in the presence of 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth at 16 °C, pH 8.0 and 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, H<sub>2</sub>S production and urease and negative for oxidase, indole production and the methyl red test.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is weak.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose and d-mannitol and is produced weakly from d-galactose and sucrose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Can utilize l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-glucose, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, d-ribose, d-salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, glycerol, glycogen, l-asparagine, glycine, acetate, pyruvate and succinate as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, formate, lactic acid or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Sensitive to (10 µg per disc) penicillin, ampicillin, kanamycin, neomycin, streptomycin, erythromycin, oxytetracycline, novobiocin and rifampicin.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;20 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 64.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LI2<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22825<sup>T</sup>  = NCCB 100314<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a moss-covered soil from Livingston Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>