<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1686_nm.11484" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11484" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11484" rank="species">Mycobacterium salmoniphilum</organism><reference id="rid.1686"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whipps</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pourahmad</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watral</surname><given-names>V.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kent</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Molecular systematics support the revival of Mycobacterium salmoniphilum (ex Ross 1960) sp. nov., nom. rev., a species closely related to Mycobacterium chelonae</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2525</fpage><lpage>2531</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64841-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978213</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium salmoniphilum</em> (<em>ex</em> Ross 1960) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium salmoniphilum</em> (sal.mo.ni.phi′lum. L. n. <em>salmo</em> -<em>onis</em> a salmon; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>salmoniphilum</em> salmon-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as given by Ross (1960) and also follows the descriptions of ‘<em>M. chelonae</em> subsp. <em>piscarium</em>’ Arakawa &#x0026; Fryer (1984) and ‘Salmoniphilum’ strains of <em>M. fortuitum</em> (Tsukamura <em>et al.</em>, 1967).</s><s>Cells are acid-fast bacilli, consistent with species of the genus <em>Mycobacterium</em>.</s><s>Growth occurs on Middlebrook 7H10 agar, blood agar, MacConkey agar and Löwenstein–Jensen slants, forming cream-coloured, smooth, shiny colonies, visible after 4–6 days.</s><s>Following incubation periods exceeding 10 days, colonies tend to appear waxy, with an irregular border and ‘fried egg’ morphology.</s><s>Growth is observed at room temperature (20 °C) and with incubation at 28 to 30 °C.</s><s>Weak or delayed growth may occur at 10 °C, and no growth is observed at or above 37 °C.</s><s>Bacilli are generally slender and straight or slightly curved, with some short and thick.</s><s>Dimensions range from 1 to 4 μm in length and 0.25 to 0.6 μm in width.</s><s>Isolates have been recovered from infected salmonid fishes (although there may be other susceptible species), found throughout the viscera and predominantly in the kidney.</s><s>Closely related species are members of the <em>M. chelonae</em> complex, i.e. <em>M. chelonae</em>, <em>M. abscessus</em>, <em>M. immunogenum</em>, <em>M. massiliense</em> and <em>M. bolletii</em>, sharing the characteristics of a positive 3 day arylsulfatase test, negative nitrate reductase test and the absence of pigmentation.</s><s>Strains can be distinguished from these species by a positive test for glucose utilization and by DNA sequences.</s><s>Sequence analysis of the SSU rRNA gene, <em>hsp65</em>, <em>rpoB</em> and ITS regions shows that isolates are phylogenetically and consistently distinct from other members of the <em>M. chelonae</em> complex.</s><s>Mycolic acid HPLC patterns are visually distinct, forming two clusters of mycolates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain SC<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 13758<sup>T</sup> =DSM 43276<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Chinook salmon (<em>Oncorhynchus tshawytscha</em>) at the Spring Creek fish hatchery in Washington state, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>