<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5710_nm.4407" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4407" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4407" rank="species">Papillibacter cinnamivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5710"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Defnoun</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ambrosio</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Papillibacter cinnamivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a cinnamate-transforming bacterium from a shea cake digester.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1221</fpage><lpage>1228</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843066</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Papillibacter cinnamivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Papillibacter cinnamivorans</i> (cin.na.mi.vo'rans. M.L. n. <i>cinnamum</i> cinnamic acid; L. part. adj. <i>vorans</i> devouring, digesting; M.L. part. adj. <i>cinnamivorans</i> cinnamic-acid-digesting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-sporulating anaerobes which stain Gram-positive and are non-motile.</s><s>The isolate utilizes cinnamate, 3-methoxycinnamate, 4-methoxycinnamate and crotonate.</s><s>No growth occurs with the following substrates: mono-methoxylated aromatic compound (2-methoxycinnamate), di-methoxylated aromatic compounds (2,3-, 2,4-, 2,5-, 2,6-, 3,5- dimethoxybenzoate, 3,5-dimethoxycinnamaldehyde), tri-methoxylated aromatic compounds (3,4,5- trimethoxybenzoate, 3,4,5-trimethoxycinnamate, 3,4,5-trimethoxyphenylacetate, 3,4,5-trimethoxyphenylpropionate), hydroxy-methoxylated aromatic compounds (ferulate, syringate and sinapate), monohydroxylated aromatic compounds (2-, 3-, 4-hydroxycinnamate, phenol and 4-hydroxybenzoate), polyhydroxylated aromatic compounds (caffeate, gallate, tyrosol, phloroglucinol, pyrogallol, catechol and hydroquinone), non-hydroxylated and non-methoxylated substituted cinnamyl derivatives (α-methylcinnamate, methyl <i>trans</i>-cinnamate, cinnamyl alcohol, <i>trans</i>-cinnamate methyl ester and coumarine), nonsubstituted aromatic compounds (benzoate, hydrocinnamate and phenylacetate), organic acids (crotonate, pyruvate, succinate, malate, fumarate, propionate and butyrate), carbohydrates (glucose, fructose, saccharose, ribose, xylose, cellobiose, maltose, galactose, mannose, lactose and arabinose), alcohols (butanol, methanol and ethanol) or extracts (Biotrypcase, peptone, Casamino acids, gelatin and casein).</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, nitrate, elemental sulfur or fumarate are not reduced.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is 7.5 (pH growth range 6.9-8.5).</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37°C (temperature growth range 15-40°C).</s><s>Optimum growth occurs in the presence of 0.5-1.0% NaCl, with no growth occurring in the presence of 2.0% NaCl.</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA is 56 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is CIN1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12816<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 700879<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from an anaerobic digester fed with shea cake, Burkina Faso.</s></p></content></protolog>