<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2031_nm.10720" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10720" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10720" rank="species">Flagellimonas eckloniae</organism><reference id="rid.2031"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flagellimonas eckloniae gen. nov., sp. nov., a mesophilic marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from the rhizosphere of Ecklonia kurome</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1050</fpage><lpage>1054</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64565-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473257</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flagellimonas eckloniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flagellimonas eckloniae</em> (ec.klo.ni′a.e. N.L. fem. n. <em>Ecklonia</em> scientific genus name of the marine alga from which the bacterium was isolated; N.L. gen. n. <em>eckloniae</em> of <em>Ecklonia</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 1.1–2.3 μm in length and 0.2–0.36 μm in diameter and motile by means of a single polar flagellum (see Supplementary Fig. S1 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Cells form irregular aggregates during growth in MB.</s><s>After 3 days of incubation on MA at 25 °C, colonies are orange-pigmented, opaque, convex and uniformly circular.</s><s>Absorption maxima of the pigments extracted with solvent solution are observed at 450 and 473 nm.</s><s>Growth occurs between 17 and 36 °C, at pH 7–9 and in the presence of 2.5–7 % sea salts.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> and Ca<sup>2+</sup> ions for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth requires the presence of 3.5–4 % (w/v) sea salts (corresponding to 2.7–3.1 % NaCl), pH 8 and 26–29 °C.</s><s>Cells hydrolyse casein, but not agar, gelatin or starch.</s><s>In API 20NE test strips, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and protease (gelatin hydrolysis) activities are positive, but reduction of nitrate to nitrogen, glucose acidification, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and arginine dihydrolase and urease activity are negative; acetoin production is weakly positive.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 MicroPlates, cells utilize dextrin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-glucuronic acid, dl-lactic acid and l-aspartic acid.</s><s>Weakly positive results are recorded for the utilization of glycogen, d-fructose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-leucine, l-proline, l-threonine, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>The dominant fatty acids are iso-15 : 0 (41.8 %), iso-15 : 1<em>ω</em>10<em>c</em> (11.4 %), 10-methyl-16 : 0 (9.2 %), 15 : 0 (7.0 %), unidentified fatty acid ECL 18.056 (6.5 %,) and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (6.0 %).</s><s>Other characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DOKDO 007<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42307<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13831<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of the marine alga <em>Ecklonia kurome</em> collected on Dokdo Island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>