<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2690_nm.3146" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3146" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3146" rank="species">Edwardsiella hoshinae</organism><reference id="rid.2690"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakazaki</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Edwardsiella hoshinae, a new species of Enterobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>347</fpage><lpage>351</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02605375</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Edwardsiella hoshinae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Edwardsiella hoshinae</i> (Latin genitive (masculine) from Hoshina, in honor of the Japanese bacteriologist Toshikazu Hoshina, who was among the first persons to work with what we now call <i>Edwardsiella</i> spp.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All 27 <i>Edwardsiella</i> strains are Gram-negative, motile, peritrichous, nonsporeforming straight rods.</s><s>They grow on nutrient agar (30 and 37°C) giving flat or slightly convex colonies about 1-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>They are facultatively aerobic.</s><s>All 27 strains produced indole from peptone water, produced lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, reduced nitrates into nitrites, and were susceptible to the vibriostatic compound O/129.</s><s>Acid was produced (in peptone water, 1 day) from glucose, D-mannose, fructose, and D-galactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the 27 <i>Edwardsiella</i> strains could grow on M70 minimal agar glucose (without growth factor), Simmons' citrate, or KCN medium.</s><s>ONPG and Voges-Proskauer tests were negative.</s><s>Oxidase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, arginine decarboxylase, DNase, chitinase, lipase (tributyrin agar), Tween-80 esterase, and gelatinase were not produced.</s><s>Acid was not produced from adonitol, D-cellobiose, dulcitol, myo-inositol, lactose, D-melibiose, α-methyl-glucoside, mucate, polygalacturonate, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Esculin was not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results of DNA-relatedness studies obtained with labeled reference DNA from <i>E. hoshinae</i> 2-78 and from <i>E. tarda</i> 10396 are shown in Table 3.</s><s>The S1-resistant core [6] (in the incubated control tube containing labeled DNA only) was calculated as 7.3 ± 1% for <i>E. hoshinae</i> 2-78 and 6.9 ± 1.3% for <i>E. tarda</i> 10396 (results at both temperatures).</s><s>Typical and atypical <i>E. tarda</i> strains were, respectively, 81.5 ± 9.2% and 71.3 ± 2.0% related to strain 10396, and, respectively, 49.1 ± 6.3% and 49.0 ± 4.6% related to strain 2-78 at 60°C. <i>E. hoshinae</i> strains were 88.4 ± 10.8% and 43.6 ± 1.7% related, respectively, to strains 2-78 and 10396 at 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results of hybridization experiments at 75°C were not dramatically different from those obtained at 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Percent divergence (∆<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) was less than 0.7% between <i>E. hoshinae</i> strains and strain 2-78, and 9.7-10% between <i>E. hoshinae</i> strains and strain 10396.</s><s>Percent divergence was less than 3% between <i>E. tarda</i> strains (whether typical or atypical) and strain 10396, and 7.3 12.1% between <i>E. tarda</i> strains (typical and atypical) and strain 2-78.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All non-<i>Edwardsiella</i> strains tested were clearly distinct from both <i>Edwardsiella</i> strains 2-78 and 10396 on the basis of DNA relatedness (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The base composition of the DNAs of <i>E. tarda</i> strains NCTC 10396 and CDC 3592-62 and <i>E. hoshinae</i> strains 2-78 and 490-72 were calculated to be, respectively (± standard deviation), 55.1 ± 0.3, 58.0 ± 0.7, 55.7 ± 0.1, and 57.1 ± 0.1 mol% G+C.</s><s>DNA of <i>Escherichia coli</i> K-12 was simultaneously found to have 51.2 ± 0.1 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We designate strata 2-78 (CIP 78.56, ATCC 33379) as the type strain for <i>E. hoshinae</i>.</s><s>Although we had only 8 strains of <i>E. hoshinae</i>, we believe that publication of this new species will help other bacteriologists find <i>E. hoshinae</i> among unidentified mannitol-positive <i>Edwardsiella</i>-like strains.</s><s>The presently known habitat of <i>E. hoshinae</i> includes birds, reptiles, and water.</s></p></content></protolog>