<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6912_nm.462" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.462" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.462" rank="species">Thermotoga hypogea</organism><reference id="rid.6912"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rimbault</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rocchiccioli</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermotoga hypogea sp. nov., a xylanolytic, thermophilic bacterium from an oil-producing well.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1013</fpage><lpage>1019</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336900</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermotoga hypogea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermotoga hypogea</i> (hy.po.ge'a. Gr. pron. <i>hypos</i>, under; Gr. n. <i>ge</i>, earth; L. fem. adj. <i>hypogea</i>, under the earth, referring to the site of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Round colonies (diameter, 1 mm) are present after 7 days of incubation at 70°C.</s><s>Cells are rods (0.5 to 1 by 2 to 3 μm), and each cell has an outer sheath-like structure (toga).</s><s>The cells stain gram negative, occur singly or in pairs, and possess laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and obligately anaerobic member of the domain Bacteria.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 70°C at pH 7.0; the temperature range is 56 to 90°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.3 to 7.4 at 70°C; growth occurs between pH 6.1 and pH 9.1.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is between 0 and 0.2% at 70°C and pH 7.0; growth occurs in the presence of NaCl concentrations ranging from 0 and 1.5%.</s><s>Uses D-glucose, DL-fructose, D-galactose, DL-lactose, DL-maltose, D-mannose, D-sucrose, D-xylose, and xylan but not D-arabinose, D-ribose, L-sorbose, L-xylose, acetate, butyrate, lactate, or propionate.</s><s>Ferments yeast extract and bio-Trypticase.</s><s>Requires yeast extract or bio-Trypticase for growth on carbohydrates.</s><s>Yeast extract cannot be replaced by Casamino Acids, a vitamin solution, or a mixture of Casamino Acids and vitamins.</s><s>The end products of glucose and xylose fermentation are acetate, CO<sub>2</sub>, H<sub>2</sub>, L-alanine, and traces of ethanol.</s><s>Uses thiosulfate as an electron acceptor during glucose fermentation, and under these conditions the biomass is greater than the biomass obtained with no added electron acceptor.</s><s>H,S is produced from thiosulfate reduction.</s><s>Elemental sulfur cannot be used as an electron acceptor, and growth is not inhibited by elemental sulfur.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50 mol% (as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography).</s><s>Isolated from an oil-producing well.</s><s>The type strain is SEBR 7054 (= DSM 11164).</s></p></content></protolog>