<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1924_nm.8577" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8577" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8577" rank="species">Enterococcus saccharominimus</organism><reference id="rid.1924"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zamfir</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engelbeen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vuyst</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus saccharominimus sp. nov., from dairy products</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2175</fpage><lpage>2179</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63193-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545454</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus saccharominimus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus saccharominimus</em> (sac.cha.ro.mi′ni.mus Gr. n. <em>sacchar</em> sugar; L. sup. adj. <em>minimus</em>; very least N.L. sup. adj. <em>saccharominimus</em> meaning that this organism differs from other enterococci in that it lyses only few sugars).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregularly sized, Gram-positive and coccal or ovoidal, which are predominantly arranged in small groups.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia sheep blood agar are smaller than commonly seen with the enterococci (up to 2 mm in diameter), unpigmented, regular and translucent, surrounded by zones of semi-transparent <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>The strains grow equally well at 30 and 37 °C.</s><s>Addition of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub> does not enhance growth.</s><s>They form deposits with clear supernatants in brain heart infusion broth (Oxoid) and react weakly with Lancefield group D antiserum (Streptococcal grouping kit; Oxoid).</s><s>Not motile.</s><s>All strains tested positive in API 20 STREP tests with Voges–Proskauer reagents and for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Aesculin is degraded weakly.</s><s>In API 50 CH galleries, acid is produced from galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, lactose and sucrose.</s><s>Reactions are strain-dependent for acid production from amygdalin, cellobiose, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, salicin, trehalose, d-turanose and d-tagatose.</s><s>All strains tested negative for activity of hippurate, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and alkaline phosphatase, and for acid production from glycerol, erythritol, dl-arabinose, ribose, dl-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, arbutin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, xylitol, d-lyxose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, gluconate and 2- and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 38–39 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: dairy products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21727<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7220<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from contaminated pasteurized cow's milk.</s></p></content></protolog>