<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8256_nm.13241" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13241" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13241" rank="species">Barnesiella intestinihominis</organism><reference id="rid.8256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dialister succinatiphilus sp. nov. and Barnesiella intestinihominis sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2716</fpage><lpage>2720</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000810-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060046</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Barnesiella intestinihominis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Barnesiella intestinihominis</em> (in.tes.ti.ni.ho′mi.nis. L. gen. n. <em>intestini</em> of the intestine; L. gen. n. <em>hominis</em> of a human being; N.L. gen. n. <em>intestinihominis</em> of the human intestine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, pleomorphic rods (0.4–1.0×1.3–13.0 μm) that hydrolyse aesculin, but are negative for indole production.</s><s>Colonies after 3 days anaerobic incubation on anaerobe basal agar are 1–3 mm in diameter, translucent with irregular margins, pale orange–yellow in colour and low convex.</s><s>Analysis of metabolic end products by HPLC from PYG broth reveals succinic and acetic acids.</s><s>Catalase, urease and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose and d-mannose, but not from d-mannitol, sucrose, salicin, d-xylose, l-arabinose, glycerol, melezitose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or trehalose.</s><s>Weak acid is produced from cellobiose.</s><s>Using the commercially available API test systems, activity is detected for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but not for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase C4, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Weak activity is detected for esterase lipase C8 and esterase C4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 11860<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21032<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15079<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>