<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6099_nm.10240" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10240" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10240" rank="species">Meganema perideroedes</organism><reference id="rid.6099"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thomsen</surname><given-names>T.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Muro</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Meganema perideroedes gen. nov., sp. nov., a filamentous alphaproteobacterium from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1865</fpage><lpage>1868</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02916-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902022</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Meganema perideroedes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Meganema perideroedes</em> (pe.ri.de.ro′ed.es. Gr. nom. neut. adj. <em>perideroedes</em> necklace-like).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species shares the characteristics listed in the genus description.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.9 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: mixed liquors of activated sludge WWTP.</s><s>Although all isolates grow on R2A medium, some (Gr1<sup>T</sup>, Gr2 and Gr10) grow well, taking only a few days to produce macroscopically visible colonies, which are dense and white.</s><s>Storage of strains Gr5 and Gr28 was unsuccessful and the strains were lost after sequencing of their 16S rRNA genes.</s><s>Strains Gr1<sup>T</sup>, Gr2 and Gr10 demonstrate a very similar morphology in that the cells in all filaments are irregularly disc-shaped and are approximately 1.5–2 μm in diameter (see Supplementary Fig. S2); they show no gliding motility.</s><s>Gram- and Neisser-staining shows that they are Gram-negative and contain Neisser-positive granules.</s><s>Only strains Gr1<sup>T</sup> and Gr10 have been characterized phenotypically; they are not able to grow on minimal media, so a full characterization of the growth requirements has not been possible.</s><s>They are not able to grow anaerobically with nitrate as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Starch and tributyrin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–35 °C and the optimum temperature for growth is 25–30 °C.</s><s>Both strains are able to grow in the presence of NaCl concentrations up to 2 %, but do not grow in the presence of 3 % NaCl.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain Gr1<sup>T</sup> is composed of C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (86.4 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (3.8 %), summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH) (2.4 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2.9 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2.3 %) and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> 10-methyl (1.1 %).</s><s>The profile of strain Gr10 is almost identical.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Gr1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15528<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-740<sup>T</sup>), isolated by micromanipulation from sludge of an industrial WWTP at Grindsted, Denmark.</s><s>There are currently three extant strains in the species.</s></p></content></protolog>