<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1882_nm.2633" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2633" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2633" rank="species">Pseudomonas lundensis</organism><reference id="rid.1882"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Molin</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ternström</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ursing</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas lundensis, a new bacterial species isolated from meat.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>342</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas lundensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas lundensis</i> (lund.en'sis. M.L. adj. <i>lundensis</i> referring to the city of Lund, Sweden)</s></p><p class="description"><s>An extensive phenotypic characterization of the species and lists of strains have been published by Molin and Ternstrom (3, 4).</s><s>A detailed genotypic characterization has been published by Ursing (in press).</s><s>Two peripheral strains of cluster 2 of Molin and Ternstrom (3), strains 99 and 102, are not considered to belong to <i>P. lundensis</i>.</s><s>These strains did not cluster with other strains when the Jaccard coefficient and the clustering level definition of Molin and Ternstrom were used (4); they are less vigorous, exhibit several atypical reactions, and, furthermore, were not included in <i>P. lundensis</i> when genetic criteria were used (Ursing, in press).</s><s>The description below</s></p><p class="description"><s>is based on 60 strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown in batch cultures are typically 0.7 to 1.0 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm, but cells in their natural habitat on meat and cells grown in continuous cultures are frequently quite small (0.5 to 0.7 by 1.0 to 1.5 μm).</s><s>The cells are asporogenous, gram negative, rod shaped, and motile at 25°C by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar (Oxoid Ltd.) are 1 to 5 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation at 25°C, circular, and smooth.</s><s>Pigments are usually not formed on nutrient agar, but a greenish tinge due to the formation of fluorescent pigments may be observed.</s><s>Fluorescent pigments are produced by all strains on King B agar, although detection of pigments may require a fluorimetric assay.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory and never fermentative.</s><s>Oxygen is the terminal electron acceptor; nitrate does not serve as an alternate electron acceptor.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is usually 0 to 33°C, but 30% of the strains are capable of slow growth at 37°C.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 25°C.</s><s>There is no growth at pH 4.5.</s><s>No growth factors are required.</s><s>No flocks with dendritic outgrowths are formed.</s><s>The organism is strictly chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated as a carbon reserve material.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is present.</s><s>The cells are catalase and cytochrome oxidase positive.</s><s>All strains except strains 134, 313,436, and 500 liquefy gelatin.</s><s>No strain except strain 469 produces lipase against Tween 80.</s><s>All strains produce acid but no gas from L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-ribose, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, and D-xylose; the last four sugars do not serve as single-carbon sources in assimilation tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid from glycerol and L-rhamnose varies between strains, as does the production of urease and proteolytic attack of egg yolk and casein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substances are assimilated by at least 90% of the strains within 7 days of incubation at 25°C (negative strains are indicated in parentheses): acetate, L-α-alanine, β-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, 2-aminoethanol (strain 178), 5-aminopentanoate, L-arabinose (strain 4 3 , L-arginine, Lasparagine, L-aspartate, betaine (strains 65 and 137), citrate (strain 478), D-fructose, fumarate, D-gluconate (strains 321, 322, 323, and 325), D-glucose, L-glutamate, L-glutamine, glycerate (strain 573T), glycerol (strain 478), heptanoate, L-histidine, <i>meso</i>-inositol (strains 137, 358, 424, 425, 433, and 436), L-lactate (strains 313 and 326), L-leucine (strain 359), L-malate (strains 8 and 178), L-ornithine, 2-okoglutarate, pelargonate, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, propionate, putrescine, pyruvate, succinate, DL-tyrosine, and m-valine (strain 359).</s><s>The assimilation of the following substances is variable (the percentages of positive strains are indicated in parentheses): D-arabinose (77%), benzoate (70%), carnosine (32%), creatine (78%), deoxycholate (85%), D-galactose (13%), DL-hydroxybutyrate (16%), L-isoleucine (89%), D-malate (21%), D-ribose (43%), sarcosine (89%), and taurocholate (88%).</s><s>Assimilation of butyrate, caproate, L-lysine, D-mannose, and trehalose is slow, and the results depend on the incubation time.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics and substances assimilated by less than 10% of the strains are given below in the type strain description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNAs of 10 strains is 59 mol% (range, 58 to 60 mol%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains 338 and 385 of Molin and Ternstrom (4) have been deposited in the Czechoslovak Collection of Microorganisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Type strain 138 (= 573 = CCM 3503) was isolated from beef.</s><s>Most of the tests (see below) were performed on three different occasions in two laboratories.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell characteristics.</s><s>The cells are gram-negative, motile by means of one polarly inserted flagellum (although no statistical evaluation has been performed), 0.7 to 0.8 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm, asporogenous, and rod shaped.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial characteristics.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, circular, and nonpigmented.</s><s>They are nonhemolytic on ox blood agar and do not glide on cytophaga agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and physiological characteristics.</s><s>Accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as intracellular inclusions does not occur.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 0 to 33°C, with optimal growth at 25°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl, but at least 6% NaCl is tolerated when cells are grown on plates and approximately 5% NaCl (but not 6% NaCl) is tolerated when cells are grown in broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine dihydrolase, catalase, and cytochrome c oxidase are produced.</s><s>A fluorescent pigment (pyoverdine) is produced on King B medium.</s><s>Phenazine pigments are not produced on King A medium.</s><s>Growth occurs on Simmons citrate agar, hippurate is hydrolyzed, and tyrosine is decomposed.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied, although this capability seems to be unstable after subculturing.</s><s>Small amounts of proteases against casein are also produced, but the standard method (1) frequently fails to detect them.</s><s>Action on egg yolk is characterized by a weak egg yolk reaction and a definite clearing zone.</s><s>There is no action against DNA or ribonucleic acid.</s><s>No lipases against Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, Tween 85, or tributyrin are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There is no growth on alginate and pectate agar; phenylalanine is not deaminated; lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated; esculin and starch are not hydrolyzed; hydrogen sulfide (triple sugar iron), indole, phosphatase, and urease are not produced; nitrate is not reduced to nitrogen gas; trimethylamineoxide is not reduced; extracellular polysaccharides are not synthesized; and methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid without gas is produced aerobically but never anaerobically from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, D-ribose, and D-xylose on modified Hugh-Leifson medium (4).</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, dextrin, D-fructose, galactitol, glucitol, glycogen (oyster), <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, lactose, D-mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, ribitol, salicin, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or xylitol.</s><s>No significant amount of acid (no zone) is produced from glycerol, although the bacterial growth may turn yellow.</s><s>The data for acid production from L-rhamnose are conflicting.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Assimilation of carbon compounds.</s><s>The following carbon sources are assimilated: acetate, D-alanine, L-alanine, β-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate (GABA), 2-aminoethanol, 5-aminopentanoate, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, L-arginine, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, benzoate, betaine, butyrate, caprate, caproate, caprylate, carnosine, citrate, creatine, D-fructose, fumarate, D-gluconate, D-glucose, L-glutamate, L-glutamine, glutarate, glycerol, heptanoate, L-histidine, DL-3-hydroxybutyratree, <i>meso</i>-inositol, isoleucine, L-lactate, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-malate, D-mannose, L-ornithine, 2-oxoglutarate, pelargonate, L-phenylalanine, propionate, L-proline, putrescine, pyruvate, D-ribose, sarcosine, spermine, succinate, taurocholate, DL-tyrosine, and DL-valine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources are not assimilated: acetamide, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, adipate, alginate, 1-aminobutane, DL-2-aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, 2-aminodeoxyglucose, DL-2-aminohexanoate (norleucine), 1-aminopentane, DL-2-aminopentanoate (norvaline), 2-aminotoluene, 3-amino-L-tyrosine, amygdalin, anthranilate, D-arabitol, arbutin, ascorbate, azelate, benzylformate, 2,3-butanediol, 2-butanol, DL-carnitine, cellobiose, citraconate, L-citrulline, creatinine, crotonate, L-cysteine, L-cystine, deoxycholate, dextrin, <i>i</i>-erythritol, esculin, 1,2-ethanediol, ethanol, D-fucose, galactitol, D-galactonate, D-galactose, geraniol, glucitol, D-glucose 6-phosphate, D-glucuronate, glycine, glycolate, l-hexanol, hippurate, histamine diphosphate, 2-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutanone (acetoin), 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutarate, 1-hydroxynaphthalene, hydroxy-L-proline, inosine, inulin, itaconate, kynurenate, lactose, lactulose, laevulinate, D-lyxose, maleate, malonate, maltose, mandelate, D-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, menthol, methanol, L-methionine, 3-methylbutanoate (isovalerate), 3-methyl-1-butanol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, 2-methyl-2,4-pentanediol, 2-methylpropan-1-ol, mucate, nicotinate, oxalate, palmitate, pectate, 1-pentanol, phenol, phenylacetate, phthalate, pimelate, propane-1,2-diol, 1-propanol, 2-propanol, 2,6-pyridine decarboxylate, pyridoxal, quinate, raffinose, L-rhamnose, ribitol, riboflavine, D-saccharate, salicin, sebacate, L-serine, L-sorbose, starch, suberate, sucrose, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, taurine, testosterone, trigonelline, tryptamine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, turanose, valerate, xylitol, D-xylose, and L-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The data for the assimilation of l-butanol, D-malate, and trehalose are in conflict.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA of the type strain is 59.7 mol% (standard deviation, 0.3 mol%).</s></p></content></protolog>