<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.752_nm.6535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6535" rank="species">Micromonospora olivasterospora</organism><reference id="rid.752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kawamoto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Micromonospora olivasterospora sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>112</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Micromonospora olivasterospora</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Micromonospora olivasterospora</i> (O.li.vas.ter.o'spo.ra. L. <i>oliva</i> an olive; Gr. <i>aster</i> a star; Gr. <i>spora</i> a seed; <i>olivasterospora</i> olive-colored spore that looks like a star)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore morphology.</s><s>Spores at maturity are spherical to oval, approximately 1 .O μm in diameter, and appear to be rough when they are examined under a phase-contrast microscope.</s><s>The roughness appears to be due to a large number of projections, which are 0.1 to 0.2 μm long.</s><s>Spores are produced on short sporophores or are sessile and occur randomly throughout the mycelial webs or in clusters within 3 to 5 days after transfer onto suitable media.</s><s>Terminal and intercalary chlamydospore-like swellings are sometimes present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Color of colonies.</s><s>Young vegetative colonies are light brown or dark yellow and later are covered with an olive or dark green waxy, lustrous layer of spores.</s><s>Olive green soluble pigments are produced in ISP media 2 and 3 and are not pH indicators.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed, and gelatin is weakly liquefied.</s><s>Skim milk is peptonized but not coagulated.</s><s>Cellulose is weakly decomposed.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive.</s><s>Good growth occurs between 28 and 38°C; no growth occurs at 47°C.</s><s>Good growth occurs between pH 6.8 and 7.8; no growth at pH 9.5 or 5.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbon utilization.</s><s>Good growth occurs on D-xylose, D-ribose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-galactose, D-mannose, maltose, sucrose, α-trehalose, and starch.</s><s>No growth occurs on Darabinose, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, lactose, amelibiose, melezitose, raffinose, glycerol, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, mannitol, and salicin.</s><s>Cellobiose is utilized moderately in yeast extract medium, but poorly in chemically defined medium containing NH<sub>4</sub>NO<sub>3</sub> as the nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen source.</s><s>Good growth occurs on NH<sub>4</sub>NO<sub>3</sub>, (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, L-serine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, and L-arginine; no growth occurs on L-alanine, Lvaline, L-homoserine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, and L-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glycosidase activity.</s><s>Activity is detectable with α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, and β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, but not with α-galactosidase, α-xylosidase, β-xylosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, β-fucosidase, and β-glucuronidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibility.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to rifampicin (MIC, 3.13 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (6.25 μg/ml), chlortetracycline (3.13 μg/ml), mitomycin C (0.39 μg/ml), penicillin G (6.25 μg/ml), ristocetin (1.56 μglml), streptomycin A (0.125 μg/ml), and neomycins (0.25 μg/ml).</s><s>This strain is moderately susceptible to spiramycin (25 μg/ml), cycloserine (25 μg/ml), and sagamicin (31.2 μg/ml) and resistant to gentamicin C complex (C<sub>1</sub>, C<sub>2</sub>, and C<sub>1a</sub>; 125 μg/ml), fortimicin A (250 μg/ml), kanamycin A (500 μg/ml), seldomycins (500 μg/ml), and spectinomycin (500 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>NaCl tolerance.</s><s>Growth is reduced at an NaCl concentration of 3% and does not occur at 4% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall composition.</s><s>Glycine, 3-hydroxy-<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glutamic acid, and Dalanine occur in the cell wall in a molar ratio of 1.00:1.16:0.926:0.58.</s><s>Glycolic acid occurs in the peptidoglycan, and its molar ratio to 3-hydroxydiaminopimelic acid is ca. 0.768.</s><s>Xylose, arabinose, and glucose are the predominant sugars in the cell walls.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phospholipid and fatty acid.</s><s>Bisphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides are present in the cells.</s><s>Most of fatty acids are saturated and branched.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are isopentadecanoic acid and isohexadecanoic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antagonistic properties.</s><s>The type strain produces fortimicins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>This organism occurs in the soil.</s><s>Type strains.</s><s>The type strain is strain MK70.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited at the ATCC as ATCC 21819.</s><s>Since the description of <i>M. olivasterospora</i> given above is based on a single strain (the type strain), the species description also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>