<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4546_nm.5542" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5542" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5542" rank="species">Enterococcus moraviensis</organism><reference id="rid.4546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doškař</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus haemoperoxidus sp. nov. and Enterococcus moraviensis sp. nov., isolated from water.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1567</fpage><lpage>1574</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491359</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus moraviensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus moraviensis</i> (mo.ra.vi.en'sis. N. L. adj. <i>moraviensis</i> pertaining to Moravia, the region in the Czech Republic from which the strains originate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, ovoid cells occurring in pairs, short chains or in small groups, elongated in the direction of chains.</s><s>Non-pigmented, non-motile, catalase-negative and group D antigen-positive.</s><s>Weak amylase production on Columbia agar.</s><s>Other physiological features as well as growth characteristics are as described above.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, L-arabinose, ribose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-tagatose and maltotriose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from inositol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, D-arabinose, D- or L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, inulin, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-or L-fucose, D- or L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Most strains do not produce acid from L-sorbose, D-raffinose or glycogen.</s><s>Acid production from starch is variable.</s><s>Positive for acetoin, hippurate, aesculin and leucine arylamidase; mostly positive for β-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for β-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase and urease; mostly negative for agalactosidase.</s><s>Variable for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase.</s><s>Positive for enzymic hydrolysis of 4MU β-D-glucoside, 4MU α-D-glucoside, L-tryptophan, 4MUN-acetyl β-dglucosaminide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-cellobioside and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl α-D-maltoside; mostly positive for hydrolysis of L-pyroglutamic acid AMC and onitrophenyl β-D-galactoside.</s><s>Negative for enzymic hydrolysis of L-valine, 4MU phosphate, 4MU β-D-glucuronide and L-isoleucine.</s><s>Variable for hydrolysis of L-phenylalanine AMC, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucoside, proline and leucine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate.</s><s>The type strain, 330<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 4856<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19486<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from spring water.</s><s>It is positive in tests for inositol, starch, L-pyroglutamic acid AMC, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactoside, proline and leucine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide and β-galactosidase; negative for L-sorbose, D-raffinose, glycogen, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, L-phenylalanine AMC, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate and α-galactosidase.</s><s>All other characteristics are in agreement with the species description.</s><s>The G­+C content of strain 330<sup>T</sup> is 36.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>