<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3577_nm.6285" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6285" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6285" rank="species">Dietzia psychralcaliphila</organism><reference id="rid.3577"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yumoto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwata</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kusumoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nodasaka</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dietzia psychralcaliphila sp. nov., a novel, facultatively psychrophilic alkaliphile that grows on hydrocarbons</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>85</fpage><lpage>90</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837320</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dietzia psychralcaliphila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dietzia psychralcaliphila</i> (psy.chral.ca.li.phil'a. Gr. adj. <i>psychros</i> cold; N.L. <i>alcali</i> alkali, from Arabic <i>al qali</i> potash soil; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> friendly to; N.L. fem. adj. <i>psychralcaliphila</i> loving cold, alkaline environments)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporeforming rods (0.8-1.0 by 1.0-2.2 μm).</s><s>Cells show a snapping-type division.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, glistening and coral red.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase reactions are positive.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate,H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, indole production, the Voges-Proskauer test and methyl red.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 7 and 10 in R broth.</s><s>Grows in media supplemented with 0-10% NaCl but not in media with salinity higher than 12.5%.</s><s>Grows at 5-30 °C, but not at 40 °C or higher.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The whole-cell fatty acids consist of C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, C<sub>18:1</sub> and 10-MeC<sub>18:0</sub> as tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids are present (34-39 carbon atoms).</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose; the glycan moiety of the cell wall contains acetyl residues.</s><s>The isolate hydrolyses lipid and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, but not casein, gelatin, starch or DNA.</s><s>Utilizes D-glucose, D-fructose, propionate, valerate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, acetate, <i>n</i>-butyrate, isobutyrate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-tridecane, <i>n</i>-pentadecane, <i>n</i>-hexadecane, <i>n</i>-eicosane, <i>n</i>-tetracosane and pristane but not D-xylose, D-arabinose, D-mannose, D-galactose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, D-cellobiose, melibiose, lactose, maltose, D-ribose, rhamnose, salicin, gluconate, glucuronate, α-D-galacturonate, glutarate, DL-malate, DL-lactate, citrate, glutamate, α-ketoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, dlglycerate, caprate, L-tartrate, L-aspartate, arabitol, aconitate, mannitol, D-sorbitol, inositol, <i>myo</i>-erythritol, D-glycerol, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-α-alanine, D-α-alanine, L-leucine, histidine, L-proline, L-tyrosine, L-lysine, L-arginine, L-ornithine, DL-phenylalanine, N-acetylglucosamine, <i>n</i>-decane, <i>n</i>-dotriacontane, cyclododecane, fluorene, anthracene or pyrene.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69.6 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ILA-1<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at The Institute of Physical and Chemical Research (RIKEN), Wako, Japan, as JCM 10987<sup>T</sup>, at the IAM Culture Collection, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan, as IAM 14896<sup>T</sup> and at the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria, Aberdeen, UK, as NCIMB 13777<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>