<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5637_nm.5566" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5566" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5566" rank="species">Vagococcus salmoninarum</organism><reference id="rid.5637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wallbanks</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martinez-Murcia</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fryer</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>16S rRNA sequence determination for members of the genus Carnobacterium and related lactic acid bacteria and description of Vagococcus salmoninarum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>224</fpage><lpage>230</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-224</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1697764</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Vagococcus salmoninarum sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are ovoid or short rods (the shape varies with cultural conditions) and occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains. Cells are gram positive, nonmotile, and catalase negative. Growth occurs at 5 and 30°C but not at 40°C. Facultatively anaerobic. No gas is produced from glucose. Acid is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, N-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, fructose, β-gentiobiose, glucose, maltose, mannose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, D-tagatose, and trehalose. Acid is not produced from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, galactose, gluconate, glycogen, glycerol, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, inulin, inositol, lactose, D-lyxose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-xyloside, methyl-D-mannoside, mannitol, rhamnose, raffinose, sorbose, sorbitol, D-turanose, D-xylose, L-xylose, and xylitol. Esculin is hydrolyzed. Arginine dihydrolase and urease negative. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. H<sub>2</sub>S is produced. The major cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types; the C<sub>18:1</sub> acid is a Δ9,10 isomer (oleic acid). The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 36.0 to 36.5 mol% (as determined by melting temperature). Isolated from diseased adult rainbow trout (<i>O. mykiss</i>). The type strain is strain NCFB 2777 (= OS1-68). The description of the type strain corresponds to that of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>