<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6180_nm.9729" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9729" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9729" rank="species">Sphingomonas yunnanensis</organism><reference id="rid.6180"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>X.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas yunnanensis sp. nov., a novel gram-negative bacterium from a contaminated plate</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2361</fpage><lpage>2364</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63697-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280497</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas yunnanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas yunnanensis</em> (yun.nan.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>yunnanensis</em> pertaining to Yunnan, a province of south-west China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming and short-rod-shaped and about 0·4–0·6 μm wide and 0·8–1·0 μm long with single polar flagella.</s><s>Forms yellow-pigmented colonies with a maximum diameter of about 5 mm after incubation at 28 °C for 48 h on ISP2 agar.</s><s>Colonies on ISP2 medium are circular, slightly convex and opaque.</s><s>The optimum growth pH, NaCl concentration and temperature are 7·0–7·5, 0–1 % and 28 °C, respectively.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Starch is not decomposed.</s><s>Positive for lipase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-maltosidase, arylamidase, milk peptonization and coagulation, nitrate reduction, Tween 20 esterase and hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Negative for ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, urease, indole production, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and gelatinase, in methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests and for tyrosinase, Tween 80 esterase, melanin, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production.</s><s>Acetamide, malonate, glucose, galactose, mannose, xylose, ribose, lactose, dextrin, amygdalin, fructose and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>α</em>-glucosamine can be utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from acetamide, lactose, galactose and mannose, whereas l-arabitol, d-arabitol, l-arabinose, galacturonate, phenol red, mannitol, 5-ketogluconate, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, rhamnose, inositol, palatinose, cellobiose and sorbitol are not used.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>The polar lipids contain diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, sphingoglycolipid and one unidentified phospholipid.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile is composed mainly of C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7c (59·8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (9·9 %), ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5·3 %), i-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (4·4 %) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH (15·8 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 003<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 204064<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12346<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a contaminated plate.</s><s>CCTCC is the China Center of Type Culture Collection (Wuhan City, Hubei Province, China).</s></p></content></protolog>