<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1539_nm.10306" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10306" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10306" rank="species">Chitinophaga skermanii</organism><reference id="rid.1539"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sridhar</surname><given-names>K.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of [Flexibacter] sancti, [Flexibacter] filiformis, [Flexibacter] japonensis and [Cytophaga] arvensicola to the genus Chitinophaga and description of Chitinophaga skermanii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2223</fpage><lpage>2228</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64359-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957125</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinophaga skermanii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinophaga skermanii</em> (sker.ma′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>skermanii</em> of Skerman, in honour of V. B. D. Skerman, an Australian microbiologist, in recognition of his numerous contributions to the taxonomy of micro-organisms).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Aerobic and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Good growth after 48 h on nutrient agar, tryptic soy agar and MacConkey agar at 30–40 °C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, orange, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges, becoming mucoid.</s><s>Orange pigmentation is non-diffusible, non-fluorescent and turns to cherry red upon the addition of 20 % KOH and retains original colour on addition of HCl.</s><s>Strains are unable to grow at 5 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–10 and in 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid profile is given in Table 1.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, acetoin production, gelatinase and oxidation of glucose, mannitol and melibiose and negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, oxidation of inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, amygdalin and arabinose and cytochrome oxidase activity.</s><s>Some differentiating tests are given in Table 3 (methods according to Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991).</s><s>In addition, the following compounds were utilized as sole carbon sources (tested with the Biolog GN system): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, dl-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and glycerol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: d-arabitol, propionic acid, citric acid, glycogen, adonitol, l-arabinose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, quinic acid, succinamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, d-serine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Positive test results for enzyme activities are seen for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; negative test results are observed for myristate esterase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-SG1B<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 52510<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109140<sup>T</sup>), isolated from faeces of the millipede <em>Arthrosphaera magna</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>