<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6943_nm.538" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.538" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.538" rank="species">Meiothermus taiwanensis</organism><reference id="rid.6943"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsay</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Meiothermus taiwanensis sp. nov., a novel filamentous, thermophilic species isolated in Taiwan.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1647</fpage><lpage>1654</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02189-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361269</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Meiothermus taiwanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Meiothermus taiwanensis</i> (tai.wan.en«sis. N.L. fem. adj. <i>taiwanensis</i> of Taiwan, from the hot springs of Taiwan where the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms stable trichomes of indeterminate length (several hundred micrometres).</s><s>Variable-length cells make filamentous trichomes and the cell lengths are 1.4-2.4 μm.</s><s>Short filaments are also present.</s><s>Septa are not visible by phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>Gram staining yields negative results.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies on <i>Thermus</i> medium are red and red/orange-pigmented, 2-3 mm in diameter after incubation for 72 h at 55°C and form a thin film on the surface of agar plates.</s><s>The temperature range for growth of the type strain is 40-70°C and the optimum growth temperature is 55°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is approximately 8.0.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:0 iso and 17:0 iso; 2-OH iso and anteiso fatty acids such as 17:0 iso 2-OH are also present.</s><s>The major distinguishing characteristic is the relatively high level of 18:0 iso diol fatty acid.</s><s>Positive for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, oxidase and catalase, hydrolysis of elastin, fibrin, gelatin, casein and DNA and degradation of aesculin.</s><s>The type strain can utilize D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, D-melibiose, D-sorbitol, D-xylose, lactose, L-arabinose, L-glutamate, maltose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, pyruvate, ribitol, succinate, sucrose, L-asparagine, L-glutamine, L-proline and L-arginine as carbon sources.</s><s>It does not hydrolyse starch or xylan and does not utilize citrate, D-trehalose, glycerol, malate or L-serine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain WR-30<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-399<sup>T</sup> =CCRC 17170<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14542<sup>T</sup>) and strain WR-220 (=ATCC BAA-400=CCRC 17171=DSM 14543) is a reference strain ; both strains were isolated from the Wu-rai hot springs of Taipei in northern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>