<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1381_nm.5412" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5412" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5347" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus paracasei tolerans</organism><reference id="rid.1381"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zanoni</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deoxyribonucleic acid homology studies of Lactobacillus casei, Lactobacillus paracasei sp. nov., subsp. paracasei and subsp. tolerans, and Lactobacillus rhamnosus sp. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>108</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-105</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus paracasei</i> subsp. <i>tolerans</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are rod shaped (ca. 0.8 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 4.0 μm), often with square ends, and occur singly or in chains. Nonmotile. Grows at 10 and 37°C; no growth at 40°C. Survives heating at 72°C for 40 s. Facultatively heterofermentative. L-(+)-Lactic acid is produced. Acid is produced from D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, lactose, D-mannose, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, and D-tagatose. Acid is not produced from adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-ketogluconate, D-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-mannoside, β-methyl-xyloside, melezitose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, D-turanose, xylitol, D-xylose, and L-xylose. Ammonia is not produced from arginine. Esculin is not hydrolyzed. Urease negative. Murein type Lys-D-Asp. The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 45 to 47 mol%. Isolated from dairy products. The type strain is strain ATCC 25599 (= NCIB 9709 = NCFB 2774). The description of the type strain corresponds to that of the subspecies.</s></p></content></protolog>