<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4487_nm.5500" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5500" rank="genus">Alkalibacterium</organism><reference id="rid.4487"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ntougias</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alkalibacterium olivoapovliticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new obligately alkaliphilic bacterium isolated from edible-olive wash-waters.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1161</fpage><lpage>1170</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11414268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alkalibacterium olivoapovliticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alkalibacterium olivoapovliticus</i> (o.li.vo.a.pov'lit.i.cus. L. n. <i>olivo</i> olives ; Gr. n. <i>apovlito</i> waste disposal; N.L. gen. n. <i>olivoapovliticus</i> from the waste of olives)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods and occur singly, in pairs or in small clusters.</s><s>The cells are 0.4-0.6x1.3-2.9 μm, show Gram-positive cell-wall behaviour and are weakly motile by polar flagella.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are small, round and glistening with diameter of 0.8-1 mm, appearing as pale white due to their small size, although the colour of bulk biomass observed after centrifugation is yellow or orange.</s><s>They are halotolerant, psychrotolerant, obligate alkaliphiles, growing above pH 8.5 with optimum growth at 3.5% (w/v) NaCl and 27-32 °C.</s><s>The major phospholipids are PG, DPG, PS and an unknown phospholipid; there are also four unidentified glycolipids.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are mainly saturated and unsaturated even-carbon-chain, with <i>n</i>-hexadecanoic, hexadecen(7)oic and octadecen(9)oic acid as the major components.</s><s>No quinones could be detected.</s><s>Sugars which are metabolized include D-glucose, D-glucose 6-phosphate, maltose, D(­+)-cellobiose, sucrose, mannose and trehalose.</s><s>Amino acids are not utilized as sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Yeast extract could be utilized as sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidasenegative.</s><s>Culture growth is inhibited by ampicillin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, kanamycin, streptomycin and trimethoprim.</s><s>Some strains are sensitive to amoxycillin or to miconazole and neomycin.</s><s>The habitat is the wash-waters of edible olives.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 39.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is WW2-SN4a<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13175<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13710<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>