<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11686_nm.19292" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19292" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19292" rank="species">Leifsonia soli</organism><reference id="rid.11686"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Senthilkumar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundaram</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia soli sp. nov., a yellow-pigmented actinobacterium isolated from teak rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1322</fpage><lpage>1327</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014373-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667370</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leifsonia soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leifsonia soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, referring to the isolation of the first strains from teak tree rhizosphere soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, convex, smooth, yellow and 1.0–2.8 mm in diameter on R2A medium after 96 h at 28 °C.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-stain-positive, motile, short rods, 0.4–0.5 μm wide by 0.6–0.9 μm long, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Tolerates up to 2.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 10–35 °C, with optimum growth at 30 °C, and at pH 5.0–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 6.8.</s><s>Negative for degradation of cellulose, gelatin and pectin.</s><s>Positive for decomposition of casein, tributyrin, starch and aesculin.</s><s>Urease, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production and reduction of nitrate are negative.</s><s>Positive for the methyl red test and negative for the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose and d-mannose but not from d-galactose.</s><s>The yellow pigment is water-insoluble and has absorption maxima at 210, 253, 450 and 480 nm in methanol.</s><s>Grows on R2A agar, TSA and NA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Tolerates up to 0.5 mM NiCl<sub>2</sub> and &#x003C;0.5 mM CdCl<sub>2</sub> in plate assays: no growth observed at higher concentrations.</s><s>With the Biolog GP2 MicroPlate system, utilizes dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, palatinose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, glycerol and adenosine, but not <em>α</em>- or <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, d-arabitol, d-galacturonic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, d-tagatose, xylitol, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d- or l-malic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, d- or l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate or dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The type strain is highly resistant (up to 500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) to ampicillin, carbenicillin, nalidixic acid and bacitracin but sensitive to (lowest concentration; μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) gentamicin (25), kanamycin (300), cefotaxime (50), chloramphenicol (300), spectinomycin (500), doxycycline (100), erythromycin (25), penicillin G (100), polymyxin B (500), rifampicin (25), novobiocin (100), tetracycline (500), cephalosporin (25), vancomycin (25) and trimethoprim (25).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains alanine, 2,4-diaminobutyric acid, glutamic acid and glycine (molar ratio 1 : 2 : 1 : 1).</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose, glucose, mannose and rhamnose.</s><s>Phospholipids detected are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and several unidentified lipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-11.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 69.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TG-S248<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24767<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15679<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of natural teak (<em>Tectona grandis</em> Linn.), the sample being collected from Field No. 37, Tamilnadu Agricultural University (TNAU), Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India.</s></p></content></protolog>