<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12679_nm.22418" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22418" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22418" rank="species">Bacillus alkalisediminis</organism><reference id="rid.12679"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Borsodi</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pollák</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kéki</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rusznyák</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kovács</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márialigeti</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tóth</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus alkalisediminis sp. nov., an alkaliphilic and moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from sediment of extremely shallow soda ponds</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1880</fpage><lpage>1886</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019489-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833886</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus alkalisediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus alkalisediminis</em> (al′ka.li.se.di.mi′nis. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of sediment; N.L. gen. n. <em>alkalisediminis</em> of alkaline sediment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, non-motile, straight rods (0.8–0.9×2.0–3.0 µm).</s><s>Central, ellipsoidal endospores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are creamish brown, circular, entire, smooth and convex.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7.0–12.0, optimally at pH 9.0.</s><s>The range of NaCl concentration for growth is 2–10 % (w/v), optimally with 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C, with optimum growth at 25–28 °C.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>No acid and gas are produced from d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol and d-xylose.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and methyl-red reactions are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not to nitrogen under aerobic conditions; no nitrate reduction under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin and aesculin is positive.</s><s>Casein, starch, urea and arginine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Simmons’ citrate is not used.</s><s>Production of H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and phosphatase is negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 80 is strain-dependent.</s><s>d-Galactose, aesculin and trehalose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilization of the following compounds as sole carbon sources is strain-dependent: d-fructose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose and gentiobiose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: glycerol, erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activity is positive.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are strain-dependent: esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are negative: alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 36.3–39.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K1-25<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 21670<sup>T</sup>  = NCAIM B02301<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of Kelemen-szék, an extremely shallow soda pond situated in Kiskunság National Park, Hungary.</s></p></content></protolog>