<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6891_nm.1287" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1287" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1287" rank="species">Rhizobium hainanense</organism><reference id="rid.6891"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>Z.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium hainanense sp. nov., isolated from tropical legumes.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>870</fpage><lpage>873</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-870</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226920</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium hainanense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium hainanense</i> (hai.nan.ense. L. adj. <i>Hainan</i>, name of a province of China; rhizobia isolated from Hainan Province)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods that are 0.25 to 0.5 by 0.5 to 2.0 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Optimum temperature 25 to 30°C and can grow at 40°C.</s><s>Optimum pH 6 to 8 and can grow at pH 5 to 10.</s><s>Generation time is 2 to 4 h in YMA medium.</s><s>Colonies in YMA are circular, opaque, and convex and have a creamy color.</s><s>They are usually 1.5 to 2.5 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation on YMA and produce acid.</s><s>Arabinose, erythritol, fructose, glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, D-ribose, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylose, DL-asparagine, and L-histidine can be used by these bacteria as the sole carbon and energy source for growth.</s><s>Calcium malonate, ferulic acid, melezitose, sodium acetate, sodium hippurate, galactose, sorbose, vanillic acid, p-alanine, and glycine cannot be used.</s><s>L-Alanine, DL-arginine, L-asparagine, DL-citrulline, DL-cystine, D-glutamic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycine, L-histidine, L-leucine, DL-ornithine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, L-tryptophan, and L-valine can be used as the sole nitrogen source, but D-valine cannot be used.</s><s>The other characteristics are as indicated in Table 2.</s><s>Strains in this species were isolated from nodules of <i>S. guyanansis</i>, <i>C. pubescens</i>, <i>D. triquetrum</i>, <i>D. gyroides</i>, <i>D. sinuatum</i>, <i>D. heterophyllum</i>, <i>T. candida</i>, <i>A. sinuata</i>, <i>Arachis hypogaea</i>, <i>Z. diphylla</i>, <i>Uraria crinita</i>, and <i>M. lathyroides</i>.</s><s>The G+C moles percent content of the DNA is 59 to 63.</s><s>The type strain is I66 (CCBAU 57015).</s><s>Its generation time is 2 h on YMB medium (24).</s><s>The G+C moles percent content of its DNA is 61 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p></content></protolog>