<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2829_nm.5667" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5667" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5667" rank="species">Streptococcus ovis</organism><reference id="rid.2829"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nikolaitchouk</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus ovis sp. nov., isolated from sheep</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1147</fpage><lpage>1150</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411683</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus ovis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus ovis</i> (o'vis. L. gen. n. <i>ovis</i> of the sheep)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci that occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies are of.5-1.0 mm diameter after 24 h and are α-haemolytic on sheep and horse blood.</s><s>Aesculin-positive colonies on Edwards medium.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, strains produce acid from glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, trehalose, sorbitol and sucrose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from dtagatose but most fail to ferment cyclodextrin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan or ribose.</s><s>Alanyl-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, esterase C-4 (weak reaction), leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase (weak reaction) activities are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, chymotrypsin, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, trypsin or urease.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, α-galactosidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase.</s><s>Hippurate hydrolysis and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>The G­C content of DNA is 38 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from clinical specimens from sheep.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 39485<sup>T</sup> (¯LMG 19174<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>