<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4674_nm.1043" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1043" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1043" rank="species">Rhodobacter euryhalinus</organism><reference id="rid.4674"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter eurynalinus sp. nov., a new halophilic purple bacterial species.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>54</volume><fpage>974</fpage><lpage>982</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodobacter euryhalinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobacter euryhalinus</i> (eu.ry.ha.li.nus. Gr. adj. Eurys: wide, gr. n. hals: salt. M. L. Masc. adj. euryhalinus: wide range salinity living)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and Pigments.</s><s>The shape of cells is from coccoid to short rods, 0.7-1.0 x 1.5-3.0 μm.</s><s>The formation of straight chains, threads, and rosettes is typical.</s><s>Motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Photosynthetic membrane system of vesicular type.</s><s>The anaerobic cell suspension is from greenish-yellow to brown, the aerobic one is red.</s><s>Absorption spectra of cell syspensions in vivo show maxima at 378, 592, 805, 855 nm (bacteriochlorophyll a) and 450-460, 479-486, 509-517 nm (carotenoids of maxima at 378, 592, 802, 855 nm (bacteriochlorophyll a) and 450-460, 479-486, 509-517 nm (carotenoids of spheroidene group; position of peaks varies depending on the age of the culture and culture conditions).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Culture.</s><s>Generally photoorganoheterotrophs may also grow microaerophillically in the dark in the presence of organic substrate and photoautotrophically utilizing hydrogen, sulfide, and thiosulfate as H-donors.</s><s>Elemental sulfur, which is an intermediate product of the oxidation of H<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub> is deposited outside the cells and may be oxidized to sulfates in the absence of sulfide in the medium.</s><s>Optimal growth conditions: pH 7-8, 25-35°C.</s><s>NaCl concentration from 0.5-12% (for different strains).</s><s>Obligatorily halophilic, can develop in a wide range of salinity.</s><s>Ammonium salts can be utilized as nitrogen source.</s><s>Only 2 of 12 strains tested are capable of assimilatory sulfate reduction; type strain is not capable of it.</s><s>Sulfide, cystein, and cystine serve as sources of sulfur for all strains.</s><s>Bacteria of the majority of strains, including the type, require four vinamins; B<sub>1</sub>, B<sub>5</sub>, biotin, p-aminobenzoate.</s><s>H-donors and carbon sources: fatty acids down to caprylate (not tested further), some amino acids and intermediates of the tricarboxylic acid cycle, glycerol, glucose, gluconate, lactate, pyruvate, fructose, yeast extract, casein hydrolysate.</s><s>Malonate, mannitol, formate, ethanol are used by some strains including the type strain.</s><s>Benzoate, methanol, tartrate, and citrate are not used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Stored nutrients: polyphosphate, poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase activity is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Content of GC in DNA fluctuates from 62.1 to 68.6 mole % (seven strains; according to melting temperature), 66.3 mole % for type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Widely distributed in shallow sea and continental salt waters with high mineralization.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain KA-65 is stored in the Geochemical Activity of Microorganisms Branch, Institute of Microbiology, Academy of Sciences of the USSR, Moscow, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>