<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6716_nm.6750" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6750" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6750" rank="species">Saccharomonospora glauca</organism><reference id="rid.6716"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Greiner-Mai</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korn-Wendisch</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kutzner</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic revision of the genus Saccharomonospora and description of Saccharomonospora glauca sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>398</fpage><lpage>405</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharomonospora glauca</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharomonospora glauca</i> (glau'ca. L . fem. adj. <i>glauca</i>, bluish, greenish, grayish blue, referring to the color of the aerial mycelium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Morphology.</s><s>Branching, nonfragmenting aerial and substrate mycelia.</s><s>Single spores are produced tightly packed on aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spores are smooth or slightly roughened, round to ovate, and 0.8 to 1.0 μm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Colonies produce light green to bluish green (turquoise) aerial mycelium, dark green substrate mycelium, and soluble pigment on GC agar and GYM agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Biochemical characteristics.</s><s><i>meso</i>-Diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, and galactose (sugar type A) are found in cell wall hydrolysates.</s><s>The main fatty acids are <i>iso</i>-branched fatty acids with 16 carbon atoms and 2-hydroxy-branched fatty acids with 16 carbon atoms (type 2a); the diagnostic phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxyphosphatidylethanolamine, and lyso-phosphatidylethanolamine; the main menaquinones are MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Physiological characteristics.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 37 to 60°C, and the optimum temperature is 50°C.</s><s>The strains are sensitive to lysozyme (200 U/ml) and resistant to 7% NaCl.</s><s>No melanin is produced.</s><s>Tyrosine, starch, triglycerides, blood cells (hemolysis), casein, collagen, and esculin are degraded.</s><s>D-Glucose, mannitol, dextrin, and arabinose are used as carbon sources.</s><s>Antibiotic activity against gram-positive bacteria occurs; the Rf of the antibiotic is 0.28.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) Phage sensitivity.</s><s>All strains of <i>Saccharomonospora glauca</i> are sensitive to ϕ771; in addition, several strains are sensitive to ϕL1g.</s><s>All strains are resistant to the Tm<sub>1</sub> family of phages, which is specific for <i>Saccharomonospora viridis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vi) Analysis of proteins and genome DNA.</s><s>All strains show identical total protein and DNA restriction patterns; esterase pattern III (four main bands) is found.</s><s>The <i>R<sub>f</sub></i> of malate dehydrogenase is 0.50.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vii) Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain K62 (= DSM 43769).</s></p></content></protolog>