<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7025_nm.2617" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2617" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2617" rank="species">Pseudomonas graminis</organism><reference id="rid.7025"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Erler</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seyfarth</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A taxonomic study of bacteria isolated from grasses: a proposed new species Pseudomonas graminis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>308</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-297</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028275</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas graminis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas graminis</i> (gra'mi.nis. L. n. <i>gramen</i> grass, <i>graminis</i> of grass, the source of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non spore-forming, straight rods (0.5-1.0 by 3.5-5.0 μm), motile, with one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, glistening, moderately convex and round with entire edges.</s><s>Oxidasenegative, catalase-positive and unable to oxidize and ferment glucose.</s><s>Does not produce fluorescent pigments on King medium B.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 40 and 80, aesculin, but not starch.</s><s>It is negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan desaminase, DNase, urease and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Does not produce indole or hydrogen sulphide.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite and denitrification is negative.</s><s>β-Haemolysis of sheep blood is negative.</s><s>Does not produce levan from sucrose.</s><s>Nutritionally versatile.</s><s>Substrates used by all strains are: adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, α-D-glucose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, Dmannose, D-sorbitol, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, Dgalactonic acid, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, D,L-lactic acid, malonic acid, D-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, L-proline, L-pyroglutamic acid, y-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol.</s><s>Substrates not used by any of the strains are: N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, cellobiose, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-melibiose, β-methyl-D glucoside, Draffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, D-trehalose, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, L-phenylalanine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glucose-1-phosphate, glucose-6-phosphate, acyclodextrin, dextrin and glycogen.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is in the range 60-61 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q9.</s><s>The major nonpolar fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid (16:0), hexadecenoic acid (16:1) and octadecenoic acid (18:1), and hydroxy fatty acids are 3-hydroxydodecanoic acid (3-OH 12:0) and 2-hydroxydodecanoic acid (2-OH 12:0).</s><s>Isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses in Paulinenaue (Germany).</s><s>The type strain is DSM 11363<sup>T</sup> (= P 294/08<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>