<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7608_nm.14039" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14039" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14039" rank="species">Catenulispora yoronensis</organism><reference id="rid.7608"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otoguro</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catenulispora subtropica sp. nov. and Catenulispora yoronensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1552</fpage><lpage>1555</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65561-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Catenulispora yoronensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Catenulispora yoronensis</em> (yo.ro.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>yoronensis</em> pertaining to Yoro Valley, Chiba, Japan, the origin of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate hyphae.</s><s>Vegetative hyphae are finely branched and do not fragment.</s><s>Monopodially or dichotomously branching aerial mycelia develop sparsely.</s><s>Light to moderate yellowish brown and/or moderate yellow colonies are formed on ISP 2.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 5–7, with optimum growth at pH 6–7.</s><s>d-Xylose, d-glucose, d-mannose, arbutin, aesculin, ferric citrate, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-melibiose, trehalose, starch, glycogen, l-fucose and gluconate are used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Positive for catalase, pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase; negative for nitrate reduction, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine aminopeptidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Cell wall contains ll-A<sub>2</sub>pm, glycine, glutamic acid and alanine (peptidoglycan type A3<em>γ</em> <em>sensu</em>; Schleifer &#x0026; Kandler, 1972).</s><s>Contains mannose, arabinose and galactose as whole-cell sugars.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TT N02-20<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 103397<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19327<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from forest soil from Yoro Valley, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>