<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8691_nm.13245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13245" rank="species">Brevibacterium marinum</organism><reference id="rid.8691"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium marinum sp. nov., isolated from seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>500</fpage><lpage>504</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65099-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218957</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium marinum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium marinum</em> (ma.ri′num. L. neut. adj. <em>marinum</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods that are long (0.6–0.9 μm wide and 1.5–2.4 μm long) at exponential phase.</s><s>As the culture ages, cells fragment into short rods (0.5–0.6 μm wide and 0.7–1.0 μm long) that occasionally occur singly and, more often, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>V-form arrangements are also observed.</s><s>Colonies are translucent, convex, smooth and circular with entire margins.</s><s>Colonial pigmentation is variable depending on the culture conditions: in the dark, colonies are white; in the light, colonies are bright yellow.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–30 °C, with an optimum of 30 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at initial pH values in the range 5.1–12.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Casein and hypoxanthine are degraded, but cellulose, dl-tyrosine and xanthine are not degraded.</s><s>Hydrolysis of DNA and starch is not observed.</s><s>In the API Coryne system, the results for nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, urease and catalase are positive.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities: pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis).</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin is not observed.</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates (d-glucose, maltose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-lactose and glycogen) is negative.</s><s>In the additional tests in the API ZYM system, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are weakly positive, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid in the cell wall.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol, with an unknown phospholipid as a minor component.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 71.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HFW-26<sup>T</sup> (=JBRI 2001<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19221<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18964<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater from Hwasun Beach in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>