<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6742_nm.8464" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8464" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8464" rank="species">Angulomicrobium amanitiforme</organism><reference id="rid.6742"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fritz</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strömpl</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic relationships of the genera Stella, Labrys and Angulomicrobium within the 'Alphaproteobacteria' and description of Angulomicrobium amanitiforme sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>651</fpage><lpage>657</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02746-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143003</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Angulomicrobium amanitiforme</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Angulomicrobium amanitiforme</em> (a.ma.ni′ti.for.me. N.L. n. <em>Amanita</em> name of fungal genus; L. adj. suffix -<em>formis</em> -<em>is</em> -<em>e</em> -like, of the shape of; N.L. neut. adj. <em>amanitiforme</em> formed like a toadstool).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is as that for the genus, with the following additions.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming, capsulated and irregularly shaped.</s><s>They are 1·0×1·5 μm in size with radial symmetry and show tetrahedral cell morphology during the early stages of cell replication.</s><s>A complex membranous system is not developed, but in addition to the cytoplasmic membrane, some peripherally aligned membranes and a membranous cell body at the site of cell division are present.</s><s>The budding process is initiated by doubling the tube part of the cell, followed by enlargement of the tube part end-section.</s><s>Finally, symmetric fission of the tube forms two mushroom-shaped cells.</s><s>Colonies are white, round and mucous with a pearly shine.</s><s>However, there is a second colony morphology with smaller, non-slimy colonies.</s><s>Nutritional type is chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> in the presence of H<sub>2</sub> is not utilized as a sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Organic growth factors are not required, but do stimulate growth.</s><s>Glucose, arabinose, galactose, fructose, mannitol, glycerol, formate, acetate, propionate, lactate, fumarate, succinate, citrate and glutarate are used as sole carbon and energy sources, whereas mannose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, dulcitol, butyrate, tartrate, urea, glycine and methanol are not.</s><s>Contrary to VKM B-1335<sup>T</sup>, strain NCIMB 1785<sup>T</sup> utilizes citrate, d-(−)-ribose and l-serine and does not utilize d-(+)-malate, d-(+)-mannose, d-(+)-melibiose, methylamine hydrochloride or (l+)- or (d−)-tartrate.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Nitrate, carbonate and sulfate are not utilized as electron acceptors.</s><s>Cytochromes <em>a</em>, <em>b</em> and <em>c</em> are present.</s><s>Acids are produced from sugar and sugar alcohols.</s><s>Growth temperature ranges from 15 to 40 °C, with an optimum growth temperature between 28 and 30 °C.</s><s>At 30 °C, growth occurs at pH values between 5·2 and 8·0, with an optimum at pH 6·8–7·0.</s><s>Main phospholipids are phosphatidyl <em>N</em>,<em>N</em>-dimethylethylamine and phophatidylcholine, containing at least one C<sub>19 : 0</sub>Δ8,9 cyclopropyl fatty acid.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 67·7 mol% for the type strain.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequencing places this species in the ‘<em>Alphaproteobacteria</em>’.</s><s>DNA–DNA hybridization between the type strain and <em>A. tetraedrale</em> DSM 5895<sup>T</sup> was 60·6 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the species is NCIMB 1785<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15561<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>