<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12476_nm.21309" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21309" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21309" rank="species">Cohaesibacter marisflavi</organism><reference id="rid.12476"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cohaesibacter marisflavi sp. nov., isolated from sediment of a seawater pond used for sea cucumber culture, and emended description of the genus Cohaesibacter</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>762</fpage><lpage>766</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021972-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20418408</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cohaesibacter marisflavi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cohaesibacter marisflavi</em> (ma.ris.fla′vi. L. neut. n. <em>mare</em> -<em>is</em> the sea; L. adj. <em>flavus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> yellow; N.L. gen. n. <em>marisflavi</em> of the Yellow Sea, referring to the isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, catalase-negative, oxidase-positive, facultatively anaerobic rods, motile by means of single polar flagella, 0.6–0.7 µm wide and 1.8–2.0 µm long.</s><s>Reproduces by binary fission or asymmetrical division.</s><s>Intracellular poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules are accumulated.</s><s>Colonies on 2216E agar medium are white, smooth, circular, lightly transparent and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 3–5 days of cultivation at 30 °C.</s><s>Grows at 10–38 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), at pH 4–9 (optimum pH 7–8) and in 0.5–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 3 %).</s><s>Sensitive (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated) to ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefalexin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), doxycycline (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), neomycin (30), novobiocin (30), penicillin G (10 IU), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30) and resistant to clindamycin (2), lincomycin (2), oxacillin (1), polymyxin B (300 IU) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for indole production, urease, β-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis), nitrate reduction and utilization of d-glucose, d-mannose, malic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and trisodium citrate and weakly positive for utilization of β-galactosidase, maltose and l-arabinose; negative for gelatin hydrolysis, d-glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and utilization of d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API ZYM test strip, positive for esterase (C4), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin, weakly positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8) and leucine aminopeptidase and negative for cystine aminopeptidase, lipase (C14), <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, valine aminopeptidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase and β-glucuronidase.</s><s>Of the 95 substrates in the Biolog GN2 system, positive for utilization of dextrin, d-fructose, raffinose, glycerol, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and sucrose.</s><s>Principal fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 is the major quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.2 mol%.</s><s>Table 1 shows the characteristics that can be used to distinguish the type strain from <em>C. gelatinilyticus</em> CL-GR15<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DQHS21<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.9157<sup>T</sup>  = NCCB 100300<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment sampled from a seawater pond used for sea cucumber culture at Jimo, Qingdao province, China, on the west coast of the Yellow Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>