<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9951_nm.14932" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14932" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14932" rank="species">Sphingobium chinhatense</organism><reference id="rid.9951"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dadhwal</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jit</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kumari</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lal</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobium chinhatense sp. nov., a hexachlorocyclohexane (HCH)-degrading bacterium isolated from an HCH dumpsite</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3140</fpage><lpage>3144</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005553-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643888</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobium chinhatense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobium chinhatense</em> (chin.hat.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>chinhatense</em> pertaining to Chinhat, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, strictly aerobic, rod-shaped and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, smooth and pinpoint after 5 days of growth on LB media.</s><s>Degrades <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>-, <em>δ</em>- and <em>γ</em>- isomers of HCH.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase activity, but negative for indole production and starch, casein and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Sensitive to 5 % NaCl but tolerant of 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow at pH 10.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but no hydrolysis of xanthine, hypoxanthine or Tweens 20 or 80 is observed.</s><s>Assimilates l-serine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, caprate, sodium benzoate and sodium pyruvate but does not assimilate lactose, d-xylose, d-rhamnose, adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-histidine, l-sorbose, dulcitol or raffinose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-galactose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-ribose, trehalose, l-proline and <em>myo</em>-inositol but no acid is produced from cellobiose, sucrose or mellibiose.</s><s>Sensitive to erythromycin (15 μg), kanamycin (30 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg) and resistant to ampicillin (10 μg).</s><s>A detailed fatty acid profile is presented in Supplementary Table S1.</s><s>Major fatty acids present are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, phospholipids, unknown aminolipid, unknown glycolipid and five unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>Major polyamine is spermidine.</s><s>The respiratory quinone consists of ubiquinone with ten isoprene units (Q-10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IP26<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC8598<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7432<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an HCH dumpsite of the lindane manufacturing industry at Chinhat, Lucknow, India.</s></p></content></protolog>