<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4081_nm.1977" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1977" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1977" rank="species">Morococcus cerebrosus</organism><reference id="rid.4081"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Long</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>G.H.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Morococcus cerebrosus gen. nov., sp. nov. and comparison with Neisseria mucosa.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>294</fpage><lpage>301</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-294</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Morococcus cerebrosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Morococcus cerebrosus</i> (ce.re.bro'sus. L. adj. <i>cerebrosus</i> pertaining to the brain, the original source of isolation of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Morococcus cerebrosus</i> is described as follows.</s><s>Colorless, spherical organisms, less than 1 μm in diameter, bound firmly together in tightly packed, mulberry-like aggregates of 10 to 20 cells, with adjacent sides often flattened.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Endospores not formed.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate not produced.</s><s>Capsules are produced in sucrose media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs on vitamin-free Casamino Acids, peptone, yeast extract, and chocolate agars, No growth occurs on Sabouraud dextrose agar, Czapek Dox agar, salmonella-shigella agar, MacConkey agar, or PYEA containing 40% bile, 0.01% potassium tellurite, or 10% NaCl or in glucose ammonium sulfate broth.</s><s>After 24 h colonies on PYEA are convex or umbonate, entire, matt, buff colored, 1 mm in diameter, and difficult to emulsify.</s><s>Colonies on sucrose agar give a black reaction with iodine.</s><s>Granular growth occurs in PYEB.</s><s>Growth occurs between 23 and 42°C and between pH 5.5 and 9.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, but may give weak acid reactions in both tubes of the Hugh-Leifson test.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Litmus milk is reduced.</s><s>Hemolyzes horse erythrocytes.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from cystine.</s><s>Deoxyribonuclease, ornithine decarboxylase, catalase, cytochrome oxidase, and methyl red positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, sucrose, and maltose but not from arabinose, ribose, xylose, rhamnose, galactose, mannose, sorbose, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, dextrin, inulin, starch, ethanol, glycerol, erythritol, adonitol, arabinol, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, or inositol.</s><s>Citrate and malonate are not oxidized.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze starch, esculin, gelatin, casein, or Tween 80.</s><s>Lecithinase, phosphatase, phenylalanine deaminase, and urease are not produced.</s><s>Arginine, glutamic acid, and lysine decarboxylases are not produced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Serum liquefaction is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to the following Mast Laboratories antibiotic disks: kanamycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), penicillin G (10 U), ampicillin (2 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), chloramphenicol (10 μg), and tetracycline (10 μg).</s><s>Resistant to cloxacillin (5-μg disk) and methicillin (5-μg disk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antigenically not related to <i>N. mucosa</i> UQM 1903.</s><s>Pathogenic to mice.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 52.3 ± 0.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>M. cerebrosus</i> is UQM 858 (UQM stands for the Department of Microbiology, University of Queensland, which is the Australian National Culture Collection).</s><s>Cultures of the type strain have also been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 33486 and with the National Collection of Type Cultures as NCTC 11393.</s></p></content></protolog>