<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9086_nm.14267" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14267" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14267" rank="species">Paenibacillus pueri</organism><reference id="rid.9086"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus pueri sp. nov., isolated from Pu'er tea.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1002</fpage><lpage>1006</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002352-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406782</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus pueri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus pueri</em> (pu′e.ri. N.L. n. <em>puerum</em> Pu'er, a tea from China; N.L. gen. n. <em>pueri</em> of Pu'er).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-positive, motile, and have a subterminal ellipsoidal spore in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSB agar are round, smooth, cream-white and approximately 3–5 mm in diameter after 1 week growth.</s><s>Single cells are slightly curved rods, measuring 2.5–3.5×0.5–0.8 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of 25–42 °C in TSB medium, with optimum growth occurring at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl and at pH 5.5–10.4.</s><s>Does not grow in media containing ≥7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows well on the surface of TSB agar when incubated under aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Gelatin, Tween 80 and starch are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose and xylan are not.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for acetoin production, citrate utilization, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and nitrate reduction, but negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S production and indole production.</s><s>Produces acid from arbutin, l-arabinose, aesculin, fructose, galactose, gentiobiose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, 5-ketogluconate, mannose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose, but not from adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, erythritol, d-arabinose, dulcitol, d-fucose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, d-lyxose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, rhamnose, sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>Cells contain MK-7 as the predominant isoprenoid quinone, and do not contain diaminopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Cells cultured in TSB medium contain anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> as the predominant cellular fatty acid.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 56.6 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, b09i-3<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13223<sup>T</sup>= CECT 7360<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Pu'er tea. b13i-1 is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>