<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1744_nm.11589" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11589" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11589" rank="species">Nocardioides marinisabuli</organism><reference id="rid.1744"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hyun</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides marinisabuli sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from beach sand</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2960</fpage><lpage>2963</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65127-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048757</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides marinisabuli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides marinisabuli</em> (ma.ri.ni.sa′bu.li. L. adj. <em>marinus -a -um</em> of the sea, marine; L. neut. n. <em>sabulum</em> gravel, sand; N.L. gen. n. <em>marinisabuli</em> of sea sand, referring to the sand sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-spore-forming and non-motile rods (0.6–0.8×1.4–2.1 μm).</s><s>Colonies of the cells are opaque, convex, circular and pale yellow in colour with an entire edge, and reach approximately 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter after growth on TSA for 7 days.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–40 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at the range of initial pH 5.1–12.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–8 % NaCl.</s><s>Assimilation of d-maltose, d-mannitol (weak) and gluconate is positive, but the following substrates are not assimilated: d-glucose, d-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, caproate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Aesculin degradation is positive.</s><s>Indole production, glucose fermentation, gelatin hydrolysis and arginine dihydrolase and urease activities are negative (API 20NE strip; bioMérieux).</s><s>Valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are negative (API ZYM strip; bioMérieux).</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-salicin, adonitol, glycerol, benzoate and formate are not used as carbon sources.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 73.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SBS-12<sup>T</sup> (=JBRI 2003<sup>T</sup>=KCCM 42681<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18965<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sand sample collected from Samyang Beach in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>