<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5881_nm.6079" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6079" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6079" rank="species">Agromyces albus</organism><reference id="rid.5881"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krausova</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces albus sp. nov., isolated from a plant (Androsace sp.)</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1435</fpage><lpage>1438</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces albus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces albus</em> (al′bus. L. adj. <em>albus</em> white, referring to the white colour of colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on CB agar are white, circular, somewhat convex, opaque and penetrate into agar media.</s><s>Forms branching hyphae (width, 0·3–0·6 μm) that break up into diphtheroid and rod-like, irregular and non-motile fragments.</s><s>No aerial mycelium or spore formation.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Aerobic; catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Mesophilic; growth occurs between 7 and 37 °C (optimum, 26–28 °C).</s><s>Adonitol, d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, lactose, lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, salicin, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose are used as carbon sources for growth in salt medium supplemented with 0·1 % (w/v) yeast extract and 0·1 % (w/v) casitone.</s><s>Dextran, dulcitol, melezitose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, ribose and sorbitol are not used as carbon sources in the same medium.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, mannose, melibiose, salicin and sucrose.</s><s>Alkaline reactions are observed with acetate, fumarate, malate and maleinate, but no reaction occurs with citrate, formate, oxalate, propionate, succinate or tartrate.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive and Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Casein, hypoxanthine, Tween 40 and starch are decomposed; gelatin, tyrosine, xanthine, Tween 60, Tween 80 and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Sensitive to 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tolerates the following antibiotics (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>): amikacin (30), clindamycin (30), lincomycin (30), rubomycin (30) and streptomycin (30).</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin (10), cefazolin (10), doxycycline (5), erycycline (10), gentamicin (30), karbonicillin (30), levomycetin (10), metacycline (10), oletetrin (10), oxacillin (30) and rifampicin (10).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 69·0 mol%.</s><s>Predominant cell-wall sugar is rhamnose; minor amounts of glucose, galactose and mannose are present.</s><s>Major menaquinone is MK-12, with a small amount of MK-11.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan amino acids are l-DAB, alanine, glutamic acid and glycine in a molar ratio consistent with peptidoglycan type B2<em>γ</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, VKM Ac-1800<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the All-Russian Collection of Microorganisms (VKM) and Ukrainian Collection of Microorganisms (UCM Ac-623<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from a sample of leaves and inflorescence of <em>Androsace</em> sp. in the family <em>Primulaceae</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>