<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8360_nm.13194" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13194" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13194" rank="species">Actinopolymorpha rutila</organism><reference id="rid.8360"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinopolymorpha rutila sp. nov., isolated from a forest soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2443</fpage><lpage>2446</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65629-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinopolymorpha rutila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinopolymorpha rutila</em> (ru.ti′la. L. fem. adj. <em>rutila</em> red inclining to golden–yellow, referring to the colour of colonies produced).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows at 15–37 °C (optimum 28 °C), pH 6–8 and in the presence of up to 5 % NaCl on ISP 2 medium.</s><s>Colonies develop well within 3–4 days and vary from smooth to rugose; colony colour is dependent on the medium used for growth, varying from pink orange–yellow to deep orange–yellow.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Forms branched substrate mycelia of uneven thickness that fragment into short chains or aggregates in the early stages of growth; branched hyphae later exhibit varied degrees of fragmentation with short to elongated rod-like elements or V-shaped elements; in the later stages of growth, poorly formed aerial hyphae are seen on ISP 2 agar.</s><s>Spores and sporangia are absent.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>In addition to the properties shown in Table 2, assimilates ribose, mannose, melibiose, maltose, melezitose, dextrin, xylitol, adonitol, d-galactose, salicin and malonate as sole carbon sources, but not dulcitol, arabitol, acetate, citrate or oxalate.</s><s>Hydrolyses hypoxanthine, xanthine, casein, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-arginine, glycine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, phenylalanine, l-proline, l-cysteine, l-valine, urea and Tween 20, but not l-tyrosine, adenine, glucosamine, Tween 60, Tween 80, cellulose or DNA.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, ribose, fucose, raffinose, sucrose, erythritol, glucose and d-xylose.</s><s>Positive for the enzymes alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, chymotrypsin and trypsin.</s><s>Tests positive for gelatin, but negative for nitrate reduction, starch hydrolysis, milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the peptidoglycan is ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Cell-wall hydrolysates contain ribose, glucose and galactose.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone; MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Phospholipids consist of phosphatidylinositol mannosides, phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;1 %) are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (22.36 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (22.09 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H (21.57 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (8.92 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (8.30 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.80 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (3.66 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2.59 %), iso-C<sub>18 : 1</sub> H (1.64 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.48 %) and 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.06 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 45725<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 206004<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18448<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected in Yunnan Province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>