<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6847_nm.4248" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4248" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4248" rank="species">Eubacterium exiguum</organism><reference id="rid.6847"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Poco</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakazawa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ikeda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium exiguum sp. nov., isolated from human oral lesions.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1120</fpage><lpage>1124</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1120</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863445</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium exiguum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium exiguum</i> (ex. i.gu'um. L. adj. <i>exiguum</i>, scanty, small, referring to the scanty or poor growth of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short gram-positive rods that are obligately anaerobic, nonmotile, and nonsporing.</s><s>Individual cells are 0.5 by 1.0 μm, and the cells occur singly or in clumps.</s><s>Sometimes cells from older cultures stain gram negative.</s><s>On BHI-blood agar plates, the cells form minute colonies that are less than 1 mm in diameter, circular, convex, and translucent even after prolonged incubation in an anaerobic glove box.</s><s>Growth in broth media is poor in the presence or in the absence of carbohydrates and is moderately enhanced in the presence of 5% bovine serum, 0.2% lysine, or 0.2% arginine.</s><s>No hemolysis occurs around colonies on BHI blood agar plates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are inert in most biochemical tests.</s><s>Starch and esculin are not hydrolyzed, and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>No liquefaction of gelatin occurs.</s><s>Indole, urease, and catalase negative.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine.</s><s>All strains are nonfermentative and do not utilize adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, esculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No detectable metabolic end products are produced in peptone- yeast extract medium supplemented with glucose or peptone- yeast extract-glucose broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human necrotic pulp samples, periapical infections, and acute dento-alveolar abscesses.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 60 to 64 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain s-7.</s></p></content></protolog>