<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8299_nm.14136" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14136" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14136" rank="species">Streptococcus plurextorum</organism><reference id="rid.8299"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casamayor</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez Del Rey</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus plurextorum sp. nov., isolated from pigs.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>504</fpage><lpage>508</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65636-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244430</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus plurextorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus plurextorum</em> (plu.rex.to′rum. L. comp. pl. <em>plures</em> more, several, many; L. pl. n. <em>exta</em> -<em>orum</em> entrails; N.L. gen. pl. n. <em>plurextorum</em> of several internal organs).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci arranged in short chains.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, circular and 1 mm in diameter after 24 h on blood agar and produce an <em>α</em>-haemolytic reaction.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37 °C but not at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH 9.6 or in broth containing 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to optochin.</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield group B antisera.</s><s>With the API 50 CH and API Rapid ID 32 Strep kits, cells are able to produce acid from d-lactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, maltose, trehalose, raffinose and sucrose but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, gentiobiose, d-ribose, melibiose, d-mannitol, inositol, dulcitol, melezitose, pullulan, inulin, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, starch, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, turanose, d-lyxose, xylitol, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-mannose, glycogen, amygdalin, arbutin, sorbitol, 2-ketogluconate, cyclodextrin or tagatose.</s><s>Delayed acid production occurs for salicin and 5-ketogluconate (API 50 CH) after 7 days incubation.</s><s>Acid production from d-galactose and d-xylose is variable (API 50 CH).</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase, acid phosphatase, leucine arylamidase (API ZYM), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase (API Rapid ID 32 Strep) are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin or <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM), <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (API Rapid ID 32 Strep).</s><s>Arginine, hippurate and urea are not hydrolysed (API Rapid ID 32 Strep).</s><s>Acetoin is not produced (Rapid ID 32 Strep).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1956-02<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7308<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52972<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the lungs of a pig with pneumonia.</s><s>The full habitat is not known.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.1 mol%.</s><s>Strain 1355-03 (=CECT 7307=CCUG 52971) is a reference strain.</s></p></content></protolog>