<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.161_nm.4478" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4478" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4478" rank="species">Anaerobranca horikoshii</organism><reference id="rid.161"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Engle</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a novel alkalitolerant thermophile, Anaerobranca horikoshii gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>454</fpage><lpage>461</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-454</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590672</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerobranca horikoshii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerobranca horikoshii</i> (hor.i.kosh'i.i. N. L. gen. n. <i>horikoshii</i>, of Horikoshi, in honor of Koki Horikoshi, a pioneer in the study of the microbiology of alkaliphilic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The rod-shaped cells, which are 8 to 22 μm long and 0.5 to 0.65 μm in diameter, form one to three branches at a frequency of 1 to 10%, and these branches can form daughter cells by restriction.</s><s>The cells are peritrichous and, during growth in low-nutrient medium (e.g., medium containing less than 0.1% yeast extract), exhibit slight tumbling motility.</s><s>Spores have not been detected.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and mainly proteolytic.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth and can be used as the sole carbon source.</s><s>During growth on yeast extract, if fumarate is added, it is reduced stoichiometrically to succinate.</s><s>All isolates are moderately alkaliphilic thermophiles.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 30 to 66°C, with an optimum temperature of 57°C, and the pH range for growth is 6.5 to 10.3, with an optimum pH of 8.5.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 33 to 34 mol% G+C. 16s rRNA analysis data place this organism in the Gram-typepositive Clostridium-Bacillus subphylum, but there are no closely related species (i.e., species whose relative distance is less than 10%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain JW/YL-138 (= DSM 9786) is the type strain of <i>A. horikushii</i> and has a G+C content of 34 mol%.</s><s>Its pH range for growth is from greater than 6.7 to less than 10.3 (60°C).</s><s>Its temperature range for growth is from greater than 34 to less than 64°C.</s><s>The cells are 0.5 to 0.6 pm wide and 11 to 20 μm long.</s><s>Fumarate is reduced to succinate in the presence of yeast extract as a growth substrate.</s></p></content></protolog>