<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8682_nm.14725" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14725" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14725" rank="species">Kribbella hippodromi</organism><reference id="rid.8682"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everest</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyers</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kribbella hippodromi sp. nov., isolated from soil from a racecourse in South Africa.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>443</fpage><lpage>446</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65278-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218947</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kribbella hippodromi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kribbella hippodromi</em> (hip.po.dro′mi. Gr. masc. n. <em>hippodromos</em> horse racecourse, N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>hippodromi</em> of/from a horse racecourse, referring to the source of isolation of the type strain, Kenilworth Racecourse, Cape Town, Western Cape, South Africa).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive and aerobic (unable to grow on ATCC medium 172 or ISP 9 with glucose under anaerobic conditions).</s><s>Colonies appear convoluted with irregular edges on most media.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium appears cream in colour with highly branched hyphae, which fragment in both liquid and agar cultures.</s><s>Aerial mycelium appears white on ISP 4.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Melanin is not produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP 6) or on tyrosine agar (ISP 7).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Produces H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Utilizes adonitol, l(+)-arabinose, cellobiose, d(−)-fructose, d(+)-galactose, d(+)-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, maltose, d(−)-mannitol, d(+)-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l(+)-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose as sole carbon sources, with weak growth on sodium acetate, sodium citrate and sodium succinate and doubtful growth on <em>α</em>-lactose and d(+)-xylose.</s><s>Unable to utilize xylitol as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Utilizes l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, potassium nitrate and l-threonine as sole nitrogen sources, with weak growth on dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>n</em>-butyric acid, l-cysteine, l-4-hydroxyproline, l-serine and l-valine and doubtful growth on l-methionine and l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Grows at 20, 30 and 37 °C, but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5, 7 and 9 (weakly at pH 4.3).</s><s>Aesculin and arbutin are hydrolysed, starch is weakly hydrolysed but pectin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Adenine, casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, Tween 80 and l-tyrosine are degraded.</s><s>Allantoin, cellulose, guanine, urea, xanthine and xylan are not degraded.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 5 % NaCl, with very weak growth at 6 % NaCl and no growth at 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin hydrochloride (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), neomycin sulfate (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), oleandomycin phosphate (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), penicillin G (10 IU ml<sup>−1</sup>), rifampicin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and streptomycin sulfate (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but sensitive to cephaloridine (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), tobramycin sulfate (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and vancomycin hydrochloride (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>No antibacterial activity is detected against <em>M. aurum</em> A+.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-diaminopimelic acid and glycine (chemotype I of Lechevalier &#x0026; Lechevalier, 1970).</s><s>Glucose and an unidentified sugar are present in the whole-cell sugar hydrolysate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, S1.4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19227<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-24553<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from Kenilworth Racecourse, Cape Town, South Africa.</s></p></content></protolog>