<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1340_nm.4454" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4454" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4454" rank="species">Veillonella caviae</organism><reference id="rid.1340"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mays</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rogosa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of the genus Veillonella Prévot.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>28</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-28</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Veillonella caviae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Veillonella caviae</i> (M.L. noun <i>Cavia</i> genus of the guinea pig; M.L. gen. noun <i>cave</i> of the guinea pig)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain and of six other strains tested are 0.2 to 0.3 μm in diameter and are arranged in masses and pairs.</s><s>Cells are gram negative, nonmotile, and nonsporeforming.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar plates (brain heart infusion agar supplemented with yeast extract and 5% defibrinated rabbit blood) are 1 .O to 2.0 mm in diameter, circular, and flat with an entire edge after 48 h at 37°C in an anaerobic atmosphere.</s><s>No surface growth is obtained on similar blood agar plates incubated aerobically or in an atmosphere enriched to 10% with carbon dioxide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth growth in prereduced peptone-yeast extract medium is lightly turbid, usually without sediment in 24 h.</s><s>In peptone-yeast extract-lactate or peptone-yeast extract-pyruvate broths, growth is turbid, usually with a smooth sediment.</s><s>Amygdalin, arabiinose, cellobiose, erythritol, esculin, fructose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, ribose., sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Neither esculin nor starch is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Small to moderate amounts of acetate and propionate are detected in peptone-yeast extract cultures.</s><s>Lactate and pyruvate are metabolized to acetate, propionate, hydrogen, and carbon dioxide.</s><s>The type strain and six other strains tested grew well in a medium containing Casamino Acids, lactate, putrescine, hypoxanthine, and vitamins.</s><s>Growth was not regularly obtained if any of these constituents was deleted from this medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the mouths of guinea pigs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiated from other species in the genus by DNA/DNA homology studies and by electrophoretic mobilities of soluble cellular proteins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 33540 (= VPI 12140 from Rogosa PV1, guinea pig mouth).</s></p></content></protolog>