<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3564_nm.10929" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10929" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10929" rank="species">Paracoccus bengalensis</organism><reference id="rid.3564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandal</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus bengalensis sp. nov., a novel sulfur-oxidizing chemolithoautotroph from the rhizospheric soil of an Indian tropical leguminous plant.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>396</fpage><lpage>403</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.10.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16824961</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the species <em>P. bengalensis</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>P. bengalensis</em> (ben.gal.enśis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>bengalensis</em> of Bengal, after the name of the province West Bengal of India from where the bacterium was isolated.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming bacterium having coccoidal or irregularly elliptical cells with a major axis of 0.8–1.0 μm and minor axis of 0.5–0.7 μm.</s><s>Colonies on LA or MSTY medium are creamy white, convex and opaque.</s><s>Maximum temperature for growth is 37 °C and range of pH tolerance is 5.0–8.5.</s><s>It has respiratory metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor but can also grow anaerobically with nitrate as the electron acceptor in heterotrophic medium.</s><s>Growth in synthetic media, particularly chemoorganotrophic growth on single carbon-compounds, requires some yet unknown growth factor that is satisfied by 50 mg l<sup>−1</sup> of yeast extract.</s><s>The bacterium is catalase, oxidase and denitrification positive; cannot liquefy gelatin, produce indole or solubilize phosphate.</s><s>The organism is a facultative chemolithoautotroph and can grow on thiosulfate, tetrathionate, soluble sulfide and elemental sulfur as the sole energy and electron source but not on thiocyanate or sulfite.</s><s>The bacterium can grow chemoorganoheterotrophically in complex media like Luria–Bertani broth, nutrient broth or minimal mineral salts plus peptone casein hydrolyzate.</s><s>In synthetic media supplemented with 50 mg l<sup>−1</sup> of yeast extract or vitamin mixture the organism can utilize d-glucose, d-fructose, d-raffinose, d-galactose, d-lactose, l-arabinose, l-glutamine, sodium benzoate, glycerol, maltose, sucrose, malate, succinate, acetate, mannitol, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine and l-glutamine as single substrates for chemoorganoheterotrophic growth.</s><s>Formate, rhamnose, citrate, oxalate, mandelate, adipate, aesculin, phenylacetate, dl-lactate, d-mannose, d-xylose, l-glutamate, l-aspartate, l-alanine, l-serine, l-lysine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-tyrosine, l-threonine and l-arginine are not utilized.</s><s>Urea, nitrate and ammonium salts are utilized as nitrogen sources while aspartate and glutamate are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacterium synthesizes the following fatty acids: Summed feature 2 (16:1 iso I &#x0026; 14:0 3-OH) (2.86%), Summed feature 3 (16:1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> &#x0026; 15:0 iso 2-OH) (0.37%), 16:0 (6.02%), 18:1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (76.96%), 18:0 (1.09%), 19:0 10 methyl (0.28%), 19:0 cyclo<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (6.78%), 10:0 3-OH (2.80%) and unknown fatty acid of ECL∼11.8 (2.85%).</s><s>The G+C content of the only strain JJJ<sup>T</sup> of this monotypic species, as determined by HPLC is 65.3 mol%.</s><s>JJJ<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22700<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 7003<sup>T</sup>) the only known strain (thus the type strain) of the species has been isolated from soil adjacent to the roots of the plant <em>Clitoria ternatea</em>, a native legume of the lower-Gangetic plains of India, particularly West Bengal.</s></p></content></protolog>