<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2635_nm.4661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4661" rank="species">Mycoplasma fastidiosum</organism><reference id="rid.2635"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lemcke</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poland</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma fastidiosum: a New Species from Horses</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>151</fpage><lpage>162</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-1-151</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma fastidiosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma fastidiosum</i> (fas. tid.i.o’sus. L. adj. <i>fastidiosus</i>, fastidious, referring to the nutritionally fastidious nature of the organism on primary isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The equine SGM strains were typical <i>Mollicutes</i> in possessing a triple-layered limiting membrane, in colonial morphology, in filterability through a membrane filter with a pore diameter of 450 nm, and in failing to revert to a bacterial form (18).</s><s>As with most mycoplasmas, they failed to produce catalase or oxidase.</s><s>A requirement by them for cholesterol could not be shown by the standard method, the two strains tested failing to grow in media in which serum was replaced by bovine serum albumin fraction V, palmitic acid, and cholesterol.</s><s>The substitution of PPLO serum fraction for cholesterol in this medium resulted in heavy growth.</s><s>Serum fraction contains cholesterol, but in this case it clearly supplied some other, unidentified component(s) required by these equine mycoplasmas.</s><s>Nevertheless, the stimulation of growth by serum fraction and the inhibition produced by sodium polyanethol sulfonate and digitonin suggest that the SGM strains are sterol dependent and that they are therefore members of <i>Mycoplasmataceae</i> or <i>Spiroplasmataceae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The tendency of the SGM strains to form filaments, the apparent twisting of the filaments, and the diagonal striations were unusual morphological features.</s><s>Despite the twisting, however, phase-contrast microscopy of live cells revealed no helical morphology like that of <i>Spiroplasma</i> spp.</s><s>The striations may be superficial, helically wound fibrils around the cell external to the membrane.</s><s>Freeze-etching might determine their position more precisely.</s><s>It would also be of interest to examine the SGM strains by microcinematography.</s><s>Fibrillar, actin-like protein has been reported in <i>M. pneumoniae</i> (14), a mycoplasma known to execute contractile and gliding movements.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Another characteristic of the SGM mycoplasmas was their nutritional fastidiousness.</s><s>On primary isolation and during early passages at least, their growth on HuS agar was superior in several respects to that on LH agar.</s><s>These growth characteristics of the SGM mycoplasmas in HuS and LH media confirm our original suggestion (15) that their isolation from nasopharyngeal swabs was facilitated by the use of HuS media which were not employed in earlier surveys of the mycoplasmal flora in the equine respiratory tract.</s><s>Both LH agar and LHg broth sustained growth poorly, and the metabolism of glucose appeared to be strongly suppressed unless the broth was aerated during incubation.</s><s>This fastidious character in early passages after isolation was also shown by the preference of the strains,especially 5889, for one of two broth bases and their failure to adapt easily to other types of serum supplement or to grow in a strictly anaerobic atmosphere.</s><s>Since the SGM mycoplasmas produced only a slow and somewhat restricted reduction in the pH of glucose-containing media, more sophisticated enzyme studies are required to establish that these organisms do indeed ferment glucose.</s><s>In contrast to the glycolytic species examined by Aluotto et al. (2), the SGM strains did not reduce tetrazolium or tellurite either aerobically or anaerobically.</s><s>However, because the SGM strains were inhibited by 0.02% tetrazolium (Aluotto et al. [2]), they had to be tested at 0.005%.</s><s>Similarly, tellurite at just under half the recommended concentration (2) was slightly inhibitory.</s><s>Isolated colonies of the SGM strains strongly adsorbed erythrocytes and lysed equine erythrocytes.</s><s>In these respects the SGM strains resemble <i>M. pneumoniae</i>.</s><s>Most species of <i>Mycoplasma</i> are resistant to erythromycin at concentrations of 10 to 100 μg/ml (13), but the SGM strains were very susceptible to this drug, a feature they share with <i>M. pneumoniae</i> (17) and <i>M. gallisepticum</i>, which are pathogens of the human and avian respiratory tracts, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>That the SGM strains constitute a group which is distinct from 58 other recognized species of <i>Mycoplasma</i> and <i>S. citri</i> is confirmed by the serological evidence.</s><s>The inhibition of strain 4822 by some <i>M. pulmonis</i> antisera in GI and MI tests and of <i>M. pulmonis</i> by 4822 antiserum A and pre-immunization serum B in GI tests on LH media is thought to be nonspecific for the following reasons.</s><s>First, not d the antisera inhibited the heterologous species.</s><s>Second, one pre-immunization serum was also inhibitory.</s><s>Last, the inhibitory effect was observed only on LH medium, which was suboptimal for the growth of SGM strains and also for <i>M. pulmonis</i> strain N14 (J.</s><s>Poland, unpublished data).</s><s>The effect was never observed with HuS media.</s><s>Nonspecific inhibitory factors for mycoplasmas occur in some rabbit sera.</s><s>Therefore the inhibition probably arose from two factors: (i) the effect of nonspecific inhibitors in some sera, and (ii) the inhibitory nature of LH media; some batches of LH media appeared more toxic than others, the sizes of the heterologous inhibition zones varying considerably in different experiments.</s><s>No cross-reactions between strains 4822 and <i>M. pulmonis</i> were detectable by either GI or MI when HuS media were used, or by IFA, a test which does not depend on specific inhibition.</s><s>These results emphasize the problems of using serological tests based on inhibition of growth by specific antibody for the identification or classification of fastidious or slow-growing mycoplasmas and underlines the advisability of using additional tests such as IFA or complement fixation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The importance of SGM strains in the equine respiratory tract is obscure.</s><s>Although the isolation rate was low, high levels of MI antibody were found in other horses in the three stables from which the isolates were recovered (15).</s><s>Hence, the organisms may have been more widespread than indicated by the isolation rate.</s><s>Although SGM strains certainly exhibit some of the properties shown by mycoplasmas pathogenic for the respiratory tracts of other hosts, their pathogenicity in horses is unknown and their isolation was not related to episodes of clinical respiratory disease (15).</s><s>Moreover, strain 4822 failed to cause clinical disease in two formerly gnotobiotic foals that had been kept in isolation, although it persisted for several weeks in the nasal cavity and evoked a strong antibody response (15).</s><s>Perhaps intranasal instillation is unsatisfactory for producing respiratory disease, as is the case with <i>M. mycoides</i> subsp. <i>mycoides</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological, biological, and serological properties of the SGM strains suggest that they comprise a new species.</s><s>Although their unique morphology distinguishes them from other <i>Mycoplasma</i> species, they do not possess the regular helical symmetry of spiroplasmas nor are they serologically related to <i>S. citri</i>, the only species of <i>Spiroplasma</i> currently recognized.</s><s>Moreover, unlike spiroplasmas, SGM mycoplasmas were isolated from a vertebrate instead of a plant, insect, or arthropod host and were able to colonize the equine respiratory tract.</s><s>Even the suckling mouse cataract agent (spiroplasma), which is pathogenic for vertebrates, was originally isolated from a pooled extract of rabbit ticks.</s><s>It is therefore suggested that the SGM strains be classified in the family <i>Mycoplasmataceae</i>.</s><s>The name <i>Mycoplasma fastidiosum</i> sp. nov. is proposed (fas. tid.i.o’sus.</s><s>L. adj. <i>fastidiosus</i>, fastidious, referring to the nutritionally fastidious nature of the organism on primary isolation).</s><s>Strain 4822 is the type strain of <i>M. fastidiosum</i>.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures (NCTC), London, where it has been given the number 10180.</s></p></content></protolog>