<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3513_nm.5465" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5465" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5465" rank="species">Aerococcus urinaehominis</organism><reference id="rid.3513"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aerococcus urinaehominis sp. nov., isolated from human urine.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>683</fpage><lpage>686</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321115</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aerococcus urinaehominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aerococcus urinaehominis</i> (u.ri'nae.ho'mi.nis. L. fem. n. <i>urina</i> urine; L. gen. n. <i>hominis</i> of man; M. L. gen. n. <i>urinaehominis</i> pertaining to human urine from which the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci occurring as single cells, in pairs, tetrads or in small groups.</s><s>It is facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>When grown on Columbia horse blood agar for 24 h at 37 °C colonies are small (&#x003C;1 mm diameter), entire, non-pigmented and α-haemolytic.</s><s>Using commercial API systems acid is produced from glucose, maltose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, D-ribose and sucrose but not from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, pullulan, sorbitol, tagatose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, D-raffinose, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Positive reactions are observed for acid phosphatase, esterase C-4 (weak reaction), β-glucuronidase and pyrazinamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cysteine arylamidase, ester lipase C8, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, glycine tryptophan arylamidase, lipase C14, leucine arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, phosphoaminidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, trypsin, urease and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and β-glucosidase may or may not be produced.</s><s>Aesculin and hippurate are hydrolysed but gelatin is not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Isolated from human urine.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 42038b<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106675<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>