<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2839_nm.6374" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6374" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6374" rank="species">Mycobacterium madagascariense</organism><reference id="rid.2839"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kazda</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daffe</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitulle</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium madagascariense sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>524</fpage><lpage>528</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-524</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium madagascariense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium madagascariense</i> (mad'a.gas.car.i.en.se. M.L. adj. <i>madagascariense</i>, belonging to the island of Madagascar, the source of the strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on a study of four strains which share the characteristics shown in Table 1.</s><s>Cells are gram-positive, acid-alcohol-fast, polymorphic rods (0.6 by 1.2 to 1.5 μm) which often form clumps but not cords or cross bands.</s><s>Spores, capsules, and aerial hyphae do not occur.</s><s>Colonies on Löwenstein-Jensen medium and on Middlebrook 7H10 agar are smooth, glistening with yellow or orange pigmentation, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 31°C; no growth occurs at 37°C or above.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Positive for pigment production, acid phosphatase activity (31°C, 4 h), arylsulfatase activity, Tween hydrolysis, and urease and nicotinamidase activities.</s><s>The strains metabolize iron and form acid from glucose, arabinose, dulcitol, fructose, mannitol, rhamnose, trehalose, and xylose (Table 1).</s><s>They do not utilize certain substrates as single carbon or single nitrogen and carbon sources and do not tolerate hydroxylamine (250 mg/ml), NaCl (3%), and NaNO<sub>2</sub> (0.1%).</s><s>Their internal similarity level is 92.50%.</s><s>The strains possess mycolate types I, IV, and VI (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phylogenetic position of this organism, based on an evaluation of partial 16s rRNA sequences, is within the rapidly growing species of the genus <i>Mycobacterium</i>.</s><s>The strains are not pathogenic for rabbits, guinea pigs, and mice.</s><s>The type strain of M. madagascariense strain is P2; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49865.</s><s>Strains of <i>M. madagascariense</i> have been isolated from three different sphagnum biotopes in Madagascar.</s></p></content></protolog>