<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1790_nm.10996" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10996" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10996" rank="species">Rhodovulum imhoffii</organism><reference id="rid.1790"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum imhoffii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>228</fpage><lpage>232</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64470-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267955</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodovulum imhoffii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodovulum imhoffii</em> (im.hof′fi.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>imhoffii</em> of Imhoff, named after Johannes F. Imhoff, a German microbiologist who has made a significant contribution to our knowledge of anoxygenic phototrophic bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.5 μm wide and 1 μm long, non-motile and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photoorganoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemoorganoheterotrophy).</s><s>The internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of phototrophic cultures is yellow to brown, whereas aerobic cultures are pink.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 467, 520, 590, 802 and 857 nm.</s><s>The photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and, probably, carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>The type strain is mesophilic (temperature range, 20–35 °C; optimum, 28 °C), with a pH optimum at 7.0–8.0 (range, pH 6.0–9.0) and a requirement for NaCl concentrations of 0.5–4.0 % for optimal growth.</s><s>Photoorganotrophy with various organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate and intermediates of the citric acid cycle (except citrate) are good carbon sources.</s><s>Growth also occurs on glycerol, glutamate, caproate and Casamino acids.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is possible in the presence of sulfide or thiosulfate as the electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as the carbon source.</s><s>Biotin is required as a growth factor.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>The natural habitat of the known strain is a marine aquaculture pond exposed to light.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA125<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13589<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18064<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from water samples from an aquaculture pond near the sea (Bay of Bengal) at Bhimunipatnam, India.</s></p></content></protolog>