<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.206_nm.2875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2875" rank="genus">Pseudoalteromonas</organism><reference id="rid.206"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gauthier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gauthier</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of the genera Alteromonas, Shewanella, and Moritella using genes coding for small-subunit rRNA sequences and division of the genus Alteromonas into two genera, Alteromonas (emended) and Pseudoalteromonas gen. nov., and proposal of twelve new species combinations.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>755</fpage><lpage>761</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-755</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547295</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Pseudoalteromonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas</i> (Pseu. do. al. te. ro. mon' as. Gr. adj. <i>pseudes</i>, false; L.n. <i>Alteromonas</i>, genus of gram-negative, aerobic, marine bacteria; L.n. <i>Pseudoalteromonas</i>, false <i>Alteromonas</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic description of the genus <i>Pseudoalteromonas</i> is the same as the description published previously in <i>Bergey’s Manual of Systematic Bacteriology</i> (6) and <i>The Prokaryotes</i> (20) for the genus <i>Alteromonas</i>, except for traits that are specific to <i>Alteromonas macleodii</i> (see below).</s><s>The cells of all <i>Pseudoalteromonas</i> species are gram-negative, non-sporeforming, straight or curved rods that are 0.2 to 1.5 by 1.8 to 3 μm.</s><s>The cells of most species are motile by means of single unsheathed polar flagella; <i>Pseudoalteromonas luteoviolacea</i> and <i>Pseudoalteromonas denitrificans</i> have sheathed flagella.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>Several species produce pigments.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophs with respiratory but not fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Catalase activity is generally weak and irregular.</s><s>All species grow at 20°C.</s><s>Only one species (<i>Pseudoalteromonas denitrificans</i>) is capable of denitrification.</s><s>None of the strains has a constitutive arginine dihydrolase system.</s><s>Strains do not accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>All species require a seawater base for growth.</s><s>Many strains require organic growth factors.</s><s>The following combination of properties is found in all 12 known species: positive for gelatinase, lipase, lecithinase, and DNase activities and utilization of D-glucose as a sole source of carbon; and negative for utilization of D-ribose, L-rhamnose, turanose, salicin, D-gluconate, glucuronate, DL-glycerate, erythritol, sorbitol, mesoinositol, adonitol, L-valine, L-ornithine, and <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 37 to 50 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Pseudoalteromonas haloplanktis</i>; the type strain of this species is strain ATCC 14393 (= strain 215 of Baumann et al. [4]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the type species, the genus comprises <i>Pseudoalteromonas atlantica</i> (3), <i>Pseudoalteromonas aurantia</i> (19), <i>Pseudoalteromonas cawageenovora</i> (3), <i>Pseudoalteromonas citrea</i> (17), <i>Pseudoalteromonas denitrificans</i> (12), <i>Pseudoalteromonas espejiana</i> (9), <i>Pseudoalteromonas luteoviolacea</i> (18), <i>Pseudoalteromonas nigrifaciens</i> (5), <i>Pseudoalteromonas piscicida</i> (7), <i>Pseudoalteromonas rubra</i> (16), and <i>Pseudoalteromonas undina</i> (9).</s></p></content></protolog>