<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8435_nm.13255" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13255" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13255" rank="species">Burkholderia sabiae</organism><reference id="rid.8435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Faria</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>James</surname><given-names>E.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elliott</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sprent</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bontemps</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia sabiae sp. nov., isolated from root nodules of Mimosa caesalpiniifolia.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2174</fpage><lpage>2179</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65816-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768625</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia sabiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia sabiae</em> (sa′bi.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>sabiae</em> from sabiá, the Portuguese name of <em>Mimosa caesalpiniifolia</em>, the tree from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are accumulated.</s><s>After 24 h growth on yeast extract-mannitol agar at 28 °C, the mean cell size is about 0.4–0.6×0.6–1.5 μm.</s><s>Growth is observed at 28, 30 and 37 °C.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, citrate, malate and phenylacetate is observed.</s><s>No indole production, gelatin hydrolysis, aesculin hydrolysis, glucose fermentation or assimilation of adipate or maltose is observed.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (positive in the Biolog GN2 system): dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, arabinose, arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, lactulose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citrate, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactate, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l- and d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon sources (negative in the Biolog GN2 system): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, sebacic acid, l-ornithine, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to amikacin (30 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), piperacillin (100 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Known strains were isolated from root nodules of <em>Mimosa caesalpiniifolia</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Br3407<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24235<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17587<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the type strain are the same as described for the species.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 64.5 mol% and the genome size is approximately 8 Mb.</s></p></content></protolog>