<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6620_nm.395" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.395" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.395" rank="species">Thermococcus zilligii</organism><reference id="rid.6620"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ronimus</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reysenbach</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Musgrave</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morgan</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The phylogenetic position of the Thermococcus isolate AN1 based on 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis: a proposal that AN1 represents a new species, Thermococcus zilligii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>168</volume><fpage>245</fpage><lpage>248</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050495</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9382704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermococcus zilligii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermococcus zilligii</i> (Named after Wolfram Zillig for his contribution to the understanding of transcription in the Archaea and the characterization of hyperthermophilic Archaea and of their viruses.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid-shaped, gram-negative, motile, 0.5–2.0 μm in diameter dependent on the phase of growth, being larger in later stages.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 75–80°C with growth occurring between 55 and 85°C.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 50 mM (0.29%), with no growth being observed above 200 mM in the presence of 0.8% peptone.</s><s>Isolate AN1 has an absolute requirement for either Na<sup>+</sup> or Li<sup>+</sup> for growth.</s><s>Sulfur [either as elemental sulfur (S<sup>0</sup>) or as cystine or oxidized glutathione with the sulfur being reduced to H<sub>2</sub>S] is also an absolute requirement.</s><s>Sulfur could not be replaced by sulfate, sulfite or thiosulfite when the cultures were continuously gassed with N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The pH optimum for growth is 7.4 (minimum, pH 5.4; maximum, pH 9.2).</s><s>The organism is strictly anaerobic, obligately heterotrophic growing on peptone (0.8%), casein or yeast extract.</s><s>The following amino acids stimulate growth when the peptone concentration is 0.1%: glutamic acid, aspartic acid, tryptophan, alanine, leucine, valine, isoleucine, threonine and arginine.</s><s>No growth is observed on carbohydrates, amino acids or organic acids when peptone is absent from the media.</s><s>Cells divide by constriction and, when grown in the presence of S0, often have an inclusion body.</s><s>The G+C content (mol%) of the genomic DNA is 46.2.</s><s>Metabolic end products when grown on trypticase peptone included H<sub>2</sub>, sulfide (H<sub>2</sub>S), CO<sub>2</sub>, NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>, acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, mercapto-based compounds and isovalerate/2-methylbutyrate.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by 100 μg rifampicin ml<sup>–1</sup>, but is inhibited by mevinolin (5 μg ml<sup>–1</sup>) and monensin (1.0 μg ml<sup>–1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a terrestrial, fresh-water geothermal pool (Rt1) in Kuirau Park, Rotorua, New Zealand.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 2770.</s></p></content></protolog>