<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2571_nm.11038" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11038" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11038" rank="species">Sphingomonas pseudosanguinis</organism><reference id="rid.2571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meurer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Esser</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas pseudosanguinis sp. nov., isolated from the water reservoir of an air humidifier</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1342</fpage><lpage>1345</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64942-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551055</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas pseudosanguinis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas pseudosanguinis</em> (pseu.do.san′gui.nis. Gr. adj. <em>pseudos</em> false; L. gen. n. <em>sanguinis</em> of the blood; N.L. gen. n. <em>pseudosanguinis</em> indicating that the strains are similar to <em>Sphingomonas sanguinis</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.8–1.5 μm in length and 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are yellow-coloured.</s><s>The following are used as substrates for growth: l-arabinose, p-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, citrate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-leucine and l-proline. <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, gluconate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, d-adonitol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, propionate, azelate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, dl-lactate, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate are not used as substrates.</s><s>Positive in tests for the hydrolysis of aesculin, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenyl phosphonate, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, pNP phosphorylcholine, l-alanine pNA, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-pna and l-proline pNA. pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The main polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidylcholine, a highly hydrophilic unknown glycolipid GL1 and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The species is characterized by the major fatty acids 18 : 1 (Summed feature 7) and 16 : 0.</s><s>Minor fatty acids are 14 : 0, 18 : 0, 17 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>The major hydroxy-fatty acid is 2-hydroxy-14 : 0.</s><s>The major polyamine is <em>sym</em>-homospermidine with the following minor polyamines: diaminopropane, putrescine, cadaverine, spermidine and spermine.</s><s>Produces predominantly ubiquinone Q-10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, G1-2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 54232<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109431<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface of an air humidifier.</s></p></content></protolog>