<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4208_nm.5404" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5404" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5404" rank="species">Lactobacillus mucosae</organism><reference id="rid.4208"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roos</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Axelsson</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jonsson</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus mucosae sp. nov., a new species with in vitro mucus-binding activity isolated from pig intestine.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>251</fpage><lpage>258</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826811</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus mucosae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus mucosae</i> (mu'co.sae. L. gen. n. <i>mucosae</i> of mucosa)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporeforming, catalase-negative rods with dimensions of 1x2-4 μm.</s><s>The cells occur singly, in pairs or as short chains and have an Orn-D-Asp peptidoglycan type.</s><s>After anaerobic growth at 37 °C for 2 d, colonies on MRS agar are 1-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>They are white, smooth and convex.</s><s>The cells are obligately heterofermentative and produce D- and L-lactic acid.</s><s>They grow at 45 °C but not at 15 °C.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, ribose, maltose and saccharose.</s><s>The majority of strains also ferment D-xylose, melibiose, D-raffinose and gluconate.</s><s>L-Arabinose, galactose or lactose may be utilized by some strains.</s><s>D-Fructose, glycerol, erythritol, L-xylose, adonitol, D-mannose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, salicine, cellobiose, trehalose, inuline, melizitose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-taganose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, 2-keto-gluconate and 5-ketogluconate are not utilized.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Arginine is cleaved.</s><s>The DNA G­C content of strain S32<sup>T</sup> is 46.5±0.2 mol%.</s><s>All strains of this species so far described have a homologue to the mucus-binding protein, Mub, and exhibit mucus-binding ability <i>in vitro</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>