<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8615_nm.13320" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13320" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13320" rank="species">Enterococcus thailandicus</organism><reference id="rid.8615"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sukontasing</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus thailandicus sp. nov., isolated from fermented sausage ('mum') in Thailand.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1630</fpage><lpage>1634</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65535-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599707</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus thailandicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus thailandicus</em> (tha.i.lan′di.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>thailandicus</em> of Thailand, pertaining to Thailand, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming, spherical or ovoid, 0.5–1 μm in diameter and arranged in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Colonies on GYP agar are circular, raised or low-convex with entire margins, and non-pigmented.</s><s>Red colonies appear on Slanetz–Bartley agar.</s><s>Grows on kanamycin aesculin azide agar.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of arginine and aesculin, and weakly positive for blood haemolysis.</s><s>Negative for catalase, hydrolysis of gelatin and starch, reduction of nitrate, and production of gas from glucose, gluconate and citrate.</s><s>Utilizes glucose fermentatively.</s><s>No acidification, coagulation, reduction or liquefaction in litmus milk.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–9.6, 15–45 °C and in 2–6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Weak growth occurs in 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, fructose, d-galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-mannitol, d-ribose, sucrose and salicin but not from adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, l-sorbose, starch, turanose, d-tagatose, d-sorbitol, raffinose, trehalose, xylitol, d-xylose, l-xylose or methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside.</s><s>Niacin, calcium pantothenate and folic acid are required for growth.</s><s>Does not contain any menaquinones.</s><s>The dominant component of the fatty acid profile is the straight-chain acid C<sub>18 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FP48-3<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13134<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 101867<sup>T</sup>=NRIC 0107<sup>T</sup>=TISTR 933<sup>T</sup>=PCU 282<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from fermented sausage (‘mum’), produced in Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>