<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4234_nm.5752" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5752" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5752" rank="species">Denitrobacterium detoxificans</organism><reference id="rid.4234"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rasmussen</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allison</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Denitrobacterium detoxificans gen. nov., sp. nov., a ruminal bacterium that respires on nitrocompounds.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>633</fpage><lpage>638</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758869</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Denitrobacterium detoxificans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Denitrobacterium detoxificans</i> (de.tox.if'i.cans. L. pref. <i>de</i> from; L. n. <i>toxicum</i> poison; L. neut. n. <i>detoxificans</i> poison-reducer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a population of ruminal microbes enriched for enhanced metabolism of 3-nitropropanol, the toxic aglycone of miserotoxin (3-nitro-1-propyl-β-D-glucopyranoside).</s><s>Nitrate, 3-nitropropanol, 2-nitropropanol, 3-nitropropionate, nitroethanol, nitroethane, 1-nitropropane, 2-nitrobutane, DMSO and trimethylamine oxide may be used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Hydrogen, formate and (DL)-lactate can be used as electron donor.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing claridied rumen fluid, peptone and a suitable electron acceptor.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced, gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Little if any acid is produced during growth in medium with hydrogen or formate as electron donor.</s><s>Acetate is the major product produced during growth on lactate ; D-lactate is used more readily than L-lactate.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid of cells grown in modified brain heart infusion medium was palmitic acid, although an abundance of other straight- and branched-chain fatty acids, aldehydes and dimethyl acetals were present.</s><s>A <i>c</i>-type cytochrome was found in the type strain, NPOH1<sup>T</sup>, which was the only strain tested.</s><s>Of four strains examined, all share close (&#x003E;99%) 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity.</s><s>All strains have been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection.</s><s>The type strain, strain NPOH1<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 700546<sup>T</sup>), grew equally well at 32, 37 and 39 °C.</s><s>Strain NPOH1<sup>T</sup> differs from the others (strain NPOH2, ATCC 700547; strain NPOH3, ATCC 700548; and MAJ1, ATCC 700549) in that it has the ability to reduce nitrate.</s></p></content></protolog>