<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1926_nm.2969" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2969" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2969" rank="species">Vibrio furnissii</organism><reference id="rid.1926"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidler</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio furnessii, formerly aerogenic biogroup of Vibrio fluvialis, a new species isolated from human feces and the environment.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>816</fpage><lpage>824</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio furnissii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio furnissii</i> (fur niss' i ) in honor of A. L. Furniss, Maidstone Public Health Laboratory, Maidstone, England, for his role in the classification of <i>V. fluvialis</i> and for his many contributions to the knowledge of the genus Vibrio.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genetic and phenotypic tests indicate that the aerogenic strains formerly included in <i>V. fluvialis</i> represent a new species in the genus <i>Vibrio</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. fluvialis</i> is a gram-negative, straight to slightly curved rod that is motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>It is an NaCl-requiring, oxidasepositive, nitrate-positive organism that ferments D-glucose and other carbohydrates with the production of acid and gas, has 50 mol% guanine plus cytosine in its DNA, and is isolated from water, animal feces, and human feces.</s><s>It is positive in reactions for methyl red, Simmons citrate, Moller arginine dihydrolase, KCN, DNase, growth in 1 and 6% NaCl, and fermentation of L-arabinose, D-arabitol, D-galactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is negative in reactions for Voges-Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S, urea, phenylalanine, Møller lysine and</s></p><p class="description"><s>ornithine decarboxylases, esculin, mucate, growth in 10% NaCl, and fermentation of adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <i>i</i>-inositol, lactose, melibiose, α-methylglucoside, raffinose, salicin, D-sorbitol, and D-xylose.</s><s>Most strains are negative in tests for indole, malonate, Jordan tartrate, and fermentation of cellobiose and are positive in tests for acetate, lipase, and growth in 8% NaCl.</s><s>Strains of <i>V. furnissii</i> give variable results in tests for ONPG, tyrosine clearing, and fermentation of L-rhamnose. <i>V. furnissii</i> gives a positive string test and grows in the presence of disks saturated with 0.1% of the vibriostatic compound 0/129 in acetone.</s><s>A further description of <i>V. furnissii</i> is given in the tables as well as below.</s><s>The type strain (holotype) of <i>V. furnissii</i> is ATCC 35016 (CDC B3215), which was isolated from feces of an adult woman with gastroenteritis in 1969.</s></p></content></protolog>