<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6137_nm.10268" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10268" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10268" rank="species">Mycobacterium colombiense</organism><reference id="rid.6137"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murcia</surname><given-names>M.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Menendez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palenque</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium colombiense sp. nov., a novel member of the Mycobacterium avium complex and description of MAC-X as a new ITS genetic variant.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2049</fpage><lpage>2054</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64190-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium colombiense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium colombiense</em> (co.lom.bi′en.se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>colombiense</em> pertaining to Colombia, the South American country where the strains were first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid-fast non-motile rods.</s><s>Visible growth with non-pigmented rough colonies appears in 3 weeks.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20 and 37 °C.</s><s>Grows on Löwenstein-Jensen, Ogawa Kudoh and Sauton agars, but does not grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Negative in tests for niacin production, acid phosphatase activity and Tween hydrolysis.</s><s>Positive for catalase activity at room temperature (approx. 20 °C).</s><s>Can be differentiated from the other three species within the MAC by the ability to produce urease.</s><s>The HPLC pattern, although similar to that of <em>M. avium</em>, <em>M. intracellulare</em> and <em>M. chimaera</em>, allows the strains to be identified on the basis of the relative height of the peaks.</s><s>Results of DNA analysis, such as the unique ITS 1 sequence (MAC-X) and the unique 16S rRNA gene sequence, allow the strains to be differentiated from other members of the MAC.</s><s>The <em>hsp</em>65 gene PRA pattern is identical to that of <em>M. avium</em> variant I (av-I).</s><s>DNA–DNA relatedness clearly differentiates <em>M. colombiense</em> as a separate species within the MAC.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type-strain, isolate 10B<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108962<sup>T</sup>=CECT 3035<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the blood of an HIV-positive patient in Colombia, South America.</s></p></content></protolog>