<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1412_nm.84" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.84" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.84" rank="species">Stygiolobus azoricus</organism><reference id="rid.1412"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segerer</surname><given-names>A.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trincone</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gahrtz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stetter</surname><given-names>K.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stygiolobus azoricus gen. nov., sp. nov. represents a novel genus of anaerobic, extremely thermoacidophilic archaebacteria of the order Sulfolobales.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>501</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stygiolobus azoricus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stygiolobus azoricus</i> (a.zo'ri.cus. M.L. masc. adj. <i>azoricus</i>, from the Azores, referring to the place of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exponentially growing cells are about 0.5 to 1.8 μm wide and occur almost exclusively singly under optimal culture conditions.</s><s>Under suboptimal conditions, especially at an elevated pH of ≥4, aggregates of 2 to 50 cells occur commonly.</s><s>Cells are frequently surrounded by pilus- or fimbrialike appendages (Fig. 3).</s><s>No flagellation has been detected.</s><s>No motility is evident in a microscopic chamber either at room temperature or at 75°C.</s><s>The envelope surrounding the cells is about 22 nm wide.</s><s>Packed cells are black.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is strictly chemolithotrophic by means of H<sub>2</sub>-S<sup>0</sup> lithoautotrophy (14).</s><s>Trace amounts of yeast extract (0.005 to 0.02%) stimulate growth.</s><s>Cells grow at temperatures ranging from about 57 to 89°C, with optimal growth occurring around 80°C (Fig. 6).</s><s>No growth is detected at 50°C (incubation time 3 weeks) and 89°C.</s><s>The pH suitable for growth ranges from 1.0 to 5.5, with optimum growth around pH 2.5 to 3 (data not shown).</s><s>No growth is detected at pH 0.8 or 6.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures of isolate FC6<sup>T</sup> can be used for at least 1 year as inocula when they are stored anaerobically at 4°C after the pH is increased to 5.5 by adding sterile CaCO<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>Cells lyse at pH values above 7.5 to 8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolates were obtained from hot water, mud, and soil at acidic geothermal springs on São Miguel Island, Azores (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is isolate FC6 (= DSM 6296).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new organisms described above are archaebacteria on the basis of the occurrence of isopranyl ether lipids in their cells (12, 37), their resistance to cell wall and protein synthesis antibiotics (17), their lack of murein (30), and the presence of elongation factor EF-G which is sensitive to diphtheria toxin (32).</s><s>They resemble chemolithotrophic members of the <i>Thermoproteales</i> (24, 70) in that they grow by means of H<sub>2</sub>-S<sup>0</sup> lithography, but strongly differ from these organisms (and from all other members of the <i>Thermoproteales</i> [for details see reference 22]) in their shape, their extreme acidophily, and their much lower G+C contents.</s><s>Although they are strict anaerobes that are incapable of S<sup>0</sup> oxidation, they are members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> (29, 59), as indicated by their morphology, their extreme thermoacidophily, their relatively low G+C contents, the presence of characteristic lipid compounds (10-12), their strongly acidic biotope, and the immunochemical cross-reactions of their DNA-dependent RNA polymerases, hydrogenases (53), and histonelike proteins with antibodies against the respective enzymes and proteins from members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i>.</s><s>None of those cross-reactions occurs with representative type species belonging to the <i>Thermoproteales, Pyrobaculum islandicum</i> DSM 4184<sup>T</sup> (21, 27), and <i>Pyrodictium occultum</i> DSM 2709<sup>T</sup> (25, 60) (Fig. 5) (36).</s><s>Usually, DNA- dependent RNA polymerases reveal immunochemical cross-reactions only within members of the same family (61).</s><s>On the basis of this criterion, isolate FC6<sup>T</sup> belongs to the family <i>Sulfolobaceae</i> (29, 59).</s><s>On the basis of their strictly anaerobic mode of life, the lack of significant DNA homology with other members of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> (Table 2), and their G + C contents of about 38 mol%, the new organisms are distinct from the four previously described genera in this order.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Stygiolobus azoricus</i> represents the first obligately anaerobic member of the <i>Sulfofobafes</i>.</s><s>This organism is incapable of oxidation of sulfur compounds.</s><s>Previously, its mode of energy conservation was considered to be characteristic of the order <i>Thermoproteales</i> (24, 69, 70).</s><s>Therefore, the <i>Sulfolobales</i> appear to be metabolically more versatile than the <i>Thermoproteales</i> (22, 51).</s><s>Since probably no significant amounts of oxygen were present on the archaean earth, it is tempting to speculate that the strictly anaerobic organism <i>Stygiolobus azoricus</i> might reflect the most ancient phenotype of the <i>Sulfolobales</i> and might even represent a missing link between the <i>Sulfolobales</i> and the <i>Thermoproteales</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>