<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1578_nm.11268" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11268" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11268" rank="species">Maritimibacter alkaliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.1578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choo</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Maritimibacter alkaliphilus gen. nov., sp. nov., a genome-sequenced marine bacterium of the Roseobacter clade in the order Rhodobacterales</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1653</fpage><lpage>1658</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64960-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625211</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maritimibacter alkaliphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maritimibacter alkaliphilus</em> [al.ka.li′phi.lus. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> (from the Arabic word <em>al-qaliy</em>) the ashes of saltwort; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>alkaliphilus</em> loving alkaline conditions].</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to having the traits reported for the genus, colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, opaque, beige-coloured and 0.8–1.3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 16–37 °C, optimally at 30 °C, but not below 10 °C or above 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 4–12 and 0.5–7.5 % NaCl, optimally at pH 10 and 2.5–3.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose utilization.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin liquefaction and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Positive (using API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>In tests with Biolog GN2 microplates, the following carbon substrates are utilized: dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, maltose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-glutamic acid, inosine and thymidine.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-mannitol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, d-glucuronic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), rifampicin (50 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg) but resistant to penicillin G (10 μg).</s><s>Cellular fatty acids comprise C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH (27.3 %), 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (19.6 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (17.3 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (15.3 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH (7.7 %), cyclo C<sub>19 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (4.8 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> plus i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (2.6 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (1.0 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.7 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.6 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (0.5 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0.5 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.5 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (0.4 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.3 %), 10-methyl C<sub>19 : 0</sub> (0.2 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0.2 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.2 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (0.2 %) and C<sub>16 : 1</sub> 2-OH (0.1 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.7 mol% by HPLC and 64.1 mol% by genome shotgun sequencing.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HTCC2654<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42376<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102057<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Bermuda Atlantic Time Series Station in the western Sargasso Sea, Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>