<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5651_nm.6015" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6015" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6015" rank="species">Knoellia subterranea</organism><reference id="rid.5651"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schutze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Knoellia sinensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Knoellia subterranea sp. nov., two novel actinobacteria isolated from a cave.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>84</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837319</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Knoellia subterranea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Knoellia subterranea</i> (sub.ter.ra'ne.a. L. pref. <i>sub</i> below, underneath; L. fem. n. <i>terra</i> soil; L. adj. <i>subterranea</i> under the earth, referring to the place of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular rods and cocci, occurring singly, in pairs, short chains or clusters.</s><s>Rods vary in their dimensions from 1.9 to 6.0 by 0.5 to 1.2 μm and cocci in diameter from 0.8 to 1.4 μm.</s><s>A rod/coccus growth cycle is exhibited on complex media.</s><s>Gram-positive, not acid-fast, non-motile, non-sporulating.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular, convex and opaque with entire margins and are white to cream-coloured.</s><s>Aerobic to microaerophilic.</s><s>Good growth occurs between pH 5 and 9 and at 28-37 °C; no growth at 42 °C or under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In R medium, NaCl is tolerated up to 4% (w/v) but not at 6% (w/v).</s><s>Catalasepositive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced; indole is not produced.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, potato starch, D-ribose and trehalose (weak).</s><s>No acid production from L-arabinose, D-glucitol, glycerol, inulin, lactose, D-mannitol, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose or D-xylose.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, gelatin, hippurate (weak), potato starch, Tween 80, tyrosine and urea (weak) are decomposed, while adenine, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acetate, formate (weak), malate and succinate are utilized as carbon sources, while aconitate, benzoate, citrate and dltartrate are not.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), neomycin (30 μg), nitrofuran (300 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), penicillin G (2 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (2 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and sulfonamide (300 μg).</s><s>Not susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg) or oxacillin (5 μg).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and bglucosidase are detected by the APIZYM enzyme assay but trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Weak reaction for lipase (C14) and acid phosphatase.</s><s>In addition to the chemotaxonomic properties described for the genus, a small amount of phosphatidyμglycerol and an unknown phospholipid are present.</s><s>No diagnostic sugars.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: soil from a hypogean environment, Reed Flute Cave, Guilin, China.</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0120<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12332<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106776<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>