<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2771_nm.6046" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6046" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6046" rank="species">Microbacterium foliorum</organism><reference id="rid.2771"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Microbacterium foliorum sp. nov. and Microbacterium phyllosphaerae sp. nov., isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses and the surface litter after mulching the sward, and reclassification of Aureobacterium resistens (Funke et al. 1998) as Microbacterium resistens comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1267</fpage><lpage>1276</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491322</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium foliorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium foliorum</i> (fo.li.o'.rum. L. pl. gen. neut. n. <i>foliorum</i> of the leaves)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-sporeforming, irregularly shaped rods, which sometimes form V-shapes and are motile by means of a single polar or lateral flagellum.</s><s>In older cultures, rods are shorter, but amarked rod±coccus cycle does not occur.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, shiny, slightly convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Oxidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Positive for catalase and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Gelatin, DNA and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilization of starch is weak.</s><s>None of the strains hydrolyses casein and Tween 80, whereas hydrolysis of Tween 60 is strain-dependent.</s><s>Arabinose, gluconate, glucose, malate, maltose, mannitol, mannose and N-acetylglucosamine are assimilated, but caprate and adipate are not used.</s><s>Citrate and phenylacetate are utilized only by certain strains.</s><s>Acid production is positive from amygdalin, L-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, D-mannose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose, but negative from adonitol, darabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, D-fucose, erythritol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, inositol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, xylitol and L-xylose.</s><s>Acid production is variable between strains of D-arabinose, methyl α-D-glucoside, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, starch and methyl β-D-xyloside.</s><s>Negative for the fermentative and oxidative production of acid from glucose, according to the method of Hugh &#x0026; Leifson (1953), but positive for oxidative acid production when tested using API 20NE and API 50CH.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2% NaCl.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is approximately 25 °C.</s><s>At 37 °C, growth is strain-dependent, but growth does not occur at 42 °C.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-12, MK-11 and MK-10.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid, 14-methyl hexadecanoic acid and 14-methyl pentadecanoic acid.</s><s>Contains peptidoglycan of the B2β (L-homoserine)-D-Glu→Gly→D-Orn type, with glycolyl residues.</s><s>The DNA G+­C composition for the type strain is 67 mol%.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose, mannose and rhamnose.</s><s>Isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses and from the litter layer after mulching of the sward.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 12966<sup>T</sup> (=P 333/02<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19580<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>