<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4315_nm.3949" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3949" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3949" rank="species">Clostridium hylemonae</organism><reference id="rid.4315"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kitahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takamine</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of Eubacterium sp. VPI 12708 and related strains with high bile acid 7alpha-dehydroxylating activity to Clostridium scindens and proposal of Clostridium hylemonae sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>971</fpage><lpage>978</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium hylemonae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium hylemonae</i> (hai.le.mon'ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>hylemonae</i> of Hylemon, after the American microbiologist Phillip B. Hylemon, for his contributions to research on bile acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the characteristics given below is based on the results of studies with the two strains TN-271<sup>T</sup> and TN-272.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>The straight or slightly curved, rod-shaped cells are 1.0-5.3x0.2-0.5 μm in size and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies are 0.5-1.0 mm in diameter, disc-shaped and greyish in colour.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C and the optimum pH is around 7.6.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Two strains produce acid from galactose, glucose, raffinose and sucrose and have variable reactions with arabinose, fructose, maltose, ribose and xylose.</s><s>None of the strains produce acid from adonitol, amygdalin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch or trehalose.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and gas are produced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Moderate amounts of acetic acid (as the endproduct) are produced in peptone/yeast extract medium supplemented with glucose; minor amounts of propionic acid, iso-butyric acid, butyric acid and iso-valeric acid are also produced.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA of strain TN-271<sup>T</sup> is 48.6 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain TN-271<sup>T</sup> and was isolated from the faeces of a healthy adult human.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (Saitama, Japan) as strain JCM 10539<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>