<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3458_nm.5447" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5447" rank="genus">Paralactobacillus</organism><reference id="rid.3458"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leisner</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rusul</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Paralactobacillus selangorensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new lactic acid bacterium isolated from chili bo, a Malaysian food ingredient.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>24</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826783</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paralactobacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paralactobacillus</i> (pa.ra.lac.to.ba.cill'us. Gr. prep. <i>para</i> resembling; M.L. n. <i>Lactobacillus</i> a bacterial genus; <i>Paralactobacillus</i> resembling the genus <i>Lactobacillus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on MRS agar after 3 d aerobic incubation at 30 °C are &#x003C;2-3 mm in diameter, round and with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Non-spore-forming, straight, slender rods 2.5-6.5 μm long and 1.0 μm wide, usually occurring singly or as pairs but sometimes in older cultures as short chains.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive and non-motile.</s><s>Homofermentative, producing D-(-)-as well as L-(+­)-lactic acid from glucose.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose and growth is not observed with gluconic acid as substrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannose and salicin but not from lactose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose or xylose.</s><s>No ammonia is produced from arginine (Leisner <i>et al.</i>, 1999).</s><s>Growth is slow in sterilized chili bo (Leisner <i>et al</i>., 1997) as well as in MRS broth at 30°C (unpublished data).</s><s>Growth occurs in MRS broth at 15°C but not at 45°C.</s><s>No growth with 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Able to grow on acetate agar and to lower pH to &#x003C;4.15 in La-broth (Leisner <i>et al</i>., 1999).</s><s>Resistant towards 30 μg vancomycin g<sup>-1</sup> (Leisner <i>et al</i>., 1999).</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced (Leisner <i>et al</i>., 1999).</s><s>G+­C content of DNA is 46 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a Malaysian food ingredient, chili bo (Leisner <i>et al</i>., 1997).</s><s>Readily distinguished from obligatory heterofermentative <i>Lactobacillus</i>, <i>Weissella</i> and <i>Leuconostoc</i> by lack of production of gas from glucose and from facultative heterofermentative Lactobacillus by lack of production of gas and acid from gluconic acid and lack of production of acid from ribose or xylose.</s><s>Two species of facultative heterofermentative <i>Lactobacillus</i>, <i>Lactobacillus acetotolerans</i> and <i>Lactobacillus homohiochii</i>, may contain strains that also show negative reactions in all three tests (Hammes &#x0026; Vogel, 1995). <i>Lactobacillus acetotolerans</i> may be differentiated from <i>Paralactobacillus selangorensis</i> by its G+­C content of 35-37 mol% and lack of growth at 15 °C, and Lactobacillus homohiochii may be differentiated by a G­+C content of 35-38 mol% and lack of growth in MRS broth (Hammes &#x0026; Vogel, 1995). <i>Paralactobacillus</i> may be distinguished from the homofermentative rod-shaped <i>Carnobacterium</i> by the ability to grow on acetate agar and the lowering of pH to below 4.15 during growth in La-broth, and from the homofermentative <i>Lactococcus</i>, <i>Enterococcus</i>, <i>Streptococcus</i>, <i>Pediococcus</i>, <i>Lactosphaera</i>, <i>Vagococcus</i> and <i>Tetragenococcus</i> by possessing a distinctive rod-shaped cell morphology.</s><s>The differentiation of <i>Paralactobacillus</i> from homofermentative <i>Lactobacillus</i> is more problematic and requires the use of a combination of characters for particular species.</s><s>The differentiation of <i>Paralactobacillus</i> from homofermentative Lactobacillus spp. of the <i>Lactobacillus</i> casei-<i>Pediococcus</i> group is given by the tests listed in Table 1 and from homofermentative <i>Lactobacillus</i> spp. of the <i>Lactobacillus delbrueckii</i> group by the tests listed in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>