<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1800_nm.4418" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4418" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4418" rank="species">Quinella ovalis</organism><reference id="rid.1800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brulla</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vicini</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clark</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stahl</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Quinella ovalis gen. nov., sp. nov., based on phylogenetic analysis.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>293</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-293</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7684240</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Quinella ovalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Quinella ovalis (o.val'is. L. fem. adj., egg-shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of Quinella ovalis is that of the genus plus the following.</s><s>Cells are oval.</s><s>They are about 3 to 4 by 5 to 8 μm in size but can be considerably smaller in the rumen if crowding occurs (21).</s><s>Photomicrographs that represent the morphology have been published (11, 16, 21, 23).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species has not been axenically cultivated, and therefore, this description is the type of the species (rule 18 in the <i>International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria</i>).</s><s>Highly enriched and partially purified cell suspensions ferment glucose, fructose, sucrose, and mannitol and slowly metabolize maltose.</s><s>Polysaccharides, amino acids, proteins, lactate, melibiose, mannose, glucosamine, galactose, rhamnose, cellobiose, lactose, glucuronic acid, xylose, arabinose, and soluble starch are not fermented or are fermented at extremely low rates (2, 13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rapid growth occurs at 37 to 39°C, and slow growth occurs at 44°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25 or 50°C (13).</s><s>It grows in the rumen at pH values at least somewhat lower than 6.0.</s><s>The higher pH limit is not known.</s><s>It produces mainly lactic acid as a fermentation product when the sugar energy source is not limiting growth, but produces mainly acetate, propionate, and CO<sub>2</sub> when the energy source is limiting and growth is slow (21), as does <i>S. ruminantium</i> (17).</s><s>When it is by far the main organism in the rumens of sheep fed mainly molasses (21), acetate and propionate are the main organic acids produced and no lactate is detectable at any time during the 24-h feeding cycle.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Q. ovalis</i> is observed in mesophilic, anaerobic, and rumen environments such as the rumens of sheep, but it is probably also widely distributed in other ruminants such as llamas (13).</s><s>The number observed in the rumen is strongly influenced by the amount of fermentable sugars, such as glucose or sucrose, in the animal’s diet (2, 13, 16, 21).</s></p></content></protolog>