<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8187_nm.13407" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13407" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13407" rank="species">Marinobacter zhejiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.8187"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huo</surname><given-names>Y.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter mobilis sp. nov. and Marinobacter zhejiangensis sp. nov., halophilic bacteria isolated from the East China Sea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2885</fpage><lpage>2889</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000786-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060077</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter zhejiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter zhejiangensis</em> (zhe.ji.ang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>zhejiangensis</em> pertaining to Zhejiang province in China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and motile.</s><s>Young cultures show rod-like cells (1.0–2.5×0.4–0.8 μm), occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on HM agar are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular and slightly irregular, elevated, semitransparent and cream-coloured after 48 h at 30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–10.0 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 1.0–3.0 %.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.5 and 15–42 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0–7.5 and 30–35 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Tweens 20 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin, starch and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Weakly positive for lecithinase.</s><s>Negative for gluconate oxidation, indole production, <em>ο</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase and urease.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: acetate, ethanol, glutamate, l-isoleucine, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate and l-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-arginine, cellobiose, citrate, l-cysteine, formate, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, gluconate, glucose, glycerol, glycine, l-histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lysine, malonate, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, l-methionine, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, l-serine, sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, tyrosine and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, trehalose or sucrose.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefoxitin, ceftriaxone, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, penicillin, polymyxin B, tobramycin and tetracycline, but not to bacitracin, nystatin or streptomycin.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CN74<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7061<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15156<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a marine sediment sample of Zhejiang, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.4±0.1 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>