<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3454_nm.275" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.275" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.275" rank="species">Halobacterium denitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.3454"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tomlinson</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jahnke</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hochstein</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halobacterium denitrificans sp. nov., an extremely halophilic denitrifying bacterium.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>66</fpage><lpage>70</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-1-66</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542071</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halobacterium denitrificans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halobacterium denitrificans</i> (deni-tri'fi-cans. M.L. part. adj. <i>denitrificans</i> denitrifying)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exponential-phase cells from liquid cultures are highly pleomorphic and disk shaped.</s><s>They are from 0.8 to 1.5 μm wide and 2.0 to 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Motility is not present.</s><s>Colonies on complex medium are 2 to 3 mm in diameter, round, convex, entire, and orange red.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative and extremely halophilic.</s><s>Cells lyse at NaCl concentrations less than 1.5 M.</s><s>Growth occurs between 1.5 M and at least 4.5 M NaCl.</s><s>Maximum growth rate between 2 and 3 M NaCl (at 37°C).</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 30 to 55°C, with maximum growth rate at 50°C (in the presence of 3 M NaCl).</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6 to 8 (optimum, 6.7) at 37°C.</s><s>Cells are red because of the presence of α-bacterioruberin.</s><s>Polar lipids are diphytanyl-glycerol-ether derivatives.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotroph. <i>H. denitrificans</i> is a facultative anaerobe capable of anaerobic growth only when nitrate (or nitrite) is present.</s><s>It reduces nitrate to nitrite, nitrous oxide, and dinitrogen when grown in the presence of 0.5% nitrate.</s><s>Only dinitrogen accumulates when it is grown in the presence of 0.1% nitrate.</s><s>Grows aerobically, but not anaerobically, in a mineral-salts medium containing 0.005% yeast extract, ammonium as the nitrogen source, and suitable carbon and energy sources such as D-glucose, D-galactose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, acetate, citrate, fumarate, glycerol, lactate, α-ketoglutarate, malate, succinate or pyruvate.</s><s>In unbuffered mineral-salts-yeast extract medium, sufficient acid is produced from utilizable carbohydrates and glycerol to change the pH from 6.7 to 4.9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth.</s><s>Growth was inhibited by aphidicolin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and novobiocin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Gelatin liquified, hydrogen sulfide produced from thiosulfate, and Tween 40 (palmitic acid ester) hydrolyzed.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze starch, urea, or Tween 80 (oleic acid ester).</s><s>Indole negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Solar evaporation ponds (salterns) in the San Francisco Bay area of California and probably in other salterns.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain S1 has been deposited as <i>Halobacterium denitrificans</i> in American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md. (ATCC 35960).</s></p></content></protolog>