<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2493_nm.11419" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11419" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11419" rank="species">Herbaspirillum rhizosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.2493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Herbaspirillum rhizosphaerae sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil of Allium victorialis var. platyphyllum</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2284</fpage><lpage>2288</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64666-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911298</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Herbaspirillum rhizosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Herbaspirillum rhizosphaerae</em> (rhi.zo.sphae′rae. N.L. gen. n. <em>rhizosphaerae</em> of the rhizosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, slightly curved rods, 0.3–0.4×1.8–2.2 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of bipolar flagella.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on NA or on NA with nitrate.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 34 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 6.5–7.5; growth occurs weakly at pH 5.0 but not at pH 4.5.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of more than 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine and urea are hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch, xanthine and Tweens 20 and 60 are not.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, glycerol, pyruvate, ribose and succinate are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>d-Xylose is utilized, but adonitol, benzoate, d-cellobiose, formate, l-glutamate, maltose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose are not utilized.</s><s>Utilization of l-malate (positive for type strain) and l-arabinose (negative for type strain) is variable.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-xylose and l-arabinose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-cellobiose, lactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, melibiose, d-melezitose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, l-rhamnose or d-raffinose.</s><s>Acid production from d-fructose (positive for type strain) and trehalose (negative for type strain) is variable.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, oleandomycin, streptomycin and tetracycline but not to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, lincomycin, novobiocin, penicillin G or polymyxin B.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, cyclo C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, UMS-37<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12558<sup>T</sup> =CIP 108917<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of <em>Allium victorialis</em> var. <em>platyphyllum</em>, wild edible greens cultivated on Ulleung island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>