<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5613_nm.11835" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11835" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3344" rank="subspecies">Xenorhabdus nematophilus beddingii</organism><reference id="rid.5613"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akhurst</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Xenorhabdus nematophilus subsp. beddingii, Enterobacteriaceae: a new subspecies of bacteria mutualistically associated with entomopathogenic nematodes.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>454</fpage><lpage>457</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-3-454</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xenorhabdus nematophilus</i> subsp. <i>beddingii</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xenorhabdus nematophilus</i> subsp. <i>beddingii</i> (bed.din'gi. i. M. L. gen. n. <i>beddingii</i> of Bedding, named for R. A. Bedding)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large, asporogenous, gram-negative rods measuring approximately 0.5 to 1.6 μm by 2 to 13 μm, also occurring as filaments more than 20 μm long.</s><s>Birefringent bodies occur within cells.</s><s>Spheroplasts occur in cultures after 2 days.</s><s>Motile and peritrichously flagellated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic with good growth on yeast extract, meat extract, and simple peptone media.</s><s>Not bioluminescent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, oxidase, cytochrome oxidase, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Tests for lysine, ornithine and glutamic acid decarboxylases, and arginine dihydrolase are negative.</s><s>Urease, phenylalanine deaminase, chitinase, and tyrosinase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid, but not gas, is produced from glucose, dextrin, fructose, maltose, D-mannose, and trehalose and, by most strains, from salicin.</s><s>Acidification of melezitose is weak and not evident after 3 days.</s><s>Acidification of glycerol and acidification of D-ribose are variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Casein and esculin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase, deoxyribonuclease, and lipase are produced.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, DL-lactate, L-malate, propionate, and succinate are utilized on OY (9) agar; benzoate, malonate, oxalate, and L-tartrate are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Occurs in two forms.</s><s>The primary form produces light brown, granular, convex, circular colonies which are 2 to 3 mm in diameter on nutrient agar after 4 days at 28°C.</s><s>It adsorbs BTB and neutral red, forming blue and brown colonies on NBTA medium and MacConkey agar, respectively.</s><s>It has antimicrobial and lecithinase activities.</s><s>Secondary- form colonies on nutrient agar are slightly wider and flatter than primary-form colonies and are not pigmented.</s><s>The secondary form does not adsorb BTB or neutral red or have antimicrobial or lecithinase activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 45.7 to 47.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The natural habitat is the intestinal lumina of two undescribed species of entomogenous nematodes, <i>Steinernema</i> species M and N (4,5), and the body cavities of insects infected with these nematodes.</s><s>Strain Q58/1 (= University of Queensland Microbiology Collection strain UQB 2871) is designated the type strain of the taxon.</s></p></content></protolog>