<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12341_nm.20371" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20371" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20371" rank="species">Spirochaeta perfilievii</organism><reference id="rid.12341"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dubinina</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grabovich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leshcheva</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gavrish</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta perfilievii sp. nov., an oxygen-tolerant, sulfide-oxidizing, sulfur- and thiosulfate-reducing spirochaete isolated from a saline spring</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>110</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018333-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173011</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Spirochaeta perfilievii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Spirochaeta perfilievii</em> [per.fi.li.e′vi.i N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>perfilievii</em> named after Professor B. V. Perfil’ev (1893–1974), the Russian microbiologist who discovered and described the ‘Thiodendron’ microbial mat].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, spherical and diffuse, up to 10–15 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative and show rotation, undulation and gliding motility typical of spirochaetes.</s><s>Helical cells with irregular coils are 0.2–0.4×10–200 μm in size.</s><s>The shortest cells are those grown under strictly anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In media with low sulfide concentrations and in the presence of some dissolved oxygen, long (beyond 200 μm) non-motile filaments with periplasmic sulfur globules predominate.</s><s>Round bodies occur under any unfavourable conditions.</s><s>The three morphotypes are often present simultaneously and in different frequencies depending on ambient conditions.</s><s>Aerotolerant anaerobe.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Cytochromes were not detected.</s><s>Mesophilic with a temperature range 4–32 °C (optimum at 28–30 °C).</s><s>Grows at pH 6.5–8.5 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).</s><s>Obligate, moderate halophile; grows in 0.1–1 M NaCl (optimum 0.35 M NaCl).</s><s>As a chemo-organoheterotroph, glucose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, cellobiose, glycogen, starch and laminarin are used as sole carbon or energy sources.</s><s>Peptides, amino acids, organic acids and alcohols are not used as sole carbon or energy sources.</s><s>Growth is not supported by alginate, arabinose, galacturonic acid, laevulose, l-rhamnose, fructose, lactose, raffinose, galactose, dextrin, d-xylose, melibiose, ribose, cellulose or any sugar alcohols.</s><s>Ammonium salts, casein hydrolysate, yeast extract, peptone and asparagine can be used as sources of nitrogen, whereas urea, nitrate, nitrite, aspartate, arginine, valine, leucine, ornithine, threonine, tryptophan and cysteine can not.</s><s>Formate, acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> are the major metabolic end products of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, sulfur and thiosulfate are reduced to sulfide.</s><s>Under micro-oxic conditions (0.5–1.5 % O<sub>2</sub> in the gas phase), sulfide is oxidized to sulfur.</s><s>Elemental sulfur accumulates in the periplasmic space as birefringent globules.</s><s>Resistant to rifampicin and neomycin.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and aldehyde C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19205<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2514<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a ‘Thiodendron’ bacterial sulfur mat in a saline spring at the Staraya Russa resort (Novgorod Region, Russia).</s></p></content></protolog>