<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4535_nm.11820" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11820" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3004" rank="species">Vibrio shiloi</organism><reference id="rid.4535"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kushmaro</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Banin</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Loya</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosenberg</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio shiloi sp. nov., the causative agent of bleaching of the coral Oculina patagonica.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1383</fpage><lpage>1388</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491336</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio shiloi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio shiloi</i> (shi'lo.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>shiloi</i> of Shilo, named after the late microbiologist Moshe Shilo)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Vibrio shiloi</i> conforms to the descriptions of the family <i>Vibrionaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Vibrio</i> (Farmer &#x0026; Hickman-Brenner, 1992).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods (2.4x1.6 μm) that are motile by a single, polar, sheathed flagellum when grown on solid or liquid medium.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow on Marine agar after 48 h incubation at 30 °C, have slightly serrated edges and do not luminesce.</s><s>When grown on 0±4% agar, the cells swarm.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Produces acid, but not gas, aerobically and anaerobically from D-glucose and sucrose.</s><s>Growth in Marine broth occurs at 16-37 °C but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Grows in Nutrient broth containing 2-4% NaCl, but no growth in 1 or 6% NaCl.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite and produces indole.</s><s>Shows positive reactions for lysine decarboxylase, β-galactosidase, gelatinase and β-glucosidase and negative reactions for ornithine decarboxylase, urease and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Cells utilize dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, cellobiose, D-fructose, L-fructose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, methyl β-D-glucoside, dpsicose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, D-trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, cis-aconitate, citric acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, DL-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, L-alanine, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-aspartate, glycyl L-glutamate, L-histidine, L-ornithine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, caminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, glycerol, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (O129 vibriostatic agent), penicillin, ampicillin, tetracycline, oxytetracycline, streptomycin and kanamycin.</s><s>Isolated from and pathogenic for the Mediterranean coral Oculina patagonica, causing death of the endosymbiotic zooxanthellae and bleaching of the coral at temperatures of 20 to 32 °C.</s><s>The type strain is strain AK1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-91<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13774<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>