<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1320_nm.7959" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7959" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7959" rank="species">Bacteroides levii</organism><reference id="rid.1320"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides intermedius comb. nov. and description of Bacteroides corporis sp. nov. and Bacteroides levii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides levii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides levii</i> (lev'i.i. L. gen.n. <i>levii</i> of Lev, named for Meir Lev, the American-English microbiologist who first isolated this organism; "<i>Bacteroides melaninogenicus</i> subsp. <i>levii</i>" Holdeman, Cato, and Moore 1977).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Except where otherwise noted, this description is based on our study of the LEV strain (ATCC 29147T) and two phenotypically similar strains (including strain JP-2 [33, 43]) isolated from cattle.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In glucose broth cultures, cells are 0.6 to 1.2 by 2 to 7 μm and occur in pairs and short chains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates are minute, circular, entire, and low convex.</s><s>After incubation for 2 to 3 days, colonies are buff to light brown; dark brown colonies develop after incubation for 5 to 7 days.</s><s>No lipase or lecithinase activity is observed on egg yolk agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose broth cultures are turbid with a smooth sediment and had a final pH of 5.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics given in Table 6, gelatin, casein, milk, and meat are digested.</s><s>There is no fermentation of adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, fructose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, maltose, mannitol, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, catalase is not produced, and hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No growth occurred in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth supplemented with 20% bile or 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 35 to 37°C; growth at 30 or 45°C is delayed and partially inhibited.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation acids detected in cultures of the type strain grown in broth medium containing 1% peptone, 1% yeast extract, 1% glucose, vitamin K, and hemin are (in milliequivalents</s></p><p class="description"><s>per 100 ml of culture): acetic, 2; propionic, 1.5 to 2; butyric, 1 to 1.5; and isovaleric, 1 to 1.5.</s><s>Isobutyric acid (0.5 meq/100 ml) and a small amount of succinic acid (0.3 meq/100 ml) also are detected.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted to acetate and propionate.</s><s>Lactate is not utilized, and threonine was not converted to propionate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vitamin K and hemin are required for growth.</s><s>Succinate stimulates growth and can replace the requirement for heme.</s><s>Cytochrome 6 is synthesized from heme and is not detected in the absence of heme.</s><s>Glutamine stimulates growth and results in increased uptake of many amino acids and dipeptides.</s><s>The cells possess superoxide dismutase activity.</s><s>Further information on the biochemical properties of <i>B. levii</i> has been described by Lev and Lev and Milford.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species has been isolated from the bovine rumen, a cattle horn abscess, and a case of bovine summer mastitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA has been reported to be 45 to 46 mol% by T<sub>m</sub> and 48 mol% by bouyant density.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 29147<sup>T</sup> (= LEV strain).</s></p></content></protolog>