<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.294_nm.1535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1535" rank="species">Aquabacter spiritensis</organism><reference id="rid.294"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Irgens</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquabacter spiritensis, gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, gasvacuolate aquatic bacterium</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>155</volume><fpage>137</fpage><lpage>142</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aquabacter spiritensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aquabacter spiritensis</i> (spi'ri.ten.sis. M.L. adj. <i>spiritensis</i>, named after Spirit Lake, Washington, USA from which it was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Aquabacter spiritensis</i> is the same as that for the genus.</s><s>Cultures usually show single encapsulated cells.</s><s>Colonies are circular, slightly convex in elevation, with entire margin and smooth, glistening surface.</s><s>The colonies may appear translucent or opaque, chalky white.</s><s>The larger the number of gas vacuoles within the cells of the colony, the whiter the colony.</s><s>Old agar slant cultures become rubbery.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but not nitrite.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 35°C at pH 7.0 to 9.0.</s><s>Does not fix nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following characteristics are negative: amylase, protease, tryptophanase (indole), nitrite reductase, nitrogenase, and phenylalanine deaminase.</s><s>Carbon sources not utilized are: formate, citrate, fumarate, aspartate, arginine, methanol, ethanol, glycerol, malonate, DL-proline, gluconate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, L-lysine and numerous carbohydrates.</s><s>The following enzymes test positive: nitrate reductase, urease, and lipase.</s><s>Organic compounds utilized as sources of carbon and energy are: acetate, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, malate, alanine, glutamate, propionate, butyrate, tributyrin, maleate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate and α-ketoglutarate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67.3 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from Spirit Lake, near Mount St.</s><s>Helens, Washington, 5 m depth, April 10, 1981.</s></p></content></protolog>