<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1162_nm.1459" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1459" rank="genus">Bradyrhizobium</organism><reference id="rid.1162"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jordan</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Rhizobium japonicum Buchanan 1980 to Bradyrhizobium gen. nov., a genus of slow-growing, root nodule bacteria from leguminous plants.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>136</fpage><lpage>139</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-136</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bradyrhizobium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram negative, aerobic, nonsporeforming, short rods 0.5 to 0.9 μm by 1.2 to 3.0 μm. Motile by one polar or subpolar flagellum. Produce slow growth on yeast extract-mannitol medium, colonies not exceeding 1 mm in diameter within 5 to 7 days at the optimal temperature of 25 to 30°C. Moderate turbidity is produced only after 3 to 5 days or longer in agitated broth. Produce an alkaline reaction in mineral salts-mannitol medium</s></p><p class="description"><s>after 28 days at 27°C.</s><s>Do not produce 3-ketolactose, and exhibit negative hypertrophyinitiating ability.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Stimulate nodule production on roots of tropical and some temperate-zone leguminous plants (<i>Leguminosae</i>) such as those of the genera <i>Glycine</i>, <i>Vigna</i>, and <i>Macroptilium</i>.</s><s>In addition to certain fast-growing strains, to be placed in the</s></p><p class="description"><s>genus <i>Rhizobium</i>, cause root nodule production on <i>Lotus</i> (<i>L. uliginosus</i> and <i>L . pedunculatus</i>), <i>Lupinus</i>, <i>Ornithopus</i>, <i>Cicer</i>, <i>Sesbania</i>, <i>Leucaena</i>, <i>Mimosa</i>,<i> Lablab</i>, and <i>Acacia</i>.</s><s>A highly specific nodulation of the nonleguminous plant <i>Parasponia</i> (Trema) by a strain of <i>Bradyrhizobium</i> sp. also occurs.</s><s>Fix atmospheric nitrogen (dinitrogen) when in the symbiotic state within root nodules, although ineffective nodules (unable to fix nitrogen) are occasionally formed.</s><s>Bacteria present in nodules as slightly swollen rods (containing polyphosphate inclusions) with rare branching or as coccus forms (in</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Arachis</i> nodules).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 62 to 66 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>B. japonicum</i> (Buchanan 1980) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>