<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11893_nm.19976" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19976" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19976" rank="species">Frondihabitans peucedani</organism><reference id="rid.11893"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Frondihabitans peucedani sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from rhizosphere soil and emended description of the genus Frondihabitans Greene et al. 2009</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1740</fpage><lpage>1744</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017947-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19734279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Frondihabitans peucedani</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Frondihabitans peucedani</em> [peu.ce.da′ni. L. n. <em>peucedanum</em> the plant hog's-fennel or sulphurwort and also a botanical genus name; L. gen. n. <em>peucedani</em> of <em>Peucedanum</em>, isolated from <em>Peucedanum japonicum</em> Thunb.].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, aerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, non-motile, irregular, short rods (0.3–0.5×0.9–1.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth and convex with entire margins and bright yellow after incubation on ISP 2 at 30 °C for 3 days.</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C (optimum 20–30 °C), at pH 5.1–12.1 (optimum pH 8.1–11.1) and with 4.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not with 5.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, but not casein, cellulose or starch.</s><s>Does not decompose hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production is not observed.</s><s>Positive for aesculin degradation but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of (API 20NE) d-arabinose, potassium gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, adipic acid, capric acid, dl-malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8) and <em>β</em>-glucosidase and negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin, cystine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>With Biolog GN2, utilizes l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol and sucrose and, in contrast to the results obtained with API 20NE, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannitol and d-mannose, but does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 or 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em> or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan type is B2<em>β</em> with ornithine as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8; small amounts of MK-9 and MK-7 are also present.</s><s>The polar lipid profile comprises phosphatidylglycerol, five unknown glycolipids, three unknown phospholipids and two unknown lipids.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RS-15<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13435<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22180<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of a plant (<em>Peucedanum japonicum</em> Thunb.) on Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>