<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9230_nm.14489" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14489" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14489" rank="species">Rhodovulum lacipunicei</organism><reference id="rid.9230"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chakravarthy</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sucharitha</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>CH.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>Ch.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum lacipunicei sp. nov., an obligate sulfide-demanding phototrophic alphaproteobacterium isolated from a purple pond in India</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1615</fpage><lpage>1619</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007617-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542142</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodovulum lacipunicei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodovulum lacipunicei</em> (la.ci.pu.ni′ce.i. L. n. <em>lacus</em> -<em>us</em> a lake, a pond; L. adj. <em>puniceus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> purple-coloured; N.L. gen. n. <em>lacipunicei</em> of/from a purple pond).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid-rod-shaped, 0.7–1 μm wide and 1.0–3.0 μm long, non-motile and divide by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy/photolithoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy/chemolithoheterotrophy).</s><s>Assimilatory sulfate reduction is not observed.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of phototrophic cultures is yellowish brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose shows maxima at 377, 449, 479, 512, 590, 806 and 860 nm, indicating the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids.</s><s>The absorption spectrum of pigments extracted with acetone shows maxima at 430, 457 and 487 nm, indicating the presence of carotenoids of the spheroidene series (spheroidenone, spheroidene and hydroxyspheroidene).</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C (range, 25–35 °C) and pH 7.0–8.5 (range, pH 6.5–9.0).</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth, but good growth occurs at up to 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Photo-organoheterotrophy with a few organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Good growth is observed with propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, lactate, fumarate, malate, crotonate, pyruvate, 2-oxoglutarate, peptone, Casamino acids and yeast extract.</s><s>Aspartate, glutamate, glucose, fructose, acetate, succinate, glycolate, ascorbate and cysteine are also utilized, but not formate, ethanol, citrate, glycerol, mannitol, caprylate, benzoate, tartrate, gluconate, sucrose, methanol, propanol, butanol or sorbitol.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is not observed in the presence of sulfide, sulfite, thiosulfate, thioglycolate, elemental sulfur, ferrous iron or hydrogen as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Obligately requires sulfide (tolerates up to 7 mM) as sulfur source for growth.</s><s>Chemoautotrophic growth is not observed in the presence of thiosulfate as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Fermentative growth is not observed in the presence of glucose as carbon source.</s><s>Biotin and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.6 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA322<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 104147<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 5700<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected from a saline pond with purple-coloured waters, located near Satpada in Orissa, India.</s></p></content></protolog>