<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1413_nm.4053" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4053" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4053" rank="species">Clostridium xylanolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.1413"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rogers</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baecker</surname><given-names>A.A.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium xylanolyticum sp. nov., an anaerobic xylanolytic bacterium from decayed Pinus patula wood chips.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>140</fpage><lpage>143</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-140</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Clostridium xylanolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium xylanolyticum</i> (xy.lan.o. ly' ti. cum. Gr. n. <i>xylanosum</i>, xylan; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; N. L. adj. <i>xylanolyticum</i>, xylan dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, and rod shaped (length, 1.8 to 3.0 μm; width, 0.5 to 0.8 μm).</s><s>A single, terminal, round endospore is formed by each cell; the spore distends the cell wall (Fig. 1).</s><s>The cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 2).</s><s>Thin sections reveal a five-layer cell wall structure (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Xylan is a good substrate for growth.</s><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, mannitol, ribose, sorbitol, and trehalose are not fermented.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied; urease, indole, lecithinase, lipase, and catalase are not produced; and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The fermentation end products from PYG (5) are formic, lactic, and acetic acids.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 35°C (Fig. 4), and the optimum pH for growth is 7.2 (Fig. 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 40 mol%.</s><s>DNA-DNA hybridization results show that under stringent conditions (60°C) the DNA of <i>C. clostridiiforrne</i> exhibits only 14% homology with the DNA of our isolate.</s><s>This suggests that although there is a low level of homology between the two DNAs, these organisms are not the same genetically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of starch and nonreduction of nitrate distinguish our isolate from <i>C. clostridiiforme</i>.</s><s>When grown on blood agar, our isolate is beta-hemolytic, whereas <i>C. clostridiiforme</i> is nonhemolytic. <i>C. clostridiiforme</i> is susceptible to clindamycin, whereas our isolate is resistant.</s><s>The G+C content of <i>C. clostridiiforme</i> is 48 mol%, whereas the G+C content of our isolate is 40 mol%.</s><s>The position of the endospores of <i>C. clostridiiforme</i> is central to subterminal, whereas the position of the endospores of our isolate is terminal.</s><s>Our isolate also differs from <i>Clostridium aerotolerans</i> ATCC 43524<sup>T</sup>, which ferments lactose, ribose, and trehalose. <i>C. aerotolerans</i> also utilizes xylan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of <i>C. aerotolerans</i> is 40 mol%, which is the same as the G+C content of our isolate.</s><s>Another <i>Clostridium</i> strain which utilizes xylan as a growth source is <i>Clostridium cellulovorans</i> DSM 3052<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>However, this organism differs from our isolate in that it ferments lactose and does not ferment melezitose, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>The DNA G + C	content	of <i>C. cellulovorans</i> is 26	mol%, which is markedly different from the DNA base composition of our isolate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 49623.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a <i>P. patula</i> chip pile which had been exposed to environmental conditions for 10 months.</s></p></content></protolog>