<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1768_nm.4420" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4420" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4420" rank="species">Schwartzia succinivorans</organism><reference id="rid.1768"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Schwartzia succinivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., another ruminal bacterium utilizing succinate as the sole energy source.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995818</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Schwartzia succinivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Schwartzia succinivorans</i> (suc.cin.i.vo'rans. L. adj. <i>succinicus</i>, succinic acid; L. part. <i>vorans</i>, devouring; L. fem. adj. <i>succinivorans</i>, succinic acid devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Each cell is a curved rod with one or more flagella emanating from the concave side at approximately the middle of the cell; the flagella occur in tufts if more than one flagellum is present.</s><s>Cells are 0.35 to 0.6 by 1.6 to 3.3 μm.</s><s>S-shaped cells and helical filaments up to 30 μm long can be formed.</s><s>Colonies on succinate agar are colorless and slightly raised with multiple lobes and smooth edges and are up to 5 mm in diameter after 48 h.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 39°C, and no growth occurs at 22°C and around 45°C.</s><s>Succinate is fermented with propionate as the only fermentation end product.</s><s>Rumen fluid and yeast extract are required for good growth.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: carbohydrates, glycerol, lactate, pyruvate, oxalate, malate, malonate, methylmalonate, fumarate, oxalacetate, glutarate, citrate, aconitate, tricarballylate, and amino acids and peptides present in acid or enzymic hydrolysates of casein.</s><s>Tests for catalase, urease, sulfide production, nitrate reduction, and gelatin liquefaction are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular fatty acid composition (means of values obtained for four strains) is as follows: 20% C<sub>15:0</sub> aldehyde, 14% C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>cis</i>7, 12% C<sub>12:0</sub>, 9% C<sub>14:0</sub>, 9% C<sub>15:0</sub>, and 9% C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>Branched-chain fatty acids are absent.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 46 mol% (as determined by UV spectroscopy).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain S1-1 is the type strain.</s><s>The four strains examined have been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen under the following accession numbers: strain S1-1<sup>T</sup>, DSM 10502<sup>T</sup>; strain S2-3, DSM 10503, strain S3-2, DSM 10504; and strain S4-2, DSM 10505.</s></p></content></protolog>