<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8403_nm.13527" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13527" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13527" rank="species">Phenylobacterium composti</organism><reference id="rid.8403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenylobacterium composti sp. nov., isolated from cotton waste compost in Korea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2301</fpage><lpage>2304</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65530-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842845</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phenylobacterium composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phenylobacterium composti</em> (com.pos′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile (with single polar flagella), Gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria (0.5×0.8–1.8 μm).</s><s>Colonies on R2A are light yellow and irregular.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–45 °C (optimally at 30 °C) and at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimally at pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Optimum NaCl concentration is 0–1 % (w/v); no growth occurs at ≥3 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80 and tyrosine, but not casein, chitin, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, hypoxanthine, pectin, starch or xanthine.</s><s>Negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API 20NE).</s><s>Weakly utilizes antipyrin, chloridazon and l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Utilizes potassium gluconate, adipic acid, suberic acid, sodium acetate, lactic acid, glycogen, valeric acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, itaconic acid, sodium malonate, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid (API 20NE and API ID 32GN).</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Resistant to fusidic acid, lincomycin, meticillin and nalidixic acid.</s><s>Sensitive to amikacin, ampicillin, cephalothin, cefotaxime, ciprofloxacin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, imipenem, kanamycin, neomycin, netilmicin, penicillin, polymyxin B, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.5 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4T-6<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12597<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19425<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from cotton waste compost, in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>