<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9284_nm.14570" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14570" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14570" rank="species">Psychrobacter lutiphocae</organism><reference id="rid.9284"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter lutiphocae sp. nov., isolated from the faeces of a seal</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2049</fpage><lpage>2053</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008706-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605717</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychrobacter lutiphocae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychrobacter lutiphocae</em> (lu.ti.phoc′ae. L. n. <em>lutum</em> faeces; L. n. <em>phoca</em> a seal; N.L. gen. n. <em>lutiphocae</em> of faeces of a seal).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, non-spore-forming, non-motile, diploid coccobacilli.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>Spermidine is the predominant polyamine.</s><s>The polar lipid profile is characterized by the presence of phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The fatty acids C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> are the major non-hydroxylated fatty acids.</s><s>The major hydroxylated fatty acid is C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 10 and 37 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar after 1 week at 37 °C.</s><s>On Columbia agar, colonies are non-pigmented, circular, smooth and opaque with a diameter of 2–4 mm.</s><s>Malate is assimilated but adipic acid, l-arabinose, capric acid, trisodium citrate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-glucose, maltose, phenylacetic acid, potassium gluconate, d-mannose and d-mannitol are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, glycogen, d-glucose, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed, but aesculin, adenine, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, testosterone, tyrosine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Activity is detected for ester lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease.</s><s>No activity is detected for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cysteine arylamidase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Indole and acetoin production are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB L-1110<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21542<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 56590<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the faeces of a seal.</s></p></content></protolog>