<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4216_nm.6265" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6265" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6265" rank="species">Corynebacterium simulans</organism><reference id="rid.4216"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wattiau</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wauters</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium simulans sp. nov., a non-lipophilic, fermentative Corynebacterium.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>347</fpage><lpage>353</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826822</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium simulans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium simulans</i> (si'mu.lans. L. v. <i>simulare</i> to simulate, because it resembles <i>Corynebacterium</i> striatum)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore forming, showing a diphtheroid arrangement.</s><s>Colonies are greyish-white, glistening and 1.2 mm in diameter on blood agar after 48 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth is facultatively anaerobic and does not occur or is very weak at 20 °C within 3 d.</s><s>The metabolism is fermentative.</s><s>Catalase is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from: glucose, sucrose, fructose and mannose.</s><s>Acid production from N-acetyl-glucosamine, galactose and ribose is variable.</s><s>Acid is not produced from: mannitol, maltose, D-  and L-xylose, glycerol, erythritol, D- and L-arabinose, adonitol, methyl β,D- xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl α,D- mannoside, methyl α,D- glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, D- turanose, D- lyxose, D-tagatose, D-  and L-fucose, D-  and L- arabitol, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Urea, aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite reduction is positive.</s><s>Alkalinization of buffered formate is positive.</s><s>No acid is produced from ethylene glycol.</s><s>Tween esterase and tyrosine clearing are positive.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase is variable.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase-lipase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive.</s><s>Lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α- and β- galactosidase, β- glucuronidase, α- and β- glucosidase, N-acetyl-β- glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Arabinose and galactose are present in the cell wall and the peptidoglycan diamino acid is <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acid is palmitic acid and oleic acid is the main unsaturated acid.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids (C22-C36) are present.</s><s>The three strains have been deposited in the DSMZ with the following accession numbers: Co 301=DSM 44392; Co 553<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44415<sup>T</sup>; and Co 55=DSM 44416.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Corynebacterium simulans</i> is Co 553<sup>T</sup> which is positive for ribose, N-acetyl-glucosamine, galactose and pyrazinamidase.</s></p></content></protolog>