<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1416_nm.3862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3862" rank="species">Wolinella curva</organism><reference id="rid.1416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Listgarten</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ebersole</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wolinella curva sp. nov.: "Vibrio succinogenes" of human origin.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>275</fpage><lpage>282</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-275</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Wolinella curva</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Wolinella curva</i> (curv'a. L. adj. <i>curva</i> curved, bent, arched)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved rods 0.5 to 1 μm wide by 2 to 6 μm long and have rounded or tapered ends.</s><s>Helical or straight cells may also exist.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Rapid, darting motility.</s><s>Endospores are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology as determined by electron microscopy.</s><s>In 2-day-old agar or broth cultures, cells of most strains appear as short, slightly curved rods with single polar flagella.</s><s>Cells with single flagella are observed less frequently among cells of the type strain than among cells of other strains of this species.</s><s>Cell length ranges from 0.65 to 4.75 μm, with mean lengths of 1.20 to 1.85 μm.</s><s>Strain VPI 10659 exhibits greater variability in cell length, with a range of 1.20 to 28.30 μm and a mean of 3.75 μm (Table 4 and Fig. 1 through 8).</s><s>Cell diameters of all strains range from 0.25 to 0.45 μm, with means of 0.35 to 0.40 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In negatively stained preparations and in ultrathin sections, the cell surface has a convoluted contour that is typical of most gram-negative bacteria (Fig. 5 through 8).</s><s>In sections, a distinct nucleoid region is present in all cells.</s><s>Polar caps similar to the structures described by Ritchie et al. (15) and Lai et al. (9) are present in all of the strains which we examined (Fig. 7 and 8).</s><s>Cytoplasmic inclusions are rare; they appear as circular electron-dense bodies that are generally 0.05 μm or less in diameter (Fig. 5).</s><s>The outer layers of the cells consist of a highly convoluted outer membrane with a less distinct inner or cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>These layers are separated by an electron-lucent space of irregular width.</s><s>A distinct, electron-dense peptidoglycan layer between the inner and outer membranes cannot readily be identified (Fig. 6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given above applies equally to all strains of <i>W. curva</i>, to <i>W. succinogenes</i> (strains ATCC 29543<sup>T</sup> and Y-IB4), and to unrelated strain VPI 10279.</s><s>Morphological characteristics are of limited value in distinguishing among these species.</s><s>In contrast, <i>W. recta</i> exhibits a distinctive cell wall structure in which the outer membrane is covered with a distinctive array of hexagonally packed macromolecular subunits (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial morphology.</s><s>Translucent colonies are produced on blood agar plates.</s><s>The following three colony types occur: 1-mm-diameter, convex colonies, which are found with agar-pitting or -corroding colonies up to 5 mm in diameter or with spreading colonies up to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Agar-corroding or spreading colonies appear to be medium dependent, as only one of these variants occurs at a time.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth requirements.</s><s>Strains grow on agar surfaces in anaerobic and microaerophilic (5% oxygen) atmospheres containing H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>There is no growth on agar surfaces in air enriched with 10% CO<sub>2</sub>, but strains grow when they are incubated in air in the freshly prepared broth medium described by Kafkewitz (7), which contains thioglycolate as a reducing agent.</s><s>All cultures require formate and fumarate for broth culture.</s><s>Strains grow less well in broth media supplemented with formate and nitrate (0.2%), but do not grow in broth media supplemented only with nitrate.</s><s>Hydrogen and formate are used as energy sources.</s><s>Formate is oxidized.</s><s>Hydrogen and carbon dioxide are produced in headspace gas over broth cultures (PPLO-FF medium).</s><s>Hydrogen is also detected in the headspace gas of <i>W. succinogenes</i> cultures.</s><s>This contrasts with a previous report (20), in which no hydrogen was detected with this species.</s><s>Fumarate is reduced to succinate.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented and are not required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics and sensitivities to inhibitory agents.</s><s>The biochemical characteristics are shown in Tables 2 and 5 . <i>Wolinella</i> strains are oxidase positive, as determined with the reagent described by Tarrand and Groschel (22).</s><s>This finding contrasts with the results of the test performed with aqueous <i>N, N,N',N'</i>-tetramethyl-<i>p</i>-phenylene diamine dihydrochloride (3), but is consistent with the description of oxidase-positive oral <i>Vibrio succinogenes</i>-like organisms (23) and the presence of cytochromes in <i>W. succinogenes</i> and its ability to use low levels of oxygen (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities.</s><s>Minimal inhibitory concentrations of antibiotics for <i>W. curva</i> (in micrograms per milliliter): bacitracin, &#x003E;128; chloramphenicol, 2 to 4; clindamycin, 0.5 to 1; colistin, 4; erythromycin, 2; gentamicin, 2; kanamycin, 4 to 8; metronidazole, 1 to 2; minocycline, 2 to 4; nalidixic acid, 64 to 128; neomycin, 4 to 8; penicillin, 32; polymixin B, 8; rifampin, 128 to &#x003E;128; streptomycin, 2; tetracycline, 1; vancomycin, &#x003E;128 (21; this study).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA homologies. <i>W. curva</i> isolates have G+C contents of 43 to 47 mol% (Table 2).</s><s>Strains of <i>W. curva</i> form a distinct group with an intergroup homology of 80 to 100% (Table 3).</s><s>The <i>W. curva</i> isolates show no significant DNA homology with the type strain of <i>W. succinogenes</i>, the type strain of <i>W. recta</i>, or strain VPI 10279.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serology.</s><s>None of the antisera against <i>Wolinella</i> strains react with the cells of other species of oral and nonoral microorganisms (Table 6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The serological relationships among <i>Wolinella</i> species are shown in Table 7.</s><s>These reactions are consistent with the findings of Badger and Tanner (2), who used an agglutination assay.</s><s>However, the ELISA has the advantage of a distinct end result with the formation of a blue color.</s><s>After the specific antiglobulin has been made, prepared, and characterized, this assay can be performed faster than multiple biochemical tests.</s><s>As used in these studies, the ELISA does not require broth culture of test strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 to 47 mol% (melting temperature method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from lesions in human oral cavities and from a blood culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 35224 (= VPI 9584).</s></p></content></protolog>