<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12286_nm.20302" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20302" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20302" rank="species">Arcicella aurantiaca</organism><reference id="rid.12286"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arcicella aurantiaca sp. nov., isolated from stream water</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2979</fpage><lpage>2983</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118286</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arcicella aurantiaca</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arcicella aurantiaca</em> (au.ran.ti.a′ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>aurantiaca</em> orange-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, strictly aerobic, vibrioid and non-motile.</s><s>After 72 h of incubation on R2A agar at 25 °C, mean cell dimensions are 0.5–0.6 μm diameter and 1.0–3.0 μm length.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are orange, non-mucous, circular, smooth and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 72 h of incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–30 °C, with 0–0.2 % NaCl and at pH 6.0–10.0.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25 °C, in the absence of NaCl and at pH 7.0.</s><s>Carotenoid/flexirubin pigments are absent.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase activities and hydrolysis of casein and starch.</s><s>Negative for lipase activity and hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and negative for indole production, d-glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase and urease activities.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, C8 esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present and C4 esterase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds in the Biolog GN2 microplate are utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-serine, inosine, uridine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Other substrates in the GN2 microplate are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, sulfamethoxazole, rifampicin, novobiocin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, penicillin G and ampicillin and resistant to gentamicin and kanamycin.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of a mixture of phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and several uncharacterized polar lipids; the predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown aminophospholipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TNR-18<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25207<sup>T</sup> =BCRC 17969<sup>T</sup>), isolated from stream water in Kaohsiung Prefecture, southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>