<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8729_nm.13573" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13573" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13573" rank="species">Rhodobacter ovatus</organism><reference id="rid.8729"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>Ch.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>Ch.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter ovatus sp. nov., a phototrophic alphaproteobacterium isolated from a polluted pond.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1379</fpage><lpage>1383</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65619-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523181</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodobacter ovatus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodobacter ovatus</em> (o.va′tus. L. masc. adj. <em>ovatus</em> egg-shaped, ovate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid, 0.9–1.2 μm wide and 1.0–2.0 μm long, non-motile and divide by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>Performs assimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of phototrophic cultures is yellowish brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 374, 446, 476, 509, 587, 803 and 851 nm, confirming the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids.</s><s>The absorption spectrum for pigments extracted with acetone gives maxima at 455 and 488 nm, indicating the presence of the carotenoids spheroidene and spheroidenone.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C (range, 25–35 °C) and pH 6.5–7.0 (range, pH 6.0–8.0).</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth, but tolerates concentrations up to 1 % (w/v).</s><s>Photo-organoheterotrophy with a few organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Good growth is observed with pyruvate and glycerol as carbon sources.</s><s>Growth occurs with acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, succinate, mannitol, sorbitol, butanol, peptone and casein hydrolysate.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is not observed in the presence of sulfide, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur or hydrogen as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Chemoautotrophic growth is not observed in the presence of thiosulfate or hydrogen as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Fermentative growth is not observed in the presence of pyruvate as a carbon source.</s><s>Biotin and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.06 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA234<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14779<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55049<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of sediment collected from Noor Mohammad Kunta (‘Pink Pond’), an industrially polluted freshwater pond in the Katedan industrial belt, Rajendranagar, Hyderabad, India.</s></p></content></protolog>