<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8818_nm.13240" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13240" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13240" rank="species">Bacteroides xylanisolvens</organism><reference id="rid.8818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chassard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Delmas</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernalier-Donadille</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides xylanisolvens sp. nov., a xylan-degrading bacterium isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1008</fpage><lpage>1013</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65504-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398210</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacteroides xylanisolvens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacteroides xylanisolvens</em> (xy.lan.i.sol′vens. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan, a vegetal polymer; L. part. adj. <em>solvens</em> dissolving; N.L. part. adj. <em>xylanisolvens</em> xylan-dissolving, referring to the ability of the micro-organism to degrade xylan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile rods, 1.8–2.5 μm long and 0.2–0.3 μm wide.</s><s>Gram-negative by staining and cell-wall ultrastructure.</s><s>No heat-resistant endospores are formed.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase- and catalase-negative.</s><s>Metabolizes xylan to acetate, propionate and succinate.</s><s>Poor growth is exhibited with arabinoxylan, pectin and galacturonic acid.</s><s>No growth occurs with starch or cellulose.</s><s>Growth occurs between 25 and 42 °C and at pH 6.0–7.2.</s><s>Optimal growth conditions are 38 °C and pH 6.8.</s><s>Rumen fluid is not required for growth.</s><s>Indole-negative but able to hydrolyse aesculin.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>No activity is detected for urease, and gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, mannitol, lactose, sucrose, maltose, salicin, xylose, arabinose, glycerol, cellobiose, mannose, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, rhamnose and trehalose.</s><s>Also able to ferment fructose, ribose, galactose and melibiose.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained (API Rapid ID 32A) for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for arginine dihydrolase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (33.8 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (23.5 %) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (10.3 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XB1A<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18836<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 53782<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces of a non-methane-excreting individual.</s><s>Strains XB4A, XB3A, XB2A2, XB41A and XO85C13, isolated from similar sources, are also included in the species.</s></p></content></protolog>