<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3905_nm.11368" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11368" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11368" rank="species">Methylibium fulvum</organism><reference id="rid.3905"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylibium fulvum sp. nov., a member of the Betaproteobacteria isolated from ginseng field soil, and emended description of the genus Methylibium.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2062</fpage><lpage>2066</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64909-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylibium fulvum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylibium fulvum</em> (ful′vum. L. neut. adj. <em>fulvum</em> deep yellow, gold-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Oxidase-positive but catalase-negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not starch, chitin, xylan, CM-cellulose, casein or DNA.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-fructose, d-lyxose, l-xylose, sucrose (weakly), acetate, 3-hydroxybutylate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamine, l-glutamate, l-phenylalanine and l-proline.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, trehalose, maltose, d-cellobiose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-lactose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, xylitol, inositol, glycerol, amygdalin, glycogen, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, dextran, pyruvate, valerate, fumarate, salicin, malate, formate, propionate, tartrate, gluconate, caprate, maleic acid, phenylacetate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, glutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-cysteine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-threonine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is weakly positive; gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulfide and indole production are all negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-melibiose, d-glucose or amygdalin.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 66.6–66.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 322<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12591<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23394<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon province, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>