<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2416_nm.11287" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11287" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11287" rank="species">Amycolatopsis echigonensis</organism><reference id="rid.2416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirose</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis echigonensis sp. nov. and Amycolatopsis niigatensis sp. nov., novel actinomycetes isolated from a filtration substrate</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1747</fpage><lpage>1751</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64791-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis echigonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis echigonensis</em> (e.chi.go.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>echigonensis</em> referring to Echigo, the old name of Niigata Prefecture, Japan, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, non-motile and Gram-positive and form a well-developed aerial and vegetative mycelium.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white and the vegetative mycelium is light yellow.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5–45 °C and the optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Grows on medium containing 3–7 % NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–11, and the optimum is pH 9.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-xylose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, inositol and d-lactose.</s><s>Production of acid from erythritol, d-adonitol and d-glucose is weak.</s><s>Using the API CORYNE and API ZYM systems, positive reactions are observed for nitrate reductase, pyrazinamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14) or <em>α</em>-fucosidase; pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activities are weak.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 72.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LC2<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15387<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AB206019<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a filtration substrate made from volcanic soil, Niigata, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>