<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3572_nm.8505" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8505" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8505" rank="species">Bacillus velezensis</organism><reference id="rid.3572"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ruiz-García</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus velezensis sp. nov., a surfactant-producing bacterium isolated from the river Vélez in Málaga, southern Spain.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>191</fpage><lpage>195</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63310-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653875</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus velezensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus velezensis</em> (vel.e.zen′sis. N.L. adj. masc. <em>velezensis</em> pertaining to Vélez, named thus for being first isolated from the river Vélez in Málaga, southern Spain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-positive rods, 0·5×1·5–3·5 μm, occurring both singly and in pairs and occasionally in short chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal and lie in paracentral or subterminal positions in non-swollen sporangia.</s><s>They do not contain parasporal crystals or accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>They are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>On TSA medium the bacteria grow in creamy-white, rough colonies with slightly irregular edges.</s><s>In liquid TSB medium a thin film is formed at the surface whilst the rest of the medium is uniformly cloudy, showing no strands or clumps.</s><s>They are capable of growing in NaCl concentrations of up to 12 % w/v.</s><s>They grow within the temperature range of 15 to 45 °C and at pH values of between 5 and 10.</s><s>They are chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Their metabolism is respiratory, with oxygen as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>They do not grow in anaerobiosis in the presence of nitrate or fumarate.</s><s>They produce acids (without gas) from aesculin, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, glycerol, d-glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glycoside, d-raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>They do not produce acids from adonitol, d-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gluconate, inulin, d-lyxose, d-melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>They reduce nitrate and produce H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Vogues–Proskauer and ONPG are positive.</s><s>They hydrolyse blood, starch, gelatin and casein.</s><s>They grow in media without yeast extract.</s><s>Indol, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase, phenylalanine deaminase and growth on lysozyme (0·001 %, w/v) are negative.</s><s>They do not hydrolyse Tween 20, Tween 80, DNA or tyrosine.</s><s>They are susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (30 μg), cephalotin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), colistin (10 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), norfloxacin (5 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), trimetroprim/sulfamethoxazole (1·25/23·75 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>They are resistant to aztreonam (30 μg).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 46·1–46·4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CR-502<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5687<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22478<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a brackish water sample taken at the mouth of the river Vélez at Torredelmar, Málaga, southern Spain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>Additionally, this strain is able to produce acids from starch and sucrose and produce dihydroxyacetone.</s><s>It is resistant to ceftazidime (30 μg).</s><s>Contrary to strain CR-14b, the type strain does not use citrate as sole source of carbon and energy and does not produce lecithinase.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15 : 0 anteiso (32·70 %), 15 : 0 iso (29·86 %) and 16 : 0 (13·41 %).</s><s>The main quinone is MK-7 (96·6 %).</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 46·4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p></content></protolog>