<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.154_nm.1607" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1607" rank="genus">Rhodobium</organism><reference id="rid.154"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Satoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new genus of marine budding phototrophic bacteria, Rhodobium gen. nov., which includes Rhodobium orientis sp. nov. and Rhodobium marinum comb. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>226</fpage><lpage>234</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-226</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodobium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobium</i> (Rho.do'bi.um. Gr. n. <i>rhodos</i>, rose; Gr. n. <i>bios</i>, life; M.L. n. <i>Rhodobium</i>, red life)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid to rod shaped, 0.7 to 0.9 μm wide, and 1.0 to 3.2 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of polar or randomly distributed flagella.</s><s>Cells multiply by budding and asymmetric cell division.</s><s>Rosette formation is rare.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cells contain intracytoplasmic membranes of the lamellar type together with bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids belonging to the spirilloxanthin series.</s><s>Facultative photoheterotrophs that grow anaerobically in the light or aerobically in the dark.</s><s>Photosynthetic cultures are pink to red, while aerobic chemotrophic cultures are colorless.</s><s>Mesophilic and halophilic.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25 to 35°C, at pH 6.9 to 7.5, and in the presence of 1 to 5% NaCl.</s><s>Photoorganotrophy with simple organic compounds as carbon sources is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 and menaquinone 10 are the major quinones.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 61.5 to 65.7 mol%.</s><s>The phylogenetic position is in the alpha-2 subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodobium orientis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>