<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8235_nm.14209" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14209" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14209" rank="species">Aequorivita capsosiphonis</organism><reference id="rid.8235"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bang</surname><given-names>B.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aequorivita capsosiphonis sp. nov., isolated from the green alga Capsosiphon fulvescens, and emended description of the genus Aequorivita.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>724</fpage><lpage>728</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004119-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329596</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aequorivita capsosiphonis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aequorivita capsosiphonis</em> (cap.so.si.pho′nis. N.L. gen. n. <em>capsosiphonis</em> of <em>Capsosiphon</em>, the scientific name of the marine alga from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic bacterium.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and non-motile.</s><s>In MB, cells are rod-shaped and 0.3–0.4×2.0–3.0 μm in size.</s><s>In MB, cells sometimes appear filamentous or helical and reach up to 15 μm in size.</s><s>Produces non-diffusible yellow- to orange-coloured pigments that are not of the flexirubin type.</s><s>On MA, colonies are opaque, convex, circular, smooth and approximately 2 mm in diameter after 5 days at 25 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7–9 (optimum, pH 7) and at 4–40 °C (optimum, 25 °C).</s><s>Requires sodium ions (at least 0.5 % NaCl).</s><s>Tolerates 8 % NaCl and grows weakly in the presence of 10 % NaCl on R2A agar and trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Does not produce indole (API 20E).</s><s>A positive reaction is obtained for H<sub>2</sub>S production in the API 20E gallery, but no H<sub>2</sub>S is detected on Kligler's iron agar.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose or maltose (each at 0.5 %, w/v).</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Produces acetoin (API 20E).</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed, but aesculin, agar, CM-cellulose, casein, dextran, DNA, egg yolk, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine, xanthine and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase activities are present, weak cystine arylamidase activity is detected and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin activities are absent.</s><s>In the API 20E system, amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol and sucrose are not assimilated.</s><s>The following substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are utilized: l-aspartic acid, l-fucose, gentiobiose, d-glucosaminic acid, glycogen, inosine, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid and l-threonine.</s><s>The following substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are utilized only weakly: adonitol, l-alanine, l-asparagine, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, raffinose, turanose and uridine.</s><s>The remaining substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), polymyxin B (300 IU) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.9 mol%.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Tables 1 and 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, A71<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22183<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15070<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from <em>Capsosiphon fulvescens</em>, a green alga collected from the South Sea, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>