<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7515_nm.2284" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2284" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2284" rank="species">Thiothrix fructosivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7515"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Howarth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Unz</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pickup</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yaguchi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Head</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic relationships of filamentous sulfur bacteria (Thiothrix spp. and Eikelboom type 021N bacteria) isolated from wastewater-treatment plants and description of Thiothrix eikelboomii sp. nov., Thiothrix unzii sp. nov., Thiothrix fructosivorans sp. nov. and Thiothrix defluvii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1817</fpage><lpage>1827</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1817</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555365</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiothrix fructosivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiothrix fructosivorans</i> (fruc.to.si.vo'rans. M. L. neut. n. <i>fructosum</i> fructose; L. part. pres. <i>vorans</i> eating; M. L. adj. <i>fructosivorans</i> fructose-eating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, 1-2-2-5 μm in diameter and 1.2-2.5 μm long, and form multicellular filaments.</s><s>Gliding gonidia are produced from the end of the filaments.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>No flagella are present but a tuft of fimbriae is present at the end of the gonidium.</s><s>A sheath is present.</s><s>Rosettes and a holdfast are formed.</s><s>Volutin inclusions, sudanophilic granules and poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are observed within cells.</s><s>Growth occurs in the temperature range 4-28°C and pH range 6.5-8.5, but there is no growth at 33°C.</s><s>Oxidase-positive and weakly catalase-positive.</s><s>No requirement for reduced inorganic sulfur for growth and is heterotrophic.</s><s>Sulfur globules are deposited within invaginations of the cytoplasmic membrane when cells are grown in the presence of a reduced inorganic sulfur compound.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch, casein, Tween 80 and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Fructose, sucrose, melezitose, pyruvate, succinate, malate, acetate, lactate and propionate are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>No growth occurs with mannoheptulose, glucose, galactose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, fucose, ribose, xylose, arabinose, glyceraldehyde phosphate, maltose, lactose, trehalose, melibiose, gentiobiose, cellobiose, raffinose, starch, inulin, salicin, aesculin, amygdalin, mannitol, inositol, glycerol, erythritol, sorbitol, gluconate, glucuronate, galacturonate, Tween 80, tributyrin, methanol, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, isoamyl alcohol, <i>n</i>-amyl alcohol, phenol, citrate, 2-oxoglutarate, formate, butyrate, hydroxybutyrate, valerate, caproate, oleate, benzoate, <i>m</i>-toluate or glycollate.</s><s>Ammonia, nitrate, proline, cysteine, asparagine, glutamine, aspartate, glutamate and glucosamine are used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Nitrite, alanine, glycine, phenylalanine, lysine, cystine, leucine or methionine cannot serve as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>No amino acids serve as sources of both carbon and nitrogen.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from activated-sludge plants.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Thiothrix fructosivorans</i> is Q<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC 49748<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>