<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12629_nm.22165" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22165" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22165" rank="species">Halomonas daqiaonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12629"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas daqiaonensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, denitrifying bacterium isolated from a littoral saltern</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1612</fpage><lpage>1616</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026344-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20693363</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas daqiaonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas daqiaonensis</em> (da.qia.o.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>daqiaonensis</em> of the Daqiao saltern, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive rods (0.3–0.6×1.2–2.2 µm) with several peritrichous flagella, appearing either singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies are cream–yellow, smooth and circular with entire edges on MY solid medium.</s><s>Produces EPS but does not form endospores or capsule.</s><s>Cells are moderately halophilic, capable of growing at 2–15 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth occurring at 7–8 % (w/v) NaCl; no growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–40 °C and pH 6–9 (optimum growth at 28–30 °C and pH 7.5).</s><s>Indole, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, O/F and ONPG tests are negative.</s><s>Positive for aerobic reduction of selenite, nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, with oxygen, nitrate or nitrite as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>No respiration with fumarate.</s><s>Accumulates PHB granules.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not casein, gelatin, starch, Tween 20, Tween 80 or urea.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Blood is not haemolysed.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar.</s><s>Cells do not produce acids from sugars (adonitol, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose or trehalose).</s><s>Positive for phenylalanine deaminase and ornithine decarboxylase, but not lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Susceptible to ciprofloxacin (5 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), doxycycline (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), cefalexin (30 mg), carbenicillin (100 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), novobiocin (30 µg), rifampicin (5 µg), penicillin G (10 IU), chloramphenicol (30 µg), ampicillin (10 µg), neomycin (30 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), oxacillin (1 µg) and polymyxin B (300 IU), but resistant to lincomycin (2 µg) and clindamycin (2 µg).</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase and leucine aminopeptidase, weakly positive for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), esterase lipase (C8), valine aminopeptidase and cystine aminopeptidase, and negative for acid phosphatase, α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphoamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, trypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, ribose, citrate, d-fructose, lactose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, maltose, succinate, acetate, fumarate, glycerol and propionate as sole carbon and energy source, but not d-mannose, cellobiose, adonitol, sorbitol, starch, aesculin, ethanol, formate, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, malonate, d-salicin or trehalose.</s><s>Utilizes l-alanine and l-valine as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy, but not dl-isoleucine, l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-histidine or l-methionine.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/ω6<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-9.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YCSA28<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.9150<sup>T</sup>  = NCCB 100305<sup>T</sup>  = MCCC 1B00920<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of Daqiao saltern, Jimo, Qingdao, on the east coast of China.</s><s>YCSA39, isolated from the same source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>