<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2406_nm.11271" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11271" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11271" rank="species">Lutimonas vermicola</organism><reference id="rid.2406"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choo</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lutimonas vermicola gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from the marine polychaete Periserrula leucophryna</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1679</fpage><lpage>1684</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65060-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684236</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lutimonas vermicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lutimonas vermicola</em> (ver.mi′co.la. L. n. <em>vermis</em> worm; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> from L. n. <em>incola</em> inhabitant; N.L. n. <em>vermicola</em> inhabitant of worms, pertaining to the origin of the type strain, a marine polychaete).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species conforms to that of the genus.</s><s>Cells are 1.6–2.5 μm long and 0.7–1.0 μm wide.</s><s>Devoid of flagellar and gliding motilities.</s><s>After 3 days of incubation, colonies on MA are circular, pulvinate, entire, smooth, opaque, yellow-coloured and 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 3–37 °C (optimum, 25 °C), at pH 5–11 (optimum, pH 8) and with 0.5–7.5 % NaCl (optimum, 1.5–2.5 %).</s><s>Absorption spectral peaks of the carotenoid pigments are observed at 427, 453 (major peak) and 478 nm.</s><s>Degrades starch and gelatin, but not elastin, CM cellulose or chitin.</s><s>Does not grow on DNase agar or MA containing casein.</s><s>In API 20NE strips, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity (substrate, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside).</s><s>Negative for urease, gelatin liquefaction and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (substrate, 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Weakly positive for <em>α</em>-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon substrates in Biolog GN2 microplates: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenyl ethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Does not utilize dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-mannitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine or urocanic acid.</s><s>Susceptible to rifampicin, vancomycin, erythromycin, penicillin G, tetracycline and chloramphenicol, but resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin and streptomycin.</s><s>In addition to the major cellular fatty acids reported in Table 2, the following fatty acids are present in minor proportions: anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (3.0 %), unknown ECL 13.565 (2.9 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (2.7 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 2-OH (2.6 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (2.5 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub> 2-OH (2.2 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B (1.2 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.0 %).</s><s>Traces (&#x003C;1 %) of the following fatty acids are also present: C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, unknown ECL 16.582, anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>14 : 1</sub> B, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, unknown ECL 11.543, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IMCC1616<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42379<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102041<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the digestive tract of a polychaete (<em>Periserrula leucophryna</em>) inhabiting a tidal flat of Donggum island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>