<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1222_nm.5665" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5665" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5665" rank="species">Streptococcus oralis</organism><reference id="rid.1222"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bridge</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus gallinarum sp. nov. and Streptococcus oralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>410</fpage><lpage>415</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-4-410</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus ferus</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus ferus</i> (fear's. L. adj. <i>ferrous</i> wild, referring to the wild rats from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci 0.5 μm in diameter that occur in pairs and chains.</s><s>Mannitol and sorbitol are fermented; raffinose is not.</s><s>An adhesive glucan is produced from sucrose.</s><s>This species is intolerant of 45°C or 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Colonies on agar containing sucrose are about 1 mm in diameter, raised, and somewhat adherent, with no liquid on or around the colony.</s><s>The final pH in 1% glucose broth is 4.2 to 4.5.</s><s>The DNA base content is 43 to 45 mol% G+C (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 8S1 (= ATCC 33477).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional comments. <i>S. ferus</i> was isolated in Florida from the mouths of wild rats that ate sugarcane and from rats living in a landfill dump in Hartford, Conn.</s><s>Strains from the two locales were homologous as determined by DNA hybridization.</s><s>Strains of <i>S. ferus</i> react with Bratthall antiserum <i>c</i>, although they are not related (as determined by DNA homology) to <i>S. mutans</i>. <i>S . ferus</i> strains do not grow on agar containing bacitracin (0.2 U/ml).</s><s>The cells produce and catabolize intracellular polysaccharide. <i>S. ferous</i> has not been isolated from humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Despite their many similarities, the five mutans streptococcal species can be readily identified by biochemical or serological differences.</s><s>It is interesting that some authors, although expressing reservations about the taxonomic separation of <i>S. mutans</i>, nevertheless point out the biochemical, serological, and genetic heterogeneity of <i>S . mutans</i> and remark on the good correlation among serotypes, biotypes, and genotypes.</s><s>That such clearly separable and genetically different organisms should all be called <i>S. mutans</i> seems unwarranted in light of modern taxonomic objectives.</s></p></content></protolog>