<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.135_nm.5955" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5955" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5955" rank="species">Cellulomonas cartae</organism><reference id="rid.135"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kandler</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cellulomonas cartae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>186</fpage><lpage>188</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellulomonas cartae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellulomonas cartae</i> (car. ta'. M.L. gen. n. <i>cartae</i> of Carta; named for G. R. Carta, the first to isolate this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile rods, 0.4 by 0.6 to 1.7 μm (Carta, U.S. Patent no. 3,778,349, 1973).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in. the logarithmic growth phase are irregular, curved, and club-shaped or are arranged in V formation (for microphotograph, see reference 7).</s><s>Approximately 4 days after exhaustion of the medium, the rods transform into shorter rods or even coccoid cells.</s><s>On PYG agar, colonies are about 2 to 5 mm in diameter, circular, convex, white, and glistening.</s><s>Cells in the logarithmic phase of growth are easily decolorized with 96% ethanol when treated for longer than 9 s and therefore appear gram negative.</s><s>However, <i>Escherichia coli</i> cells stain gram negative even after ethanol treatment for as short as 3 s.</s><s>Therefore, in comparison with <i>E. coli</i>, <i>C. cartae</i> is definitely gram positive.</s><s>This observation was confirmed by an electron micrograph (Fig. 1) of an ultra-thin section of <i>C. cartae</i>, in which the typical cell wall profile of a gram-positive organism is evident.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following are utilized as sole carbon sources: glucose, mannose, maltose, sucrose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, lactose, gluconate, mannitol, ribose, L-lactate, acetate, pyruvate, glycerol, and cellobiose.</s><s>Raffinose, DL-malate, and D-lactate are not used as sole carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from glucose, mannose, sucrose, mxylose, L-arabinose, ribose, gluconate, glycerol, lactose, pyruvate, and cellobiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetic acid is the main acidic intermediary product of aerobic glucose dissimilation.</s><s>Maximum acetic acid production (6.5 μmol of acid per ml of PYG medium) is reached in 48 to 72 h.</s><s>The pH of the medium is 4.8.</s><s>L-Lactic acid is produced in much smaller quantities (1 μmol/ml of medium).</s><s>After exhaustion of glucose, the acids are oxidized, resulting in an increase of the pH of the medium (pH 8.8) after 8 days.</s><s>Resting cells ferment glucose anaerobically to CO<sub>2</sub>, acetic acid, and L-lactic acid.</s><s>Cellulose strips are attacked from the edges in liquid medium within the first 48 h.</s><s>No colonies are visible on the strips.</s><s>After 48 h, the paper is totally converted to a pulpy mass.</s><s>The pH after 4 days is 5.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Starch is hydrolyzed and gelatin is slowly liquefied (in accord with Carta’s results [Carta, U.S. Patent no. 3,778,349, 19731).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is produced (Carta, U.S. Patent no. 3,778,349, 1973).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrite is produced from nitrate (in accord with Carta’s results [Carta, U.S. Patent no. 3,778,349, 19731).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is not produced (Carta, U.S. Patent no. 3,778,349, 1973).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Urease and lysine decarboxylase are not produced (Carta, US.</s><s>Patent no. 3,778,349, 1973).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic to facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-base composition: 76.6 mol% guanine plus cytosine (6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall composition, amino acids: DL-alanine, D-glutamic acid, L-lysine, D-serine, and D-aspartic acid; peptidoglycan type: Lys-D-Ser-D-Asp (6); sugars: galactose, fucose, and rhamnose (6).</s><s>The cell walls do not contain teichoic acid or teichuronic acid (Fiedler, personal communication), DNA-DNA hybridization experiments revealed a moderate relationship to other strains of <i>Cellulomonas</i> (12 to 20%); almost no genetic relationship was found between <i>C. cartae</i> and strains of <i>Arthrobacter</i> (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 20106 (= ATCC 21681).</s></p></content></protolog>