<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8086_nm.14661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7760" rank="species">Planctomyces staleyi</organism><reference id="rid.8086"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Starr</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sayre</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of ATCC 27377 to Planctomyces staleyi sp. nov. and Conservation of Pasteuria ramosa Metchnikoff 1888 on the Basis of Type Descriptive Material.  Request for an Opinion.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>666</fpage><lpage>671</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-666</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planctomyces staleyi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planctomyces staleyi</i> sp. nov. (M. L. adj.; sta’ley.i.), named in honor of James T. Staley, imaginative and industrious isolator of unusual bacteria, including ATCC 27377<sup>T</sup> (15)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Planctornyces staleyi</i> sp. nov. is ATCC 27377 (ICPB 2138; Staley “Michigan strain”).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although occasional cells take the Gram stain, the reaction of <i>Planctomyces staleyi</i> is predominantly gram negative, as is to be expected from the gram-negative cell envelope profile of strains belonging to morphotype IV of the <i>Blastocaulis- Planctomyces</i> group (13); in those morphotype IV strains thus examined, no discrete peptidoglycan layer can be visualized in thin sections by transmission electron microscopy (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine plus cytosine (G+C) content of the DNA of ATCC 27377<sup>T</sup> (M.</s><s>Mandel, personal communication) is 59 mol% by buoyant density (variance in four independent determinations was zero); the value reported elsewhere (15) for the same strain as analyzed by the same method and by the same analyst was 57 mol% G+C.</s><s>The corresponding value for ICPB 4362 is 58 mol% G + C (M.</s><s>Mandel, personal communication).</s><s>Other strains belonging to morphotype IV (though not necessarily to <i>Pfanctomyces stafeyi</i>) give values ranging from 56 to 63 mol% G+C (M.</s><s>Mandel, personal communication).</s></p></content></protolog>