<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8339_nm.13346" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13346" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13346" rank="species">Haloferula phyci</organism><reference id="rid.8339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Katsuta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloferula rosea gen. nov., sp. nov., Haloferula harenae sp. nov., Haloferula phyci sp. nov., Haloferula helveola sp. nov. and Haloferula sargassicola sp. nov., five marine representatives of the family Verrucomicrobiaceae within the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia'.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2491</fpage><lpage>2500</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000711-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloferula phyci</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloferula phyci</em> (phy′ci. L. gen. n. <em>phyci</em> of a sea-weed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.8–1.0 μm in width and 1.2–1.5 μm in length.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/5-strength MA medium are circular, convex and pale-orange in colour.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25–30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at either 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth and can be tolerated up to 5 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase-negative but oxidase-positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are positive, but esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-ornithine, inosine and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate are oxidized, but dextrin, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, furanose, d-galacturonic acid, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, uridine, thymidine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, l-fucose, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine and 2-aminoethanol are not oxidized.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains muramic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AK18-024<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08341<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22200<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine algae.</s></p></content></protolog>