<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4505_nm.5612" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5612" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5612" rank="species">Streptococcus australis</organism><reference id="rid.4505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willcox</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Knox</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus australis sp. nov., a novel oral streptococcus.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1277</fpage><lpage>1281</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491323</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus australis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus australis</i> (aus.tra'lis. L. gen. n. <i>australis</i> of the south, southern, relating to the region in which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporulating, catalase-negative cocci.</s><s>Colonies grow to diameters of approximately 0.5-1.0 mm on blood agar plates and the cells form short chains.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>α-Haemolytic on Columbia blood (sheep) agar plates.</s><s>The biochemical analysis was performed using Rapid ID32 Strep kits.</s><s>All strains produced alkaline phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, acidified media containing lactose, pullulan, maltose and sucrose and hydrolysed arginine.</s><s>No strain was able to produce β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-galactosidase, acetoin (Voges-Proskauer reaction), pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, N-acetyl β-glucosaminidase, β-mannosidase or urease.</s><s>No strain acidified media containing ribose, mannitol, sorbitol, trehalose, raffinose, glycogen, melibiose, melezitose, L-arabinose, D-arabinose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside or tagatose.</s><s>Strains were unable to hydrolyse hippurate.</s><s>The production of bgalactosidase was dependent on the substrate used [either 2-naphthyl β-D-galactopyranoside (-) or pnitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside (­+)].</s><s>Strains have a peptidoglycan linkage type of Lys-Ala-Gly and do not produce neuraminidase (Willcox, 1996).</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 43.5±1.2 mol%.</s><s>The strains were isolated from the saliva of humans.</s><s>The type strain is AI-1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700641<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13166<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>