<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6714_nm.5245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5245" rank="species">Staphylococcus delphini</organism><reference id="rid.6714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Varaldo</surname><given-names>P.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biavasco</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Satta</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus delphini sp. nov., a new coagulase-positive staphylococcal species isolated from dolphins.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>436</fpage><lpage>439</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus delphini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus delphini</i> (del.phi'ni. L. gen. n. <i>delphini</i>, of a dolphin)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cocci, 0.8 to 1.0 μm in diameter, arranged predominantly in clusters but occasionally occurring in pairs or singly.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, entire, 5 to 7 mm in diameter, slightly convex, smooth, glistening, butyrous, and opaque with a tendency to become slightly translucent after continued incubation.</s><s>Pigment not produced.</s><s>Facultative anaerobes; growth is best under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Fairly good growth at 45°C or in the presence of 15% NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth in semisolid thioglycolate medium is evident after 24 to 48 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rabbit, pig, bovine, and human plasmas are coagulated; clot formation is slightly faster with strain Heidy<sup>T</sup> than with strain Nono (1 h versus 4 h with rabbit and pig plasmas, 4 h versus 24 h with bovine plasma, and 24 h versus 48 h with human plasma).</s><s>The strains produce catalase, phosphatase, urease, caseinase, and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Deoxyribonuclease activity is weak and not resistant to heating.</s><s>Acetoin, gelatinase, clumping factor, and egg yolk factor are not produced.</s><s>Hemolysis is demonstrated on bovine, sheep, and human blood agar.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced aerobically from glucose, fructose, mannose, maltose, lactose, and sucrose, and moderately from mannitol (acid is produced from mannitol more slowly by strain Heidy<sup>T</sup> than by strain Nono).</s><s>No acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, trehalose, or xylitol.</s><s>Glucose, but not mannitol, is utilized anaerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains are susceptible to novobiocin and lysostaphin and resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>As determined by agar dilution tests, the lysostaphin minimal inhibitory concentrations are 3.12 μg/ml for strain Heidy<sup>T</sup> and 6.25 μg/ml for strain Nono; for both strains, the minimal inhibitory concentration of novobiocin is 0.2 μg/ml, and that of lysozyme is &#x003E;1 mg/ml).</s><s>The strains show no β-lactamase activity and are susceptible to the most common antistaphylococcal antibiotics; as determined by disk diffusion tests, both strains are susceptible to penicillin G, oxacillin, cephalothin, cefamandole, cefoxitin, cefuroxime, cefotaxime, vancomycin, teicoplanin, rifampin, cotrimoxazole, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, lincomycin, tetracycline, gentamicin, netilmicin, and of loxacin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacteriolytic activity pattern strongly resembles that of human staphylococci of lyogroup V (i.e., Staphylococcus epidermidis) (23), with an optimal NaCl concentration for lytic activity of 2 to 3%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The PBP profile is characterized by the occurrence of two bands having molecular weights of 85,000 and 79,000 (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nontypable when the basic sets of phages are used.</s><s>Both strains show a plasmid profile characterized by one small plasmid (about 2.2 kilobases).</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is Lys-Gly<sub>5-6</sub>.</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acid consists of glycerol and N-acetylglucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 39 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains appear to be potentially pathogenic for dolphins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain Heidy (=DSM 20771) is the type strain of <i>S. delphini</i>. <i>S. delphini</i> can be differentiated from all other known staphylococci primarily on the basis of coagulase, phosphatase, and heat-labile deoxyribonuclease production, carbohydrate reaction pattern, bacteriolytic activity pattern, PBP profile, and a rather high G+C content.</s><s>The major features useful in distinguishing between <i>S. delphini</i> and the most closely phenotypically related Staphylococcus species are summarized in Table 2.</s><s>The bacteriolytic activity patterns of the same species are compared in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>