<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12693_nm.22433" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22433" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22433" rank="species">Persicivirga ulvanivorans</organism><reference id="rid.12693"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Barbeyron</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lerat</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sassi</surname><given-names>J.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Le Panse</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Helbert</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collén</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Persicivirga ulvanivorans sp. nov., a marine member of the family Flavobacteriaceae that degrades ulvan from green algae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1899</fpage><lpage>1905</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024489-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833882</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Persicivirga ulvanivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Persicivirga ulvanivorans</em> (ul.va.ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>ulvanum</em> ulvan, a polysaccharide extracted from Ulvaceae of the genus <em>Ulva</em>; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <em>ulvanivorans</em> ulvan-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-flagellated, Gram-stain-negative rods of 0.8–1.0 µm in diameter and 1.5–5.5 µm long, with rounded ends, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cells are non-motile in liquid phase, and do not show gliding motility on solid surfaces.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are circular, shiny, orange to red and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days; flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Spreading does not occur at the margins of the colonies.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, chemo-organotrophic and heterotrophic, with an oxidative metabolism that uses oxygen as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Nitrate cannot be used as electron acceptor.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 20–30 °C; growth occurs between 4 and 35 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5–8.0; growth does not occur at pH 6.0 or 10.0.</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 2.5 % (w/v); no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and at concentrations &#x003E;6.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for cytochrome oxidase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities, weakly positive for catalase activity, but negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, β-galactosidase, α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, Tweens 20, 40 and 60, starch and ulvan (Fig. 2d), but not aesculin, urea, Tween 80, alginic acid, agar, ι-carrageenan, κ-carrageenan or gelatin.</s><s>Unable to utilize d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, maltose, l-arabinose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, gluconic acid, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, phenylacetic acid and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine as carbon source.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, mannitol, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin, inositol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of (µg ml<sup>−1</sup>) streptomycin (200), tetracycline (10), chloramphenicol (10), kanamycin (200), gentamicin (4), netilmicin (4), tobramycin (8), amikacin (16), ofloxacin (4), fosfomycin (32), colistin (2) and nalidixic acid (8) but not in the presence of penicillin G (20), ampicillin (20), carbenicillin (10), rifampicin (5), cefalotin (8), cefoxitin (8), cefotaxim (4), imipenem (4) or meropenem (4).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PLR<sup>T</sup> ( = CIP 110082<sup>T</sup> = DSM 22727<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from faeces of the marine mollusc <em>Aplysia punctata</em> fed with green algae, both collected at Presqu’île de Pen Lan, Pleubian, Brittany, France.</s></p></content></protolog>