<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9697_nm.14843" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14843" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14843" rank="species">Marinococcus luteus</organism><reference id="rid.9697"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>L.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinococcus luteus sp. nov., a halotolerant bacterium isolated from a salt lake, and emended description of the genus Marinococcus</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2875</fpage><lpage>2879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009670-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628611</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinococcus luteus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinococcus luteus</em> (lu′te.us. L. masc. adj. <em>luteus</em> orange, referring to the colour of the colonies of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile cocci about 0.1–0.5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are circular, tangerine-coloured, convex and opaque on modified ISP 5 medium.</s><s>Grows over a wide range of NaCl concentration (0–25 %, w/v), with optimal growth in the presence of 10–15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth is weak in the absence of NaCl; no growth is observed in the presence of only KCl or MgCl<sub>2</sub> . 6H<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C and at pH 6.0–8.0; optimal growth at 28 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, nitrate reduction, milk peptonization and coagulation, and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Indole, melanin and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Casein, cellulose, starch, urea, and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for gelatin liquefaction.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase, but negative for valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin, l-arabinose, d-glucose, glycerol, l-rhamnose and d-xylose (API 50CHB).</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: d-arabinose, l-arginine, dextrin, d-galactose, d-glucose, l-lysine, d-mannose, d-mannitol, l-proline, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, trisodium citrate and d-xylose.</s><s>The following are not utilized: adenine, adonitol, l-asparagine, d-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, glycerol, glycine, l-histidine, hypoxanthine, inositol, lactose, maltose, xylitol, l-serine, sodium acetate, sodium propionate, trehalose, l-threonine, l-tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7; MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) is present as a minor component.</s><s>The polar lipid profile comprises diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides, phosphatidylinositol, two unknown phosphoglycolipids and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 91094<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13214<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 208014<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Barkol Lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>