<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4892_nm.1388" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1388" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1388" rank="species">Mycoplana dimorpha</organism><reference id="rid.4892"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oyanagi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Araki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Recharacterization and emended description of the genus Mycoplana and description of two new species Mycoplana ramosa and Mycoplana segnis.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>434</fpage><lpage>442</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Mycoplana dimorpha</i> Gray and Thornton 1928.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Reduction of nitrate is variable. The Voges- Proskauer test is positive. Catalase positive. Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, and glycerol oxidatively, but acid is not produced from maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, inositol, and soluble starch. L-Arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, glycerol, succinic acid, L-glutamic acid, L-asparatic acid, acetic acid, putrescine, spermidine, and spermine are utilized as sole sources of carbon, but lactose, trehalose, inositol, soluble starch, citric acid, formic acid, methanol, ethanol, n-butanol, monomethylamine, methane, and butane are not. Biotin is required for growth. Ammonia and urea are utilized as sole sources of nitrogen. Most strains utilize nitrate as a sole nitrogen source. The DNA base composition ranges from 64 to 65 mol% G+C. The major hydroxy fatty acid is 3-hydroxy- C<sub>14:0</sub> acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain TK0055 (= ATCC 4279 = IFO 13291 = NCIB 9439), which was isolated from soil by Gray and Thornton in 1928.</s><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 64.5 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolate TKO066 is also an <i>M. dimorpha</i> strain.</s></p></content></protolog>