<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12174_nm.20171" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20171" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20171" rank="species">Vogesella mureinivorans</organism><reference id="rid.12174"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jørgensen</surname><given-names>N.O.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandt</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nybroe</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vogesella mureinivorans sp. nov., a peptidoglycan-degrading bacterium from lake water</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2467</fpage><lpage>2472</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018630-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19946047</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vogesella mureinivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vogesella mureinivorans</em> (mu.re.i.ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>mureinum</em> murein, cell wall; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> eating, devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>mureinivorans</em> murein-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods, non-sporulating and 2.7±0.9×0.8±0.1 μm (mean±sd, <em>n</em>=16) in size.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum and accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSB from 5–37 °C and pH 6–9, with optima at 20–30 °C and pH 6–7, respectively.</s><s>Doubling times in 1/10 and full strength TSB at optimum conditions are 4.3 and 1.6 h, respectively.</s><s>Concentrations of up to 1 % NaCl are tolerated, but optimum growth occurs at 0.1 % NaCl.</s><s>After 24 h of growth on LB or TSB, colonies are circular with a lobate margin, low convex, smooth, nonfluorescent and transparent to slightly greyish.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin, glycogen, casein, PG and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>Positive enzyme activities include lysozyme, DNase, casein protease, <em>β</em>-1,4-glucanase, chitinase, chitobiase, leucine and valine arylamidases, and acid and alkaline phosphatases.</s><s>The following compounds support growth: d-glucose (weak reaction), d-fructose, l-fucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, methyl-pyruvate, mono-methyl succinate, acetic acid, cis-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and urocanic acid.</s><s>Compounds that do not support growth are l- or d-arabinose, l or d-xylose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, l-arginine, l-ornithine, l-tryptophan and urea.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but the reduction is not coupled to anaerobic growth.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed, and oxidation and fermentation of d-glucose are negative (Hugh–Leifson test).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.2 mol%.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 389<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21247<sup>T</sup> =LMG 25302<sup>T</sup>) isolated from the clear-water Lake Sjælsø, Zealand, Denmark.</s></p></content></protolog>