<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3842_nm.6074" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6074" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6074" rank="species">Agrococcus jenensis</organism><reference id="rid.3842"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrococcus jenensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus of actinomycetes with diaminobutyric acid in the cell wall</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>234</fpage><lpage>239</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-234</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573501</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agrococcus jenensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agrococcus jenensis</i> (je.nen'sis. M.L. adj. <i>jenensis</i>, referring to the Thuringian town Jena, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular, spherical or ovoid to short rods.</s><s>The cells are 0.7 to 1.0 by 0.7 to 1.7 μm.</s><s>A few cells may be up to 2.6 μm long.</s><s>The cells occur singly, in pairs, in short flexible chains of about three to six cells, or in small irregular clusters.</s><s>Colonies are circular, slightly convex, and smooth.</s><s>Colony diameters range from 2 to 4 mm.</s><s>The color of the colonies varies depending on the culture conditions and illumination from whitish to yellow to intense orange.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite; hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Starch and esculin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein is variable.</s><s>Acids are produced only from fructose, glycerol, inulin, mannitol, L-rhamnose, and D-glucitol.</s><s>Malate and succinate are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, formate, and tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Urea, xanthine, hypoxanthine, gelatin, adenine, tyrosine, and Tween 80 are not decomposed or hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, nitrofuran, oxacillin, oxytetracycline, penicillin G, polymyxin B, rifampin, and streptomycin.</s><s>Cells are resistant to sulfonamide.</s><s>The G+C content is 74 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is soil and sandstone surfaces.</s><s>The type strain is strain 2002-39/1, which has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures as strain DSM 9580.</s></p></content></protolog>