<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5738_nm.1304" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1304" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1304" rank="species">Rhizobium tianshanense</organism><reference id="rid.5738"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characteristics of Rhizobium tianshanense sp. nov., a moderately and slowly growing root nodule bacterium isolated from an arid saline environment in Xinjiang, People's Republic of China.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>153</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-153</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857795</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium tianshanense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium tianshanense</i> (tian. shan. en' se. M. L. adj. <i>tianshanense</i>, referring to the Tianshan Mountains in the Xinjiang region of the People's Republic of China, where strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.25 to 0.9 by 1.2 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Cells move by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on YMA are circular, opaque, and convex, have a creamy color, and are usually 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 5 to 7 days of incubation.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 25 to 30"C, and the optimum pH is 6 to 8.</s><s>Strains can grow on YMA in the presence of 1.0% NaC1.</s><s>Some strains can grow at 4 or 10°C.</s><s>Glucose, mannitol, glycerol, xylose, fucose, erithritol, DL-proline, L-(+)-glutamic acid, and rhamnose are used as sole carbon and energy sources by all strains, and lactose, maltose, sucrose, pyruvate, raffinose, sorbitol, fructose, mannose, arabiose, citrate, and dulcitol are used by some strains.</s><s>Tagatose, galactose, melibiose, sorbose, inulin, benzoate, malate, vanillic acid, inositol, salicytol, fumarate, pyrocatechol, starch, and dextrin are not utilized.</s><s>Produces an acid reaction on YMA.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrate, and many amino acids, including glutamate, glycyl-L-leucine, norvaline, threonine, arginine, proline, and glycine, are used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Peptone is not utilized.</s><s>No megaplasmid is observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 to 63 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A-1BS (=CCBAU3306).</s><s>The generation time of this strain is 5 h, and the G+C content of its DNA is 61 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>