<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2500_nm.11436" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11436" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11436" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter paludis</organism><reference id="rid.2500"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter paludis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Mucilaginibacter gracilis sp. nov., pectin-, xylan- and laminarin-degrading members of the family Sphingobacteriaceae from acidic Sphagnum peat bog</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2349</fpage><lpage>2354</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65100-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter paludis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter paludis</em> (pa.lu′dis. L. gen. n. <em>paludis</em> of a swamp, of a marsh, of a bog).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Colony colour varies from light pink to reddish.</s><s>Utilizes d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, sodium d-galacturonate, sodium d-gluconate, d-glucose, d-lactose, leucrose, maltose, d-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, d-mannose, <em>myo</em>-inositol and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Does not utilize acetate, adonitol, arabitol, arbutin, butyrate, capronate, citrate, d-arabinose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, dulcitol, fumarate, inulin, malate, mannitol, propionate, pyruvate, salicin, sorbitol, succinate or valerate.</s><s>Capable of fermenting glucose and sucrose.</s><s>Hydrolyses chondroitin 6-sulfate, gellan gum, laminarin, pectin, pullulan, starch and xylan but not alginate, CM-cellulose, cellulose, chitin, aesculin, fucoidan, heparin or lichenan.</s><s>Produces acid from cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, mannose, laminarin and xylan.</s><s>Optimal growth at 20–25 °C and at pH 6.0–6.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain TPT56<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1394<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2446<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar in the Tomsk region of western Siberia.</s></p></content></protolog>