<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1377_nm.4032" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4032" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4032" rank="species">Clostridium tetanomorphum</organism><reference id="rid.1377"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wilde</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tosunoglu</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schallehn</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herwig</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschalk</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium tetanomorphum sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>134</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-127</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium tetanomorphum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium tetanomorphum</i> (te.ta.no.mor´phum. Gr. n. <i>tetanus</i>, tetanus; Gr. n. <i>morphe</i>, shape; M.L. adj. <i>tetano-morphum</i>, [<i>Clostridium</i>] <i>tetani</i> shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on our own data, on data in Bergey’s Manual (4, 9, and on the data of Nakamura et al. (29) and some other authors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slender rods (0.7 to 1.0 by 3.0 to 10.0 μm) with rounded to tapered ends, are occasionally slightly curved, occur singly or in pairs, and are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Spores are spherical or elliptical, terminal to subterminal, swelling the cells.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on PY agar are irregular with lobate margins, 2 to 5 mm in diameter, flat, gray, and semitranslucent with glossy surfaces.</s><s>There is a tendency to swarm on moist plates.</s><s>Colonies on PYG agar are white, opaque, and convex, with a mottled internal structure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose and maltose are fermented; acid and gas are produced.</s><s>The pH of cultures in glucose media usually is lowered from 6.9 to 5.0 after 5 days.</s><s>Most strains, including the type strain, also ferment inositol, ribose, and xylose.</s><s>Fewer strains ferment cellobiose, fructose, salicin, and sorbitol; the type strain utilizes fructose, salicin (weakly), and sorbitol.</s><s>Growth is strongly stimulated in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Arabinose, adonitol, galactose, lactose, mannose, rhamnose, saccharose, and sorbose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Products of glucose fermentatjon are <i>n</i>-butanol, ethanol, acetate, and butyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glutamate is fermented via the methylaspartate pathway to acetate, butyrate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and NH<sub>3</sub> (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Histidine is fermented (36).</s><s>Threonine is degraded to propionate (14); tyrosine is degraded to phenol (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ethanolamine is fermented to acetate, ethanol, and NH<sub>3</sub>; during growth the pH is lowered usually by 1 U.</s><s>Betaine, choline, and creatine are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lecithinase is not produced; lipase is produced on tributyrin; indole production is variable; and gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Meat, casein, and milk are not digested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is generally not reduced (29); some strains may be positive for this characteristic (31).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs in glutamate media with a low complex nutritional content (e.g., 0.05% yeast extract).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nontoxigenic .</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid (37).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA (as determined by the thermal denaturation method) is 25.4 to 28.5 mol%; (27.5 mol% for strain NCTC 543<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 543 (=DSM 4474), which was isolated as strain 259E<sup>T</sup> in 1920 from septic wounds by M.</s><s>Robertson, Lister Institute, London, United Kingdom.</s></p></content></protolog>