<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12751_nm.22534" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22534" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22534" rank="species">Propioniciclava tarda</organism><reference id="rid.12751"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sugawara</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaku</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propioniciclava tarda gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a methanogenic reactor treating waste from cattle farms</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2298</fpage><lpage>2303</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027482-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20971831</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Propioniciclava tarda</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Propioniciclava tarda</em> (tar′da L. fem. adj. <em>tarda</em> slow or inactive, referring to the slow growth of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses the following characteristics in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cobalamin (vitamin B<sub>12</sub>) is an essential requirement for growth.</s><s>In the absence of cobalamin, cells are irregular rods with tapered ends (0.5–0.8×0.6–1.8 µm) and occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>In the presence of cobalamin, cells are slender irregular rods (3–6 µm long) with crescent-shaped arrangements.</s><s>Growth is very slow, even in the presence of cobalamin.</s><s>Grows under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Grows at 20–37 °C (optimum 35 °C) and pH 5.3–8.0, preferring slightly alkaline conditions (optimum pH 7.5).</s><s>Addition of NaCl to the medium inhibits growth.</s><s>Positive for catalase and nitrate-reducing activities.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Oxidase, indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Sensitive to bile.</s><s>Utilizes fructose, galactose, glucose, cellobiose, lactose and salicin as preferable substrates.</s><s>The final pH of media after growth with glucose is 4.8–4.9.</s><s>Produces acetate and propionate with a small amount of succinate.</s><s>Mannose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, mannitol, amygdalin, aesculin, pyruvate and lactate are also utilized with slow growth.</s><s>Arabinose, ribose, xylose, rhamnose, sorbose, carboxymethylcellulose (CMC), cellulose (cellulose powder and filter paper), glycogen, inulin, starch, xylan, pectin, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, glycerol, ethanol, fumarate, malate and succinate are not utilized.</s><s>Anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> DMA are the major cellular fatty acids; C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and DMA type compounds are the major fatty acid constituents.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WR061<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 15804<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22130<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of rice-straw residue in a methanogenic reactor treating waste from cattle farms.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.3–69.5 %.</s></p></content></protolog>