<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5983_nm.1678" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1678" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1678" rank="species">Ralstonia mannitolilytica</organism><reference id="rid.5983"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Baere</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steyaert</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wauters</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Des Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suyama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verschraegen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Ralstonia pickettii biovar 3/'thomasii' strains (Pickett 1994) and of new isolates related to nosocomial recurrent meningitis as Ralstonia mannitolytica sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>547</fpage><lpage>558</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321101</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ralstonia mannitolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ralstonia mannitolytica</i> (man.ni.to'ly.ti.ca. N.L. adj. <i>mannitolytica</i> cleaving mannitol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species accommodates the <i>Ralstonia pickettii</i> biovar 3/`<i>thomasii</i>' strains and at least some of the strains known as `<i>Pseudomonas thomasii</i>'.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating rods that are motile by means of one polar flagellum (motility was not observed for the culture collection <i>R. mannitolytica</i> type strain, LMG 6866<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Aerobic growth is observed at 30, 37 and 42 °C and strains are viable for less than 6 d on TSA at room temperature.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Strains are resistant to desferrioxamine, O:129 and colistin.</s><s>No acid is produced from ethylene glycol.</s><s>Urease, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase (Rosco), Tween esterase and phenylalanine deaminase tests are positive.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide production, alkaline phosphatase (Rosco), arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis tests are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from glucose, L-arabinose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, D-arabitol and D-xylose.</s><s>Alkalinization occurs on minimal mineral agar with acetate, serine, malonate, β-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, succinate, fumarate, butyrate, formate, malate, mucate, galacturonate, citrate, histidine and lactate, but not with acetamide, adipate, alginate, allantoin, amygdalin, L-arginine, benzoate, L-ornithine, maleate or tartrate.</s><s>Testing by means of API 20NE, API 50CH and ID 32GN indicates that the strains assimilate acetate, N-acetylglucosamine, L-alanine, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, caprate, citrate, fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, 2- ketogluconate, glycerol, histidine, D-lactate, malate, malonate, mannitol, L-proline, propionate, serine, suberate and D-xylose, but not adipate, amygdalin, L-fucose, glycogen, inositol, itaconate, 5-ketogluconate, maltose, mannose, melibiose, phenylacetate, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, salicin, D-sorbitol or 3- hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, the following enzymes are detected: C4 esterase, C8 esterase-lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, acidic and alkaline phosphatase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, aand β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, amannosidase and α-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>The following cellular fatty acid components are present: 16:1<sup>9cis</sup> (range 30-38 mol%), 16:0 (21-30 mol%), 18:1<sup>11cis</sup> (7-15 mol%) and 14:0 (5-7 mol%).</s><s>The DNA G­C content is 66.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 6866<sup>T</sup> (deposited as `<i>Pseudomonas thomasii</i>' in 1972) (=NCIB 10805<sup>T</sup>) (Phillips et al., 1972).</s><s>The <i>R. mannitolytica</i> strains used in this study have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection (Laboratorium voor Microbiologie Ghent, Belgium) as LMG19090, LMG 19091 and LMG 19092.</s></p></content></protolog>