<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3722_nm.10750" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10750" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10750" rank="species">Gordonia soli</organism><reference id="rid.3722"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordonia soli sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from soil</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2597</fpage><lpage>2601</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64492-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082398</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gordonia soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gordonia soli</em> (so.li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of/from the soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, partially acid–alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycete that forms elementary branching hyphae that fragment into rods and cocci.</s><s>Pale orange-coloured, circular colonies (about 2 mm in diameter) with filamentous margins are formed on TSA after incubation for 2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Neither aerial hyphae nor diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–10.0 and at 28–35 °C, but not at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>Degrades starch, produces catalase and oxidase, but does not hydrolyse allantoin or arbutin.</s><s>Acid and alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and pyrazinamidase are produced, but myristate lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase and trypsin are not.</s><s>Does not ferment d-glucose, glycogen, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-ribose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, d-alanine (weak), l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine (weak), l-alaninamide, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, d-fructose 6-phosphate (weak), <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-glutamic acid, glycogen (weak), <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid (weak), d-malic acid (weak), mannan, d-mannose, 3-methyl d-glucose (weak), d-psicose, l-pyroglutamic acid, pyruvic acid (weak), putrescine, d-sorbitol (weak), succinic acid (weak), sucrose (weak), Tweens 20 and 40 and uridine 5-monophosphate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic properties are typical of the genus <em>Gordonia</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-AB07<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 16810<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44995<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from the campus of National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>