<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7203_nm.7356" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7356" rank="genus">Kitasatospora</organism><reference id="rid.7203"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A proposal to revive the genus Kitasatospora (Ōmura, Takahashi, Iwai, and Tanaka 1982).</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1048</fpage><lpage>1054</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1048</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336904</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Kitasatospora</i> Omura, Takahashi, Iwai, and Tanaka 1982.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kitasatospora</i> (Ki.ta.sa.to.spo'ra. Jpn. n. Kitasato, a Japanese microbiologist; M.L. fem. n. <i>spora</i> spore; M.L. fem. n. <i>Kitasatospora</i>, Kitasato spore)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from this study and previous studies (12, 15, 29).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The substrate mycelium is as well-developed as <i>Streptomyces</i> substrate mycelium, and the aerial mycelium bears long spore chains containing more than 20 spores.</s><s>No fragmentation of substrate mycelium occurs.</s><s>No sporangia are formed.</s><s>The major constituents of the cell wall are glycine, galactose, and <i>meso</i>-DAP or LL-DAP, depending on the type of cells analyzed.</s><s>When cells are grown on agar media, the aerial spores contain LL-DAP, whereas the substrate mycelium contains <i>meso</i>-DAP.</s><s>When cells are grown in liquid media, submerged spores are formed, and the spores contain LL-DAP and the filamentous mycelia contain <i>meso</i>-DAP.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain galactose, but lack arabinose, madurose, and xylose.</s><s>The phopholipid type is type 11.</s><s>The glycolate test is negative.</s><s>The organism is gram positive, aerobic, and chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>The growth temperature range is 15 to 42°C, and the pH range is 5.5 to 9.0.</s><s>The G+C content is 66 to 73 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <i>Kitasatospora</i> can be distinguished from the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> by the ratio of <i>meso</i>-DAP to LL-DAP in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The <i>meso</i>-DAP content is 49 to 89% in <i>Kitasatospora</i> strains and 1 to 16% in Streptomyces strains.</s><s>Galactose is present in the whole-cell hydrolysates of <i>Kitasatospora</i> strains but not in the whole-cell hydrolysates of <i>Streptomyces</i> strains.</s><s>In the dendrogram constructed by using 16s rRNA sequences of actinomycete species, <i>Kitasatospora</i> species form a tight clade which excludes all <i>Streptomyces</i> species; and in the dendrogram based on the 16s-23s rRNA gene spacers, the genera <i>Kitasatospora</i> and <i>Streptomyces</i> form distinct clades.</s><s>The genus <i>Kitasatospora</i> can be readily distinguished from the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> by specific nucleotide signatures in the sequences of both the 16s rRNA and the 16s-23s rRNA gene spacers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of the genus is <i>Kitasatospora setae</i> Omura, Takahashi, Iwai, and Tanaka 1982 (15).</s></p></content></protolog>