<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2067_nm.5748" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5748" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5748" rank="species">Collinsella stercoris</organism><reference id="rid.2067"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kageyama</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of genus Collinsella and proposal of Collinsella stercoris sp. nov. and Collinsella intestinalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1767</fpage><lpage>1774</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Collinsella stercoris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Collinsella stercoris</i> (ster'co.ris. L. n. <i>stercus</i> faeces; L. gen. n. <i>stercoris</i> of faeces, referring to the source of the isolate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.3-0.4x1.3-2.4 μm in size and occur in chains of 2-20 cells.</s><s>Colonies are white or grey in the centre with clear margins on EG agar.</s><s>Gram-positive and obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Spores and ¯agella are absent.</s><s>Can be cultivated for 2 d at 37 °C on EG agar in an anaerobic jar with 100% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Cells produce acid from glucose, mannose, galactose, fructose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose and salicin, but not from L-arabinose, D-xylose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, mannitol, sorbitol, inositol, erythritol, aesculin or amygdalin.</s><s>Cells show strong activity of leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, but do not show any activity of lipase (C4), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase or α-fucosidase.</s><s>Cell wall contains A4β-type peptidoglycan with an (L-Ala)-D-Glu-L-Orn-D-Asp peptide subunit, and interpeptide bridge consists only of D- Asp.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 61.2 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from human faeces.</s><s>Type strain is JCM 10641<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13279<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>