<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5853_nm.6569" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6569" rank="genus">Catellatospora</organism><reference id="rid.5853"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal to transfer Catellatospora ferruginea and 'Catellatospora ishikariense' to Asanoa gen. nov. as Asanoa ferruginea comb. nov. and Asanoa ishikariensis sp. nov., with emended description of the genus Catellatospora.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>967</fpage><lpage>972</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02011-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054264</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Catellatospora</i> Asano &#x0026; Kawamoto 1986</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Aerobic. Gram-positive. Catalase-positive. Urease-negative. Nitrate is reduced to nitrite. H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced. Mesophilic. Vegetative hyphae are branched but not fragmented. Bright yellow or creamy colony mass. Aerial mycelium is not formed. Chains of nonmotile spores arise singly or in tufts from vegetative hyphae on the surface of agar media. Globose bodies are produced in some species. Contains mesodiaminopimelic acid and 3-hydroxydiaminopimelic acid as diamino acids, a glycolylated peptidoglycan and whole-cell sugars of rhamnose, ribose, xylose, mannose and glucose. Arabinose and galactose are variable according to the species. The predominant menaquinones are tetra- and hexa-hydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units [MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>, H<sub>6</sub>)] or tetra-hydrogenated menaquinone with ten isoprene units [MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>)]. Phosphatidylethanolamine or phosphatidylmethylethanolamine is present as a diagnostic phospholipid. The fatty acid pattern is type 3b. Mycolic acids are absent. The G+C content of the DNA is 70.4-71.5 mol%. Members of this genus form a coherent group within the radiation of family <i>Micromonosporaceae</i> on the basis of 16S rDNA sequence data. The genus contains three species, <i>C. citrea</i> (with the subspecies <i>C. citrea</i> subsp. <i>citrea</i> and <i>C. citrea</i> subsp. <i>methionotrophica</i>), <i>C. koreensis</i> and <i>C. tsunoense</i>. The type species is <i>Catellatospora citrea</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>