<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2642_nm.11850" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11850" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11174" rank="species">Ectothiorhodosinus mongolicum</organism><reference id="rid.2642"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryantseva</surname><given-names>I.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Panteleeva</surname><given-names>E.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kolganova</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Makhneva</surname><given-names>Z.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moskalenko</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ectothiorhodosinus mongolicum gen. nov., sp. nov., a new purple bacterium from a soda lake in Mongolia.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>73</volume><fpage>66</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="168">Microbiology (Reading, England)</source><abbrev>Microbiology</abbrev><issn>1350-0872</issn><essn>1465-2080</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ectothiorhodosinus mongolicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ectothiorhodosinus mongolicum</i> (mon'go'l.i.cum. M.L. fem. adj. <i>mongolicum</i> related or belonging to Mongolia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are nonmotile, vibrio-shaped, semicircular, or toroid.</s><s>The cell size is 0.3–0.5 x 0.7–1 μm.</s><s>Cell division occurs by means of a nonuniformly ingrowing cellular septum.</s><s>The color of the cell suspension is pink to brownish red.</s><s>Cells contain bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids of the spirilloxanthin series.</s><s>The internal photosynthetic membranes have the form of concentric lamellae lining the cell wall.</s><s>In some of the cells, no lamellae or any other intracytoplasmic membranes can be revealed.</s><s>The size of the peripheral antenna of the pigment–protein complex is 2 or 3 times smaller (one LH1–RC ensemble per one LH2 complex) than in other species of purple bacteria.</s><s>Electron-dense polyphosphate inclusions are present in the cells.</s><s>Anaerobe.</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic growth occuring in the presence of sulfide is scarce.</s><s>Good growth under photolithoheterotrophic and photoorganoheterotrophic conditions.</s><s>Sulfide and thiosulfate are utilized as electron donors.</s><s>Globules of elemental sulfur are formed as an intermediate product of oxidation of reduced sulfur compounds and are deposited outside the cells.</s><s>The end oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and carbonates, acetate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, propionate, succinate, and fumarate are utilized as additional sources of carbon.</s><s>Alkaliphile, the pH optimum for growth is 8.3–9.1, and the growth range is 7.6–10.1.</s><s>Moderate halophile.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration in the medium is 1–7%; the growth range is 0.5–9%.</s><s>The optimal carbonate content is 2% (0.24 M); the growth range is 1–10% (0.1–1.2 M).</s><s>The temperature optimum for growth is 30–35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 57.5 mol % (Tm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat is near-shore sediments of subsaline soda lakes rich in organic matter and sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M9<sup>T</sup> isolated from a sample of decomposing near-shore algae driven by the wind to the shoreline of the steppe soda lake Lake Dzun Uldziin Nur in southeastern Mongolia.</s><s>Deposited with the German Culture Collection (DSMZ) under the number DSM 15479<sup>T</sup> and with the Collection of Unique Cultures, Institute of Microbiology, Russian Academy of Sciences (UNIQEM) under the number U217<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>