<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6233_nm.1905" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1905" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1905" rank="species">Methylovorus glucosotrophus</organism><reference id="rid.6233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Govorukhina</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylovorus, a new genus of restricted facultatively methylotrophic bacteria.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>158</fpage><lpage>162</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-158</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</i> (glu.cos.o.tro'hus. M.L. n. <i>glucosum</i>, glucose; Gr. adj. <i>troph-o</i>, pertaining to nutrition; M.L. adj. <i>glucosotrophus</i>, glucose consuming)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on studies of the type strain <i>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</i> 6B1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and general characteristics are as given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies on methanol-mineral salt agar are white or slightly colored.</s><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved rods, usually 1.0 to 1.3 μm in length and 0.5 to 0.6 μm in diameter, motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Growth is good at 25 to 45°C and pH 6.5 to 8.0, with optima at 35 to 37°C and pH 7.0 to 7.2.</s><s>Generation times when grown on methanol and glucose are 2 and 17 h, respectively.</s><s>No vitamins or any additional growth factors are required.</s><s>Methanol and glucose are used as the only carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The following compounds are used as nitrogen sources: ammonium salts, nitrates, methylamine, and peptone.</s><s>The strain assimilates methanol via the RUMP pathway.</s><s>Neither α-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase nor the glyoxylate shunt enzymes (isocitrate lyase and malate synthase) are present.</s><s>Ammonia is assimilated by the glutamate cycle; glutamate dehydrogenase is absent.</s><s>The major fatty acids are palmitic (C<sub>16:0</sub>) and palmitoleic (C<sub>16:1</sub>) acids.</s><s>The guanine + cytosine content of DNA is 55.8 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 6B1.</s><s>This strain was isolated from waste waters of Alma-Ata city (USSR).</s><s>It is deposited in All-Union Collection of Microorganisms as <i>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</i> B-1745.</s><s>This species also includes strains 6B2, 6a, F1, and 12.</s></p></content></protolog>