<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1537_nm.10292" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10292" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10292" rank="species">Loktanella koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.1537"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Loktanella koreensis sp. nov., isolated from sea sand in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2199</fpage><lpage>2202</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64276-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957121</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Loktanella koreensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Loktanella koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>koreensis</em> pertaining to Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming and short rod- to ovoid-shaped (0.5–0.8×0.8–1.5 μm).</s><s>Colonies are round, convex with a clear margin and light beige in colour after 2 days on MA plates.</s><s>Able to grow between 5 and 30 °C and at pH 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction and hydrogen sulfide production, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, glucose fermentation, indole production and Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Does not grow on nutrient agar, trypticase soy agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, weakly hydrolyses gelatin (prolonged incubation of more than 10 days), but does not hydrolyse agar, alginic acid, casein, chitin, carboxymethyl-cellulose, DNA, pectin, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine or urea.</s><s>With API 20NE and API 50CH strips, no growth is observed on carbohydrates and acids are not produced from any substrate.</s><s>Using API ZYM strips, alkaline phosphatase (weak), esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase (weak), cystine arylamidase (weak), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (weak), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (weak), <em>β</em>-galactosidase (weak) and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (weak) are detected, but lipase (C14), trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acid is 18 : 1 <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (approx. 67 %).</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GA2-M3<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11519<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17925<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sea sand taken from Homi cape, Pohang City, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain GA2-M3<sup>T</sup> is 60.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>