<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.422_nm.14073" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14073" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4080" rank="species">Caloramator viterbensis</organism><reference id="rid.422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seyfried</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lyon</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caloramator viterbensis sp. nov., a novel thermophilic, glycerol-fermenting bacterium isolated from a hot spring in Italy.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1177</fpage><lpage>1184</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01472-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148625</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Caloramator viterbensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Caloramator viterbensis</i> (vi.ter.ben'sis. L. masc. adj. <i>viterbensis</i> pertaining to <i>Viterbo</i> in Italy (ancient name Viterbium), the region from which the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods 0.4-0.6x2.0-3.0 μm in dimension.</s><s>Cells occur singly and stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Neither spores, heat-resistant (85 °C for 15 min) cells nor motility have been observed.</s><s>The temperature range for growth at pH 6.0 is 33-64 °C, the optimum at 58 °C.</s><s>The pH<sup>25C</sup> range for growth is 5.0-7.8, with an optimum at 6.0-6.5.</s><s>Growth is observed with glycerol, glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, sucrose, cellobiose, lactose, starch and yeast extract.</s><s>Xylose, arabinose, acetate, lactate, formate, methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, iso-propanol, n-butanol, propionate, acetone, succinate, ethylene glycol, 1,2-propanediol, phenol and benzoate are not fermented.</s><s>Various single amino acids (0.5%, w/v), with the exception of arginine, serve as carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>No growth occurs under autotrophic conditions in the presence of H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Fermentation of glycerol yields acetate and 1,3-propanediol as the only detectable organic products; significant amounts ofH<sub>2</sub> are produced during growth.</s><s>Glucose is mainly fermented to ethanol plus CO<sub>2</sub>, H<sub>2</sub> and acetate.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, rifampicin and kanamycin (100 lg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Addition of streptomycin and tetracycline of the same concentration results in retardation of growth.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 32 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from a hot spring at Bagnaccio (near Viterbo, Italy).</s><s>The type strain is JW/MS-VS5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13723<sup>T</sup>=ATCC PTA 584<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>