<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12486_nm.21321" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21321" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21321" rank="species">Sphaerotilus montanus</organism><reference id="rid.12486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gridneva</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chernousova</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dubinina</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Detkova</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grabovich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic investigation of representatives of the genus Sphaerotilus: descriptions of Sphaerotilus montanus sp. nov., Sphaerotilus hippei sp. nov., Sphaerotilus natans subsp. natans subsp. nov. and Sphaerotilus natans subsp. sulfidivorans subsp. nov., and an emended description of the genus Sphaerotilus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>916</fpage><lpage>925</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023887-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495027</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphaerotilus montanus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphaerotilus montanus</em> (mon.ta′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>montanus</em> referring to a mountain, pertaining to an iron spring, located in the foothills of the North Caucasus, Russia, the place from where the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 0.8–1.4×3.3–6.0 µm, arranged in chains within sheaths.</s><s>Gram-negative-staining.</s><s>The swarmers that are released from one of the ends of the filaments are motile by means of bundles of polar flagella.</s><s>Possess sheaths with encrustations of ferric oxides.</s><s>Filaments are not mobile.</s><s>Branching is absent.</s><s>Filaments may be attached by means of a holdfast to solid substrates.</s><s>Cells contain granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as a reserve material.</s><s>Colonies with fibrous edges are rusty yellow-coloured due to the deposition of ferric oxides and are 2–5 mm in size.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 7–36 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 28–30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5–8.5, with optimum growth at pH 7.5.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic; metabolism is respiratory and aerobic.</s><s>Lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, oxaloacetate, oxalate, 2-oxoglutarate, malate, malonate, citrate, benzoate, succinate, aconitate, glyoxylate; aspartate, glutamate, phenylalanine, tryptophan, proline, ornithine, alanine; glycerol, ethanol, butanol, propanol, mannitol, sorbitol; lactose, glucose, sorbose, mannose, sucrose, maltose, fructose, arabinose, peptone, yeast extract and casein hydrolysate are utilized as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acetate, formate, salicylate, glycolate, iso-citrate, iso-butanol, galactose, raffinose, cysteine, cystine, lysine, serine, methionine, histidine, asparagine, tyrosine and petroleum products are not utilized.</s><s>Peptone, yeast extract, aspartate, glutamate, cysteine, casein hydrolysate, ammonium and nitrate are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Methionine is not used as a nitrogen source.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Casein and starch are not hydrolysed; gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Nitrate and fumarate are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Indole is not formed.</s><s>No growth in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl is found.</s><s>Positive in tests for oxidase and catalase activities.</s><s>Pigments are not formed when the organism is grown on a medium containing aromatic amino acids.</s><s>Acids are not formed in the presence of sugars.</s><s>The major quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HS<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 21226<sup>T</sup> = VKM B-2519<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a ferrous iron-containing cold mountainous spring located in the foothills of the North Caucasus, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>