<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6726_nm.2967" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2967" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2967" rank="species">Vibrio fluvialis</organism><reference id="rid.6726"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shread</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Furniss</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy and description of Vibrio fluvialis sp. nov. (synonym group F vibrios, group EF6).</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6971864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio fluvialis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio fluvialis</i> (flu.vi.a'lis, L. adj. of or belonging to a river)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(synonyms group F Furniss et al. (1977), group EF6 Huq et al. (1980)l.</s><s>Gram negative short rods; axis straight or curved; sides usually parallel; ends rounded; occurring singly, in pairs and occasionally in short chains of three to four organisms; may be pleomorphic.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar sheathed flagellum in liquid media.</s><s>On solid media lateral, unsheathed flagella of shorter wave length may be produced.</s><s>Sodium chloride may be required for growth and the optimum concentration for growth is 1-3% (w/v).</s><s>Colonies on Heart Infusion Agar are opaque, shiny, smooth, round, domed, entire, may be mucoid and are 2-3 mm in diameter after 18 h at 30°C.</s><s>No pigments are produced.</s><s>Facultative anaerobe.</s><s>Metabolism of glucose is fermentative and gas may be produced.</s><s>Kovacs oxidase positive.</s><s>Reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Grow on simple mineral media on a variety of organic carbon sources.</s><s>The mol % G + C content of the DNA ranges from 49.3-50.6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species may be divided into biovars I and II.</s><s>The biochemical and physiological characteristics of the species, biovars, holotype and working type of biovar II are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Those characters particularly useful for the identification of the species and biovars are shown in Tables 4 and 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biovar I strains are widely distributed throughout the aquatic environment particularly in brackish and estuarine waters but other sources have included shellfish and sewage.</s><s>They may also be isolated from the faeces of humans suffering with diarrhoea but their enteropathogenicity has not been firmly established.</s><s>Biovar II strains occur in the same aquatic habitats as biovar I but unlike them they are rarely, if ever, isolated from human faeces, They have, however, been isolated from faeces of cattle, pigs and rabbits.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The holotype is VL 5125 (strain 30) which has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures as NCTC 11327.</s><s>We recommend VL 2386 (Strain 3) as a working type for biovar II and this has been acceded to the NCTC as NCTC 11328.</s><s>In addition we have deposited VL 2926 (strain 25), VL 5909 (strain 48) and VL 5975 (strain 49) under the numbers NCTC 11329, 11330 and 11331 respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>