<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9279_nm.14564" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14564" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14564" rank="species">Ideonella azotifigens</organism><reference id="rid.9279"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Noar</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buckley</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ideonella azotifigens sp. nov., an aerobic diazotroph of the Betaproteobacteria isolated from grass rhizosphere soil, and emended description of the genus Ideonella</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1941</fpage><lpage>1946</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003368-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567574</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ideonella azotifigens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ideonella azotifigens</em> [a.zo.ti.fi′gens. N.L. n. <em>azotum</em> (from french noun <em>azote</em>) nitrogen; L. v. <em>figere</em> to fix, attach; N.L. part. adj. <em>azotifigens</em> nitrogen-fixing].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-negative, rod-shaped, 0.5–1.0 μm in width and 2–6 μm in length and contain polyhydroxybutyrate-like granules when grown on dNfb media with mannitol.</s><s>Cells grown in nutrient broth are generally smaller (0.5×2.0 μm) and do not contain granules.</s><s>Able to fix nitrogen.</s><s>Colonies are 1 mm diameter, generally round, convex with entire margins, mucoid, shiny and cloudy to opaque when grown on N-free media with mannitol at 30 °C for 2 days.</s><s>Colonies continue to grow on prolonged incubation (1 week or more), spreading, merging together and producing prodigious amounts of slime which drips off the surface of inverted plates.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 35 °C, but not at temperatures higher than 35 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is between 6 and 7.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth and growth does not occur at NaCl concentrations of 0.5 % or greater.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and gelatinase and weakly catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not produce urease, arginine dihydrolase, indole or dihydroxyacetone.</s><s>Growth is strictly aerobic and neither chlorate nor nitrate can be reduced.</s><s>Compounds that can be used as sole carbon sources for growth include acetate, cellobiose, glucose, malate, mannitol, mannose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, but not cellulose or 2-hydroxyisobutyrate.</s><s>Amino acids that can be used as sole carbon sources for growth include glutamic acid, but not arginine or glycine.</s><s>Lipolytic against Tweens 20, 40, 60, 80 and 85.</s><s>Proteinolytic against casein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 1a22<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15503<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21438<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil in association with the rhizosphere of a perennial grass.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>