<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5484_nm.2499" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2499" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2499" rank="species">Halomonas canadensis</organism><reference id="rid.5484"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huval</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Latta</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kushner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vreeland</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of two new species of Halomonas: Halomonas israelensis sp.nov. and Halomonas canadensis sp.nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>1124</fpage><lpage>1131</lpage><source id="217">Canadian Journal of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Can J Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0008-4166</issn><essn>1480-3275</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8542554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas catadensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas catadensis</i> (cana.den.sis; pertaining to Canada)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the observations of Vreeland (1984) as amended by the data in this paper. <i>Halomonas catadensis</i> appears as straight or curved Gram-negative rods with rounded ends.</s><s>They divide by transverse fission, and occur singly, in pairs, or short chains.</s><s>Pleomorphic cells are not present.</s><s>Both culture age and NaCl concentration affect chain length.</s><s>Pleomorphic cells are not present.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>They are motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies formed on complex CAS medium with 8% NaCl 2-6 mm in diameter after 7 days at 30°C.</s><s>Colonies produce a nondiffusible white pigment.</s><s>The colonies are translucent and convex with a smooth glistening surface.</s><s>They grow from pH 5.0 to 9.0 in CAS medium with 8.0% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal temperature is 30°C and they are aerobic and halotolerant. <i>Halomonas canadensis</i> grows well from 3.0 to 25% NaCl and from 15 to 30°C.</s><s>It grows poorly below 1.0% NaCl and cannot grow without some NaCl added to its medium.</s><s>It grows in medium with 8 to 32% NaCl at 45°C and cannot grow below 5°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Halomonas canadensis</i> requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth and KCl Will not substitute for NaCl.</s><s>It is catalase positive and cytochrome oxidase negative, but Kovac's oxidase test may give a positive reaction.</s><s>It reduces NO<sub>3</sub> to NO<sub>2</sub> and produces indole.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are present.</s><s>This species is phenylalanin deaminase negative and grows throughout a thioglycollate tube supplemented with 8.0% NaCl.</s><s>The present strain is urease negative although the original isolate may have been urease postive (Vreeland 1984).</s><s>Cultures lyse in distilled water.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and acetylmethyl carbinol are not produced.</s><s>The addition of Ca<sup>+2</sup> to its medium is not required.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, starch and agar are not utilized.</s><s>It is insensitive to valinomycin, monensin, aphidicolin, penicillin G, ampicillin, streptomycin, vibriostat 0.129, and novoblocin (see Vreeland 1984),and is sensitive to chloramphenicol and oxytetracycline (see Vreeland 1984).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds have been found to serve as sole sources of carbon and energy in chemically defined media: acetate, citrate, DL-malate, succinate, lactate, glucose, xylose.</s><s>L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-mannitol, mesoinositol, ethanol, mannose, aesculin, glycerol, and gluconic acid.</s><s>In the present study, this bacterium utilized cellobiose, lactose, and sucrose, but these three sources were not used according to a previous description (Vreeland 1984).</s><s>This species cannot utilize butyrate, isobutyrate, propionate, tartarate, benzoate, maltose, melibiose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, ethylene glycol, <i>n</i>-hexadecane, pyridine-1-oxide, fonnaldehyde, formamide, N,N-dimethylacetamide, and ethylenediamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of this species is 57 ± 1 mol% (buoyant density) and 54-55 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s><s>The DNA shows 55% homology to <i>H. dongala</i> ATCC 33173<sup>T</sup>, 34% homology to <i>H. halodurans</i> ATCC 29686<sup>T</sup>, and 20% homology to <i>H. israelensis</i> ATCC 43985<sup>T</sup> when determined by the dot blot method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species has been isolated as a contaminant on Sehgal and Gibbons medium containing 25% NaCl (Mathesoo et al. 1976).</s><s>The type strain of this species is NRCC 41227<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 43984).</s></p></content></protolog>