<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2207_nm.2357" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2357" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2357" rank="species">Legionella gormanii</organism><reference id="rid.2207"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Morris</surname><given-names>G.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Feeley</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patton</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella gormanii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>718</fpage><lpage>721</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7276144</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella gormanii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella gormanii</i> (pronounced gor-mahń-ē) in honor of George W. Gorman, who isolated LS-13 and was a pioneer in the isolation of legionellae from environmental and clinical sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>An LLO isolate that is phenotypically similar to, but genetically distinct from, the four named species of <i>Legionella</i> has been reported and referred to as LS-13 (1, 5).</s><s>It was isolated from wet soil collected from a creek bank during an investigation of Legionnaires disease caused by <i>L. pneumophila</i> at a country club in Atlanta (4).</s><s>The method of isolation was similar to that previously described for isolating <i>L. pneumophila</i> from environmental samples (14).</s><s>The procedure involved the injection of a suspension of the soil in distilled water into two guinea pigs.</s><s>One of the two guinea pigs had a fever for 2 days and was killed and examined at that time.</s><s>The second guinea pig did not have a fever but was killed and examined at 7 days after injection.</s><s>Spleen tissue from each guinea pig was inoculated to Feeley-Gorman and charcoal yeast extract agars and injected into six embryonating eggs (6).</s><s>Embryos in the two eggs inoculated with spleen tissue from the first guinea pig died between 3 and 12 days.</s><s>The egg yolk sacs were harvested and cultured on Feeley-Gorman and charcoal yeast extract agar.</s><s>Embryos in eggs inoculated with tissue from the second guinea pig did not die. <i>Legionella</i>-like growth resulted on only one plate-charcoal yeast extract agar inoculated with egg yolk sac.</s><s>No growth was observed on any of the other plates inoculated with yolk sac or guinea pig spleen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic characteristics of LS-13 were compared with those of the four described <i>Legionella</i> species and found to be very similar to those of <i>L. dumoffii</i> and <i>L. bozemanii</i> in that LS-13 emitted a blue-white fluorescence on exposure to long-wavelength (366-μm) ultraviolet light and produced beta-lactamase (Table 1).</s><s>LS-13 differed in that it did not grow on Feeley-Gorman agar and it had serologically distinctive somatic antigens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain LS-13 was distinguishable by direct immunofluorescence from the other four species of <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>The LS-13 strain did not stain when reacted with hyperimmune fluorescein isothiocyanate-conjugated rabbit antisera prepared against all species of <i>Legionella</i>, including all serogroups of <i>L. pneumophila</i>.</s><s>However, a direct immunofluorescence conjugate prepared with antiserum against strain LS-13 reacted 4+ with the LS-13 strain but was nonreactive with isolates of <i>L. dumoffii</i>, <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. micdadei</i>, and <i>L. pneumophila</i> (all serogroups) at routine test dilution.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gas-liquid chromatographic analysis of the cellular fatty acids of strain LS-13 showed an abundance of branched-chain fatty acids similar to those of other legionellae.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile of LS-13 was similar to those of <i>L. bozemanii</i> and <i>L. dumoffii</i> in that the major acid was a-15:0 rather than i-16:0 as in L. pneumophila (5, 7, 10).</s><s>Unlike <i>L. micdadei</i>, LS-13 id not contain a-17:1 (5, 9, 15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Relatedness among strain LS-13 and species of <i>Legionella</i> was determined by deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) hybridization.</s><s>Sheared, denatured, in vitro <sup>3</sup>H-labeled DNA from <i>L. pneumophila</i> strain Philadelphia 1, <i>L. bozemanii</i> strain WIGA, <i>L. micdadei</i> strain TATLOCK, and <i>L. dumoffii</i> strain NY-23 was reacted with similarly treated unlabeled DNA from a series of <i>Legionella</i> strains under conditions that allow DNA reassociation (Table 2).</s><s>Regardless of whether LS-13 DNA or DNA from another <i>Legionella</i> species was labeled, LS-13 was '33% related to other legionellae.</s><s>This level of relatedness is far below the 70% or more seen between strains of the same species.</s><s>Thus, LS-13 does not belong to any of the previously described</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Legionella</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We have collected evidence of infection with strain LS-13 in both humans and experimental animals.</s><s>During a retrospective medical record review of patients in Connecticut who had a clinical syndrome compatible with Legionnaires disease, a formalinized autopsy lung specimen from a 69-year-old man who died with pneumonia in 1978 revealed typical cells with a 4+ fluorescence to a conjugate prepared with antiserum to LS-13.</s><s>There were no detectable reactions to conjugates against <i>L. pneumophila</i> serogroups 1 to 6, <i>L. bozemanii</i> (WIGA), <i>L. micdadei</i> (TATLOCK), or <i>L. dumoffii</i> (NY-23).</s><s>Paired sera from three patients analyzed at the Bacterial Immunology Branch at the Center for Disease Control by the indirect fluorescent antibody test for Legionella have shown a ≥4-fold rise to LS-13, but were negative for the other <i>Legionella</i> species (H.</s><s>Wilkinson, personal communications).</s><s>Evidence of infection in guinea pigs is that the guinea pigs yielding the isolate of LS-13 had a disease resulting in fever for 2 days before autopsy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>These data indicate that LS-13 is closely related to the other four species of <i>Legionella</i> on the basis of growth characteristics, biochemical reactions, and gas-liquid chromatography profile.</s><s>It shows DNA relatedness to other legionellae but is distinct from all named species.</s><s>Despite the fact that the only strain isolated thus far was from the environment, it is likely that this organism is responsible for human legionellosis.</s></p></content></protolog>