<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9707_nm.14857" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14857" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14857" rank="species">Methylophilus rhizosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.9707"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sa</surname><given-names>T.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylophilus rhizosphaerae sp. nov., a restricted facultative methylotroph isolated from rice rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2904</fpage><lpage>2908</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009811-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628595</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylophilus rhizosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylophilus rhizosphaerae</em> (rhi.zo′spha.e′rae. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhiza</em> root; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> -<em>ae</em> ball, any globe, sphere; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>rhizosphaerae</em> of the rhizosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-endospore forming, strictly aerobic, motile rods (0.5–1.2×0.25–0.3 μm), occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, and translucent with regular edges, slow-growing and 0.3–0.6 mm in diameter after 96 h at 28 °C on AMS.</s><s>Growth occurs on NA supplemented with 1 % methanol, R2A, NFb medium (Baldani &#x0026; Döbereiner, 1980) with 1 g ammonium chloride l<sup>−1</sup> as combined nitrogen source, and Colby and Zathman medium (Colby &#x0026; Zatman, 1973) supplemented with 0.2 % methanol and 2 % MH medium.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 2.0 % NaCl or higher.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C (optimum, 28 °C) and pH 4.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.8).</s><s>Does not grow at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase and urease are positive.</s><s>Pectinase, cellulase, protease, arginine dihydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and indole production are positive.</s><s>Starch, glycerol tributyrate, casein and aesculin are not hydrolysed; hydrolysis of gelatin is weak.</s><s>Methanol, dichloromethane, ethanol, trimethylamine, methylamine, succinate and diethanolamine are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride, potassium nitrate, 1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate, l-alanine, l-glutamine, glycine, urea, methylamine, potassium thiocyanate and trimethylamine are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as nitrogen sources: l-glutamate, potassium cyanate, l-tryptophan, l-aspartic acid, diethylamine and diphenylamine.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, d-fructose, formic acid and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>In the API 20NE and API 32GN tests, no single carbon/nitrogen source was assimilated.</s><s>In API ZYM assays, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), trypsin, acid phosphatase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and summed feature 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CBMB127<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 13099<sup>T</sup>=NCCB 100233<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from rhizosphere soil of rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L. cv O-dae) collected at the vegetative stage (V10) of the plant.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.9 mol%.</s><s>Strain CBMB145 is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>