<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12101_nm.20091" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20091" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20091" rank="species">Paenibacillus prosopidis</organism><reference id="rid.12101"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Valverde</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fterich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahdhi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramírez-Bahena</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caviedes</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mars</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Llorente</surname><given-names>I.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus prosopidis sp. nov., isolated from the
nodules of Prosopis farcta</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2182</fpage><lpage>2186</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014241-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897617</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus prosopidis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus prosopidis</em> (pro.so′pi.dis. L. n. <em>prosopis</em> name of a plant, and also a botanical genus name; L. gen. n. <em>prosopidis</em> of <em>Prosopis</em>, isolated from <em>Prosopis farcta</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-variable and motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Round, terminal spores are formed in slightly or non-swollen sporangia.</s><s>Catalase-positive and weakly oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar medium are white–cream, round, smooth and convex with approximate diameters of 1–3 mm.</s><s>The major quinone is MK-7 and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid is not detected in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The lipid profile consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, a glycolipid, six phospholipids, an unidentified lipid, and two unknown aminophosphoglycolipids.</s><s>The main fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is negative.</s><s>Does not grow at pH 5.7 or at pH 9.</s><s>Grows between pH 6.5 and 8 (optimal pH 7).</s><s>Grows in the presence of 2 % NaCl but not 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 37 °C but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth at 40 °C is weak.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase but does not produce indole, phenylalanine deaminase, urease, arginine dehydrolase, ornithine or lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Acetoin production is weak.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not gelatin in API20NE and API20E, respectively.</s><s>Hydrolyses cellulose, starch and xylan but not casein.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, assimilation of glucose, l-arabinose, mannitol, maltose, gluconate and malate is positive and that of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, citrate, adipate, l-malate and phenylacetate is negative.</s><s>Assimilation of mannose is weakly positive.</s><s>Acid, but not gas, is produced from glucose.</s><s>In API 50CH, acid production from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, glucose, dulcitol, sorbitol, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose and amygdalin is positive.</s><s>Acid production from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, l-lyxose, tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabinitol and l-arabinitol is negative.</s><s>Acid production from mannose, fructose and glycogen is weakly positive.</s><s>Hydrolysis of arbutin and aesculin is positive.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PW21<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25259<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7506<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22405<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the nodules of <em>Prosopis farcta</em> in Tunisia.</s></p></content></protolog>