<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4455_nm.7870" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7870" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7870" rank="species">Treponema parvum</organism><reference id="rid.4455"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wyss</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gmür</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thurnheer</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüpbach</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guggenheim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema parvum sp. nov., a small, glucoronic or galacturonic acid-dependent oral spirochaete from lesions of human periodontitis and acute necrotizing ulcerative gingivitis.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>955</fpage><lpage>962</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411720</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema parvum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema parvum</i> (par.vum. L. neut. adj. <i>parvum</i> small)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small, obligately anaerobic, helically coiled, motile treponeme.</s><s>The cells are approximately 1 μm long and 0.18 μm wide, with a wavelength of 0.8 μm and an amplitude of 0.3 μm.</s><s>In rapidly growing cultures cells may be shorter than 1 wavelength but chains of more than 10 wavelengths are also common.</s><s>Cells contain two periplasmic flagella, one originating at each pole, which overlap in the central region of the cell.</s><s>In liquid medium undulation, flexing and rotation of cells does not appear to result in directional motility.</s><s>However, in media of higher viscosity or when cells creep along a surface translational movement is readily detectable.</s><s>Cells can be stored frozen (liquid nitrogen or mechanical freezer) in OMIZ-Pat/HuS medium supplemented with 10-20% glycerol.</s><s>The four isolates OMZ 832, 833<sup>T</sup>, 842 and 843 are strictly carbohydratedependent; either GluA or GalA is sufficient for growth, though growth is strongly promoted by addition of any one of the following: L-arabinose, dgalactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, pectin, D-ribose or D-xylose.</s><s>No growth-stimulating effect was seen with D-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucuronic acid, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, D-sucrose, D-trehalose nor L-xylose.</s><s>The chemically complex (undefined) components of OMIZ-Pat, i.e. YEM (fractionated yeast extract) and DANP (fractionated peptone) (Wyss &#x0026; Ermert, 1996), are not strictly required for growth but are strongly stimulatory.</s><s>Similarly, human serum or FBS are not required but are growth-promoting at 1% (v/v).</s><s>FBS is not inhibitory even at 10% (v/v).</s><s>On OMIZPat/HuS agarose <i>T. parvum</i> forms off-white diffuse subsurface colonies up to 3 mm in diameter after 5 d of anaerobic incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>The four OMZ isolates showed uniform reaction in ApiZym tests with weak activities of alkaline phosphatase and esterase C4 and C8, intermediate activities of acid phosphatase and naphthol phosphohydrolase and strong activity of β-glucuronidase.</s><s>The type strain, OMZ 833<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from subgingival plaque of a human deep periodontal lesion and has been deposited at the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC), Manassas, VA, under the accession number ATCC 700770<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Strain OMZ 842, isolated from a Chinese ANUG lesions patient, has been deposited at the ATCC under the accession number ATCC 700773 as a reference strain for a serotype distinct fromOMZ 833<sup>T</sup> (no reactivity with mAb 465TP1).</s></p></content></protolog>