<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2954_nm.5556" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5556" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5556" rank="species">Atopobacter phocae</organism><reference id="rid.2954"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Atopobacter phocae gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel bacterium isolated from common seals.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1755</fpage><lpage>1760</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Atopobacter phocae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Atopobacter phocae</i> (pho'cae. N.L. gen. n. <i>phocae</i> of or pertaining to the common seal <i>Phoca vitulina</i>, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On blood agar cells are short, irregular rods that form small, smooth, grey, pin-sized colonies after 24 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Haemolysis is not observed.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Growth is observed at 25 but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, acid is produced from cyclodextrin, glucose, glycogen, maltose, pullulan and ribose, but not from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, raffinose, sorbitol, tagatose and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid from lactose, sucrose and trehalose may or may not be produced.</s><s>Activity for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase C-4 (weak reaction), ester lipase C-8 (weak reaction), pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (weak reaction), pyrazinamidase (weak reaction) and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase is detected.</s><s>No activity for N-acetylglucosamidase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycine tryptophan arylamidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C-14, trypsin or valine arylamidase is detected.</s><s>Activity for β-galactosidase may or may not be detected and β-galacturonidase activity is either weak or negative.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, hippurate and urease are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The cell wall contains an L-Orn-D-Asp-based murein (type A4β).</s><s>Isolated from dead common seals.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 42358<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106392<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>