<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5271_nm.5985" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5985" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5985" rank="species">Brachybacterium nesterenkovii</organism><reference id="rid.5271"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gvozdyak</surname><given-names>O.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogina</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of the genus Brachybacterium: Brachybacterium nesterenkovii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>74</fpage><lpage>78</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-1-74</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1736971</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachybacterium nesterenkovii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachybacterium nesterenkovii</i> (nes. te. ren. ko' vi.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>nesterenkovii</i>, of Nesterenko, named for O. A. Nesterenko, a Ukrainian microbiologist who has made a valuable contribution to the systematics of coryneform and nocardioform bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the stationary growth phase cells are coccoid (diameter, 0.5 to 1 μm).</s><s>During the logarithmic growth phase the cells are coccoid, oval, angular, and short rods that vary in size from strain to strain (up to 2 μm long).</s><s>V-shaped cells are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are matte and convex with regular edges; their surfaces are usually smooth but may be rough.</s><s>The colony diameter on BEA is up to 1.5 mm (rarely, 3 mm).</s><s>The color of the colonies is lemon yellow on BEA and milk agar and pale greyish white on glucose-asparagine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures grow well on BEA and somewhat poorly on milk agar, and growth is weak on glucose-asparagine agar.</s><s>When cultures are grown in peptone broth, the medium remains transparent or becomes translucent, and some flocculent sediment is formed.</s><s>A growth ring usually is not observed.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Gram positive, not acid fast, nonmotile, and nonsporeforming.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows well at 18 to 37°C.</s><s>Grows on medium containing 20 μg of furazolidone per ml and forms acid from glycerol in the presence of erythromycin.</s><s>Does not grow on Simmons citrate agar.</s><s>Does not tolerate NaCl; grows well in the presence of 0 to 0.5% NaCl and weakly in the presence of 5% NaCl and does not grow in the presence of 7.5% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced aerobically from ribose, galactose, glucose, fructose, maltose, sucrose, and glycerol.</s><s>Erythrose, arabinose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, and sorbitol are not attacked.</s><s>Variable results are observed for acid formation from xylose, mannose, D-melibiose, salicin, and starch.</s><s>Utilizes tartrate, oxaloacetate, and maleate.</s><s>Some strains poorly utilize acetate, lactate, pyruvate, and succinate.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase negative and negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Ammonia production from arginine is detected 21 days after inoculation.</s><s>Hydrolyzes esculin and starch but not tyrosine, gelatin, xanthine, hypoxanthine, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, and urea.</s><s>Lecithinase, hydrogen sulfide, and acetoin negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, oxacillin, methicillin, carbenicillin, benzylpenicillin, streptomycin, neomycin, kanamycin, erythromycin, oleandomycin, rifampin, lincomycin, ristomycin, tetracycline, and chloramphenicol.</s><s>Not susceptible to polymyxin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan has <i>meso</i>-DAP, alanine, and glutamic acid (1:2:3).</s><s>There are significant amounts of glucose, galactose, and rhamnose in the cells.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The main fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from milk and milk products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>B. nesterenkovii</i> is strain 35 (= IMV Ac-752).</s></p></content></protolog>