<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8245_nm.13598" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13598" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13598" rank="species">Salinibacterium xinjiangense</organism><reference id="rid.8245"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinibacterium xinjiangense sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from the China No. 1 glacier.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2739</fpage><lpage>2742</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65802-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060050</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinibacterium xinjiangense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinibacterium xinjiangense</em> (xin.jiang.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>xinjiangense</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, psychrophilic, irregular rods, non-spore-forming, non-flagellated and non-gliding, 1.4–2.3 μm long and 0.5–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, smooth, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 4–23 °C and pH 5.0–9.0, with optimum growth at 18–19 °C and approximately pH 6.0–8.0.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–14 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch and Tweens 20, 60 and 80, but not gelatin or casein.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, indole production, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin, urease, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Tests for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase are positive.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: sucrose, glucose, cellobiose, d-mannose, melibiose, maltose, galactose, arabinose and fructose.</s><s>Acids are produced from glucose, fructose, d-mannose and galactose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: melezitose, erythritol, sorbose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, tartrate, pyruvate, fumarate, succinate, hippurate and uric acid.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-10, followed by a smaller amount of MK-11.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains ornithine and lysine as diamino acids, along with alanine, glycine and glutamic acid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 0543<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.5381<sup>T</sup> =JCM 13926<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the China No. 1 glacier (Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region).</s></p></content></protolog>