<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9094_nm.14282" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14282" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14282" rank="species">Lysobacter panaciterrae</organism><reference id="rid.9094"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter panaciterrae sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>958</fpage><lpage>963</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002394-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406775</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter panaciterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter panaciterrae</em> (pa.na.ci.ter′rae. N.L. n. <em>Panax -acis</em> scientific name for ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panaciterrae</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar plates for 3 days are 1.5–3.0 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, non-glossy and cream-coloured, but take on a weak brownish yellow swarming form after 1 month.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.0–8.5, with an optimum between pH 6.5 and 7.0.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse gelatin and casein, but not chitin, starch, cellulose, xylan, lipids or DNA.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite and nitrite is not reduced to nitrogen gas.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-mannose, d-lyxose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, aesculin, acetate, caprate, citrate, formate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, malate, pyruvate, succinate, valerate, glycogen, l-aspartate, l-glutamine and l-tyrosine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: l-fructose, d- and l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-xylose, salicin, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, amygdalin, inulin, dextran, propionate, maleate, fumarate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, lactate, malonate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, gluconate, dulcitol, inositol, d-adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methanol, ethanol, glycerol, urea, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-glutamate, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>Positive for tryptophan deaminase and the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Production of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, hydrogen sulfide and indole is negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, but not from melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the predominant quinone.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol are the main polar lipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 67.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 068<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12601<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17927<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>