<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.274_nm.5725" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5725" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5725" rank="species">Rubrobacter xylanophilus</organism><reference id="rid.274"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carreto</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wait</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riley</surname><given-names>P.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sharp</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rubrobacter xylanophilus sp. nov., a new thermophilic species isolated from a thermally polluted effluent.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>460</fpage><lpage>465</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rubrobacter xylanophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rubrobacter xylanophilus</i> (xy. la. no' phi. lus. Gr. n. <i>xylon</i>, wood; M. L. n. <i>xylanum</i>, xylan; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, liking, friendly to; M. L. adj. <i>xylanophilus</i>, liking xylan)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. xylanophilus</i> forms pleomorphic short rod-shaped cells that are 0.9 to 1.0 μm wide and 1.0 to 3.0 μm long; coccoid cells are also present.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Colonies on <i>Thermus</i> medium incubated at 60°C for 7 days are 1.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, circular, convex, smooth, opaque, and light pink.</s><s>Motility and endospores are not observed.</s><s>Strain PRD-1<sup>T</sup> is aerobic, and no growth occurs under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth occurs in basal salts medium containing (NH<sub>4</sub>), SO<sub>2</sub> and an appropriate carbon source.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 60°C; no growth occurs at temperatures below 40°C or above 70°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.5 to 8.0; growth does not occur at pH values below 6.0 or above 10.0.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase, catalase, and β-galactosidase are present.</s><s>Xylan is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Non-fermentative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs in <i>Thermus</i> medium containing 6.0% NaCl.</s><s>Gelatin, hide powder azure, arbutin, esculin, and hippurate are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Growth occurs on many common sugars, organic acids, and amino acids.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is menaquinone 8, and the major fatty acid is 14-methyl-18:O.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is type A3α.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67.6 mol%.</s><s>The natural habitat of <i>R. xylanophilus</i> is not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain PRD-1 has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 9941.</s></p></content></protolog>