<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6803_nm.9233" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9233" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9233" rank="species">Vibrio rotiferianus</organism><reference id="rid.6803"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomez-Gil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio rotiferianus sp. nov., isolated from cultures of the rotifer Brachionus plicatilis.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>239</fpage><lpage>243</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02430-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656179</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio rotiferianus</em> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio rotiferianus</em> (ro.ti.fer.i.a′nus. English n. <em>rotifer</em>; L. masc. suff. <em>-ianus</em> pertaining to; N.L. masc. adj. <em>rotiferianus</em> pertaining to rotifers).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative curved rods (0·8–1·2×2·0–3·5 μm), facultative anaerobic, motile by means of more than one polar flagella.</s><s>Non-pigmented, translucent, non-luminescent colonies on marine agar with no swarming.</s><s>Bright, round, 2–3 mm yellow colonies, with umbilicated growth in TCBS agar.</s><s>No growth occurs without NaCl ions in the culture medium; growth occurs in the presence of 1·5, 3·0 and 6·0 % NaCl (w/v), but not at 8 or 10 %; grows at 28–40 °C, but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), oxolinic acid (2 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), and to the vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10 and 150 μg; resistant to kanamycin (30 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and gentamicin (10 μg).</s><s>Arginine-dihydrolase-negative, lysine- and ornithine-decarboxylase-positive, ferments glucose without producing gas; positive for indole, oxidase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and gelatinase.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-, H<sub>2</sub>S- and citrate-negative.</s><s>Phenotypic differences are observed between the strains (Table 2).</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon source: alaninamide, α-cyclodextrin, α-d-glucose, methyl β-d-glucoside, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-serine, d-trehalose, gentiobiose, glucose 6-phosphate, glycogen, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, inosine, l-alanine (LMG 21460<sup>T</sup> and LMG 21458 weakly positive), l-alanine-glycine (LMG 21460<sup>T</sup> and LMG 21458 weakly positive), l-arabinose, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-serine, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, psicose, sucrose, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>None of the strains utilizes the following carbon sources: 2,3-butanediol, 2-aminoethanol, acetic acid, adonitol, α-d-lactose lactulose, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, dl-carnitine, d-alanine, d-arabitol, d-galactonic acidolactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-mannitol, d-saccharic acid, d-sorbitol, formic acid, γ-aminobutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucuronamide, glycerol, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-hydroxyproline, i-erythritol, itaconic acid, l-fucose, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenyl alanine, l-proline, l-pyro glutamic acid, l-rhamnose, malonic acid, methyl pyruvate, <em>meso</em>-inositol, monomethyl succinate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, phenyl ethylamine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, propionic acid, putrescine, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, turanose, Tween 40, Tween 80, urocanic acid or xylitol.</s><s>All are weakly positive for dl-lactic acid (except LMG 21457, positive).</s><s>All strains have activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterease (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>None showed activity of lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The following cellular fatty acids are present in descending order (mean percentage of the five strains analysed; maximum, minimum of the total fatty acid content): 16 : 0 (25·40; 28·47, 21·18), 18 : 1ω7<em>c</em> (10·79; 12·34, 9·13), 14 : 0 (9·52; 10·31, 8·89), 12 : 0 3-OH (2·91; 3·84, 2·33), 18 : 0 (1·10; 1·35, 0·75).</s><s>Undefined fatty acids are also observed, summed feature 3 (16 : 1ω7<em>c</em> and/or 15 iso 2-OH – 37·14; 39·77, 34·79), summed feature 2 (14 : 0 3-OH and/or 16 : 1 iso I – 7·05; 8·65, 5·98) and one unknown (0·74; 0·98, 5·98).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44·5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 21460<sup>T</sup> (=CAIM 577<sup>T</sup>), reference strains are LMG 21456, LMG 21457, LMG 21458 and LMG 21459; isolated from a rotifer (<em>Brachionus plicatilis</em>) flow-through culture system.</s></p></content></protolog>