<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11585_nm.18620" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18620" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18620" rank="species">Lentibacillus jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.11585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lentibacillus jeotgali sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from traditional Korean fermented seafood</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1017</fpage><lpage>1022</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013565-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666788</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lentibacillus jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lentibacillus jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-flagellated, Gram-positive, strictly aerobic rods and approximately 0.5–1.0 μm wide and 2.0–4.0 μm in length.</s><s>Single, terminal, spherical endospores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>The colonies are opaque ivory, smooth, circular, raised and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after cultivation at 37 °C for 3 days on MA supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs in 3–20 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 10–15 %), at temperatures ranging from 10 to 45 °C (optimum 37 °C), and in the pH range 6.0–8.0 (optimum pH 8.0).</s><s>The isolate is catalase-positive, but oxidase- and urease-negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not gelatin, arginine, casein, Tween 80, starch, DNA, tyrosine, cellulose, xanthine or hypoxanthine.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, arbutin, aesculin, maltose, inulin, glycogen and 2-ketogluconate, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, salicin, cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (36.4 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (30.3 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (18.2 %).</s><s>The major cellular polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid of the cell wall is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The G+C content is 42.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Grbi<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13300<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15795<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s></p></content></protolog>