<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.13153_nm.1581" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1581" rank="genus">Methylobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.13153"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoppe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium bullatum sp. nov., a methylotrophic bacterium isolated from Funaria hygrometrica</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>34</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>482</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.12.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21612883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium bullatum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0100"&#x003E;<em>Methylobacterium bullatum</em> (F3.2<sup>T</sup>) (=DSM 21893<sup>T</sup> = LMG 24788<sup>T</sup>) (bul.la’tum. L. neut. adj. bullatum, furnished with a boss or stud, equipped with an adorned surface) was isolated from <em>Funaria hygrometrica</em>. The type strain is <em>Methylobacterium bullatum</em> (F3.2) (=DSM 21893<sup>T</sup> = LMG 24788<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0105"&#x003E;Cells of <em>Methylobacterium bullatum</em> sp. nov. are Gram-stain-negative rods (0.6–1.3 μm × 1.3–3.3 μm), rarely branched or pleomorphic, occurring singly, in pairs or in aggregates.</s><s>They are motile by a polar to subpolar flagellum in the liquid phase of the medium.</s><s>They always contain polyhydroxybutyrate granules (PHB) and sometimes polyphosphate granules <a href="#bib0120">[24]</a>.</s><s>They are strictly aerobic, catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0110"&#x003E;Cells of this species show a polymorphic cell surface with short appendages.</s><s>Colonies grown on GP agar for seven days are about 1.8 mm in diameter.</s><s>They could be described as smooth, circular, regular-edged, shiny and red coloured.</s><s>The red pigment of the cells is water-insoluble.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–33 °C (optimum at 28 °C).</s><s>There exists a pH tolerance at 5.5–8.0 (optimum: 6.5–7.0 at 28 °C) and a NaCl-tolerance of 0.6%.</s><s>Cells of this species are biofilm-producers.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced and nitrate is reduced neither to nitrite nor to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Urease activity is positive, but β-galactosidase, l-arginin dihydrolase and β-glucosidase activity are not apparent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0115"&#x003E;Starch, gelatine and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Strain F3.2<sup>T</sup> produces the hormone auxin (IAA) and siderophores.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, ammonium sulfate, potassium nitrate, sodium nitrate, glutamate and urea are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0120"&#x003E;The major cellular fatty acids of <em>M. bullatum</em> sp. nov. are C<sub>18:1</sub><em>ω</em>7c (81.7%) and summed feature C<sub>16:1</sub><em>ω</em>7c and/or iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>2OH (11.7%) (<a href="#tbl0005">Table 1</a>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0125"&#x003E;Strain F3.2<sup>T</sup> produces acid from glycerol, d-arabinose and d-fructose but not from d-glucose, saccharose, lactose, maltose, d-xylose, ammonium acetate, sodium citrate (variable) and sodium glutamate glycerol (variable).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0130"&#x003E;Different compounds serving as the sole carbon and energy sources were tested and the results are shown in <a href="#sec0035">Table S2</a>, also with the remaining carbon sources of the API 50CH test stripes.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 67.1 mol%.</s><s>F3.2<sup>T</sup> contains a cryptic plasmid with a size of 43 ± 1 kb, designated pFL110.</s></p></content></protolog>