<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2408_nm.11273" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11273" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11273" rank="species">Sediminitomix flava</organism><reference id="rid.2408"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sediminitomix flava gen. nov., sp. nov., of the phylum Bacteroidetes, isolated from marine sediment</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1689</fpage><lpage>1693</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64854-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684238</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sediminitomix flava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sediminitomix flava</em> (fla.va. L. fem. adj. <em>flava</em> reddish yellow, the colour of the colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are large and orange-coloured with non-entire margins on HSMA plates.</s><s>The colour of the colonies is due to saproxanthin.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C and is optimal at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 2–4 % (w/v) NaCl and weakly at 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for the degradation of starch, gelatin, DNA, aesculin, alginate, Tweens 20, 40 and 80 and for the production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Weakly positive result in tests for the degradation of agar.</s><s>Negative in tests for the degradation of cellulose, CM-cellulose, chitin, carrageenan, urea and for indole production.</s><s>Grows on 1 % (w/v) peptone agar prepared with artificial seawater, but does not grow on 1 % (w/v) tryptic soya agar prepared with artificial seawater or on casein plates [0.2 % (w/v) Bacto tryptone, 0.1 % (w/v) Bacto yeast extract, 1.2 % (w/v) casein and 1.5 % (w/v) agar dissolved in artificial seawater].</s><s>Sensitive to treatment at 55 °C for 10 min.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrite is not reduced to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Positive result in tests for <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Positive result for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities in the API ZYM test.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-xylose, galactose, glucose, amygdalin, aesculin, cellobiose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and 2-ketogluconate in API 50CH tests.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Mok-1-85<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 101625<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12970<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109411<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediment from Okinawa Island, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>