<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5744_nm.1773" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1773" rank="family">Comamonadaceae</organism><reference id="rid.5744"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comamonadaceae, a new family encompassing the acidovorans rRNA complex, including Variovorax paradoxus gen. nov., comb. nov., for Alcaligenes paradoxus (Davis 1969).</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>445</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-445</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Comamonadaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Comamonadaceae</i> (Co.ma.mo.na.da'ce.ae. M . L. fem. n. <i>Comamonas</i>, type genus of the family; -<i>aceae</i>, suffix to denote family; M. L. fem. pl. n. <i>Comamonadaceae</i>, <i>Comamonas</i> family)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved rods or spirilla.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Mostly motile by means of either one polar flagellum, bipolar tufts of one to five flagella, or degenerate peritrichous flagella.</s><s>No endospores or microcysts are formed.</s><s>Coccoid bodies are rarely formed in some [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] species.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic or chemolithotrophic at the expense of H<sub>2</sub> or CO oxidation.</s><s>Oxidative metabolism, using oxygen as a terminal electron acceptor; some species can also use nitrates.</s><s>Oxidase positive, except for members of the genus <i>Xylophilus</i>.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature ranges from 28 to 30°C, except for <i>Xylophilus</i> spp. and [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>psychrophilum</i>, which grow best at 24 and 18°C, respectively.</s><s>Yellow insoluble pigments are produced by <i>Xylophilus</i>, <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, and <i>Variovorax</i> strains.</s><s>Nitrogen fixation has been described for some <i>Hydrogenophaga</i> strains (20).</s><s>Generally, these organisms use only very few carbohydrates, but they use a wide variety of organic acids, including amino acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are palmitoleic acid (16:1), palmitic acid (16:0), and <i>cis</i>-vaccenic acid (∆11-18:1).</s><s>The mean G+C contents of the DNAs range from 57 to 70 mol%.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from soil, water in natural and industrial environments, clinical samples, and infected plant material.</s><s>No pathogenic effects have been reported for the strains isolated from clinical samples (genera <i>Comamonas</i> and <i>Acidovorax</i>).</s><s>Members of the genus <i>Xylophilus</i> are pathogenic for grapevines, and the strains belonging to the [<i>P.</i>] <i>avenae</i> rRNA branch are pathogenic for various grasses, orchids, or members of the family Cucurbitaceae.</s><s>The family <i>Comamonadaceae</i> belongs to rRNA superfamily III or the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Strains belonging to this family have <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> values of at least 75°C versus rRNA from <i>C. acidovorans</i> Stanier 14<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>All strains group within a ∆<i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> range of 5°C.</s><s>The type genus is <i>Comamonas</i> (De Vos et al. 1985) Tamaoka et al. 1987.</s><s>The following other taxa belong to the <i>Comamonadaceae</i>: the genera <i>Acidovorax</i>, <i>Variovorax</i>, <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, and <i>Xylophilus</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>anulus</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>delicatum</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>giesbergeri</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>gracile</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>metamorphum</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>]  <i>sinuosum</i>, [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] <i>psychrophilum</i>, and the [<i>P.</i>] <i>avenae</i> rRNA branch, which contains [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>cattleyae</i>, "[<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>setariae</i>," [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>rubrilineans</i>, [<i>Pseudomonas pseudoalcaligenes</i>] subsp. <i>citrulli</i>, and [<i>Pseudomonus pseudoalcaligenes</i>] subsp. <i>konjaci</i>.</s><s>Differentiating features have been described previously (36).</s><s>A key for the differentiation of the different groups in the <i>Comamona daceae</i> is presented below:</s></p><p class="description"><s>I.</s><s>Not maintainable on nutrient agar (36)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A.</s><s>Yellow pigmented, very slow growth in general and oxidase absent: <i>Xylophilus</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>B.</s><s>Unpigmented, oxidase present: [<i>Aquaspirillum</i>] species (see above)</s></p><p class="description"><s>II.</s><s>Good growth on nutrient agar</s></p><p class="description"><s>A.</s><s>Yellow pigmented and usually capable of chemolithotrophic growth with hydrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>1.</s><s>Grows with L-arabitol, mesaconate, and citrate as sole carbon sources: <i>Variovorax</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>2.</s><s>Does not use L-arabitol, mesaconate, and citrate as sole carbon sources: <i>Hydrogenophaga</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>B.</s><s>Unpigmented, no chemolithotrophic growth with hydrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>1.</s><s>Bipolar tufts of flagella, does not grow with D-glucose as a sole carbon source: <i>Comamonas</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>2.</s><s>One polar flagellum, grows with D-glucose as a sole carbon source</s></p><p class="description"><s>a.</s><s>Isolated from infected plant material: [<i>P.</i>] <i>avenue</i> rRNA branch (see above)</s></p><p class="description"><s>b.</s><s>Not isolated from infected plant material: <i>Acidovorax</i></s></p></content></protolog>