<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4390_nm.2608" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2608" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2608" rank="species">Pseudomonas frederiksbergensis</organism><reference id="rid.4390"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnsen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sørensen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jacobsen</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas frederiksbergensis sp. nov., isolated from soil at a coal gasification site.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1957</fpage><lpage>1964</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155968</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas frederiksbergensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas frederiksbergensis</i> (fre.de.riks.ber.gen'sis. M.L. adj. <i>frederiksbergensis</i> pertaining to Frederiksberg near Copenhagen, Denmark, from where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, non-spore-forming rods of approximately 0.5-0.8x1.5-3.0 μm.</s><s>A transmission electron micrograph is shown in Fig. 2.</s><s>Colonies are smooth and pale yellowish on LB agar.</s><s>No fluorescent pigments are produced on King's B or Gould's S1 agar.</s><s>The species is oxidase- and catalase-positive, denitrifying and shows hydrolysis of gelatin and accumulation of PHB, but no levan production on sucrose-rich agar or blue pigment formation on potato dextrose agar.</s><s>Indole is not produced during growth on tryptophan.</s><s>The species shows no acidification of glucose or hydrolysis of aesculin or starch.</s><s>No arginine dihydrolase, urease or β-galactosidase reactions are seen.</s><s>Growth takes place from 4 to 30 °C, but not at 37 °C, and no growth occurs in the presence of 4% NaCl.</s><s>Growth and respiration occurs on N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, c-aminobutyrate, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, bromosuccinate, carnitine, citrate, D-fructose, D-galactonate lactone, D-galactose, D-galacturonate, D-gluconate, D-glucosaminate, α-D-glucose, glucuronamide, D-glucuronate, L-glutamate, α-ketoglutarate, glycerol, L-histidine, β-hydroxybutyrate, hydroxy-L-proline, inosine, <i>meso</i>-inositol, DL-lactate, L-leucine, D-mannitol, D-mannose, methylpyruvate, L-ornithine, L-proline, putrescine, L-pyroglutamate, quinate, L-serine, succinate, sucrose, D-trehalose, Tween 40, Tween 80, uridine and urocanate.</s><s>Growth (respiration not tested) also occurs on N-acetyL-L-glutamate, adenosine, benzylamine, caprate, citraconate, 2-ketogluconate, lactamide, L-lactate, D-malate, L-malate, pyruvate, D-ribose and L-valine.</s><s>No growth or respiration occurs on N-acetyl-β-D-galactosamine, adonitol, D-cellobiose, α-cyclodextrin, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, β-gentiobiose, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glycyl-L-aspartate, γ-hydroxybutyrate, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetate, itaconate, α-D-lactose, lactulose, L-rhamnose, D-melibiose, β-methyl- D-glucoside, phenylethylamine, D-raffinose, sebacate, D-sorbitol, thymidine, α-ketovalerate or xylitol.</s><s>No growth (respiration not tested) occurs on N-acetyl-β-D-mannosamine, adenosine-5'-monophosphate, adipate, starch, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabitol, arbutin, β-cyclodextrin, dulcitol, aesculin, fructose 6-phosphate, D-fucose, 5-ketogluconate, inulin, D-lactate methyl ester, β-D-lactose, D-lyxose, maltotriose, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, mannan, D-melezitose, α-methyl-D-galactoside, β-methyl-D-galactoside, amethyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, 3-methylglucose, β-methylxyloside, palatinose, phenylacetate, salicin, sedoheptulosan, L-sorbose, stachyose, D-tagatose, thymidine-5'-monophosphate, L-tryptophan, D-xylose or L-xylose.</s><s>Mean G+­C content is 59.6 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from tar-polluted soil on Gould's S1 agar and subsequently screened on phenanthrene-coated minimal agar.</s><s>The type strain, JAJ28<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at DSMZ under DSM 13022<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>