<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6627_nm.3041" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3041" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3041" rank="subspecies">Salinivibrio costicola vallismortis</organism><reference id="rid.6627"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baresi</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinivibrio costicola subsp. vallismortis subsp. nov., a halotolerant facultative anaerobe from Death Valley, and emended description of Salinivibrio costicola.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>615</fpage><lpage>622</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758867</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Salinivibrio costicola</i> subsp. <i>vallismortis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Salinivibrio costicola</i> subsp. <i>vallismortis</i> (val.lis. mor'tis. L. gen. n. <i>vallis</i> of the valley ; L. gen. n. <i>mortis</i> of death; M. L. fem. n. <i>vallismortis</i> of the valley of death, named after Death Valley, California, USA)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, short, curved rods, 1.0-1.8x0.5-0.6 μm, highly motile by means of one or rarely two subpolar flagella.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or rarely in chains.</s><s>Colonies (up to 3 mm) are round with entire edges, smooth, convex, opaque and creamy white.</s><s>Halotolerant.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentration of 0-12.5%.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 2.5% NaCl.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C, growth occurs at 20-50 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5-8.2; optimum pH for growth is 7.3.</s><s>No growth factors are required for growth, but yeast extract enhances growth.</s><s>Either organic or inorganic nitrogen sources are sufficient.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin (200 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), penicillin-G (250 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), D-cycloserine and tetracycline (both 600 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultative anaerobe.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Oxidaseand catalase-positive.</s><s>Gelatin, starch and lipid (Tween 80) are hydrolysed.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and Voges- Proskauer tests are positive.</s><s>Aesculin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase and β-galactosidase tests are negative.</s><s>Fumarate, nitrate and sulfate are not reduced.</s><s>No growth occurs with H#/CO#.</s><s>D-Glucose, D-mannose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, adipate, caprate, D-gluconate, pyruvate, L-glutamic acid and yeast extract are metabolized aerobically.</s><s>Slight growth occurs on D-xylose, L-histidine and L-proline.</s><s>The following compounds are not used: L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, D-galacturonate, lactose, maltose, L-rhamnose, salicin, citrate, 2-oxoglutarate, DL-lactate, L-malate, malonate, phenylacetate, propionate, valerate, ethanol, D-mannitol, minositol, D-sorbitol, DL-α-alanine, β-alanine, L-leucine, L-serine, L-tyrosine, benzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, betaine, sarcosine and spermine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellobiose, fructose, D-glucose, maltose, mannose, trehalose, N-acetylglucosamine, glycogen, starch and pyruvate are fermented.</s><s>The major products from glucose fermentation are ethanol, isobutyrate, propionate, lactate, formate and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The following compounds are not fermented: arabinose, galactose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, methanol, sorbitol, formate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, ascorbate, citrate, fumarate, lactate, oxalate, succinate, tartrate, betaine, methylamine, trimethylamine, sarcosine, Casamino acids, cellulose, chitin and pectin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA is 50 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>The type strain is strain DV<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 8285<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from Death Valley, California, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>