<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5219_nm.6576" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6576" rank="genus">Catenuloplanes</organism><reference id="rid.5219"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catenuloplanes japonicus gen. nov., sp. nov., nom. rev., a genus of the order Actinomycetales.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>805</fpage><lpage>812</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Catenuloplanes</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Catenuloplanes</i> (Ca.te.nul.o.plan'es. L. f. n. <i>catenula</i>, short chain; Gr. n. <i>planes</i>, a wanderer; Gr. n. <i>Catenuloplanes</i>, a wanderer, a motile cell of a short chain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and not acid fast and form truly branching hyphae.</s><s>Nonfragmenting, yellowish orange to orange substrate mycelium is formed.</s><s>Monopodially or dichotomously branched aerial mycelium develops sparsely.</s><s>Spores are formed in chains.</s><s>The aerial mycelium contains short spore chains arranged in spirals having one or two turns that are hooked or rarely flexuous.</s><s>The spore chains and aerial mycelium often aggregate into clusters resembling a flower or a sporodochium.</s><s>The spores are rod shaped, straight or curved (0.6 to 0.8 by 2 to 4 μm) with smooth surfaces, and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction is positive.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed, but hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Adenine, xanthine, hypoxanthine, and cellulose are not decomposed or hydrolyzed.</s><s>Decomposes calcium malate, tyrosine, esculin, and urea.</s><s>Not resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>Milk is coagulated and peptonized.</s><s>Acids are produced from many carbohydrates.</s><s>Many organic acids and carbohydrates are utilized as carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain D-glutamate, D-serine, L-serine, gllycine, D-alanine, and L-lysine (cell wall type VI), and mannose, xylose, and glucose are present as cell wall sugars.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs aire between 71.0 and 72.7 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>10</sub>); in addition, small amounts of MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosplhatidylcholine, and phosphatidylethanolamine are present as diagnostic phospholipids (type PIII).</s><s>The type species is <i>Catenuloplanes japonicus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>