<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1818_nm.10744" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10744" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10744" rank="species">Gluconacetobacter kombuchae</organism><reference id="rid.1818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dutta</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gachhui</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nitrogen-fixing and cellulose-producing Gluconacetobacter kombuchae sp. nov., isolated from Kombucha tea.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>357</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64638-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267978</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gluconacetobacter kombuchae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gluconacetobacter kombuchae</em> (kom.bu′chae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>kombuchae</em> from Kombucha, a kind of fermented tea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, approximately 2.0–3.0 μm long and 0.1–0.2 μm wide, and occur singly or in bunches.</s><s>Gram-negative, motile with polar flagellation, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs on nitrogen-free LGI plates at 30 and 37 °C and in LGI broth under microaerophilic conditions with formation of a cellulosic pellicle on the surface.</s><s>Colonies grown on LGI plates are smooth, round, dull, dry, white and opaque, 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days.</s><s>Dark-yellow colonies are formed on LGI agar supplemented with 0.001 % bromothymol blue.</s><s>Colonies on potato agar are light brown after 5 days of incubation, but the intensity increases after 10 days.</s><s>The type strain is aerobic and fixes atmospheric nitrogen microaerobically.</s><s>It oxidizes ethanol to acetic acid, turning EYC or GYC opaque plates transparent, and overoxidizes acetate and lactate to CO<sub>2</sub> and water.</s><s>l-Alanine supports growth, as well as the formation of a pellicle, as the sole source of carbon and nitrogen in LGI broth.</s><s>Can utilize the single amino acids l-cysteine and l-threonine as sole sources of carbon and nitrogen but not l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Butanol (0.1 %) can not support growth in nitrogen-free medium.</s><s>In the absence of yeast extract, the type strain can utilize different carbon sources such as d-arabinose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol and glycerol, but not d-galactose or d-xylose, and can grow on 30 % sucrose and 30 % glucose.</s><s>Formation of a cellulosic pellicle is prevalent in the presence of almost all the general carbon sources used except sorbitol and gluconate.</s><s>Can not utilize d-cellobiose, maltose or lactose in LGI medium for growth.</s><s>The ubiquinone present is of the type Q-10 and the DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain RG3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23726<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 6913<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Kombucha tea.</s></p></content></protolog>