<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9278_nm.14563" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14563" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14563" rank="species">Roseibaca ekhonensis</organism><reference id="rid.9278"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labrenz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseibaca ekhonensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an alkalitolerant and aerobic bacteriochlorophyll a-producing alphaproteobacterium from hypersaline Ekho Lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1935</fpage><lpage>1940</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016717-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567566</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseibaca ekhonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseibaca ekhonensis</em> (ek.ho.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>ekhonensis</em> pertaining to Ekho Lake, the lake in Antarctica from which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cell sizes are in the range 0.80–1.20×1.20–4.00 μm, with a mean size of 1.00×2.50 μm.</s><s>Colonies on PYGV with ASW are 3 mm in diameter, circular with regular edges, gleamy, convex, and red with whitish-pinkish peripheries.</s><s>Bchl <em>a</em> is produced with a maximal absorbance band at 865–866 nm.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–30 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 16 °C and pH 7.0–9.5.</s><s>NaCl tolerance ranges from 0–1.0 to 3.5–4.0 %, with an optimum of 2.5 %.</s><s>Positive for peroxidase and cytochrome oxidase, and weakly-positive for catalase activity.</s><s>Cells depend on thiamine and vitamin B<sub>12</sub>, but not on biotin, nicotinic acid or sodium pantothenate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U) and streptomycin (10 μg), and resistant to polymyxin B (300 U) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Does not grow on <em>α</em>-d-glucose anaerobically in the absence of nitrate.</s><s>DNA, gelatin, lipase (Tween 80), starch and alginate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not grow in minimal medium (Labrenz <em>et al.</em>, 1998) with 0.2 % (w/v) methanol, methanesulfonic acid or butyrate.</s><s>With the API 50 CH system the following carbon compounds are not metabolized: erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, amidone, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, gluconic acid, 2-ketogluconic and 5-ketogluconic acid.</s><s>In the Biolog system, does not metabolize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol or 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetate, pyruvate, malate, citrate, succinic acid, glutamic acid, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glycerol, inositol, aesculin, salicin, d-lyxose and d-arabitol.</s><s>Does not produce acid or acetoin from <em>α</em>-d-glucose.</s><s>Sulfide and indole are not produced.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EL-50<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11469<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7235<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Ekho Lake, Antarctica (Vestfold Hills).</s></p></content></protolog>