<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1511_nm.4961" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4961" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4961" rank="species">Bacillus peoriae</organism><reference id="rid.1511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Montefusco</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus peoriae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>388</fpage><lpage>390</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus peoriae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus peoriae</i> (pe.o'.riae L. gen. n. <i>peoriae</i>, named after Peoria, where the study on the organism was done)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile vegetative cells are 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide and 3.0 to 6.0 μm long (as determined by phase microscopy) and occur singly and in short chains.</s><s>They produce ellipsoidal spores in definitely swollen sporangia and are gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are translucent, thin, smooth, circular, and entire and measure about 2 mm in diameter after 2 days at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol (Voges-Proskauer test) is produced.</s><s>The pHs in Voges-Proskauer broth range from 5.0 to 6.5.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide, indole, and dihydroxyacetone are not formed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Citrate and succinate, but not propionate, are utilized.</s><s>Casein, pectin, starch, and xylan are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Egg yolk lecithin, Tween 80, and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>Litmus milk is acidified and curdled.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine, lysine, ornithine, phenylalanine, and tyrosine are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum, maximum, and minimum growth temperatures range from 28 to 30°C, from 35 to 45°C, and from 5 to 10°C, respectively.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.6 or 5.7, variably in 0.001% lysozyme, and not in 3% NaCl.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from arabinose, glucose, mannitol, and xylose.</s><s>Other carbohydrates fermented include cellobiose, galactose, fructose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, ribose, rhamnose, salicin, and sucrose.</s><s>Glycerol and trehalose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant densities for 28 strains ranged from 1.6986 to 1.7005 g/cm<sup>3</sup>, and the G+C values determined from these values ranged from 45 to 47 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated mainly from soil and rotting vegetative materials.</s><s>NRRL B-14750 in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection, Peoria, Ill.</s></p></content></protolog>