<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8042_nm.8821" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8821" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8821" rank="species">Roseivirga ehrenbergii</organism><reference id="rid.8042"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalinovskaya</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Roseivirga seohaensis (Yoon et al. 2005) Lau et al. 2006 as a later synonym of Roseivirga ehrenbergii Nedashkovskaya et al. 2005 and emendation of the species description. Int. J. Syst. Evol. Microbiol., 2008, 58, 1194-1197.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1194</fpage><lpage>1197</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64104-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450712</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Roseivirga ehrenbergii</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseivirga ehrenbergii</em> [eh.ren.ber′gi.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>ehrenbergii</em> of Ehrenberg, after the German biologist Christian Gottfried Ehrenberg (1795–1876), for his contribution to the development of microbiology].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as given by Nedashkovskaya <em>et al.</em> (2005a) with the following additions.</s><s>Cells range from 0.2 to 0.5 μm in width and from 2.1 to 4.0 μm in length.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are 1–4 mm in diameter and pink–orange-pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–40 °C, at pH 5.5–9.5 and with 1–8 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 23–30 °C, at pH 7.0–8.0 and with 2–3 % NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 is strain-dependent.</s><s>Does not form acid from d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>myo</em>-inositol or sorbitol.</s><s>According to Microlog GN2 (Biolog), the type strain KMM 6017<sup>T</sup> utilizes glycogen, l-arabinose, methyl pyruvate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and putrescine but does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, lincomycin and oleandomycin and resistant to benzylpenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymixin B and streptomycin.</s><s>Resistance to ampicillin and tetracycline is strain-dependent.</s><s>Fatty acids accounting for more than 1.0 % of the total are iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>G (20.5–34.2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (24.0–33.5 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (7.7–11.2 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4.1–7.6 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.0–5.6 %), iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (3.2–5.2 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (2.4–4.5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.6–1.8 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (0–1.8 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.1–1.2 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (0.9–1.1 %) and summed feature 3 (1.7–4.8 %), comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Polar lipids of strain SW-152 are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, an unidentified phospholipid and a ninhydrin-positive lipid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40–41 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 6017<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12282<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22567<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the green alga <em>Ulva fenestrata</em> collected in Pallada Bay, Gulf of Peter the Great, East Sea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A reference strain, SW-152 (=JCM 12600=KCTC 12312; the type strain of <em>Roseivirga</em> <em>seohaensis</em>), was isolated from a seawater sample in the Yellow Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>