<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6902_nm.8165" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8165" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8165" rank="species">Gelidibacter mesophilus</organism><reference id="rid.6902"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gelidibacter mesophilus sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium in the family Flavobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1325</fpage><lpage>1329</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02009-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148647</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gelidibacter mesophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gelidibacter mesophilus</i> (me.so.phi'lus. Gr. n. <i>mesos</i> middle; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> loving; N.L. adj. <i>mesophilus</i> middle (temperature)-loving, mesophilic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 1.5-3.5 μm long by 0.5 μm wide, strictly aerobic, non-flagellated.</s><s>Colonies on MA are mucoid, sticky, yellow-pigmented and not luminescent.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are absent.</s><s>Strains do not glide on MA, but they do glide on BM when any of the following carbohydrates are added: L-rhamnose, D-raffinose, sucrose, cellobiose or melibiose.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate to nitrite.Nogrowth occurs without addition of NaCl to the culture medium or at NaCl concentrations of 8% or more.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 4 and 37 °C.</s><s>Both strains are negative for the following tests: Thornley's and Mùller's arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase and indole production.</s><s>Both strains hydrolyse starch and gelatin weakly, but not casein, alginate, agar, Tween 80, lecithin or DNA.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-galactose, trehalose, D-mannose, maltose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, cellobiose, lactose and amygdalin.</s><s>Neither of the strains utilizes the following substrates: D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-fructose, salicin, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, saccharate, glycerate, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, pyruvate, citrate, aconitate, 2-oxoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, DL-malate, acetate, DL-lactate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, glycine, L-leucine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-arginine, L-tyrosine, L-glutamate, L-alanine, γ-aminobutyrate, L-ornithine, L-citrulline, sarcosine and putrescine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 38.8 to 40.3 mol%(Tm method).</s><s>Isolated from sea water from the Mediterranean coast of Valencia (Spain).</s><s>The type strain, 2SM29<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at the Colección Española de Cultivos Tipo (Valencia, Spain) as strain CECT 5103<sup>T</sup> and at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 14095<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Strain 2SM28 (=CECT 5104=DSM 14094) is a reference strain.</s></p></content></protolog>