<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5705_nm.9966" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9966" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9966" rank="species">Clostridium schirmacherense</organism><reference id="rid.5705"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Alam</surname><given-names>S.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dixit</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dube</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palit</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium schirmacherense sp. nov., an obligately anaerobic, proteolytic, psychrophilic bacterium isolated from lake sediment of Schirmacher Oasis, Antarctica</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>715</fpage><lpage>720</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63808-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium schirmacherense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium schirmacherense</em> (schir.ma.cher.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>schirmacherense</em> pertaining to Schirmacher Oasis in Antarctica).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods (2–4×0·5–0·7 μm) that form spores.</s><s>Spores are subterminal and distend the cell.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic and chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Grows at temperatures in the range 5–35 °C and produces maximum cell mass at 5–10 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is between 6 and 9, with an optimum at pH 8·0.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth but is tolerated up to a concentration of 7·5 % (Table 1).</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin and casein, produces H<sub>2</sub>S but does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for catalase, oxidase, lipase, indole production and <em>β</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Utilizes raffinose, glucose, adonitol, rhamnose and ribose but not sucrose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, lactose, inositol, trehalose, maltose, dulcitol, xylan, arabitol, xylose, inulin, amygdalin, glycogen, galactose or sorbitol.</s><s>Complex substrates such as yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone and gelatin are also fermented.</s><s>Some amino acids, including arginine, serine, leucine, isoleucine, cysteine and glutamate, are utilized whereas asparagine, proline, glutamine, aspartate, glycine, lysine, methionine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine, valine, 2-aminobutyric acid, ornithine and phenylalanine are not utilized.</s><s>Sulfite and thiosulfate are reduced but sulfate, elemental sulfur and fumarate are not reduced.</s><s>The major fermentation end-products are as follows: acetate, propionate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from glutamate; acetate and butyrate from isoleucine; acetate, propionate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from cysteine; formate, acetate and propionate from arginine; acetate, propionate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> from leucine; and acetate, isobutyrate and butyrate from serine.</s><s>Details of the amino acid fermentation products are available as supplementary data (Supplementary Table S1) in IJSEM Online.</s><s>Glucose is fermented to formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isovalerate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> (Supplementary Table S2 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Contains diphosphatidylglycerol as the major phospholipids, and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell wall.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 24 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AP15<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17394<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13289<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from lake sediments of Schirmacher Oasis, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>