<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6524_nm.1158" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1158" rank="genus">Sulfitobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6524"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sorokin</surname><given-names>D.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sulfitobacter pontiacus gen. nov., sp. nov. - a new heterotrophic bacterium from the Black Sea, specialized on sulfite oxidation.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>354</fpage><lpage>365</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sulfitobacter pontiacus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sulfitobacter pontiacus</i> (Sul.fi.to.bacter M.L. n. <i>sulfitum</i>, sulfite; M.L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, equivalent of Gr. neut. n. <i>bacterion</i>, a rod; M.L. masc. n. <i>sulfitobacter</i>, sulfite rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rod-shaped strictly aerobic heterotrophic eubacterium.</s><s>Depending on growth conditions, rods are either straight with sharpened ends or dumbbell-shaped with a tendency for polar growth, cell differentiation, and rosette formation.</s><s>Cells vary in size in a wide range of (0.45 - 1.3) x (2 - 5) μm.</s><s>Depending on growth conditions, cells may be motile by means of 1 - 5 subpolar flagella.</s><s>Growth in liquid medium is homogeneous.</s><s>On an acetate agar medium, colonies are colorless, flat, and translucent and have even margins, up to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Does not grow chemolithoautotrophically on thiosulfate, sulfite, and H<sub>2</sub> as electron donors.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, propionate, butyrate, pyruvate, lactate, gluconate, acids of the Krebs cycle (except citrate and <i>cis</i>-aconitate), glycerol, glutamate, proline, aspartate, asparagine, serine, α-alanine, ornithine, and arginine as the sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is accumulated in cells grown on acetate.</s><s>Ammonium is used as the nitrogen source.</s><s>Growth in a mineral medium with acetate is stimulated by yeast extract and thiamine.</s><s>The respiratory chain includes cytochromes c<sub>551</sub>, b<sub>558</sub>, and cytochrome c oxidase of the aa<sub>3</sub> type.</s><s>When growing organotrophically on acetate, the organism can oxidize thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, and sulfite to sulfate, the sulfite-oxidizing activity being higher by two orders of magnitude.</s><s>Grows in acetate-limited chemostat culture at extremely high sulfite concentrations.</s><s>Thiosulfate and sulfite stimulate acetate-dependent growth in a continuous culture.</s><s>Sulfite is oxidized by highly active inducible AMP-independent soluble sulfite oxidase that donates electrons from sulfite to the respiratory chain at the level of cytochrome c via soluble cytochrome c.</s><s>The G + C content of DNA is 62.1 ± 0.4 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>The member of α-3-subdivision of <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Isolated from the water of H<sub>2</sub>S-O<sub>2</sub> interface of the eastern part of the Black Sea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species <i>Sulfitobacter pontiacus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>