<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3886_nm.9745" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9745" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9745" rank="species">Alcaligenes aquatilis</organism><reference id="rid.3886"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Samyn</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alcaligenes aquatilis sp. nov., a novel bacterium from sediments of the Weser Estuary, Germany, and a salt marsh on Shem Creek in Charleston Harbor, USA</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2571</fpage><lpage>2575</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63849-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280529</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alcaligenes aquatilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alcaligenes aquatilis</em> (a.qua′ti.lis. L. masc. adj. <em>aquatilis</em> living, growing or found in, or near, water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative short rods (0·7–1·1 μm×1·0–2·5 μm) and are motile via peritrichous flagella.</s><s>They form non-pigmented or yellow-pigmented (strains LMG 22999 and ATCC 700596), circular, low-convex and smooth colonies with spreading, irregular edges and a diameter of 2·0–5·0 mm on trypticase soy agar plates after 2 days incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>The growth temperature is in the range 4–35 °C, while the optimal growth temperature ranges from 18 to 24 °C.</s><s>Tests for catalase and cytochrome oxidase are positive (except for strain ATCC 700596, which is catalase-negative).</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced under anaerobic conditions, but slight growth is observed under these conditions after 5 days incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Positive for the alkalinization of asparagine, citrate and glutamine.</s><s>Positive for the utilization of sodium acetate, sodium citrate and malonate for most of the strains (with the exception of strain ATCC 700596, which is negative for utilization of sodium citrate and malonate).</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity is not detected.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced, and starch, gelatin, aesculin and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Strains LMG 22996<sup>T</sup>, LMG 22997, LMG 22998 and LMG 22999 are able to reduce nitrite but not nitrate.</s><s>No acids are produced from carbohydrates (except for strain ATCC 700596, which produces acid from maltose, mannitol, xylose and l-arabinose).</s><s>No activity detected for arginine dihydrolase (variable for strain ATCC 700596), lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Growth is not observed on glucose, l-arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, adipate, salicin, d-melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionate, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, l-proline, rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, d-sucrose, itaconate, malonate, l-alanine or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Growth is observed on caprate (except for strain ATCC 700596), malate, phenylacetate, valerate, citrate, histidine, suberate, acetate, dl-lactate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate and l-serine.</s><s>Cells contain the fatty acids C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, summed feature 2 (comprising any combination of C<sub>12 : 0</sub> aldehyde, an unknown fatty acid of equivalent chain length 10·928, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH) and summed feature 3 (C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) as the main constituents.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the strains is 56 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 22996<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50924<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Reference strains are LMG 22997, LMG 22998 and LMG 22999, isolated from sediments of the Weser Estuary, Germany, as was the type strain, and M3A (=ATCC 700596), isolated from sediments of Shem Creek, Charleston Harbor, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>