<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3887_nm.9750" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9750" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9750" rank="species">Leadbetterella byssophila</organism><reference id="rid.3887"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cha</surname><given-names>I.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leadbetterella byssophila gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from cotton-waste composts for the cultivation of oyster mushroom.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2297</fpage><lpage>2302</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63741-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280486</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leadbetterella byssophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leadbetterella byssophila</em> (bys.so′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>byssos</em> cotton; N.L. adj. <em>philus</em> friendly to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>byssophila</em> liking cotton).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0·6–0·9×2–7 μm) and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are orange and convex with entire margin.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of 15–45 °C, pH 6·0–8·0 and in the presence of 1 % (w/v) NaCl, but not at 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows on 0·5 % yeast extract medium.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, starch, tyrosine and Tween 20 are degraded.</s><s>Positive for O/F test (glucose) and indole production.</s><s>Casein, cellulose, chitin, DNA, Tweens 40 and 80 and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Growth on carbohydrates (API 20NE) is observed for glucose, arabinose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose.</s><s>Positive for indole production and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API 20NE).</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction and arginine dihydrolase (API 20NE).</s><s>Enzymic activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is detected for <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>d-Arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, d-celiobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, starch and gentiobiose are oxidized or weakly oxidized (API 50CH).</s><s>i-Erythritol, d-melibiose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, d-fructose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, dextrin, l-fucose, uridine, glycogen, d-galactose, d-raffinose, l-alaninamide, l-ornithine, thymidine, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-galacturonic acid, dl-lactic acid, l-alanine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, sucrose, l-alanylglycine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-trehalose, l-asparagine, lactulose, turanose, l-aspartic acid, l-serine, glycerol, l-arabinose, maltose, l-glutamic acid, l-threonine, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate, d-arabitol, methyl pyruvate, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glucose 1-phosphate, d-cellobiose, d-mannose, monomethyl succinate, glycyl l-glutamic acid and d-glucose 6-phosphate are assimilated or weakly assimilated (Biolog GN 20).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain 4M15<sup>T</sup> is 33·0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4M15<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11308<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17132<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from cotton-waste composts in the Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>