<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7439_nm.3190" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3190" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3190" rank="species">Erwinia pyrifoliae</organism><reference id="rid.7439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhim</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Geider</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia pyrifoliae sp. nov., a novel pathogen that affects Asian pear trees (Pyrus pyrifolia Nakai)</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>899</fpage><lpage>905</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-899</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319516</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia pyrifoliae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia pyrifoliae</i> (py.ri.fo'liae. L. gen. fem. n. <i>pyrifoliae</i> of <i>pyrifolia</i>, the species name of the host plant, the Nashi pear, <i>Pyrus pyrifolia</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, peritrichous, straight rods.</s><s>The strains are facultatively anaerobic, oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>Strains grow on YPDA medium, producing colonies that are 2 mm after 48 h at 28°C.</s><s>Colonies are circular white, well-domed and opaque.</s><s>Glucose (dextrose) is fermented without gas production.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is (weakly) positive.</s><s>Polypectate gel is not acidified or liquefied.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysin decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not present.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>RCS are produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inulin, lactose, methyl α-glucoside, melibiose, D-arabitol, D-arabinose or raffinose.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannitol, sorbitol, saccharose.</s><s>There is no alkalinization of malonate, citrate or D-tartrate.</s><s>β-Galactosidase is not produced.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy: D-fructose, D-galactose, D-trehalose, saccharose, methyl D-glucopyranoside, D-ribose, L-arabinose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, L-malate, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, succinate, fumarate, L-glutamate, L-proline.</s><s>The following substances are not utilized: D-mannose, D-sorbose, α-D-melibiose, D-raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, methyl β-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, aescuh, D-xylose, palatinose, α-L-rhamnose, α-L-fructose, D-melibiose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, xylitol, dulitol, D-tagatose, maltitol, D-turanose, adonitol, hydroxyquinoline β-glucuroside, 3-methyl D-glucopyranoside, D-saccharate, mucate, L-tartrate, D-tatrate, mesotartrate, D-malate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, tricarballylate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, keto-D-gluconate, L-tryptophan, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, phydroxybenzoate, quinate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, betaine, putrescine, aminobutyrate, histamine, DLlactate, caprate, caprylate, L-histidine, glutarate, DL-glycerate, aminovalerate, ethanolamine, tryptamine, itaconate, hydroxybutyrate, D-alanine, malonate, propionate, L-tyrosine, ketoglutarate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pathogen was isolated from necrotic symptoms of leaves and branches of <i>Pyrus pyrifolia</i> cv. 'Shingo'.</s><s>It is closely related to the fire blight pathogen <i>Erwinia amylovora</i> for the DNA sequence of the 16s rDNA, but distantly for its intergenic transcribed spacer region (ITS).</s><s>It does not contain plasmid pEA29 (Rhim et al., 1999).</s><s>The G + C content of the genomic DNA is 52 mol%.</s><s>The type strain (E 16/96<sup>T</sup>)as been deposited in the Collection Franqaise des Bactkries Phytopathogenes as CFBP 41 72<sup>T</sup> and the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as DSM 12163<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Additional strains deposited are Ep8/95 (=DSM 12393), Ep1/96 (=CFBP4171=DSM 12162), Ep28/96 (=CFBP 4173), Ep31/96 (=CFBP 4174) and Ep4/97 (=DSM 12394).</s></p></content></protolog>