<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4249_nm.1062" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1062" rank="genus">Hyphomonas</organism><reference id="rid.4249"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiner</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Melick</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Neill</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quintero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hyphomonas adhaerens sp. nov., Hyphomonas johnsonii sp. nov. and Hyphomonas rosenbergii sp. nov., marine budding and prosthecate bacteria.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>459</fpage><lpage>469</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758848</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of genus <i>Hyphomonas</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyphomonas</i> species are of marine origin, share a biphasic life cycle and normally generate only a single polar prosthecum. They catabolize amino acids for energy and growth (with the exception of strain MHS-2<sup>T</sup>, which can utilize sugars). They are isolated from many ocean niches, including the open ocean (the pelagic zone), mud sloughs and two different hydrothermal vent sites (surface waters and depths of 2600 m). Members of the genus <i>Hyphomonas</i>, like other budding, prosthecate bacteria, undergo a rather complex life cycle termed a `biphasic life cycle '. It requires 265 min for <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i> to complete a full cycle at 36 °C. The life cycle consists of a swarm-cell stage that eventually metamorphoses into a benthic, reproductive cell during the biphasic developmental cycle. Members of <i>Hyphomonas</i>, especially the vent strains, grow in a broad range of environmental conditions, including those involving considerable temperature, pressure and salinity variations. They are primary colonizers of submerged marine surfaces, some species producing dense biofilms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Briefly, the morphological characteristics of <i>Hyphomonas</i> cells are as follows: rod-shaped to oval mature cells measuring 0.5-1.0x1.0-3.0 μm; buds are produced at the tips of polar prosthecae, which measure 0.2-0.3 μm in diameter and are 1.5 times the length of the cell body; and swarm cells are motile by means of a single polar to lateral flagellum located on developing buds of younger daughter cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-acid-fast, aerobic, non-sporeforming and chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>All strains investigated so far are catalase-positive, oxidase-positive, urease-negative, indole-negative, hydrogen sulfidenegative, non-saccharolytic and non-pathogenic for mammals.</s><s>Peptone is normally required for growth.</s><s>With one exception, all strains denitrify.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature range is 22-37 °C at 101 kPa. <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i>, <i>Hyphomonas polymorpha</i>, <i>Hyphomonas oceanitis</i> and <i>Hyphomonas hirschiana</i> have a Q-11 ubiquinone type along with a significant amount of Q-10 (approx. 10% of total ubiquinones) and minor amounts of Q-9 and Q-12. <i>Hyphomonas jannaschiana</i> has Q-10 as its major quinone, with trace amounts of Q-9 and Q-11.</s><s>Synthesize many apparent high-molecular-mass proteins (≥64 kDa).</s><s>The dominant fatty acid, common to all <i>Hyphomonas</i> spp., is octadecenoic acid (18: 1).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57-64 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>