<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12635_nm.22174" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22174" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22174" rank="species">Mannheimia caviae</organism><reference id="rid.12635"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bojesen</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mannheimia caviae sp. nov., isolated from epidemic conjunctivitis and otitis media in guinea pigs</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1699</fpage><lpage>1704</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026518-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20729306</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mannheimia caviae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mannheimia</em> <em>caviae</em> sp. nov. (ca′vi.ae. N.L. n. <em>Cavia</em> generic name of the guinea pig; N.L. gen. n. <em>caviae</em> of <em>Cavia</em>, of a guinea pig).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile at 22 and 37 °C and are Gram-negative-staining, coccoid or pleomorphic rods.</s><s>Colonies on bovine blood agar are regular, circular and slightly raised with an entire margin.</s><s>The surface of the colonies is smooth, shiny and opaque with a greyish tinge.</s><s>Colonies have a diameter of 1.0–1.5 mm after 24 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>β-Haemolysis is not observed on calf blood agar.</s><s>CAMP negative on calf blood agar [CAMP is an abbreviation of the first initials of family names of the authors who described the test (Christie <em>et al.</em>, 1944)].</s><s>The consistency of the colonies is unguent-like and the colonies do not adhere to the agar surface.</s><s>All strains tested are positive for catalase and oxidase activities and demonstrate a fermentative reaction in Hugh and Leifson medium with (+)-d-glucose.</s><s>Strains give a positive result in tests for porphyrin, nitrate reduction, alanine aminopeptidase, ornithine decarboxylase, phosphatase, growth on MacConkey agar, ONPG (o-nitro-phenyl-d-galactopyranoside), β-glucosidase (p-nitrophenyl β-d-glucopyranoside; NPG), α-galactosidase, β-xylosidase and production of acid from glycerol, (+)-l-arabinose, (−)-d-ribose, (+)-d-xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, (−)-d-mannitol, (−)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, (+)-d-glucose, cellobiose, lactose, (+)-melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, aesculin, amygdalin, arbutin, gentiobiose and salicin.</s><s>Symbiotic growth (NAD requirement) is not observed.</s><s>The Simmons citrate test is negative, as well as the formation of acid from mucate, base formation from malonate, H<sub>2</sub>S/TSI, growth in the presence of KCN, methyl red test, Voges–Proskauer test at 37 °C, production of gas from nitrate, urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, indole, gelatinase, hydrolysis of Tween 20 and 80, formation of pigment, α-glucosidase (p-nitrophenyl α-d-glucopyranoside; PNPG), β-glucuronidase (p-nitrophenyl β-d-glucopyranosiduronic acid; PGUA), α-mannosidase, production of acid from <em>meso</em>-erythritol, adonitol, (+)-d-arabitol, xylitol, (−)-l-xylose, dulcitol, (+)-d-fucose, (+)-d-mannose, (+)-l-rhamnose, (−)-l-sorbose, maltose, trehalose, (+)-melezitose, dextrin, (+)-d-glycogen, inulin, (+)-turanose, β-N-CH<sub>3</sub>-glucosamide and production of gas from (+)-d-glucose.</s><s>Variations are observed as to acid production from (−)-d-sorbitol and α-fucosidase, the type strain is negative and positive, respectively, for these tests.</s><s>Acid formation from (−)-d-arabinose is negative for the type strain, but strain Pg20 gives a late positive reaction.</s><s>Acid formation from (−)-l-fucose is negative for the type strain, but strains Pg19 and Pg20 give a late positive result.</s><s>All isolates conform to the phenotypic characteristics as described for the genus <em>Mannheimia</em> (Angen <em>et al.</em>, 1999).</s><s>These characteristics allow the species to be separated from other species of the genus <em>Mannheimia</em> by at least four characteristics.</s><s>The detailed phenotypic characteristics for all three isolates are presented in this study.</s><s>Both ubiquinones and demethylmenaquinone are present in the type strain according to Mannheim <em>et al.</em> (1978).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, T138021-75<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 59995<sup>T</sup> = DSM 23207<sup>T</sup>) was obtained from purulent conjunctivitis in guinea pigs.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA of the type strain is 41.4 mol % (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>) (Mannheim <em>et al.</em>, 1978).</s><s>Other strains are Pg19 and Pg20.</s></p></content></protolog>