<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6002_nm.3112" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3112" rank="genus">Buchnera</organism><reference id="rid.6002"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Munson</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kinsey</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Buchnera gen. nov. and Buchnera aphidicola sp. nov., a taxon consisting of the mycetocyte-associated, primary endosymbionts of aphids.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>566</fpage><lpage>568</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-4-566</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Buchnera</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Buchnera</i> (Buch.ne'ra. M.L. fem. n. <i>Buchnera</i>, named for Paul Buchner, a German biologist who made extensive contributions to the study of endosymbiosis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Round or slightly oval cells (diameter, 2 to 5 μm) that have a typical gram-negative cell wall and lack flagella.</s><s>Cells divide by binary fission.</s><s>These organisms do not form a morphologically distinct resting stage or endospores.</s><s>Found in the mycetocytes of aphids in vesicles derived from the host membranes.</s><s>Cannot be cultivated outside the host.</s><s>Essential for the survival of the aphid.</s><s>On the basis of the sequences of their 16s rRNAs, the members of this genus form a distinct lineage within the gamma-3 subgroup of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> (14, 19, 22).</s><s>Table 1 shows the sequence signatures that distinguish the genus <i>Buchnera</i> from members of the related family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and the more distantly related organism <i>Ruminobacter amylophilus</i>, both of which are in the gamma-3 subgroup (12, 22).</s><s>The sequence signatures of the gamma-3 subgroup have been described previously by Woese (22)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional descriptive information.</s><s>A variety of antibiotics (penicillin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, neomycin? tetracycline) eliminate the endosymbionts, leading to a loss of the reproductive potential of the aphids (4,8, 10).</s><s>The endosymbionts have been purified from several species of aphids (6, 10).</s><s>Peptidoglycan has been detected in the cell wall of the endosymbiont obtained from <i>A. pisiam</i> (7, 8).</s><s>The genome size of this species has been found to be 1.4 x 10<sup>10</sup> daltons (9).</s><s>The endosymbionts resemble other slow-growing bacteria in having only one copy of the gene coding for 16s rRNA (14, 18, 19).</s><s>The G+C contents of the 16s rRNAs of these organisms are 48 to 50 mol%, compared with the values of 53 to 54 mol% found for four other representatives of the gamma-3 subgroup (15, 18, 19).</s></p></content></protolog>