<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4062_nm.3340" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3340" rank="genus">Wigglesworthia</organism><reference id="rid.4062"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aksoy</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wigglesworthia gen. nov. and Wigglesworthia glossinidia sp. nov., taxa consisting of the mycetocyte-associated, primary endosymbionts of tsetse flies.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>848</fpage><lpage>851</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-848</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Wigglesworthia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Wigglesworthia</i> (Wiggles.worth'i.a. M.L. fem. n. <i>Wigglesworthia</i>, named after the parasitologist V. B. Wigglesworth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mycetomes are packed with rod-shaped microorganisms that are up to 4 to 5 μm long (Fig. 1).</s><s>The microorganisms are in the cytoplasm of the specialized epithelial cells called mycetocytes.</s><s>They have a typical gram-negative cell wall and lack flagella.</s><s>The cells appear to divide by binary fission.</s><s>These organisms have not been cultivated outside their hosts, although it is possible to keep them metabolically active for at least 72 h under transient tissue culture conditions (2).</s><s>It is possible to study the gene expression and protein transport in P-endosymbionts of tsetse flies by using transient tissue culture conditions, and in this way the major protein product has been identified as a groEL homolog by immunological cross-reactivity (2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of their 16s rDNA sequences, members of this genus form a distinct lineage in the 7-3 subdivision of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>As shown in the phylogenetic tree in Fig. 2, they are closely related to members of the genus <i>Buchnera</i>, to S-endosymbionts of other insects, and to <i>Escherichia coli</i>.</s><s>Table 1 shows the sequence signatures in the 16s rDNA that distinguish the genus <i>Wigglesworthia</i> from members of the genus <i>Buchnera</i> and from other members of the γ-3 subgroup.</s></p></content></protolog>