<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6928_nm.5988" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5988" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5988" rank="species">Brachybacterium sacelli</organism><reference id="rid.6928"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium fresconis sp. nov. and Brachybacterium sacelli sp. nov., isolated from deteriorated parts of a medieval wall painting of the chapel of Castle Herberstein (Austria).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1641</fpage><lpage>1646</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02229-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachybacterium sacelli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachybacterium sacelli</i> (sa.cel'li. L. gen. n. <i>sacelli</i>, of the chapel)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells vary in shape from coccoid forms (single or in agglomerates) in the stationary phase, to short rods in the exponential phase.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, do not form endospores and stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Colonies onMAafter 24 h are small (&#x003C;1 mm), cream-coloured, smooth, glistening, circular in outline and low convex.</s><s>No growth in an anaerobic chamber on MA.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5-40°C, with optimal growth between 20 and 30°C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration range for growth is 0-15% (w/v).</s><s>Grows at pH 5.</s><s>Catalase is produced, oxidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-negative and β-galactosidase-positive.</s><s>Strains assimilate gluconate, maltose, mannose, mannitol and N-acetylglucosamine, but not adipate, arabinose, caprate, citrate, glucose and malate.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and is of the type A4γ (<i>m</i>-Dpm←D-Glu←D-Glu) with glycine bound to the α-carboxyl group of D-glutamic acid at position 2 of the peptide subunit.</s><s>Muramic acid residues are glycolylated.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and one unidentified glycolipid were found as polar lipids.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-7 in combination with either MK-8 in lower but still considerable amounts, or in approximately equal amounts.</s><s>MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) or MK-9 are present in minor amounts in some strains.</s><s>The main fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>The type strain produced acid from D-fructose, D-glucose, DL-lactose, maltose, D-mannose and sucrose, but not from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-melezitose and D-sorbitol.</s><s>The G+C content is 70.3 mol% for the type strain.</s><s>The type strain was deposited in the BBCM/LMG as LMG 20345<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14566<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The 16S rRNA sequence of this strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJ415384.</s></p></content></protolog>