<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6265_nm.9892" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9892" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9892" rank="species">Thalassomonas loyana</organism><reference id="rid.6265"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barash</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sharon</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosenberg</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassomonas loyana sp. nov., a causative agent of the white plague-like disease of corals on the Eilat coral reef.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>368</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63800-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449441</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassomonas loyana</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassomonas loyana</em> (loy′an.a. N.L. fem. adj. <em>loyana</em> named in honour of the Israeli biologist Y. Loya).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0·5–0·8 μm in width and 1–2 μm in length.</s><s>They form translucent, convex, smooth-rounded colonies with an entire margin that are cream-coloured and 3 mm in size on MA after 3 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs on 0 or ≥ 10·0 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs below 15 °C or at 37 °C or above.</s><s>Tests negative for indole, arginine dihydrolase, oxidase and urease activities.</s><s>Weakly positive for gelatinase activity and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Does not ferment glucose, but hydrolyses aesculin.</s><s>According to Biolog tests, is able to utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-raffinose, turanose, acetate, citrate, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactate, malonate, propionate, succinate, l-alanylglycine, l-glutamate, glycyl-l-aspartate, glycyl-l-glutamate, l-histidine, l-proline, dl-carnitine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize Tween 40, Tween 80, l-arabinose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethylester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenyethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol or dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate as sole carbon source.</s><s>Weakly positive for utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, sucrose, formic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine and 2-aminoethanol according to the Biolog system.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (31·3 %; comprising 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 iso 2-OH), 14 : 0 (13·1 %), 17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (11·7 %), 12 : 0 3-OH (6·3 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (6·6 %), 16 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (5·7 %), 16 : 0 (4. 6 %), 15 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (3·1 %), 11 : 0 3-OH (2·5 %), 12 : 0 (2·3 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1·9 %), 13 : 0 (1·2 %), 14 : 1<em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (1·2 %) and 15 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1·2 %).</s><s>Produces amylase, alginase, DNase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but not agarase or <em>κ</em>-carragenase.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc) erythromycin (10), kanamycin (10), gentamicin (10), ampicillin (10) and tetracycline (10).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species, CBMAI 722<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22536<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from diseased coral in Eilat, Israel.</s></p></content></protolog>