<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12628_nm.22164" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22164" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22164" rank="species">Photobacterium aphoticum</organism><reference id="rid.12628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lucena</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muvira</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium aphoticum sp. nov., isolated from coastal water</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1579</fpage><lpage>1584</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025171-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20675441</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Photobacterium aphoticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Photobacterium aphoticum</em> (a.pho′ti.cum. Gr. pref. <em>a</em> not; Gr. n. <em>phos</em>, <em>photos</em> light; L. neut. suff. -<em>icum</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. neut. adj. <em>aphoticum</em> referring to the non-luminescent character of the species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, motile bacilli, 0.7–1.1×2.2–3.3 µm.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Ferments glucose, galactose and melibiose without production of gas.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows on MA, producing regular colonies 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter with a diffusible light-brown pigment after 24 h of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>No luminescence was observed on MA or LM.</s><s>Grows on TCBS agar producing green (sucrose-negative) colonies.</s><s>Grows at 15 and 37 °C but not at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows well on 0.85–7 % total salts but no growth is observed at 0.35 % or less or in 8 % salinity or greater.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite but not to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Positive for arginine dihydrolase (ADH) and β-galactosidase (ONPG) activities, aesculin hydrolysis and DNase activities but negative for indole production from tryptophan, urease activity, Voges–Proskauer reaction and hydrolysis of gelatin, casein, starch, alginate, agar and Tween-80.</s><s>Produces acid from the following carbohydrates (API 20 E and API 50 CHE): d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, maltose, melibiose and starch.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, β-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>α-Glucosidase activity is variable.</s><s>Does not assimilate any of the substrates included in the API 20 NE system and is unable to grow on any of the carbon sources tested on BM agar, including 26 carbohydrates, 12 organic acids and 16 amino acids, suggesting a nutritional requirement that is covered by yeast extract. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, d-glucose and d-mannose are oxidized in Biolog GN microplates after 24 h incubation.</s><s>Other substrates give variable responses (d-galactose and dextrin) or negative reactions.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/ω6<em>c</em> (37.2 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (10.1 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/ω6<em>c</em> (13.4 %).</s><s>C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and summed features 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I) and 9 (C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 10-methyl and/or iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>) are also present in minor amounts (2–4 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M46<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7614<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 23057<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal seawater in Valencia, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>