<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8834_nm.13652" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13652" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13652" rank="species">Sutterella parvirubra</organism><reference id="rid.8834"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sutterella parvirubra sp. nov. and Megamonas funiformis sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>970</fpage><lpage>975</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65456-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398204</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sutterella parvirubra</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sutterella parvirubra</em> (par.vi.rub′ra. L. adj. <em>parvus</em> small; L. adj. <em>ruber</em> -<em>bra</em> -<em>brum</em> red; N.L. fem. adj. <em>parvirubra</em> small and red, referring to cell size and cell mass colour).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming and coccoid to coccobacillary, approximately 0.4–1×0.4–2 μm, which stain Gram-negative.</s><s>Colonies on GAM agar after 2 days anaerobic incubation are 0.2–1.1 mm in diameter, circular, flat and translucent.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are negative.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Asaccharolytic.</s><s>Weak activity for arginine arylamidase, ester lipase C8 and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase may be detected.</s><s>Using commercially available API test systems, no activity is detected for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase C4, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, lipase C4, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, phosphoamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase, urease or tyrosine arylamidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIT 11816<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19354<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14724<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human faeces.</s><s>Strains YIT 11817 and YIT 11818 are also assigned to this species.</s></p></content></protolog>