<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4689_nm.10548" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10548" rank="genus">Gordona</organism><reference id="rid.4689"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward-Rainey</surname><given-names>N.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for a new hierarchic classification system, Actinobacteria classis nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>479</fpage><lpage>491</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-479</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordona</i> nom.rev., gen.nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-positive, slightly acid-fast short rods or coccoid forms. Rod-coccus life cycle. Mycelium are not formed. Non-motile and neither conidia nor endospores are produced. Growth occurs at 28 and 37°C but not at 45°C. Obligately aerobic chemoorganotrophic with an oxidative type metabolism. Acid is produced from glucose and some other sugars. A wide range of organic compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth. Catalase positive. Oxidase negative. Nitrate is reduced to nitrite. Urease positive. Casein, cellulose, chitin, elastin and xylan are not degraded. Arylsulphatase negative. Cell wall peptidoglycan is based upon meso-diaminopimelic acid (variation Alγ). Glycan moiety of peptidoglycan contains N-glycolylmuramic acid. Wall sugars are arabinose and galactose. Mycolic acids are present with a range of ca. 48 to 66 carbon atoms. Long-chain fatty acids are predominantly of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated, and 10-methyl branched types. MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone; a few strains may have comparable amounts of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>). The major phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol dimannosides. The G+C content of DNA is 63 to 69 mol%. Isolated from sputa of patients with pulmonary disease and from soil. The type species of <i>Gordona</i> is <i>Gordona bronchialis</i> Tsukamura 1971.</s></p></content></protolog>