<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5075_nm.7213" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7213" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7213" rank="species">Streptomyces pseudoechinosporeus</organism><reference id="rid.5075"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Elytrosporangium brasiliense Falcao de Morais et al., Elytrosporangium carpinense Falcao de Morais et al., Elytrosporangium spirale Falcao de Morais et al., Microellobosporia cinerea Cross et al., Microellobosporia flavea Cross et al., Microellobosporia grisea, Konev et al. Pridham and Microellobosporia violacea, Tsiganov et al. Pridham to the genus Streptomyces, with emended description of the species.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>48</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces pseudoechinosporeus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces pseudoechinosporeus</i> (pseu.do.e.chi'no.spo'reus. Gr. adj. <i>pseudo</i> false. Gr. adj. <i>echinos</i> spring appearance. Gr. n. <i>spora</i> seed. M.L. adj. <i>pseudoechino-sporeus</i> false spring spored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from several sources (Konev et al., 1967; Lechevalier and Lechevalier, 1970 b; Pridham, 1974).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic organisms with extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Single, or chains of up to three spores formed on both the substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>The spores have smooth Surfaces and are unequal in size (1.8 to 3.5 μm diam.).</s><s>They were originally thought to be spiny but are now known to be heavily encrusted in needle-like crystals.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is white to glaucous grey; the reverse colour is pink to light violet pink.</s><s>Does not form melanin pigments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is degraded but cellulose is nor.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or produce hydrogen sulphide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, inulin, D-lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, L-rhamnose, starch, sucrose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources but cellulose and sorbitol are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grow at 20, 26 and 37°C but not at 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The wall peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid as the major diamino acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mole % G plus C content of the DNA is 69 (Tsyganov et aI., 1970).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sand collected from the south-wesr part of the Kyzyl-Kum desert, USSR.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 19618 (= DSM 43035 = KCC 3066 = IFO 12518).</s></p></content></protolog>