<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6994_nm.5120" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5120" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5120" rank="species">Paenibacillus brasilensis</organism><reference id="rid.6994"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>von der Weid</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duarte</surname><given-names>G.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Elsas</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seldin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus brasilensis sp. nov., a novel nitrogen-fixing species isolated from the maize rhizosphere in Brazil.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2147</fpage><lpage>2153</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02272-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508882</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus brasilensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus brasilensis</i> (bra.sil.en'sis. N.L. adj. <i>brasilensis</i> referring to Brazil, the country where the strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, motile rods.</s><s>Spores are oval to ellipsoidal and predominantly central to subterminal and distend the sporangium.</s><s>Young GB (Seldin et al., 1983) broth cultures are Gram-positive or Gram-variable.</s><s>On GB agar, colonies are 15-30 mm in diameter, whitish, circular to slightly irregular, convex and mucoid.</s><s>On TBN (Seldin et al., 1984) agar, colonies are about 10 mm in diameter, bright yellow, circular, convex, with entire margins and they adhere to the agar.</s><s>TY broth and agar (van Elsas &#x0026; Penido, 1981) permit poor growth.</s><s>In GB or TBN broth, strains grow abundantly, forming a mucous pellet at the bottom of the tube.</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 42°C; the optimum is 30-32°C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.7, in the presence of 2% NaCl, but not 5% NaCl, and in the presence of lysozyme.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer-positive.</s><s>Dihydroxyacetone is not produced from glycerol.</s><s>No crystalline dextrins are formed in rolled-oat medium.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from glucose.</s><s>Other characteristics of the species can be found in Table 1.</s><s>In addition to the carbohydrates shown in Table 1, acid is produced from galactose, D-fructose, amygdalin, aesculin, maltose, melibiose, sucrose and draffinose, but is not produced from erythritol, L-xylose, adonitol, L-sorbose, L-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5- ketogluconate.</s><s>Nitrogen fixation (acetylene reduction) detected.</s><s>Isolated from the rhizosphere of maize sown in Cerrado soil, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</s><s>The type strain is PB172<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-413<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14914<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given for the species, except for the following results for variable characteristics: positive for liquefaction of gelatin; positive for fermentation of trehalose and D-turanose; negative for fermentation of β-gentiobiose.</s></p></content></protolog>