<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9238_nm.14500" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14500" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14500" rank="species">Microbulbifer epialgicus</organism><reference id="rid.9238"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishijima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takadera</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imamura</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>K.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagao</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sano</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbulbifer variabilis sp. nov. and Microbulbifer epialgicus sp. nov., isolated from Pacific marine algae, possess a rod–coccus cell cycle in association with the growth phase</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1696</fpage><lpage>1707</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006452-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbulbifer epialgicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbulbifer epialgicus</em> (e.pi.al′gi.cus. Gr. prep. <em>epi</em> upon; N.L. masc. adj. <em>algicus</em> pertaining to water plants, to algae; N.L. masc. adj. <em>epialgicus</em> living on algae).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on MA are irregular (young cultures), convex, glossy, transparent to opaque (older cultures).</s><s>Colour of colonies is pale brown, becoming browner in the central portion of older cultures.</s><s>Colonies on 1/10 MA are very thin and spreading.</s><s>Fluorescent pigment is not produced on King's B medium.</s><s>The organism possesses a rod–coccus cell cycle in association with the growth phase; cells are straight, slender, flexible rods in young cultures, and all convert to coccoid–ovoid cells when proliferation ceases by successive division and a probable simultaneous fragmentation of rod cells and rounding of each unit.</s><s>Coccoid–ovoid cells are arranged in orderly chains, and revert to the rod form when transferred to fresh medium.</s><s>Coccoid–ovoid cells are optically dense and have a coarse surface.</s><s>They survive for extended periods and are considered to be a resting form.</s><s>Spherical bodies (aberrant form) are formed.</s><s>The rod cells of the type strain are 3.0–13.5 μm long and 0.35–0.65 μm wide on 1/10 MA in young cultures and the coccoid–ovoid cells are 0.45–1.10 μm in diameter and 0.75–1.10 and 0.40–0.75 μm along their major and minor axes, respectively, on 1/10 MA in older cultures.</s><s>The rod cells possess fibrous peritrichous structures on the surface.</s><s>Slightly halophilic; the range of NaCl concentrations for growth is 0.5–6.5 % (w/v) with an optimum of 2.0 %.</s><s>Does not grow in the absence of NaCl or in 7.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> and a bivalent cation, Mg<sup>2+</sup> or Ca<sup>2+</sup>, for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C with an optimum of 30 °C, but not at 5 or 45 °C.</s><s>It grows at pH 6.0–9.0 and optimally at pH 7.0–8.0, but not at pH 5.5 or 9.5.</s><s>Cells use ammoniacal nitrogen; does not require growth factors and does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>Polyhydroxybutyrate is not accumulated.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Starch, gelatin, casein, DNA, Tween 80 and lecithin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Agar, chitin and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, urease, indole production and PNPG test.</s><s>d-Glucose, mannose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, starch, propionate, l-alanine, l-glutamate and l-asparagine are used.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, melezitose, glycerol, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, dulcitol, formate, acetate, fumarate, dl-malate, malonate, succinate, citrate, alginate, benzoate, gluconate, dl-serine and l-arginine are not used.</s><s>Tests for the following enzymes are positive with the API ZYM gallery: alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase (weak), trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Hydroxy fatty acids are C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylserine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 49 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is F-104<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC03330<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18651<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the surface of a green alga collected on the seashore in Palau in the Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>