<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1543_nm.10949" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10949" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10949" rank="species">Phycicoccus jejuensis</organism><reference id="rid.1543"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phycicoccus jejuensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from seaweed</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2369</fpage><lpage>2373</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64271-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012564</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phycicoccus jejuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phycicoccus jejuensis</em> (je.ju.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>jejuensis</em> of Jeju, Republic of Korea, the site at which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile, non-endospore-forming, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells are cocci that occur singly, in pairs, in short chains or in clusters.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, translucent and moderately yellow in colour.</s><s>The chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction is observed.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, DNA and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Elastin is degraded.</s><s>Glucose fermentation does not occur.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C, with an optimum at 30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 40 °C.</s><s>The pH for growth is in the range pH 5.1–10.1, with an optimum of pH 7.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–7 % NaCl.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: dextrin, glycogen, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Utilization of the following substrates is weakly positive: inulin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, maltotriose, 3-methyl d-glucoside, d-lactic acid methyl ester, monomethyl succinate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid and adenosine 5′-monophosphate.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, methylpyruvate and d-malic acid are not used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Of the tests in the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are positive.</s><s>Tests for <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 74 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KSW2-15<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42315<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24460<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from dried seaweed on Gwakji beach on Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>