<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4327_nm.6573" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6573" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6573" rank="species">Catellatospora koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.4327"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catellatospora koreensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from a gold-mine cave.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1103</fpage><lpage>1111</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843051</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Catellatospora koreensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Catellatospora koreensis</i> (ko.re.en'sis. M.L. adj. <i>koreensis</i> of Korea (pertaining to Korean soil from which the organism was isolated))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms a welL-developed, branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>An aerial mycelium is absent.</s><s>Short chains of spores are borne directly on substrate mycelium.</s><s>Spores are cylindrical and non-motile.</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>The colour of substrate mycelium is cream to light yellow.</s><s>Globose bodies are formed.</s><s>A soluble pigment is not produced.</s><s>Good growth on oatmeal agar, inorganic salt}starch agar, glucose/asparagine agar, glucose}yeast extract agar, Hickey-Tresner agar and Bennett agar.</s><s>Poor to moderate growth on glycerol/asparagine agar, yeast extract agar, nutrient agar, tyrosine agar and tapwater agar.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0-9.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is between 20 and 37 °C.</s><s>Utilizes L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-raffinose, starch, sucrose and D-xylose as carbon sources.Noutilization of D-arabinose, dextran, gluconate, inulin, D-melezitose, melibiose, methyl α-dglucoside, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, L-sorbose, D-trehalose, adonitol, dulcitol, butanol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, ethanol, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, 2-propanol, propanol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol and D-xylitol.</s><s>Does not degrade adenine, hippurate, hypoxanthine, DL-tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, gelatin and starch but not DNA.</s><s>Grows on 0.001% brilliant green and 0.0001% crystal violet.</s><s>No growth on 3% NaCl and 0.01% lysozyme.</s><s>Susceptible to 50 μg novobiocin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 20 μg vancomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 100 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, and 10 μg tetracycline ml<sup>-1</sup>, but resistant to 50 μg gentamicin ml<sup>-1</sup>and 5 μg neomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, rhamnose, ribose, xylose, mannose and glucose (a type II cell wall and a variant of sugar pattern D).</s><s>The acyl type of muramic acid is glycolyl.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), with minor amounts of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The diagnostic phospholipids contain phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>Glucosamine-containing phospholipid and phosphatidylcholine are absent.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids (&#x003E;15±0% of total) are iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and C<sub>17:1</sub> acids.</s><s>A signi®cant amount of saturated, unsaturated and anteiso-branched fatty acids are also present.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 70.4 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from a gold-mine cave.</s><s>The type strain is LM 042<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 50729<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>