<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8757_nm.13715" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13715" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13715" rank="species">Elioraea tepidiphila</organism><reference id="rid.8757"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Elioraea tepidiphila gen. nov., sp. nov., a slightly thermophilic member of the Alphaproteobacteria</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>773</fpage><lpage>778</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65294-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398168</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Elioraea tepidiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Elioraea tepidiphila</em> (te.pi.di.phi′la. L. adj. <em>tepidus</em> warm; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>tepidiphila</em> loving warmth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 1.0–1.5 μm long and 0.5–1.0 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies on R3A medium without starch and glucose are not pigmented.</s><s>Slightly thermophilic; the optimum growth temperature is about 45–50 °C and growth does not occur at 25 or 55 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 8.0 and 8.5; growth does not occur at pH 5.5 or 10.0.</s><s>Grows in media with up to 1.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 18 : 0 (24.8 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (19.0 %), 19 : 0 2-OH cyclo <em>ω</em>8 (Δ11 : 12) (18.6 %), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (12.4 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11-methyl (8.0 %), 16 : 0 (5.4 %) and 18 : 0 3-OH (3.8 %).</s><s>Starch, xylan and hippurate are degraded; aesculin, arbutin, gelatin, casein and elastin are not degraded.</s><s>DNase-positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase test positive in API ZYM; other activities test negative.</s><s>Succinate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, glutamate, fumarate, gluconate, citrate, proline and glutamine are assimilated; glucose, mannose, galactose, fructose, sorbose, d- and l-arabinose, ribose, xylose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, cellobiose, melibiose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, l-fucose, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, erythritol, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, acetate, aspartate, formate, glucuronate, alanine, asparagine, phenylalanine, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, arginine, serine, threonine, valine, ornithine and cysteine are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following carbohydrates using API 50CH: ribose, fructose, l-sorbose, tagatose and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70.9±0.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TU-7<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17972<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109115<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hot spring at Furnas on the island of São Miguel in the Azores.</s></p></content></protolog>