<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8270_nm.6033" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6033" rank="family">Microbacteriaceae</organism><reference id="rid.8270"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>An update of the structure and 16S rRNA gene sequence-based definition of higher ranks of the class Actinobacteria, with the proposal of two new suborders and four new families and emended descriptions of the existing higher taxa.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>589</fpage><lpage>608</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65780-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244447</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the family <em>Microbacteriaceae</em> Park <em>et al.</em> 1995 (effective publication Park <em>et al.</em>, 1993), emend. Rainey <em>et al.</em> 1997</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The family contains the type genus <em>Microbacterium</em> Orla-Jensen 1919, emend. Takeuchi and Hatano 1998, as well as the genera <em>Agreia</em> Evtushenko <em>et al.</em> 2001, <em>Agrococcus</em> Groth <em>et al.</em> 1996, <em>Agromyces</em> Gledhill and Casida 1969, emend. Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em> 1992, <em>Clavibacter</em> Davis <em>et al.</em> 1984, <em>Cryobacterium</em> Suzuki <em>et al.</em> 1997, <em>Curtobacterium</em> Yamada and Komagata 1972, <em>Frigoribacterium</em> Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> 2000, <em>Frondihabitans</em> Greene <em>et al.</em> 2009 (previous illegitimate name <em>Frondicola</em> Zhang <em>et al.</em> 2007b), <em>Glaciibacter</em> Katayama <em>et al.</em> 2009, <em>Gulosibacter</em> Manaia <em>et al.</em> 2004, <em>Klugiella</em> Cook <em>et al.</em> 2008, <em>Labedella</em> Lee 2007, <em>Leifsonia</em> Evtushenko <em>et al.</em> 2000, <em>Leucobacter</em> Takeuchi <em>et al.</em> 1996, <em>Microbacterium</em> Orla-Jensen 1919, emend. Takeuchi and Hatano 1998, <em>Microcella</em> Tiago <em>et al.</em> 2005, emend. Tiago <em>et al.</em> 2006, <em>Microterricola</em> Matsumoto <em>et al.</em> 2008, <em>Mycetocola</em> Tsukamoto <em>et al.</em> 2001, <em>Okibacterium</em> Evtushenko <em>et al.</em> 2002, <em>Plantibacter</em> Behrendt <em>et al.</em> 2002, <em>Phycicola</em> Lee <em>et al.</em> 2008b, <em>Pseudoclavibacter</em> Manaia <em>et al.</em> 2004, <em>Rathayibacter</em> Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em> 1993, <em>Rhodoglobus</em> Sheridan <em>et al.</em> 2003, <em>Salinibacterium</em> Han <em>et al.</em> 2003, <em>Subtercola</em> Männistö <em>et al.</em> 2000 and <em>Yonghaparkia</em> Yoon <em>et al.</em> 2006.</s><s>The pattern of 16S rRNA signature nucleotides is shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>