<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12505_nm.21346" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21346" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1476" rank="species">Bradyrhizobium denitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.12505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Berkum</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leibold</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eardly</surname><given-names>B. D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for combining Bradyrhizobium spp. (Aeschynomene indica) with Blastobacter denitrificans and to transfer Blastobacter denitrificans (Hirsch and Muller, 1985) to the genus Bradyrhizobium as Bradyrhizobium denitrificans (comb. nov.)</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>215</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.07.014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16564957</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bradyrhizobium denitrificans</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of the type strain LMG 8443 of <em>B. denitrificans</em> (de.ni.tri’fi.cans L. prep. <em>de</em> away from; L. n. <em>nitrum</em> soda; M. L. n. <em>nitrum</em> nitrate; M. L. v. <em>denitrifico</em> denitrify; M. L. part. adj. <em>denitrificans</em> denitrifying) is the same as the genus <a href="#bib10">[10]</a> and species description <a href="#bib8">[8]</a> and includes the following:</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells rod-shaped with rounded poles.</s><s>Buds rod-shaped and originating sub-polarly (<a href="#fig3">Fig. 3</a>).</s><s>Cells are noncapsulated, gram-negative, not acid-fast, do not form spores or cysts, 0.6–0.8×1.5–2.3 μm.</s><s>Grow in liquid media as turbidity.</s><s>Colonies glistening, raised and round with entire edges, and may form pink or orange pigments with light exposure or in the dark.</s><s>Grow well on dilute media at 30 °C, some strains tolerate 41 °C.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, they utilize a range of carbohydrates including: <em>α</em>-oxoglutarate, fructose, galactose, glucose, glutamate, glycerol, lactose, mannitol, pyruvate, ribose, and succinic acid.</s><s>Some strains also utilize acetate, citrate, ethanol (0.4% v/v), formate, formamide, fumarate, glycine, glucuronic acid lactone, histidine, leucine, malate, maltose, methanol (0.5% v/v), <em>N</em>-acetyl glucosamine, proline, sucrose, and tartrate as carbon sources.</s><s>Carbon sources that are not utilized include: alanine, arginine, aspartate, caproate, cellobiose, dextrin, indole, inulin, lactate, phenylalanine, pthalate, proprionate, salicin, serine, or starch.</s><s>Pigmented strains are capable of aerobic heterotrophic photosynthesis growth under light.</s><s>Ammonium salts, Bacto-peptone, casein hydrolysate, and yeast extract are all utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Most strains can utilize nitrate as a sole nitrogen source, and most are capable of dissimilatory nitrate reduction.</s><s>Nitrite is not utilized as a nitrogen source.</s><s>Some strains are capable of utilizing methylamine HCl and urea as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Strains are able to invade roots and stems of some species of <em>Aeschynomene</em> and elicit the production of root nodules, where they participate in endosymbiotic nitrogen fixation.</s></p></content></protolog>