<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.130_nm.8103" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8103" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8103" rank="species">Flavobacterium multivorum</organism><reference id="rid.130"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Owen</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium multivorum, a new species isolated from human clinical specimens and previously known as Group IIk, Biotype 2.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>21</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium multivorum</i> (mul.ti.vo'rum. L. adj. <i>multus</i> many; L. trans.v. <i>vorare</i> to swallow; M.L. adj. <i>multivorus</i> intended to mean "produces acid from many carbohydrates")</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the type strain, B5533 (= NCTC 11343), also listed in Tables 2 through 4, are as follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods, 1.0 μm in length, of regular shape with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Nonmotile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular, low convex, smooth, and opaque colonies developing on nutrient agar after 2 days; colonies nonhemolytic on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar; on nutrient agar, production of a yellow pigment which is not fluorescent.</s><s>No production of brown pigment on tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic; no growth under anaerobic conditions in an atmosphere of pure hydrogen, but possible growth in the presence of 7% (vol/vol) CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 37°C but not at 5 or 42°C.</s><s>Optimum temperature: about 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of catalase, cytochrome oxidase, and deoxyribonuclease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of urease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No toleration of KCN at a concentration of 0.0075% (wt/vol).</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 20 and Tween 80.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of nitrate to nitrite; no reduction of nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of indole and hydrogen sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on MacConkey agar, but not on cetrimide agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No digestion of casein and no hydrolysis of gelatin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of esculin and tributyrin, but not starch or tyrosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No utilization of citrate and malonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No oxidation of gluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of arginine deimidase, arginine deiminase, lysine decarboxylase, and ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of 3-ketolactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of selenite and and no deamination of phenylalanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of phosphatase and β-D-galactosidase (when tested, respectively, by method 1 of Cowan and the method given by Holmes et al.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, fructose, lactose, maltose, raffmose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from adonitol, dulcitol, ethanol, inositol, mannitol, or sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid or gas from glucose in peptone-water medium; production of acid in only the open tube of Hugh and Leifson oxidation-fermentation glucose medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of the following enzymes (using various API ZYM galleries): alkaline phosphatase, esterase-lipase (C-8), L-Ieucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, β-D-galactosidase, α-D-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminidase, lactosidase, ,β-D-cellobiosidase, L-pyroglutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-phenylalanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-lysyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-histidyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-L-aspartyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-arginyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-alanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-L-glutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, S-benzyl-L-cysteyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-methionyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-glycylglycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-L-phenylalanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-L-prolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-leucyl-glycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-seryl-L-tyrosyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-glutaminyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-L-glutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-ornithyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-seryl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-threonyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-tryptophyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of the following enzymes (using various API ZYM galleries): esterase (C-4), lipase (C-14), L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-benzoyl-DL-arginyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-glutaryl-L-phenylalanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-D-galactosidase, β-D-glucuronidase, β-D-glucosidase, α-D-mannosidase, α-L-fucosidase, β-D-xylosidase, phosphatase, α-D-xylosidase, β-D-fucosidase, β-L-fucosidase, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminidase, arylsulfatase, α-L-arabinosidase, L-tyrosyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-hydroxyprolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-benzoyl-L-Ieucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-carbobenzoxY-L-arginyl-4-methoxyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-isoleucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, and L-prolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to streptomycin, kanamycin, gentamicin, tobramycin, amikacin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephaloridine, erythromycin, polymyxin B, and nalidixic acid and moderately susceptible to sulfamethoxazole, co-trimoxazole, trimethoprim, chloramphenicol, and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content of DNA: 39.3 mol% (thermal denaturation temperature estimation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: isolated from a spleen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two additional strains of <i>F. multivorum</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: NCTC 11033 and NCTC 11034 (group Ilk, biotype 2, strains A8895 and B3159, respectively) .</s></p></content></protolog>