<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10093_nm.15046" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15046" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15046" rank="species">Aeromonas fluvialis</organism><reference id="rid.10093"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Alperi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Murcia</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monera</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saavedra</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Figueras</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas fluvialis sp. nov., isolated from a Spanish river</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>72</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011643-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648345</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromonas fluvialis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aeromonas fluvialis</em> (flu.vi.a′lis. L. fem. adj. <em>fluvialis</em> belonging to a river).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, Gram-stain-negative, non-spore-forming rods, non-encapsulated, mobile by single polar flagella, 0.6–0.7 μm wide and 3–3.5 μm long, oxidase- and catalase-positive, reduce nitrate to nitrite and are resistant to vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are 4–5 mm in diameter, opaque, circular and beige in colour after 48 h at 30 °C.</s><s>No brown diffusible pigment is produced on TSA at room temperature or 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C after 24 h in TSB.</s><s>Grows at 37 °C but not at 4 °C or 40 °C on TSA.</s><s>No haemolysis observed on sheep blood agar at 30 °C.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar and on TSB without NaCl but not with 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth at pH 9 after 24 h on TSB but no growth at pH 4.5.</s><s>Produces indole from tryptophan and gas from glucose, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and able to use citrate.</s><s>Negative for production of hydrogen sulphide from cysteine, VP test and hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin and elastin.</s><s>No DNase, urease or l-tryptophan deaminase activity.</s><s>Does not produce ADH, LDC or ODC.</s><s>Able to use d-mannose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate and malic acid as sole carbon and energy sources, but not l-arabinose, d-mannitol, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid or trisodium citrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, lactose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and potassium gluconate, but not from erythritol, l- or d-arabinose, l- or d-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, l- or d-fucose, l- or d-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Resistant to amoxycillin, amoxycillin plus clavulanic acid and ticarcillin, intermediately resistant to ticarcillin plus clavulanic acid and susceptible to the rest of the antimicrobials tested.</s><s>The API20E and API20NE profiles obtained for strain 717<sup>T</sup> were 1240024 and 7062744 respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 717<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7401<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24681<sup>T</sup>), isolated from water of the Muga river, Girona, north-east Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>