<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.417_nm.1479" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1479" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1479" rank="species">Bosea thiooxidans</organism><reference id="rid.417"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Das</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mishra</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oxidation of thiosulfate by a new bacterium, Bosea thiooxidans (strain BI-42) gen. nov., sp. nov.: analysis of phylogeny based on chemotaxonomy and 16S ribosomal DNA sequencing.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>981</fpage><lpage>987</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-981</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863427</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bosea thiooxidans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bosea thiooxidans</i> (thi.o. ox'i. dans. Gr. n. <i>thion</i>, sulfur; M.L.v. <i>oxido</i>, make acid, oxidize; M.L. part. adj. <i>thiooxidans</i>, oxidizing sulfur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This bacterium was isolated from agricultural soil.</s><s>Cells are straight rods that are 0.85 μm wide by 1.4 to 1.6 μm long.</s><s>Cells occur singly.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on agar containing thiosulfate and succinate or yeast extract are smooth, mucoid, round, and cream colored; these colonies are about 1 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 4 days of incubation.</s><s>No sulfur deposition occurs on the colony surfaces.</s><s>Glutamate, glutamine, and aspartate, but not NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>, NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, and urea, can serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>This organism can denitrify and produce gas only in heterotrophic growth medium containing nitrate.</s><s>It has glutamate awotrophy and requires yeast extract (0.1 g/liter) as a growth factor.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0 to 9.0, and the optimum pH is 7.5 to 8.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A variety of organic compounds support heterotrophic growth in GYM medium.</s><s>These compounds include glucose, fructose, rhamnose, xylose, sorbose, ribose, arabinose, galactose, citrate, gluconate, succinate, malate, acetate, glutamate, glutamine, proline, cysteine, aspartic acid, serine, asparagine, alanine, lysine, common hexoses, pentoses, and organic acids, pyruvate, and some amino acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is a chemolithoheterotroph.</s><s>Thiosulfate stimulates growth in the presence of succinate. <i>Tetrathionate</i> is oxidized slowly.</s><s>Sulfite, thiocyanate, and elemental sulfur do not support growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 68.2 mol%.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 is the major ubiquinone.</s><s>A culture of the type strain has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 9653.</s></p></content></protolog>