<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.673_nm.2712" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2712" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2712" rank="species">Azomonas macrocytogenes</organism><reference id="rid.673"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>New</surname><given-names>P.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tchan</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azomonas macrocytogenes, (ex Baillie, Hodgkiss and Norris 1962, 118) nom. rev.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>382</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-381</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>This aerobic, nonsymbiotic, nitrogen-fixing organism was originally included by Jensen in the microcyst-forming genus <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i>, although the author was not certain whether cysts are actually formed (7). Baillie et al. (2) assigned the organism to the genus <i>Azomonas</i> on the basis of polar flagellation and lack of cyst formation. However, Thompson and Skerman (11) have reported cyst formation by four of seven strains. The discrepancies in the reports may be reconciled by the electron microscopic study of Tchan (lo), which shows that the cystlike cells of <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> are surrounded by a thick layer of capsular-like material rather than the layered outer wall of a typical cyst of <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i>. On the basis of a numerical taxonomic study, Thompson and Skerman (11) excluded <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> from the genera <i>Azomonas</i> and <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> and placed it in the new genus <i>Azomonotrichon</i>. The exclusion of this organism from the genus <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> is supported by deoxyribonucleic acid base composition and homology studies (4) and ribosomal ribonucleic acid cistron similarities (5); however, the exclusion from the genus <i>Azomonas</i> is not so justifiable. <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> and <i>Azomonas insignis</i> are more similar to each other than to the third member of the genus, Azomonas agilis, in terms of flagellation (2) and deoxyribonucleic acid base composition (4). Although the three species differed as much from one another as from species of <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i> in terms of their ribosomal ribonucleic acid cistrons, de Smedt et al. (5) proposed that all three species should be included in the genus <i>Azomonas</i> until more information becomes available.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We therefore propose the revival of the name <i>Azomonas macrocytogenes</i>.</s><s>The organism has been described previously (3, 11).</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 12335 (= strain 0 of Jensen [7] = NCIB 8700 = WR 111).</s></p></content></protolog>