<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8407_nm.13382" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13382" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13382" rank="species">Lactobacillus fabifermentans</organism><reference id="rid.8407"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Bruyne</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Camu</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vuyst</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus fabifermentans sp. nov. and Lactobacillus cacaonum sp. nov., isolated from Ghanaian cocoa fermentations.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>7</fpage><lpage>12</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001172-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus fabifermentans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus fabifermentans</em> (fa.bi.fer.men′tans. L. n. <em>faba</em> a bean; L. part. adj. <em>fermentans</em> fermenting; N.L. part. adj. <em>fabifermentans</em> of fermenting beans).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-negative, facultatively anaerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Cells are long rods (1.0–3.0 μm wide and 10.0 μm long) that appear singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies are greyish white, opaque, smooth and circular with a convex elevation and an entire margin (diameter approx. 1.0 mm).</s><s>Growth is observed at temperatures from 10 °C (from day 8 of incubation) up to 37 °C (immediate growth from day 1 of incubation).</s><s>At 37 °C, growth is observed in MRS broth (pH 3.9).</s><s>Growth occurs in MRS broth supplemented with 6 % NaCl.</s><s>The type strain (LMG 24284<sup>T</sup>) produces lactic acid only as a metabolite from glucose.</s><s>The ratio of production of d- and l-lactic acid isomers is 80 : 20.</s><s>No gas production is observed.</s><s>Arginine is deaminated.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate or 2- or 5-ketogluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 24284<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21115<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a cocoa bean heap fermentation in Ghana.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>