<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11904_nm.19990" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19990" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19990" rank="species">Amorphus orientalis</organism><reference id="rid.11904"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>S.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amorphus orientalis sp. nov., an exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium isolated from salt mine sediment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1750</fpage><lpage>1754</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015735-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749037</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amorphus orientalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amorphus orientalis</em> (o.ri.en.ta′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>orientalis</em> eastern, bacterium inhabiting the east).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are cream–white, smooth, circular, convex and opaque with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-motile, rod-shaped structures of 1.0–2.5 μm in length that differ morphologically.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C; optimum is 28 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.5–8.5; optimum is 7.5.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–12 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive for urease, arginine dihydrolase and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Negative for aesculin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, glucose acidification, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, and l-phenylalanine deaminase activity.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized: l-arabinose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, citrate, dextrin, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, sucrose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, citric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, succinic acid and glycerol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: adonitol, d-arabitol, d-fructose, l-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, formic acid, d- and l-lactic acids, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-aspartic acid, l-ornithine, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, d- and l-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, d- and l-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate and d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities: alkaline and acid phosphatases, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), myristate lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc) novobiocin (30), gentamicin (10) and penicillin (10), but resistant to ampicillin (10), erythromycin (15), chloramphenicol (30), norfloxacin (10) and streptomycin (10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM D10<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21202<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 208035<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt sediment sample collected from the Fenggang salt mine in Yunnan, south-west China.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>