<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8700_nm.13605" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13605" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13605" rank="species">Sanguibacter soli</organism><reference id="rid.8700"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pulla</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>T.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soung</surname><given-names>N.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sanguibacter soli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>538</fpage><lpage>541</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65399-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sanguibacter soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sanguibacter soli</em> (so′li. L. neut. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, motile rods when grown on R2A agar (Difco) at 30 °C for 5 days.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 5 days are yellow.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5–9.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, glycerol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, aesculin and salicin, but not from gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, d-arabinose, d- or l-fucose, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-rhamnose, raffinose, ribose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose, d-adonitol (ribitol), d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol (galactitol), erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, xylitol, amygdalin or inulin.</s><s>Positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase (C8), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, protease (gelatin hydrolysis) and urease.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, l-arabinose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, glycogen and salicin, but not 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, adipate, caprate, citrate, gluconate, itaconate, l-lactate, l-malate, malonate, phenyl acetate, propionate, suberate, n-valerate, l-fucose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-proline or l-serine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.8 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The predominant quinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids include unknown ECL 13.961 (45.81 %), 17 : 0 anteiso (23.46 %), 18 : 0 iso (15.42 %), unknown ECL 14.966 (8.70 %), 12 : 0 anteiso (3.35 %) and 18 : 3<em>ω</em>6,9,12<em>c</em> (2.63 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DCY22<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13155<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14841<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>