<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3373_nm.4148" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4148" rank="genus">Roseburia</organism><reference id="rid.3373"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Savage</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseburia cecicola gen. nov. sp. nov., a motile , obligately anaerobic bacterium from a mouse cecum.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>618</fpage><lpage>627</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-618</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Roseburia gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Roseburia (Rose.bur'.i.a. M.L. fem. n. <i>Roseburia</i> in honor of Theodor Rosebury, an American microbiologist who studied and described microorganisms indigenous to humans)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slightly curved rod-shaped cells (0.5 by 2.5 to 5 μm) occur singly and in pairs.</s><s>Actively motile at 37°C in anaerobic broth by means of 20 to 35 flagella which are inserted along the concave side and occasionally along one end of the cell.</s><s>The flagella appear as a single, subterminal fascicle when cells are examined by phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>Gram-negative, as determined by the staining reaction and by electron microscopy of ultrathin cell sections.</s><s>Cells do not form spores.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth in VTY broth (final cell density, 5 x 10<sup>8</sup> cells per ml; population doubling time, 2h) at 37°C.</s><s>Grows at 30°C but not at 22 or 45°C.</s><s>Cultured in VTY broth (medium containing volatile fatty acids, yeast extract, Trypticase peptone, inorganic salts, hemin, and glucose) under anaerobic conditions (95% N<sub>2</sub>-5% C0<sub>2</sub> atmosphere).</s><s>No growth occurs aerobically.</s><s>Subsurface colonies in VTY medium supplemented with 0.7% Noble agar are 1 mm in diameter, brownish white, lens shaped, and occasionally surrounded by gas pockets which split the agar medium.</s><s>Surface colonies are white, mucoid, granular in appearance, 1.5 to 3 mm in diameter, and circular with smooth edges.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Butyrate is the major or sole acid product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Acetate is utilized during glucose fermentation.</s><s>The products of growing cells (in micromoles per 100 μmol of glucose and 100 μmol of acetate utilized) are as follows: butyrate, 154; ethanol, 12; C0<sub>2</sub>, 240; H<sub>2</sub>, amount undetermined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic, catalase negative, obligate anaerobe.</s><s>The G+C content of strain GMT DNA is 42.3 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Isolated from mouse cecal mucosa.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: <i>R. cecicola</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>