<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3362_nm.5016" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5016" rank="genus">Exiguobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.3362"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lund</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemotaxonomic study of an alkalophilic bacterium, Exiguobacterium aurantiacum gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>129</volume><fpage>2037</fpage><lpage>2042</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Exiguobacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Exiguobacterium</i> (L. adj. <i>exiguus</i> short, small; Gr. neut. dim. n. <i>bakterion</i> a small rod; M.L. neut. n. <i>Exiguobacterium</i> small rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells vary in shape from rods (3.2 x 1.2 μm) in the exponential phase to short, almost coccoid forms (1-4 x 1.1 μm) in the stationary phase (Gee et al., 1980).</s><s>Both rods and coccoid cells are Gram-positive, non-acid fast and motile; endospores are not formed.</s><s>The organism is facultatively anaerobic, catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, sucrose, galactose and some other sugars.</s><s>In anaerobic conditions with glucose as substrate, lactate, acetate and formate are major end products, the proportions depending on cultural conditions (Gee et al., 1980).</s><s>The cell wall contains a group A type peptidoglycan based on lysine.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>Menaquinones are the sole respiratory quinones; the principal quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The DNA base compositions of two strains are 53.2 to 55.8 mol% G + C.</s><s>The type species is <i>Exiguobacterium aurantiacum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>