<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4614_nm.3051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3051" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3051" rank="species">Aeromonas bestiarum</organism><reference id="rid.4614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carnahan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altwegg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luthy-Hottenstein</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas bestiarum sp. nov., formerly genomospecies DNA group 2 A. hydrophila, a new species isolated from non-human sources.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>156</fpage><lpage>165</lpage><source id="158">Medical Microbiology Letters : an international journal for rapid communications on all aspects of medical and clinical microbiology</source><abbrev>Med Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>1018-4627</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Designation of <i>Aeromonas bestiarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas bestiarum</i>  (bes.ti.a' rum, derived from the Latin noun, <i>bestiarum</i>, meaning of beasts (whether wild or domestic))</s></p><p class="description"><s>This designation was selected since a majority of the strains originated from veterinary and environmental sources (73%).</s><s>The type strain of this species is designated as ATCC 51108<sup>T</sup> (formerly CDC 9533-76, CIP 7430, Popoff C218), previously deposited at ATCC in 1992 by F.</s><s>W.</s><s>Hickman-Brenner.</s><s>The biochemical profile of phenotypic characteristics for the type strain ATCC 51108<sup>T</sup> and the other 8 <i>A. bestiarum</i> strains is listed in Table 1.</s><s>This species has a unique biochemical profile of negative reactions for: utilization of D-L lactate, acid production from sorbitol, and a positive reaction for utilization of urocanic acid (25°C and 35°C±1°)(Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Clinical/Significance.</s><s>Of the 9 confirmed <i>A. bestiarum</i> strains, only two (27%) were isolated from human sources.</s><s>Whether or not these 2 strains were associated with patent clinical infection is not known.</s><s>To examine their potential role in human infections, it will be important to isolate and study a large number of <i>A. bestiarum</i> strains in a suitable animal model.</s><s>In a recent study of 80 hybridized <i>Aeromonas</i> strains that established baseline data on the pathogenicity of 12 <i>Aeromonas</i> genomospecies in outbred mice, five HG 2 strains from environmental and animal sources were tested (9).</s><s>They ranked seventh in decreasing order of relative virulence between HGs 1and 3.</s><s>HG1 <i>A. hvdrophila</i> displayed the second highest virulence potential of 12 genomospecies tested and HG3 <i>A. salmonicida</i> strains were ranked just below HG 2 <i>A. bestiarum</i>.</s><s>This suggests a possible low virulence potential for humans among <i>A. bestiarum</i> strains and may in part explain the low incidence with which they are isolated in relation to the large numbers of clinical <i>Aeromonas</i> strains found among HGs 1,4 and 8 as reported in previous studies(2,5, 10).</s></p></content></protolog>