<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6152_nm.3103" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3103" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3103" rank="species">Arsenophonus nasoniae</organism><reference id="rid.6152"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gherna</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Werren</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weisburg</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cote</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arsenophonus nasoniae gen. nov., sp. nov., the causative agent of the son-killer trait in the parasitic wasp Nasonia vitripennis.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>563</fpage><lpage>565</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-4-563</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arsenophonus nasoniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arsenophonus nasoniae</i> (na. so.' ni. ae. N. L. <i>Nasonia</i>, genus of a fly; <i>nasoniae</i>, of the genus <i>Nasonia</i>.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are nonmotile, non-spore-forming, long rods, occasionally filamentous in young cultures (0.40 to 0.57 μm wide by 6.9 to 10.0 μm long).</s><s>Colonies are mucoid, grey-white, round, and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Does not utilize (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, KNO<sub>3</sub>, complete defined amino acid mixtures, or acid-hydrolyzed peptones (Casamino Acids) as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Enzymatically digested proteins best serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, fructose, and sucrose as primary carbon sources; weak growth is obtained with cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, fructose, and sucrose.</s><s>Growth is negative with adonitol, L-arabinose, dulcitol, glycerol, <i>i</i>-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, and raffinose.</s><s>Positive for gelatin liquefaction and catalase.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, Voges-Proskauer, methyl red, indole, hydrogen sulfide, oxidase, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, arginine dehydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, and urease.</s><s>Minimum, optimum, and maximum temperatures are 15, 30, and 35°C, respectively.</s><s>Cells grow at a pH of 6.2 to 8.7, with an optimum pH range of 7.4 to 8.0.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is SKI4 (= ATCC 49151), isolated from an <i>N. vitripennis</i> son-killer strain collected near Salt Lake City, Utah. <i>A. nasoniae</i> is the causative agent of the son-killer trait in the parasitic wasp <i>N. vitripennis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>