<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.78_nm.4038" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4038" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4038" rank="species">Clostridium thermocopriae</organism><reference id="rid.78"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toda</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thermocopriae sp. nov., a cellulolytic thermophile from animal feces, compost, soil, and a hot spring in Japan.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>279</fpage><lpage>281</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Clostridium thermocopriae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Clostridium thermocopriae (ther. mo. co' pri.ae. Gr.n. <i>thermos</i>, heat; Gr.n. <i>kupria</i>, compost; M.L. gen.n. <i>thermocopriae</i> of heat compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 0.4 to 0.7 μm wide by 2.0 to 8.0 μm long (type strain, 0.5 to 0.7 by 2.2 to 6.0 μm) in PY medium containing 1% cellobiose after growth for 18 h at 55 to 60μC.</s><s>These organisms produce terminal spherical endospores (diameter, 1.2 to 1.6 μm) which swell the cells.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Colonies on cellulose agar medium are smooth and 1 to 2 mm in diameter and have clear zones (diameter, 2 to 4 mm) showing complete solubilization of cellulose within 3 to 6 days.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 60°C; growth occurs at 47 to 74°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0 to 8.0; the optimum pH is 6.5 to 7.3.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Gelatin is not digested.</s><s>The type strain and two other strains hydrolyze starch.</s><s>The type strain and three other strains produce curd in milk.</s><s>These organisms utilize cellulose, hemicellulose, cellobiose, glucose, fructose, maltose, and mannose; the final pH in PY broth is 5.2 to 5.9 (Table 1).</s><s>The pH of modified CM3 broth supplemented with cellobiose is 4.9 to 5.3 after incubation for 2 days.</s><s>The type strain and four other strains utilize arabinose, lactose, and trehalose.</s><s>The type strain and three other strains utilize glycogen and amygdalin.</s><s>Melibiose and mannitol are not utilized.</s><s>In the fermentation of carbohydrates, carbon dioxide, hydrogen, ethanol, and acetic, butyric, and lactic acids are produced, but propionic and valeric acids are not produced.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 36.7 to 37.8 mol% (type strain, 37.2 mol%).</s><s>Isolated from camel feces, compost, soil, and a hot spring in Japan (Table 2).</s><s>The type strain is strain JT3-3 (=IAM 13577) (Fig. 1).</s></p></content></protolog>