<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2262_nm.3984" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3984" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3984" rank="species">Clostridium paradoxum</organism><reference id="rid.2262"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a moderately thermophilic anaerobic alkaliphile, Clostridium paradoxum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>450</fpage><lpage>460</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-450</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium paradoxum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium paradoxum</i> sp. nov.; para.doxum. Gr. <i>para</i> (akin to Gr.pro, before, ahead) plus <i>doxos</i> (fr. Gr. dokein, to seem, to think, opinion); Gr. <i>paradoxon</i>, fr. neut. of <i>paradoxos</i>, contrary to expectation; M.L. <i>paradoxum</i>, referring to the unusual property of sporulated cells to be highly motile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following characterization of the new clostridial species is based on the properties of the type strain, JW-YL-7.</s><s>Physiological and morphological properties were corroborated with the strains JW-YL-1, JW-YL-2, JW-YL-4, JW-YL-8, JW-YL-12, and JW/YL-L15, isolated from the sewage plant in Athens and Atlanta, Ga. (Table 1).</s><s>On the basis of the ability to grow at the high pH values of 10.5 and above, the morphology of the vegetative and sporulated cells, and the motility of the sporulated cells, the additional strains listed in Table 1 are assumed to belong to the same species.</s><s>However, no numerical taxonomy has been done to further verify this assumption.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony morphology.</s><s>In agar shake-roll tubes containing YTP medium without glucose at pH 10.0 to 10.5 and 50°C, the agar surface colonies were white, translucent, and circular to slightly irregular.</s><s>Colonies in the agar were lens shaped and creamy white.</s><s>No pigmentation was observed when cells were grown in either liquid or on solidified YTP and YTG media.</s><s>After 3 to 5 days, colonies usually started to turn transparent as the cells began to form autoplasts (L-form) and to lyse.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology of vegetative cells.</s><s>Exponential cells, grown in liquid or agar-solidified medium, were rods of 0.7 to 1.1 μm in diameter and 2 to 4.5 μm in length.</s><s>Chains of two and more cells were seen in the early exponential phase.</s><s>When grown at the optimal pH of 10.1 and at 50°C, the cells from the exponential growth phase were regular to slightly bent rods (Fig. 2A).</s><s>The morphology became more pleiomorphic in the stationary growth phase (within 6 to 20 h), with slightly deformed, swollen or curved cells (Fig. 2B and C).</s><s>Occasionally, L-form types of cells were seen, mainly during prolonged incubation (1 to 2 days or longer) at either elevated temperatures (55 to 60°C) or low pH values (around pH 7.1,50°C) close to the minimum pH for growth (Fig. 3A).</s><s>Some of these cells still possessed flagella (Fig. 3B) and stayed motile.</s><s>At or near the pH<sub>max</sub> (10.9 to 11.1) at 50°C or around 60 to 63°C at pH 10.1, the organism frequently developed into filamentous rods (Fig. 3C), with a length of up to 50 μm, without visual septation or changes in diameter.</s><s>The electron micrographs revealed a variation in cell division.</s><s>Some stages suggest a pinching mode (Fig. 4A to C) while others indicate more of a septation mechanism (Fig. 4D to H).</s><s>Frequently, dividing cells showed the formation of excess membrane structures (Fig. 4C to H), indicating that the cell division process might be inhibited.</s><s>On the other hand, at this time, it cannot be excluded that this is an artifact caused by the fixation process for electron microsopy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram stain reaction and Gram type.</s><s>The Gram stain reaction was negative, regardless of the growth phase; however, the test for the formation of the lipopolysaccharide-polymyxin B complex gave no indication of the presence of lipopolysaccharide (35).</s><s>Thus, the organism is regarded as a Gram-type-positive organism (31).</s><s>This is also indicated by the fine structure of the cell wall, although atypically thin for a Gram-type-positive bacterium, as revealed in the photomicrographs of ultrathin sections (Fig. 4).</s><s>This is also in agreement with the data from the 16s rRNA sequence analysis, indicating that the organism belongs to the Gram-type-positive Clostridium and Bacillus subphylum (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sporulation.</s><s>Generally, high rates of sporulation (up to 90%) were observed in both liquid and solidified agar YTG media, leading to the formation of swollen sporangia of the "drumstick" type (Fig. 2B and C).</s><s>Spores were round and 1 to 1.1 μm in diameter.</s><s>In the absence of glucose, sporulation frequency decreased to 10 to 20%.</s><s>During growth on glucose, the majority of the cells sporulated after 24 to 48 h of incubation.</s><s>The sporulation was pH dependent (Fig. 5).</s><s>At pH 7.0 to 7.5, no sporulation was seen with the vegetative cells, which were wider in diameter (1 to 1.1 μm) than at pH 10.1 (0.7 to 1.0 μm).</s><s>During growth at pH 10.9 to 11.0, the vegetative cells developed into a pseudofilamentous form and the frequency of sporulation decreased from 85 to 95% (at pH 10.1) to 1 to 5%.</s><s>The formation of spores was usually observed during the late exponential or early stationary phase; the ratio of spores and vegetative cells remained relatively constant during the stationary phase until the inception of death phase, when the cells began to lyse and the released spores accumulated into large clumps (Fig. 2D).</s><s>The clumps of spores were seen in both shaken and unshaken cultures.</s><s>Frequently, the formation of structures resembling prespores was seen on the distal end of the sporulated mother cell (Fig. 2B and C), with no visible septation (Fig. 6A and B).</s><s>The electron micrograph of ultrathin sections revealed the typical endospore structure for the fully developed spore (Fig. 6C).</s><s>Sporulation was also dependent on concentrations of Na<sup>+</sup> and K<sup>+</sup> added to the medium (Fig. 7), exhibiting a very sharp optimum (50 to 150 mM NaCl) in the absence of added KCl.</s><s>No sporulation occurred below 10 mM NaCl regardless of whether 25 or 100 mM added KCl was present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motility and flagellation.</s><s>The motility of the cells was pH dependent (Fig. 5) and was also influenced by the concentrations of sodium and potassium ions present in the culture medium (Fig. 7).</s><s>At pH 10.1, exponentially growing cells were motile, as were most of the cells in early or midstationary growth phase.</s><s>Surprisingly, sporulated cells were highly motile, with swimming in the direction of either end (i-e., containing the spore or not) of the cell.</s><s>The sporulated cells exhibited longer phases of smooth swimming than the vegetative cells, which appeared to tumble most of the time.</s><s>Electron micrographs revealed two to six peritrichous flagella per cell of up to 12 to 15 μm in length and 90 to 92 nm in diameter (Fig. 8), with a flagellum wave length of 2.0 to 2.2 μm (Fig. 8A).</s><s>The subunits are helically packed along the filament axis of the flagellum with an angle of less than 60° formed between the axis of the longitudinal rows of subunits and the axis tangential to the left or right oblique rows of subunits (Fig. 8B), representing the type I1 flagellum as defined by Aragno et al. (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth properties. (i) Effects of pH and temperature on growth.</s><s>The pH range for growth was 7.3 to 11.0 (tested at 50°C), with an optimum between pH 9.8 and 10.3 (Fig. 9A).</s><s>By the stringent definition of Krulwich and Guffanti (16), the isolates are facultative alkaliphiles.</s><s>In contrast to aerobic alkaliphiles which lower or raise the pH in the medium to their optimal pH, as shown by Ueyama and Horikoshi (Fig. 2.3, reference ll), none of the isolated anaerobic strains tested exhibited this phenomenon; because of the formation of acidic fermentation products, the pH became more acidic.</s><s>The average change in pH ranged in the absence of glucose from 0.1 to 0.5 pH unit and 0.4 to 1.0 pH unit in the presence of 0.3% added glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The marginal temperature data for growth in YTG medium (pH 10.1) were as follows: T<sub>max</sub> &#x003E;62°C and &#x003C;63.5°C; T<sub>opt</sub>, 50 to 58°C; T<sub>min</sub>, &#x003C;32°C and &#x003E;30°C (incubation for up to 5 days; longer incubation times render the medium unsuitable).</s><s>No significant differences were observed in the growth temperature optimum and range when the cells were grown in the presence and absence of glucose (Fig. 9B).</s><s>With YT medium (0.5% yeast extract, 0.3% tryptone), the doubling time at the pH<sub>opt</sub> , of 10.1 and T<sub>opt</sub> of 55°C was 16 min in the presence of O.5% glucose and 22 min in the absence of glucose.</s><s>This is the shortest doubling time observed for a strict anaerobic bacterium, regardless of the extreme environment.</s><s>We speculate that this short doubling time could be one of the reasons that this alkali-thermophile can be found in relatively high numbers in mesophilic sewage sludge with pH values usually around neutral but, which, especially in pockets of the anaerobic sludge vessel, can undergo shifts in pH and temperature for short periods of time and thus render the environment temporarily favorable for these organisms to grow.</s><s>However, the monitoring data we received from several of the sewage plants did not show any values above 38°C and pH 7.6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Effects of Na<sup>+</sup> and K<sup>+</sup> on growth.</s><s>At pH 9.6, the optimal sodium concentration for growth (maximal OD<sub>600</sub>) was between 50 and 100 mM, while at pH 7.5 the range was extended to from 50 to 500 mM (Fig. 7).</s><s>The addition of 25 or 100 mM KCl increased the stimulation by NaCl and shifted the inhibitory effect of sodium ions to higher concentrations; e.g., in the presence of added potassium ion, the optimum concentration for growth was between 150 and 300 mM NaCl instead of 50 to 100 mM NaCl without added potassium.</s><s>At both alkaline and neutral pH values and in the presence and absence of added potassium ions, 1 M NaCl inhibited growth completely.</s><s>Potassium had less of a stimutulatory effect on growth than on motility and sporulation.</s><s>In presence of 25 and 100 mM added KCl, the optimum and inhibitory concentrations of added NaCl were shifted to higher concentrations (Fig. 7).</s><s>Furthermore, in the presence of 25 to 100 mM potassium, the extent of the sodium-induced effect was dependent on the culture age; e.g., at the early exponential growth phase (2 h) a higher percentage of cells were motile compared with the percentages in the late exponential growth phase and the transition phase (4 and 10 h, respectively).</s><s>Furthermore, at the early exponential growth phase the optimal NaCl concentration was around 50 to 100 mM NaCl.</s><s>Similar data were obtained in the absence of glucose (data not shown).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The aeration pool samples and the anaerobic digestor samples from the Athens Sewage Plant had similar sodium concentrations (3 to 3.5 mM) but differed slightly in the potassium concentrations (0.5 versus 1.2 mM).</s><s>These data suggest that <i>C. paradaxum</i> and alike strains live in the sewage sludge at suboptimal Na<sup>+</sup> and K<sup>+</sup> concentrations. (iii) Substrates and fermentation products.</s><s>No growth was observed under aerobic conditions, i.e., when aerobically prepared YTG, YTP, and nutrient broth (Difco) media, either liquid or solidified with 2% agar and with a pH of 10.1, were used.</s><s>The organism requires prereduced (i-e., resazurin-colorless) medium containing either yeast extract or tryptone, which cannot be replaced by peptone.</s><s>The addition of 0.1 to 0.5% (wt/vol) peptone to media containing 0.3% (wt/vol) yeast extract or tryptone had no beneficial effect on growth.</s><s>Substrates which were utilized in the presence of 0.1% (wt/vol) yeast extract included glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, and pyruvate.</s><s>In addition, some strains were able to use lactose (JW-YL-4 and JW-YL-7<sup>T</sup>) and cellobiose and xylitol (JW-YL-2 and JW-YL-7<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The substrates not utilized were galactose, xylose, ribose, L-(+)-arabinose, mannose, mannitol, rhamnose, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, malonate, glycerol, lactate, formate, pectin, starch, cellulose, ethanol, methanol, H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, and Casamino Acids.</s><s>Moreover, the addition of 0.5% (wt/vol) D-mannose, methanol, and ethanol inhibited growth, compared with growth in unamended yeast extract-containing base medium.</s><s>With or</s></p><p class="description"><s>without glucose, at pH 7.5 and 10.5, acetate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub> were the major products; however, one product could not be identified (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical properties. (i) Dissimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>No dissimilatory sulfate reduction was detected, thus excluding the organism from the sporeforming, dissimilatory sulfate-reducing genus <i>Desulfotomaculum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Fatty acid analysis.</s><s>PLFAME (ester-linked phospholipid fatty acid methyl ester) profiles were determined (Table 4).</s><s>Under alkaline growth conditions (pH 10.1 to 10.5), the patterns of PLFAME profiles of strains JW-YL-7<sup>T</sup>, JWYL-8, and JWTYL-L15-1 were similar but were different from the one obtained for an asporogenous strain, JWTYL-23-2 (“<i>C. thermophilum</i>”; unpublished data), isolated from sewage sludge from the Atlanta Sewage Plant.</s><s>However, when JW-YL-7<sup>T</sup> was grown at pH 7.4 to 7.6, at which it does not form spores, its PLFAME pattern was similar to that of the Atlanta strain.</s><s>However, further experiments, isolation of further strains, and data for other thermophiles and alkaliphiles are required before further conclusions can be drawn.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) An-Ident tests.</s><s>In An-Ident tests (API Analytab Products, Plainview, N.Y.), strong positive results were obtained for the following reactions: α-glucosidase, indoxylacetate hydrolysis, arginine aminopeptidase, and arginine utilization.</s><s>Weak positive reactions were found for indole production and catalase production.</s><s>The other reactions (N-acetylglucosaminidase, L-arabinosidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, leucineaminopeptidase, proline aminopeptidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine aminopeptidase, alanine aminopeptidase, histidine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase, and glycine aminopeptidase) were negative.</s><s>The same results were obtained for incubations at either pH 8.5 or 10.5 and at 37 or 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Sensitivity to antibiotics.</s><s>Strain JW-YL-7<sup>T</sup> was tested in YTG medium at both pH 7.4 and 10.1.</s><s>Growth was inhibited by 25 pg of chloramphenicol, erythromycin, tetracycline, monesin, gramicidin s, and lasalocid per ml and 50 μg of gentamicin per ml.</s><s>The inhibition spectrum is in agreement with that for strains belonging to the (eu)bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) G+C content (mole percent).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the genomic DNA was 30.0 2 0.1 mol% for the six tested strains, JW-YL-1, -2, -4, -7<sup>T</sup>, -8, and -12, as determined by complete P1 nuclease and alkaline phosphatase digestion and HPLC analysis of the nucleosides (22, 32).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain JW-YL-7, isolated from the sewage plant in Athens, Ga., is designated as the type strain of <i>Clostridium paradoxum</i> and is deposited with the German Culture Collection (DSM 7308).</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 30 mol%.</s><s>The properties are as described</s></p><p class="description"><s>above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>