<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4312_nm.4981" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4981" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4981" rank="species">Bacillus siralis</organism><reference id="rid.4312"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pettersson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Silva</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uhlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus siralis sp. nov., a novel species from silage with a higher order structural attribute in the 16S rRNA genes.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2181</fpage><lpage>2187</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155995</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus siralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus siralis</i> (si.ra'lis. L. masc. n. <i>sirus</i> grain pit, silo; L. adj. <i>siralis</i> belonging to the silo)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 2.0-3.0 μm in length by about 0.5-0.8 μm in diameter and occur singly.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Spores are oval, located subterminally to terminally in a swollen sporangium.</s><s>Colonies on BHI agar after incubation for 24 h are 3-5 mm diameter, brown to light brown in colour.</s><s>The colony surface is granular, but glistening and shiny, circular, entire.</s><s>On nutrient agar, the colonies are smaller (1-3 mm in diameter), pale and opaque.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate in broth is reduced to nitrite, but not nitrogen gas.</s><s>Arginine is not hydrolysed (strain 1HR is an exception) and citrate is not used as carbon source.</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin (5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Butanediol (Voges-Proskauer test) is not produced and acids are not produced from a range of sugars and sugar alcohols including arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and gelatin, but not starch, are hydrolysed.</s><s>Grows in 7% NaCl, but not 10%, and at 50 °C, but not 55 °C.</s><s>Contains characteristic inserts of 49 bases in the distal region of the 16S rRNA genes.</s><s>The full sequence of the 16S rRNA gene has database accession number AF071856.</s><s>Source: silage.</s><s>The type strain (171544<sup>T</sup>) has been deposited in the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria as NCIMB 13601<sup>T</sup> and in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur as CIP 106295<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>