<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7511_nm.2428" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2428" rank="genus">Methylomonas</organism><reference id="rid.7511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the methanotrophs: Description of Methylobacter gen.nov., emendation of Methylococcus, validation of Methylosinus and Methylocystis species, and a proposal that the family Methylococcaceae includes only the Group I Methanotrophs.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>753</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-735</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Extended description of the genus Methylomonas</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are rod-like to coccobacillary and 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide by 1.0 to 2.0 μm long. Motile by means of a single polar flagellum. Produces poly-β-hydroxybutyrate inclusions and desiccation-sensitive <i>Azotobacter</i> type cysts. Most strains produce capsules. Forms a surface pellicle when grown in static liquid culture. Pink and orange carotenoid pigments are produced. Optimum growth occurs at temperatures between 25 and 35°C; no growth occurs at temperatures above 40°C. Growth occurs between pH 5.0 and 9.0; optimum growth occurs at pH 6.5 to 7.0. NaCl is not required for growth. NaCl inhibits growth at a concentration of 1.5% (wt/vol). Cells are susceptible to lysis by 0.2% (wt/vol) SDS. The Benson-Calvin cycle is not present. Urease is produced. The major PLFAs are 14:O and 16:1ω8c. The major ubiquinone is 18-methylene-ubiquinone 8 (only determined for <i>Methylomonas methanica</i>) (12). The G+C content is 51 to 59 mol% (T<sub>i</sub>). The type species is <i>Methylomonas methanica</i> (56). Other species include <i>Methylomonas fodinarum</i> and <i>Methylomonas aurantiaca</i> (6).</s></p></content></protolog>