<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12709_nm.22473" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22473" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22473" rank="species">Pasteuria aldrichii</organism><reference id="rid.12709"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Giblin-Davis</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nong</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Preston</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Center</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brito</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dickson</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>‘Candidatus Pasteuria aldrichii’, an obligate endoparasite of the bacterivorous nematode Bursilla</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2073</fpage><lpage>2080</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021287-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870891</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria aldrichii’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria aldrichii’ (al.dri′chi.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>aldrichii</em> of Aldrich, named in honour of Dr Henry Aldrich for his many contributions to research and teaching in microbiology at the University of Florida).</s></p><p class="description"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria aldrichii’ [(<em>Firmicutes</em>) NC; G+; M; NAS (GenBank no. GU186440); morphology (see following description); S (<em>Bursilla</em> sp. RGD244 (sp. PS1179), pseudocoelom)] Giblin-Davis <em>et al.</em>, 2004, this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately endoparasitic bacterium of the pseudocoelom of <em>Bursilla</em> nematodes that cannot be cultivated on cell-free media, only by attachment of endospores to species of the genus <em>Bursilla</em> and co-cultivation in soil with bi-weekly inoculations of nematodes.</s><s>Transmission occurs horizontally.</s><s>Host infection is via cuticular penetration by attached endospores, occurring at all stages of host development, except L1 and egg stages.</s><s>Sporogenesis, which leads to the death of the host, occurs in the pseudocoelom of L3-stage through to adult-stage nematodes.</s><s>Sporogenesis is typical of other nematode-specific species of the genus <em>Pasteuria.</em> Host range appears to be limited to species of the genus <em>Bursilla</em>.</s><s>Cells are non-motile with a Gram-reaction-positive vegetative phase. ‘Mycelium’ is septate, hyphal strands branch dichotomously with expansion of hyphal tip forming early sporangium.</s><s>SEM and TEM reveal dorsal peripheral fibres of the host-attached mature endospore, which are covered with a dense layer of adhesion fibres, except for a slight gap encircling the endospore that appears to be diagnostic for this species.</s><s>Lateral views with TEM show that the peripheral fibres comprise thin ‘wing-like’ structures that are narrowly (1/6–1/3 the height of the lateral wall) attached to the anterior-most region of the lateral walls of the spore.</s><s>This is a diagnostic feature, relative to other species of the genus <em>Pasteuria</em> described from nematodes where the peripheral fibres are broadly attached to the lateral walls of the spore (&#x003E;2/3 the height of the lateral wall).</s><s>In lateral views with TEM, the ratio of the combined widths of the dorsal and ventral adhesion layers relative to the peripheral fibre layers is about 2 : 1 in ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria aldrichii’ versus ~1 : 5 in all other described species of bacteria from nematodes.</s><s>The sporangium and central-body diameters overlap with other described species of the genus <em>Pasteuria</em> identified from nematode hosts.</s><s>In lateral views with TEM, the shape of the central body is a rounded-ellipse, similar to the circular shape seen in <em>P. ramosa</em>, which contrasts with the rectangular to rounded-trapezoidal shape seen in transverse sections of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria usgae’, the horizontally oriented elliptical shapes seen in <em>P. penetrans</em> and <em>P. nishizawae</em>, and the rounded-square shape seen in <em>P. thornei</em>.</s><s>The outer spore coat of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria aldrichii’ is thickest dorsally, and thinnest across the bottom of the spore, which contrasts with ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria usgae’, which is seven to eight times thicker laterally than across the bottom, and with all other described species, having outer spore coats with relatively uniform thickness.</s><s>No basal ring exists around the pore opening, as in <em>P. penetrans</em>.</s><s>There are no lateral microprojections of the outer spore coat as there are in ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria usgae’, <em>P. penetrans</em> and <em>P. nishizawae.</em> The epicortical wall remnant of the mature endospore is difficult to discern in TEM sections but appears to be concentric in lateral view, similar to what has been described for <em>P. ramosa</em>, <em>P. nishizawae</em> and <em>P. penetrans</em>.</s><s>Spores are not found in distinctive clumps from the disintegration of the mother thallus as described for the putative ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Pasteuria hartismeri’ (Bishop <em>et al.</em>, 2007).</s></p></content></protolog>