<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2420_nm.11294" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11294" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11294" rank="species">Streptomyces vietnamensis</organism><reference id="rid.2420"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phuong</surname><given-names>L.T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanh</surname><given-names>V.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryan</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces vietnamensis sp. nov., a streptomycete with violet blue diffusible pigment isolated from soil in Vietnam</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1770</fpage><lpage>1774</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64774-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684254</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces vietnamensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces vietnamensis</em> (vi.et.nam.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>vietnamensis</em> pertaining to Vietnam, the geographical location from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive and forms a white aerial mycelium and a reddish-brown substrate mycelium.</s><s>Verticils are not present.</s><s>The mycelium does not fragment.</s><s>Straight to flexuous chains of cylindrical spores are produced.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are produced on ISP2, ISP3, ISP4 and ISP5 media and on Gause's synthetic agar, but not on Czapek solution agar.</s><s>Melanin is produced on ISP7.</s><s>Although growth on ISP4 is initially slow, very good growth with profuse sporulation is observed on this medium after 14 days.</s><s>Very good growth occurs on ISP2, Gause's synthetic agar and ISP3.</s><s>Moderate growth is observed on ISP5 but only poor growth on Czapek agar.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is reddish brown on ISP2, ISP5, Gause's synthetic agar, ISP4 and ISP3, but greyish orange on Czapek medium.</s><s>Cell wall contains ll-DAP (cell-wall type I).</s><s>Whole-cell sugar pattern contains diagnostic sugars: mannose, small quantities of ribose and galactose.</s><s>No antibiosis is exhibited against <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 6538, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> ATCC 6633, <em>Candida albicans</em> ATCC 10231 or <em>Penicillium citrinum</em> AS3.2788.</s><s>Utilizes melibiose, glucose, sorbinose, sucrose, d-fructose, xylose, d-galactose, rhamnose and arabinose.</s><s>Positive for production of H<sub>2</sub>S, but pectin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GIMV4.0001<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC M 205143<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15340<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a forest soil sample in Vietnam</s></p></content></protolog>