<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12768_nm.22548" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22548" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22548" rank="species">Pseudomonas bauzanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12768"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas bauzanensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2333</fpage><lpage>2337</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026104-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21037038</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas bauzanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas bauzanensis</em> (bau.za.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bauzanensis</em> referring to <em>Bauzanum</em> medieval Latin name of Bozen/Bolzano, a city in South Tyrol, Italy, where the species was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, motile, short rods (0.7–0.9×1.1–1.7 µm after 4 days at 20 °C on R<sub>2</sub>A agar).</s><s>Grows on R<sub>2</sub>A agar, nutrient agar, trypticase soy agar and King’s B agar.</s><s>Colonies on R<sub>2</sub>A agar are white, round, convex, smooth and with entire margins (1.5–2 mm in diameter after 6 days at 20 °C).</s><s>Negative for production of a cellular (methanol-extractable) or diffusible fluorescent pigment.</s><s>Good growth occurs in R<sub>2</sub>A liquid medium at 5–30 °C (highest cell yields at 10–20 °C); growth at 1 and 37 °C is absent in R<sub>2</sub>A liquid culture and on R<sub>2</sub>A agar plates.</s><s>On R<sub>2</sub>A agar, growth occurs at pH 7–8 and with 0–7 % (w/v) NaCl; growth is delayed with 10 % (w/v) NaCl and absent with 15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Negative for production of indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and urease, utilization of citrate, reduction of nitrate and hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and leucine arylamidase; weakly positive for valine arylamidase and lipase (C14); and negative for gelatinase, amylase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase, ornithine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>With API 20 NE, assimilates capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate, but not d-glucose, d-mannitol, maltose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>With EcoPlates, utilizes pyruvic acid methyl ester, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, d-malic acid, Tweens 40 and 80 and weakly utilizes l-serine, but does not utilize d-glucosaminic acid, d-galacturonic acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, cellobiose, α-lactose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-xylose, i-erythritol, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, glucose 1-phosphate, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, d-galacturonic acid, γ-lactone, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-hydroxybenzoic acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, α-cyclodextrin or glycogen.</s><s>Does not ferment glucose, mannitol, sucrose, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin or l-arabinose.</s><s>Resistant to (µg per disc) tetracycline (30) and erythromycin (15), and sensitive to kanamycin (30), amikacin (30), gentamicin (10), streptomycin (10), ampicillin (10), nalidixic acid (30), chloramphenicol (30) and rifampicin (30).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo.</s><s>The quinone system consists predominantly of ubiquinone Q-9.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown phospholipid; an unknown aminophospholipid and 11 unknown polar lipids are also present.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BZ93<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22558<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 1.9095<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 26048<sup>T</sup>) and was isolated from soil contaminated with hydrocarbons and heavy metals in Bozen, South Tyrol, Italy.</s></p></content></protolog>