<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8811_nm.13268" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13268" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13268" rank="species">Chromobacterium aquaticum</organism><reference id="rid.8811"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromobacterium aquaticum sp. nov., isolated from spring water samples.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>877</fpage><lpage>880</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65573-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398186</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chromobacterium aquaticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chromobacterium aquaticum</em> (a.qua′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>aquaticum</em> living, growing, or found in or by water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped (0.3–0.5 μm long and 1.5–2 μm wide) and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h incubation on tryptone soy agar and nutrient agar at 32 °C.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard medium at 32 °C are tan-coloured, smooth, shiny and convex with a spreading edge, 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter and are non-fluorescent.</s><s>No violet coloured pigmentation.</s><s>Positive for haemolytic activity (5 % sheep blood), lecithinase and lipase production.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 32 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 6.0; growth occurs at pH 5 and 9.5, but not at pH 4.0 and 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3.5 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0–0.1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No anaerobic growth on plain nutrient agar or tryptone soy agar supplemented with nitrate was observed.</s><s>No poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granule accumulation.</s><s>Shows aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase-, gelatinase- and aesculin-positive, catalase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of strain CC-SEYA-1<sup>T</sup> is shown in Table 2.</s><s>Dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, i-erythritol (weak), cellobiose, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, d-mannose, d-psicose, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside (weak), trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid (weak), <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid (weak), dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine (weak), urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine (weak), 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate were utilized (Biolog GN-II).</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, l-arabinose, dl-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucuronic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and glycerol were not utilized as carbon sources (Biolog GN-II).</s><s>Positive (API 20E and 20NE) for arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, gelatinase, glucose oxidation, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase, assimilation of glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid, but negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lysine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, acetoin production, mannitol oxidation, inositol oxidation, sorbitol oxidation, rhamnose oxidation, sucrose oxidation, melibiose, amygdalin oxidation, arabinose oxidation, arabinose assimilation, mannose assimilation, mannitol assimilation, maltose assimilation and adipic acid assimilation.</s><s>Positive for alkaline and acid phosphatase, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), myristate lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-B-1-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase in API ZYM enzyme reactions.</s><s>Sensitive to cotrimoxazole, tetracycline, minocycline, nor/quinolones 2G, levofloxacin and nitrofurantonin; resistant to penicillin, gentamicin, erythromycin, clindamycin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, rifampicin, fusidic acid, quinupristine-dalfo, coagoxacillin and oxacillin.</s><s>Further physiological features are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, isolated from spring-water samples from Yang-Ming Mountain, Taipei County, Taiwan, is CC-SEYA-1<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 55175<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17769<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>