<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2706_nm.6317" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6317" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6317" rank="species">Mycobacterium alvei</organism><reference id="rid.2706"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ausina</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luquin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García Barceló</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lanéelle</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lévy-Frébault</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Belda</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prats</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium alvei sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>535</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-529</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1390105</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium alvei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium alvei</i> (al've.i. L.gen.n.<i>alvei</i>, bed of a river, referring to the place where this species was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of <i>M. alvei</i> are short rods that are 1 to 3 μm long and 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide; they are mainly strongly acid fast, except for a small number (less than 10%) of cyanophil forms.</s><s>The cells are gram-positive rods and frequently appear to be coccoid.</s><s>Smears prepared from Youmans medium (without Tween 80) and Middlebrook 7H12 medium contain clumps of rods but not cords.</s><s>Colonies on Löwenstein-Jensen medium and on Middlebrook 7H10 agar are eugonic, rough, and nonpigmented in the dark and also after exposure to light.</s><s>Growth occurs within 5 days at 30"C, the optimum growth temperature.</s><s>At 37°C, the organisms grow more slowly (growth appears within 10 to 15 days), and they do not grow at 45 or 52°C.</s><s>The type strain produces thermostable catalase and is positive for arylsulfatase (3 days), nitrate reductase, urease, β-glucosidase, and β-galactosidase.</s><s>No growth occurs in MacConkey agar without crystal violet.</s><s>Salicylate is not degraded to catechol.</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Iron uptake is negative.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in the presence of sodium chloride (5%) and picric acid (0.2%).</s><s>Inositol, mannitol, and sodium citrate are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, and trehalose but not from dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>The type strain is resistant to D-cycloserine, streptomycin, isoniazid (0.1 and 1 mg/liter), rifampin, <i>p</i>-aminosalicylic acid, and thiacetazone and is susceptible to isoniazid (10 mg/liter), kanamycin, and capreomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gas chromatography of the total fatty acid methyl esters reveals the presence of tuberculostearate.</s><s>Pyrolytic C<sub>2</sub>-C<sub>3</sub> cleavage gives intense peaks corresponding to docosanoate and tetracosanoate, indicating that characteristic α-branched, β-hydroxylated mycobacterial mycolates are present.</s><s>Secondary alcohols are not detected.</s><s>As determined by TLC, <i>M. alvei</i> contains α-mycolates and ω-1 methoxymycolates.</s><s>Since as determined by gas chromatography <i>M. alvei</i> produces lipid profiles similar to those of the other rapidly growing nonphotochromogenic mycobacteria (18, 20, 25,45), analysis of the mycolic acid pattern allows a clear distinction between <i>M. alvei</i> and the previously described <i>Mycobactenum</i> species.</s><s>Recently, we have found that <i>M. porcinum</i>, <i>M. senegalense</i>, and some strains of <i>M. fortuitum</i> and "<i>Mycobactenum peregrinum</i>" also contain appreciable amounts of 0-1 methoxymycolate, but in these species this mycolate is always accompanied by an epoxymycolate (Table 3) (26,27,31).</s><s>However, in <i>M. alvei</i> the ω-1 methoxymycolate is the only oxygenated compound (28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain CR-21 (= CIP 103464)</s></p></content></protolog>