<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3828_nm.6771" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6771" rank="genus">Thermocrispum</organism><reference id="rid.3828"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Korn-Wendisch</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kempf</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Majazza</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kutzner</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermocrispum gen. nov., a new genus of the order Actinomycetales, and description of Thermocrispum municipale sp. nov. and Thermocrispum agreste sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>67</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-67</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857810</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermocrispum</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermocrispum</i> (Ther.mo.cris' pum. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, warm, hot; L. neut. adj. <i>crispum</i>, tightly curled; N.L. neut. n. <i>Thermocrispum</i>, a heat-loving, tightly curled organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are gram-positive, aerobic, catalase-positive, non-acid-fast, thermophilic organisms which produce filamentous, branched hyphae.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white, and the vegetative mycelium is yellow to light brown.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are straight to flexuous and often aggregate into clusters, so-called pseudosporangia, which fragment into rod-like structures; true sporangia are not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms grow well on CYC agar, GYM agar, Hickey-Tresner agar, oatmeal agar, potato-carrot agar, PM agar, R2A agar, and R8 agar, as well as TSA.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 62.5°C, and the optimum temperature for growth is 45 to 55°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0 and 11.0.</s><s>The strains grow in the presence of 5% NaCl, novobiocin, and cristal violet.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite under aerobic conditions.</s><s>The strains degrade or hydrolyze casein, tyrosine, gelatin, DNA, and esculin, and lipolysis of Tween 80 and tributyrin occurs.</s><s>Chitin, adenine, hypoxanthine, xanthine, poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid, starch, and xylan are not degraded or hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urea and allantoin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is not produced.</s><s>No cellulolytic activity occurs.</s><s>Not resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, mannose, cellobiose,  sucrose, trehalose, inositol, dextrin, sodium malonate, and sodium pyruvate are utilized as sole carbon sources, but xylose, rhamnose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, adonitol (=ribitol), xylitol, inulin, and sodium propionate are not utilized.</s><s>Melezitose, mannitol, and sorbitol (=glucitol) are poor substrates and may or may not be utilized as sole carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-DAP, and the whole-cell sugar pattern type is type C; major amounts of arabinose, mannose, and glucose are present, and only traces of galactose are detected.</s><s>Phospholipid type PII.</s><s>No mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 69 to 73 mol%.</s><s>Resistant to a set of phages for the genera <i>Amycolatopsis</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia</i>, <i>Saccharomonospora</i>, <i>Saccharopolyspora</i>, and <i>Saccharothrix</i>.</s><s>Sensitive to genus-specific phages isolated from different habitats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus is related to members of the <i>Pseudonocardiaceae</i> and to the genera <i>Saccharothrix</i>, <i>Kutzneria</i>, and <i>Actinokineospora</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Thermocrispum municipale</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>