<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10339_nm.16852" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16852" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16852" rank="species">Kribbella ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.10339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kribbella ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>364</fpage><lpage>368</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008516-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651720</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kribbella ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kribbella ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming actinomycete.</s><s>Extensively branched substrate mycelium penetrating into the agar and aerial mycelium are observed on R2A agar plates (Difco) and most media tested.</s><s>Grows at 8–37 °C (no growth at 6 or 42 °C) and pH 5.5–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs with up to 4.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Unable to reduce nitrate or nitrite under either aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Negative for production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Gelatinase- and Voges–Proskauer test-positive.</s><s>Utilizes glucose as a sole carbon source but does not produce acid or gas from glucose.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan; H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from sodium citrate.</s><s>Degrades chitin, starch and casein, but not xylan, DNA or cellulose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, asparagine, aspartic acid, cellobiose, fructose, fumaric acid, gluconate, glutamic acid, glutamine, glycerol, glycogen, histidine, lactate, malate, melibiose, oxalic acid, phenylalanine, pyruvic acid, raffinose, sodium acetate, succinic acid, threonine, trehalose and valerate, but not adipate, adonitol, alanine, arginine, benzoic acid, caprate, cysteine, dextran, dulcitol, ethanol, formic acid, d-fucose, glutaric acid, glycine, 3- and 4-hydroxybenzoates, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inulin, isoleucine, itaconate, leucine, lysine, d-lyxose, maleic acid, malonate, methanol, methionine, phenyl acetate, proline, propionate, d-ribose, salicin, serine, sorbitol, l-sorbose, suberate, tartaric acid, tryptophan, tyrosine, valine or xylitol.</s><s>Grows with antibiotic discs containing the following (μg): streptomycin sulfate (2, 4), gentamicin sulfate (2), tetracycline hydrochloride (4.5, 7.2), chloramphenicol (5, 10), kanamycin (2, 4), penicillin (6, 12) and erythromycin (2, 4); does not grow with streptomycin sulfate (6, 12), gentamicin sulfate (4, 6, 12), tetracycline hydrochloride (10, 15), chloramphenicol (15, 30), kanamycin (6, 12), penicillin (18, 24) or erythromycin (6, 9).</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are the major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-diaminopimelic acid, glycine, alanine and glutamate.</s><s>The polar lipids detected are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars detected are ribose, xylose and galactose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 001<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19134<sup>T</sup> =DSM 17941<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>