<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12659_nm.22194" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22194" rank="genus">Cosenzaea</organism><reference id="rid.12659"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Giammanco</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefevre</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giammanco</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pignato</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of the genera Proteus, Morganella and Providencia by comparison of rpoB gene sequences of type and clinical strains suggests the reclassification of Proteus myxofaciens in a new genus, Cosenzaea gen. nov., as Cosenzaea myxofaciens comb. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1638</fpage><lpage>1644</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021964-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20709916</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cosenzaea</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cosenzaea</em> (Co.sen.za′e.a. N.L. fem. n. <em>Cosenzaea</em> named after Benjamin J. Cosenza, the microbiologist who first described this micro-organism as <em>Proteus myxofaciens</em> in 1966).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A member of the family <em>Enterobacteriaceae</em> as defined by Penner (2005a).</s><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, straight rods, 0.4–0.8×1.0–3.0 µm and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Grows on solid media producing a thin uniform film.</s><s>Haemolysis occurs on blood agar.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C.</s><s>Based on 16S rRNA sequence data, the genus <em>Cosenzaea</em> belongs to the family <em>Enterobacteriaceae</em> within the tribe <em>Proteeae</em> together with the genera <em>Proteus</em>, <em>Providencia</em> and <em>Morganella.</em> Conforming to the general definition of the family <em>Enterobacteriaceae</em>, <em>Cosenzaea</em> are facultatively anaerobic and chemo-organotrophic, having both respiratory and a fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed, indole is not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and Simmons citrate tests are positive.</s><s>Oxidatively deaminates phenylalanine and tryptophan.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Tyrosine is not decomposed as is demonstrated by the inability to produce a clearing in agar media supplemented with the insoluble amino acid.</s><s>Slime is produced at 25 °C in trypticase soy broth.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced but only after 3–4 days of incubation.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed at 22 °C.</s><s>Grows on media containing KCN.</s><s>Malonate is not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, glycerol and α-methyl-glucoside.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics that distinguish the genus <em>Cosenzaea</em> from related genera within the tribe <em>Proteeae</em> are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain of the type species is 36.5 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Cosenzaea myxofaciens</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics that differentiate members of the genus <em>Cosenzaea</em> from related genera within the tribe <em>Proteeae</em> of the family <em>Enterobacteriaceae</em></s></p><p class="description"><s>Genera: 1, <em>Cosenzaea</em> gen. nov.; 2, <em>Proteus</em>; 3, <em>Morganella</em>; 4, <em>Providencia</em>. +, Positive; −, negative.</s></p></content></protolog>