<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1799_nm.12232" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12232" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5280" rank="species">Staphylococcus vitulus</organism><reference id="rid.1799"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Webster</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bannerman</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubner</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ballard</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bruce</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of the Staphylococcus sciuri species group with EcoRI fragments containing rRNA sequences and description of Staphylococcus vitulus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>454</fpage><lpage>460</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-454</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520736</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus vitulus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus vitulus</i> (vit'u.lus. N. L. n. <i>vitulus</i>, veal)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. vitulus</i> below is based on the results of a study of 11 strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A total of 10 of the 11 strains produce colonies that are less than 3 mm in diameter when the organisms are grown aerobically on P agar (18) at 35°C.</s><s>Colonies on P agar are usually raised with ulcerated, irregular centers, are opaque, and often have sectored or irregular edges; 10 of the 11 strains studied produce cream to yellow pigmentation, and 1 strain produces unpigmented colonies.</s><s>Colonies grown on tryptic soy agar are much larger (8 to 12 mm in diameter) and not as irregular as</s></p><p class="description"><s>colonies grown on P agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony growth is reduced or inhibited at 40°C, and none of the strains grows at 45°C.</s><s>The cells are not motile, and the organisms do not grow anaerobically in thioglycolate semisolid agar.</s><s>However, they exhibit minimal growth on sheep blood agar and tryptic soy agar plates incubated at 35°C in anaerobic jars.</s><s>The cells are gram-positive cocci, do not form spores, and occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads, and in clusters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce zones of greening on bovine blood agar.</s><s>All strains are negative for staphylocoagulase, thermonuclease, alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, β-glucuronidase, and β-galactosidase activities, arginine utilization, and acetoin production.</s><s>All strains are negative for aerobic production of acid from the following substrates: mannose, lactose, galactose, melezitose, xylitol, rhamnose, turanose, arabinose, maltose, N-acetylglucosamine, and raffinose.</s><s>All strains are negative for anaerobic production of acid from glucose and mannitol.</s><s>All strains are positive for catalase activity, modified oxidase activity, and aerobic production of acid from the following substrates: mannitol, glycerol, sucrose, and fructose.</s><s>The variable characteristics of <i>S. vitulus</i> are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major API profiles are 4200 (six strains) and 4700 (three strains).</s><s>STAPH Trac profiles exhibit variation with respect to acid production from maltose, raffinose, xylose, and trehalose, nitrate reduction, alkaline phosphatase, and acetoin production, indicating that there is no predominant profile.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Eco</i>RI fragments containing rRNA sequences.</s><s>The patterns of all <i>S. vitulus</i> strains cluster on the basis of similarity and are distinguishable from the patterns of all other bacteria examined, including all previously described <i>Staphylococcus</i> species.</s><s>The species can be recognized by a high level of correlation with the pattern types described in this paper.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities.</s><s>As determined by agar disk diffusion tests, all strains of <i>S. vitulus</i> are susceptible to furazolidone, penicillin, erythromycin, and clindamycin.</s><s>All strains are resistant to bacitracin and novobiocin.</s><s>Three strains that produce pattern type dd 756 (DD 756<sup>t</sup>, DD 4524, and DD 4753) are resistant to tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. vitulus</i> is ATCC 51145 (= DD 756).</s><s>It has all of the characteristics of the species described above.</s><s>In addition, it has the properties described below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical (diameter, 0.9 to 1.1 μm) and occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads, and in clusters.</s><s>P agar colonies are raised with ulcerated, irregular centers, irregular edges, and cream pigmentation; the colonies are approximately 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies on tryptic soy agar are raised with wide, depressed centers; each colony has a slightly irregular edge, and is pigmented, with a pinkish center blending to a cream edge.</s><s>These colonies are approximately 10 to 11 mm in diameter.</s><s>β-Glucosidase is produced.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The standard slide test is negative for clumping factor.</s><s>The Staph Latex kit reaction is strongly positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced aerobically from D-xylose and D-ribose.</s><s>No acid is produced aerobically from D-cellobiose, salicin, and D- trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is resistant to tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 34 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain produces a type dd 756 pattern when it is studied by using the methods described in this paper.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>S. vitulus</i> can be distinguished from other bacterial species by examining the pattern of restriction fragments containing rRNA sequences that results when the methods described in this paper are used. <i>S. vitulus</i> can also be distinguished by its novobiocin resistance, positive oxidase reaction, strong positive Staph Latex kit reaction, absence of alkaline phosphatase activity, and lack of acid production from L-arabinose, maltose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-mannose, and raffinose.</s><s>The major phenotypic features that are useful for distinguishing <i>S. vitulus</i> from other novobiocin-resistant, oxidase-positive <i>Staphylococcus</i> species are summarized in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>