<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2677_nm.954" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.954" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.954" rank="species">Rickettsia aeschlimannii</organism><reference id="rid.2677"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beati</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meskini</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thiers</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia aeschlimannii sp. nov., a new spotted fever group rickettsia associated with Hyalomma marginatum ticks</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>548</fpage><lpage>554</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-548</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103647</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia aeschlimannii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia aeschlimannii</i> (ae.schli.man'.ni.i, L. gen. n. <i>aeschlimannii</i>, of Aeschlimann, named after Andrk Aeschlimann, a Swiss zoologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Rickettsia aeschlimannii</i> is an obligate intracellular bacterium of the tick <i>Hyalomma marginatum</i>, which grows in several cell lines (Vero, L929, and Hel).</s><s>It can be grown in Earle’s MEM supplemented with 4% fetal calf serum and 2 mM L-glutamine at 32°C.</s><s>After Giménez staining, this organism is rod shaped (data not shown).</s><s>As determined by electron microscopy, this rickettsia has features in common with the other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>Mouse antisera against this rickettsia show cross-reactivity against antigens of other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>MIF, SDS-PAGE, Western immunoblotting, PFGE, PCR-RFLP, and citrate synthase gene and 16s rDNA sequencing indicated that this rickettsia is clearly different from all other recognized SFG rickettsial species, the most closely related organisms being <i>R. massiliae</i>, <i>R. rhipicephali</i>, and strain Bar29.</s><s>No information is available about the possible pathogenicity of this organism for vertebrate hosts.</s><s>The geographic distribution of this bacterium is likely to correspond to the areas where <i>H. marginatum</i> ticks have been analyzed (Morocco, Zimbabwe, and Portugal).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain MC16<sup>T</sup>, isolated from <i>H. marginatum marginatum</i> in Morocco, is held in the collection of the World Health Organization Collaborative Center for Rickettsial Reference in Marseille, France.</s></p></content></protolog>