<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2277_nm.9594" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9594" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9594" rank="species">Microbacterium xylanilyticum</organism><reference id="rid.2277"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium xylanilyticum sp. nov., a xylan-degrading bacterium isolated from a biofilm</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2075</fpage><lpage>2079</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63706-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166712</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium xylanilyticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium xylanilyticum</em> (xy.la.ni.ly′ti.cum. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan, a plant polymer; Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus -a -um</em> dissolving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>xylanilyticum</em> xylan-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods and show primary branching.</s><s>Gram-positive, oxidase-positive and catalase-positive.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar, trypticase soy agar and nutrient agar at 15–37 °C, but growth is weak at 5 °C and no growth is observed at temperatures above 42 °C or on MacConkey agar.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 25–30 °C and the optimal pH is 6–8.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1, 2 and 4 % NaCl, but growth is weak in the presence of 6·5 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, rough, slightly convex and circular with irregular margins.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>The methyl-red test is negative, but the Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and xylan are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>According to the results from the API ZYM test, l-leucyl 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 5·4), 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside and 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-l-fucopyranoside are hydrolysed, but 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 8·5), 2-naphthyl butyrate, 2-naphthyl caprylate, 2-naphthyl myristate, l-valyl 2-naphthylamide, l-cystyl 2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-benzoyl-dl-arginine 2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-glutaryl-phenylalanine 2-naphthylamide, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate, 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide and 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, d-turanose and d-xylose, but not from erythritol, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, inulin, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: mannitol, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, maltose, l-arabinose, dl-lactate, histidine, glycogen and l-proline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: rhamnose, salicin, inositol, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, itaconate, propionate, suberate, caprate, malonate, valerate, acetate, citrate, malate, l-alanine, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate and l-serine.</s><s>Menaquinones MK-12, MK-11 and MK-13 are the major quinones.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is composed largely of 15 : 0 anteiso (52·6 %), 16 : 0 iso (25·4 %) and 17 : 0 anteiso (11·2 %).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is of the B2<em>β</em> type, (l-homoserine)-d-glu→gly→d-Orn, with glycolyl residues.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are glucose and galactose.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and unknown polar lipids including glycolipid and phospholipid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 69·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is S3-E<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16914<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19079<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the biofilm of a membrane bioreactor.</s></p></content></protolog>