<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8281_nm.14129" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14129" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14129" rank="species">Pseudonocardia endophytica</organism><reference id="rid.8281"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia endophytica sp. nov., isolated from the pharmaceutical plant Lobelia clavata.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>559</fpage><lpage>563</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64740-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244441</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia endophytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia endophytica</em> (en.do.phy′ti.ca. Gr. <em>endo</em> within; Gr. <em>phyton</em> plant; L. fem. suff. -<em>ica</em> adjectival suffix used with the sense of belonging to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>endophytica</em> within plant, endophytic, pertaining to the original isolation from plant tissues).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are aerobic.</s><s>Forms yellowish-brown substrate mycelium and white aerial mycelium on TSA and ISP2.</s><s>The substrate mycelium fragments into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Spore chains form on aerial mycelium.</s><s>No pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C, pH 6.0–8.0 and 0–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from arbutin, aesculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, maltose, melezitose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose and turanose, but not from adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, lactose, lyxose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbose, starch, tagatose, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>Utilizes l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-malic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, propionic acid, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid and succinic acid, but not acetic acid, l-alaninamide, d- or l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, lactamide, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, pyruvic acid or l-serine.</s><s>Ornithine decarboxylase and malonate tests give positive reactions; negative for nitrate reduction, milk peptonization and coagulation, gelatin liquefaction, growth in cellulose, gluconate test, H<sub>2</sub>S, melanin and urease production and starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Other physiological properties are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The cell-wall chemotype is type IV.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids contain phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine and diphosphatidylglycerol (phospholipid type PIII pattern).</s><s>Major fatty acids are i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 and i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 56035<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44969<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AA 206026<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19150<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a plant sample collected from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, south-western China.</s></p></content></protolog>