<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12507_nm.21350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21350" rank="species">Gibbsiella quercinecans</organism><reference id="rid.12507"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirk</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Palenzuela</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Gibbsiella quercinecans gen. nov., sp. nov., associated with Acute Oak Decline</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>444</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.08.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21115313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>G. quercinecans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0105"&#x003E;<em>G. quercinecans</em> (quer.ci.ne’cans. L.n. <em>quercus</em>, oak, oaktree; L.v. <em>necare</em>, to kill, to destroy; N.L. part. adj. <em>quercinecans</em>, oak-destroying (causing necrosis of oak)).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0110"&#x003E;Cell morphology and colony morphology are as given for the genus.</s><s>Phenotypic properties are as given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, some strains may produce acid from d-arabinose, d-cellobiose, gentiobiose, l-fucose and potassium gluconate and utilize d-cellobiose, lactulose, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, succinamic acid, l-aspargine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, d,l,α-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose-6-phophate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, erythritol, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxy-phenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, d,l-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine and 2-aminoethanol.</s><s>The G + C content ranges from 56.0 to 56.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0115"&#x003E;The type strain is FRB 97<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25500<sup>T</sup> = NCPPB 4470<sup>T</sup>), isolated from <em>Q. petraea</em> in Hoddesdon Park Wood, Hertfordshire, England.</s><s>Strains of this species have been isolated from various oak species exhibiting symptoms of Acute Oak Decline.</s></p></content></protolog>