<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12289_nm.20310" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20310" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20310" rank="species">Granulicella rosea</organism><reference id="rid.12289"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Granulicella paludicola gen. nov., sp. nov., Granulicella pectinivorans sp. nov., Granulicella aggregans  sp. nov. and Granulicella rosea sp. nov., acidophilic, polymer-degrading acidobacteria from Sphagnum  peat bogs</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2951</fpage><lpage>2959</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021824-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118293</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Granulicella rosea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Granulicella rosea</em> (ro′se.a. L. fem. adj. <em>rosea</em> rose-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus but with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–1.0×1.5–9.0 μm.</s><s>Colony colour varies from pale pink to pink.</s><s>Produces copious amounts of EPS.</s><s>Growth is non-homogeneous in liquid medium.</s><s>Able to utilize the following carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v): d-glucose, d-fructose, maltose, d-xylose, sodium d-galacturonate, glucuronate, pyruvate, malate and salicin.</s><s>Unable to utilize d-arabinose, sucrose, d-galactose, lactose, lactulose, leucrose, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbose, trehalose, d-fucose, cellobiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, dulcitol, arbutin, inulin, acetate, gluconate, lactate, succinate, butyrate, oxalate, propionate, formiate, fumarate, capronate, citrate, valerate, ethanol or methanol.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, laminarin, pectin, lichenan, starch and xylan but not sodium alginate, CM-cellulose, cellulose, chitin, chitosan, fucoidan or pullulan.</s><s>Esterase (C8) is present.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are absent: valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, esterase (C4), urease and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM test).</s><s>Oxidase-negative.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Capable of growth at pH 3.0–7.5 (optimum pH 4.5) and at 2–33 °C (optimum 18–22 °C).</s><s>Resistant to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, streptomycin, neomycin, lincomycin and novobiocin but susceptible to ampicillin and kanamycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain TPO1014<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18704<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1396<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Obukhovskoe, Yaroslavl region, European North Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>