<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9276_nm.14559" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14559" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14559" rank="species">Paracoccus saliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.9276"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus saliphilus sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a saline soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1924</fpage><lpage>1928</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005918-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567556</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus saliphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus saliphilus</em> (sa.li.phi′lus. L. n. <em>sal</em>, <em>salis</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>saliphilus</em> salt-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile, coccoid to rod-shaped, 1.6–2.0×2.5–5.5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, flat and colourless to yellow–brown.</s><s>Moderately halophilic; grows over a wide range (1–15 %, w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimal growth at 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–55 °C and at pH 6.0–8.0; optimal growth is at 37 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase and the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and methyl red.</s><s>Gelatin, urea and aesculin are hydrolysed, but casein, starch, CM-cellulose, pectin, tyrosine and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are not.</s><s>Enzyme activities (tested in the API ZYM system) are observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; no activity is observed for lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon or nitrogen and energy sources with the Biolog GN2 system: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-fucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, dl-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, dl-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>p</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, sebacic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid and phenylethylamine.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the predominant isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 60.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 90738<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 206074<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22163<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>