<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3184_nm.3975" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3975" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3975" rank="species">Clostridium methylpentosum</organism><reference id="rid.3184"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Himelbloom</surname><given-names>B.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium methylpentosum sp. nov.: a ring-shaped intestinal bacterium that ferments only methylpentoses and pentoses.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>151</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>293</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00406553</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2742449</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium methylpentosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium methylpentosum</i> (me'.thyl.pen.to'.sum. M.L. neut. adj. <i>methylpentosum</i>, pertaining to methylpentose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods (0.3 x 2.0 μm) bent in the shape of rings, with the ends of the rods usually overlapping.</s><s>Cells grow singly or forming left-handed helical chains (coils), most chains consisting of 3 to 4 cells and longer chains consisting of up to 50 cells.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-motile.</s><s>Endospores distend the cell, are spherical to oval and terminally located.</s><s>Endospores are formed on plates of Sweet E agar medium (Holdeman et al. 1977) supplemented with L-rhamnose.</s><s>Large capsules are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on L-rhamnose agar medium are white, circular, convex, opaque, smooth, mucoid, and measure 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Optimum growth rate and highest final cell densities are at 45°C.</s><s>No growth at 25°C or 50°C.</s><s>At 37°C with L-rhamnose as the fermentable substrate, growth yields are 4 x 10<sup>8</sup> colony-forming units per ml and the population doubling time is 1.2 h.</s><s>Cultures in L-rhamnose broth have a pH of 4.5-5.0 after incubation for 16 h at 37°C</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Does not carry out dissimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>Only L-rhamnose, L-fucose, L-lyxose, and D-arabinose are used as fermentable substrates for growth, among many compounds that were tested.</s><s>Does not utilize as fermentable substrates for growth: N-acetylglucosamine, amino acids, L-arabitol, L-arabinose, L-ascorbate, cellobiose, D-fructose, fucoidan, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-galacturonate, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, 2-deoxy-D-glucose, D-glucuronate, glycerol, lactate, lactose, D-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, D-mannose, pectin, polygalacturonate, 1,2-propanediol, pyruvate, raffinose, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, D-xytose, and L-xylose.</s><s>Exogenous biotin, vitamin B<sub>12</sub> and bicarbonate are required for growth.</s><s>Exogenous folic acid and riboflavin are stimulatory for growth.</s><s>Grows in 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growing cells ferment L-rhamnose or L-fucose forming propionate, <i>n</i>-propanol, acetate, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> as end products.</s><s>Acetate, glycolaldehyde, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub> are end products of L-lyxose or D-arabinose fermentation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% guanine + cytosine of the DNA is 46 (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: R2; deposited with the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC strain number 43829).</s><s>Inasmuch as the description of the species is based on a single strain (the type strain), the description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>