<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3825_nm.5782" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5782" rank="species">Actinomyces georgiae</organism><reference id="rid.3825"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces georgiae sp. nov., Actinomyces gerencseriae sp. nov., designation of two genospecies of Actinomyces naeslundii, and inclusion of A. naeslundii serotypes II and III and Actinomyces viscosus serotype II in A. naeslundii genospecies 2</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>273</fpage><lpage>286</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-273</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397195</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces georgiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces georgiae</i> (geor'gi.ae. N. L. gen. n. <i>georgiae</i>, of Georg, named in honor of Lucile Georg, a pioneer in <i>Actinomyces</i> taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on a study of 36 strains.</s><s>Strains are facultatively anaerobic, gram-positive, nonmotile, nonsporing rods that occur in pairs, short chains, and forms and may have swellings; branching is seldom seen.</s><s>Cells of the type strain grown for 24 h in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth are 0.9 to 1.0 μm wide and 3.3 to 6.1 μm long.</s><s>In broth medium without a fermentable carbohydrate, cells are shorter and may even be coccoid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although strains grow reasonably well on the surfaces of blood agar plates incubated in air enriched to 10% with CO<sub>2</sub>, 55% of the strains produce better surface growth when they are incubated anaerobically in anaerobe jars or streak tubes.</s><s>Colonies of the type strain incubated anaerobically are 1 mm in diameter, circular, entire, pulvinate, translucent, white, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Colonies of other strains range from 0.5 to 2 mm in diameter and usually are circular, entire, low convex, opaque (smaller colonies are transparent to translucent), white (27% are tan or beige), shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Addition of 0.02% Tween 80 to broth medium enhances the growth or fermentation of 62% of the strains; it does not inhibit the growth or fermentation of any strain tested.</s><s>In prereduced anaerobically sterilized broth medium, 53% of the strains grow better or have a lower pH in peptone-yeast extract-glucose media when the media are inoculated aerobically and the tubes are closed with rubber stoppers than when the media are inoculated anaerobically under CO<sub>2</sub> or aerobically and the tubes are covered with sterile aluminum foil.</s><s>Twenty percent of the strains grow equally well under all conditions of inoculation, and 27% grow equally well either under CO<sub>2</sub> or restoppered after aerobic inoculation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in prereduced anaerobically sterilized peptoneyeast extract-glucose-Tween 80 broth is turbid (85%) with smooth (38%), flaky (26%), crumby or granular (24%), or stringy to ropy (12%) sediment that occasionally adheres to the bottom of the tube.</s><s>Broth cultures without turbidity often have crumby to coarse granular sediment.</s><s>Good growth is produced in peptone-yeast extract (basal medium) broth cultures, and excellent growth is produced in peptone-yeast extract medium that contains a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The pH values of peptone-yeast extract cultures that are inoculated aerobically and restoppered are 6.6 to 7.8; the pH values of peptone-yeast extract cultures that are inoculated under CO<sub>2</sub> are 5.7 to 6.3.</s><s>The pH of peptone-yeast extract-glucose cultures is 4.7 (range, 4.5 to 5.2) and is the same under all conditions of inoculation if growth is equivalent.</s><s>The acid products (in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture) from 4- to 5-day-old peptone-yeast extract-glucose- Tween 80 broth cultures are as follows: succinic acid, 1.4 (range, 0.3 to 4.0); formic acid, 1.0 (range, 0.4 to 1.8); and acetic acid, 1.0 (range, 0.2 to 2.7).</s><s>Small amounts of lactic acid (0.4 meq/100 ml; range, 0.1 to 0.8 meqllOO ml) are detected in 70% of the cultures, and pyruvate (0.6 meq/100 ml; range, 0.2 to 1.5 meq/100 ml) accumulates in 54% of the cultures.</s><s>Lactate and pyruvate accumulate only in cultures that are inoculated aerobically and restoppered and are not detected in cultures that are inoculated under CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Accumulation of lactate and pyruvate probably results from an insufficiency of bicarbonate in the medium or CO<sub>2</sub> in the headspace gas.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas of peptone-yeast extract-glucose-Tween 80 cultures incubated for 4 to 5 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains grow well at 37°C.</s><s>No strain produces urease (urease broth) (13).</s><s>Fermentation of glycerol is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 16:0,18:1 <i>cis</i>-9, and 14:0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There is no reaction with fluorescent antibody conjugates to <i>A. israelii</i> serotype I, <i>A. israelii</i> serotype II (<i>Actinomyces gerencseriae</i> [see below]), <i>A. naeslundii</i> serotypes I, II, and III, Actinomyces serotype WVA 963, <i>A. viscosus</i> serotype II, <i>A. meyeri</i>, and <i>A. odontolyticus</i> serotypes I and II.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics of the species are shown in Tables 3 and 4.</s><s>Differential characteristics are shown in Table 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VPI D145A-7 (= ATCC 49285).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 65 to 69 mol%</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human gingival crevices. <i>A. georgiae</i> accounts for 1.4% of the human healthy periodontal flora (Table 6).</s></p></content></protolog>