<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1378_nm.11689" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11689" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3346" rank="subspecies">Xenorhabdus nematophilus poinarii</organism><reference id="rid.1378"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akhurst</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of Xenorhabdus, a genus of bacteria symbiotically associated with insect pathogenic nematodes.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>38</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-38</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Xenorhabdus nematophilus</i> subsp. <i>poinarii</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xenorhabdus nematophilus</i> subsp. <i>poinarii</i> (poi.nar´i.i. M.L. gen n. <i>poinarii</i> of Poinar; named for G. O. Poinar, Jr., who has made major contributions to the understanding of the nematode-bacterial association and was involved in isolating the symbiont of <i>N. glaseri</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies formed on NA by the primary forms of the bacteria symbiotic with <i>Neoaplectana</i> spp. (groups I through IV) were convex, circular with slightly irregular margins, 1.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter after 4 days, and slightly granular; pigmentation varied with the nematode species (Table 2).</s><s>The secondary-form colonies of these bacteria were similar to the primary-form colonies but somewhat flatter, wider (diameter, 2.5 to 3.5 mm), and more lightly pigmented.</s><s>On tergitol-7 medium containing TTC, the primary forms of group I and group II bacteria produced blue and green colonies, respectively, surrounded by decolorized zones after 3 to 5 days.</s><s>Secondary-form colonies did not absorb bromthymol blue; these colonies were red.</s><s>Neither form of the group III bacterium absorbed bromthymol blue, and both forms produced red colonies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On NA, the primary forms of all bacteria symbiotic with <i>Heterorhabditis</i> spp. (group V) except isolate T280/1 formed colonies that were mucoid, convex, circular with slightly irregular margins, and 3 mm in diameter after 4 days; isolate T280/1 primary-form colonies were slightly flattened and 4 mm in diameter.</s><s>The pigmentation of the colonies of some isolates varied with time; all were yellow after 2 days and then some progressed through orange to red or through light brown to pink.</s><s>The secondary form colonies of these bacteria were much flatter and wider (4.5 mm after 4 days) than the primary-form colonies, had more irregular margins, and were not mucoid.</s><s>Two of the secondary-form isolates were further differentiated as follows: isolate T280/2 formed rough colonies and isolate HP/2 formed yellow colonies, whereas isolate T280/1 formed smooth colonies and isolate HP/1 formed orange colonies.</s><s>Colonies of the primary form on tergitol-7 medium containing TTC were green with orangish brown centers and were surrounded by clearing zones diffused with pigment.</s><s>None of the secondary-form colonies except those of isolate T280/2 absorbed bromthymol blue from tergitol-7 medium containing TTC.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Xenorhabdus nematophilus</i> subsp. <i>poinarii</i> bacteria symbiotic with <i>N. glaseri</i></s></p><p class="description"><s>(type strain, G1 [= UQM 22161).</s></p></content></protolog>