<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5916_nm.10115" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10115" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10115" rank="species">Flavobacterium weaverense</organism><reference id="rid.5916"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium weaverense sp. nov. and Flavobacterium segetis sp. nov., novel psychrophiles isolated from the Antarctic</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1239</fpage><lpage>1244</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64164-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium weaverense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium weaverense</em> (wea.ver.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>weaverense</em> pertaining to the Weaver Peninsula, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive and psychrophilic.</s><s>Cells are non-motile long rods during the exponential phase (approx. 1.6–12.5×0.3–0.5 μm) and become short rods during the stationary phase (approx. 0.7–1.5×0.3–0.4 μm).</s><s>Colonies are convex, translucent, glistening, viscid, yellow, circular with entire margins and become mucoid after prolonged incubation on R2A or AOA.</s><s>Does not glide or adhere to agar plates.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Congo red is not adsorbed.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A, AOA, MA, NA and TSA, but not on cetrimide or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Grows well under aerobic conditions, weakly under microaerobic conditions (with 5–15 % O<sub>2</sub> and 5–12 % CO<sub>2</sub>, created by use of the CampyPack Plus system) and poorly under anaerobic conditions (with 4–10 % CO<sub>2</sub>, created by use of the GasPack Plus system).</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–12 (optimum pH 6–7) and with 0–3 % NaCl (optimum 1 %).</s><s>Grows at 5.0–19.9 °C with notional minimum, optimum and maximum growth temperatures of −29.7, 15.3 and 19.9 °C, respectively.</s><s>Minimum doubling time is 2.9 h.</s><s>Decomposes starch and Tween 80, but not alginate, chitin or elastin.</s><s>Positive reaction for urease.</s><s>Negative reactions for l-phenylalanine deaminase, indole production and alkalinization on Christensen's citrate agar.</s><s>Test for arginine dihydrolase is positive on Thornley's semi-solid medium, but negative with the API 20NE kit.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose and maltose, but not from d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, d-raffinose, d-salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, lactose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>In API ZYM kits, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are present; weak cystine arylamidase and trypsin activities are present; and esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose as sole carbon sources in API 20NE kits, but not arabinose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 2.</s><s>Maximum absorption peak of pigment is at 451 nm and the next shoulder is at 479 nm.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH; the full fatty acid profile is given in Table 1.</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AT1042<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 14048<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12223<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12384<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from the Weaver Peninsula, King George Island, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>