<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1233_nm.5237" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5237" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5237" rank="species">Staphylococcus caprae</organism><reference id="rid.1233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poutrel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus gallinarum and Staphylococcus caprae, two new species from animals.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>480</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus caprae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus caprae</i> (ca. prae. L. fem. n. <i>capra</i> goat; L. fem. gen. n <i>caprae</i> of a goat)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Staphylococcus caprae</i> is associated with goats; this description is based on results obtained with 10 strains isolated from goat milk.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S . caprae</i> cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-positive cocci 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter and occur singly, in pairs, in short chains, or in small groups.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire edges, low convex, opaque, nonpigmented, and glistening.</s><s>Colony diameters reach 5 to 6 mm after 2 days on brain heart infusion agar; on tryptose soya agar colonies are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 1 day at 37°C and 2 to 4 mm in diameter after 2 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grow well aerobically and anaerobically in semisolid thioglycolate medium.</s><s>They grow equally well at 37 and 45°C.</s><s>Growth is slower at 30°C, and at 25°C strong inhibition is evident.</s><s>Uniform turbidity with a small deposit is produced in nutrient broth.</s><s>All strains studied produce predominantly L-lactic acid from glucose under anaerobic growth conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Weak hemolysis is observed irregularly after overnight incubation on sheep blood agar.</s><s>After 2 days at 37°C all strains show a narrow clear hemolysis zone surrounded by a broad zone of faint discoloration.</s><s>These broad zones become more visible after the plates are kept at 4°C in a refrigerator and are reminiscent of the hemolytic effects of β-hemolysin (sphingomyelinase C), which is produced by many animal <i>S . aureus</i> strains and most <i>Staphylococcus intermedius</i> strains. <i>S . caprae</i> zones differ from zones produced by <i>S. aureus</i> and <i>S . intermedius</i> in their delayed appearance and in their diffuse edges.</s><s>On human blood all <i>S . caprae</i> strains produce only a narrow zone of clear hemolysis, which is visible after incubation for 1 day at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adegoke and Ojo described four goat strains which possessed similar hemolysis characteristics and were negative for coagulase and clumping factor.</s><s>It is possible that these strains belong to the same species as our strains.</s><s>Other goat strains isolated in Nigeria differed from these strains by being positive for coagulase, clumping factor, and staphylokinase production or by having negative hemolysis characteristics.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>S. caprae</i> strains are negative in the heat-stable nuclease test but produce broad reaction zones in deoxyribonuclease plate tests.</s><s>These zones, which are probably due to a heat-labile nuclease are one to three times the diameters of the inoculation streaks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive results are obtained with all strains in the following biochemical tests: catalase; phosphatase; acetoin production from glucose and pyruvate; nitrate reduction; arginine hydrolysis; and acid production from trehalose, mannose, glycerol, galactose, and lactose.</s><s>All strains except strain 142.22 are urease positive.</s><s>Two strains (strains 143.22 and 141.15) are maltose negative.</s><s>All strains are negative for the following reactions: coagulase with rabbit plasma; clumping factor with rabbit and human plasma; oxidase; protease on casein and gelatin; hyaluronidase; staphylokinase; hydrolysis of polysorbate (Tween 80); and esculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, fucose, β-gentiobiose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, glucitol, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, or xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan type of three strains (strains CCM 3573, 141.15 and 143.23) studied is L-Lys-Gly<sub>4-5</sub>, L-Sero<sub>0.8-1.2</sub> .</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acids of these strains are composed of glycerol, N-acetylglucosamine, and small amounts of glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to novobiocin (MIC, 0.1 μg/ml), penicillin G (MIC, ≤0.06 μg/ml, with one exception; strain 141.15 has a penicillin G MIC of 0.5 μg/ml), tetracycline hydrochloride (MIC, ≤0.5 μg/ml), erythromycin (MIC, ≤0.5 μg/ml), lincomycin (MIC, ≤1 μg/ml), streptomycin (MIC, ≤16 μg/ml), neomycin (MIC, ≤1 μg/ml), furazolidone (MIC, ≤8 μg/ml), and sulfamethoxazole (MIC, 4 to 8 μg/m).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains are resistant to lysozyme (MIC, &#x003E;800 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The lysostaphin MIC is 128 to 256 μg/ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results of DNA-DNA hybridization studies indicate the phylogenetic relationships to other staphylococci, in particular the relationships to <i>S. capitis</i> and <i>S . epidermidis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics that differentiate <i>S. caprae</i> from other coagulase-negative staphylococci are shown in Table 3.</s><s>In particular, the unique fermentation pattern of <i>S . caprae</i> with its negative mannitol, fructose, and sucrose reactions is useful in the identification of this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 143.22 (= CCM 3573) is designated the type strain of <i>S. caprae</i>.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a milk sample taken from a goat, and its characteristics are described below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 143.22<sup>T</sup> cells are nonmotile, nonsporeforming, gram-positive cocci that occur in pairs or singly in groups or short chains.</s><s>The cell diameter is 0.8 to 1 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 143.22<sup>T</sup> colonies are circular with entire edges, low convex, opaque, nonpigmented, and glistening, with diameters ranging from 2 to 6 mm.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows better at 37 to 45°C than at 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Positive for catalase, phosphatase, acetoin, nitrate, and arginine and negative for coagulase, clumping factor, oxidase, protease, hyaluronidase, staphylokinase, urease, polysorbate (Tween 80), and esculin.</s><s>Hemolytic on human blood agar.</s><s>Produces a double hemolysis zone after 2 days on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Heat-labile nuclease positive; heat-stable nuclease negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces acid from galactose, lactose, glycerol, mannose, and trehalose, No acid is produced from amygdalin, arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, fucose, β-gentiobiose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, sorbitol, turanose, xylitol, or xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to novobiocin, penicillin G, tetracycline hydrochloride, erythromycin, lincomycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, neomycin, furazolidone, and sulfamethoxazole.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lysostaphin MIC: 128 μg/ml.</s><s>Resistant to lysozome.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Class I fructose 1,6-diphosphate aldolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type: L-Lys-Gly<sub>4.2</sub>, L-Ser<sub>0.9</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Composition of cell wall teichoic acid: glycerol, N-acetylglucosamine, and small amounts of glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of DNA: 36.1 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>