<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7008_nm.5885" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5885" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5885" rank="species">Citricoccus muralis</organism><reference id="rid.7008"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Altenburger</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lubitz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Citricoccus muralis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium isolated from a medieval wall painting.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2100</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02309-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508874</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Citricoccus muralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Citricoccus muralis</i> (mu.ra'lis. L. adj. <i>muralis</i>, -<i>le</i> pertaining or belonging to walls)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics are as described for the genus.</s><s>Colonies reach a maximum size of 3 mm after 2 weeks incubation.</s><s>They are yellow-pigmented, circular, convex and opaque.</s><s>No acid is produced from glucose, sucrose, salicin, inositol, rhamnose, trehalose, cellobiose or D-mannose.</s><s>Gluconate, D-glucose, D-maltose, D-mannose, D-sucrose, D-trehalose, acetate, propionate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, DL-lactate, L-malate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-aspartate, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate are assimilated.</s><s>N-Acetyl dgalactosamine, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, <i>p</i>-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, α-dmelibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, maltitol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, putrescine, trans-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, itaconate, mesaconate, suberate, L-alanine, β-alanine, L-histidine, L-ornithine and L-tryptophan are not assimilated.</s><s>Aesculin, pnitrophenyl (<i>p</i>NP) α-D-glucopyranoside, 2-deoxythymidine-5'-<i>p</i>NP phosphate, L-alanine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide (L-alanine <i>p</i>NA) and L-proline <i>p</i>NA are hydrolysed. <i>p</i>NP β-D-Galactopyranoside, <i>p</i>NP β-dglucuronide, <i>p</i>NP β-D-glucopyranoside, <i>p</i>NP β-dxylopyranoside, bis-<i>p</i>NP phosphate, <i>p</i>NP phenylphosphonate, <i>p</i>NP phosphorylcholine and L-glutamate-γ-3-carboxy <i>p</i>NA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 20 and 80 are decomposed.</s><s>Casein and starch are not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production are negative.</s><s>Ureasepositive.</s><s>Good growth occurs at room temperature and at 28°C.</s><s>Moderate growth occurs at 4°C and no growth is seen at 37°C.</s><s>Good growth occurs at NaCl concentrations up to 7% (w/v), weak growth at 10% (w/v) and no growth at 15% (w/v).</s><s>Growth is observed at initial pH values between 6 and 10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from a medieval wall painting in the church of St Georgen in Styria, Austria.</s><s>The type strain is strain 4-0<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11442<sup>T</sup>=CCM 4981<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>