<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12744_nm.22524" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22524" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22524" rank="species">Streptomyces scopuliridis</organism><reference id="rid.12744"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farris</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duffy</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Findlay</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olson</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces scopuliridis sp. nov., a bacteriocin-producing soil streptomycete</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2112</fpage><lpage>2116</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023192-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870885</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces scopuliridis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces scopuliridis</em> (scop.ul.i′rid.is. L. masc. n. <em>scopulus</em> cliff, bluff, crag; L. gen. n. <em>Iridis</em> of or belonging to the goddess of the rainbow; N.L. gen. n. <em>scopuliridis</em> from a rainbow cliff, referring to the location of isolation, Rainbow Bluff, a woodland bluff in Lynn, Alabama).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming actinomycete.</s><s>Substrate and aerial mycelia are produced; however, the aerial hyphae fail to undergo the sporulation process.</s><s>The substrate and aerial hyphae branch extensively, and the aerial hyphae remain white upon maturation.</s><s>The reverse side of the substrate mycelium produces a golden brown pigment on ISP3, ISP4 and ISP5 media.</s><s>In addition to the characters described in Table 1, nitrate is reduced to nitrite and growth occurs at sodium chloride concentrations of 4–7 % (w/v), at pH 6.0–11.0 and at temperatures of 15–37 °C.</s><s>Hydrolyses adenine, casein, aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine, starch and xanthine, but not cellulose.</s><s>The four most abundant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and the G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.</s><s>Produces a broad spectrum bacteriocin with activity against Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RB72<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 41917<sup>T</sup>  = NRRL B-24574<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from Rainbow Bluff, a woodland bluff in Lynn, Alabama.</s></p></content></protolog>