<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.671_nm.5260" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5260" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5260" rank="species">Staphylococcus lugdunensis</organism><reference id="rid.671"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Freney</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brun</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meugnier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nervi</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fleurette</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus lugdunensis sp. nov. and Staphylococcus schleiferi sp. nov., two new species from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>168</fpage><lpage>172</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-2-168</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus lugdunensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus lugdunensis</i> (<i>lugdunensis</i>, Latin adjective of Lugdunum, the Latin name of Lyon, a French city where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on 11 clinical strains.</s><s>Cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-positive cocci; 0.8 to 1.O μm in diameter; occurring singly, in pairs, small clusters, or chains composed of three to five cells.</s><s>Grows on 10% (wt/vol) NaCl in P agar after 24 h and on 15% NaCl after 96 h.</s><s>Grows well in brain heart broth at 30 to 45°C and weakly at 20°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows heavily throughout the tube of thioglycolate medium.</s><s>D-Lactic acid is the predominant acid produced from glucose under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase not produced.</s><s>Coagulase test negative with rabbit and bovine plasma.</s><s>Heat-stable nuclease negative.</s><s>Staphylokinase not produced.</s><s>Clumping factor positive with human plasma.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetoin produced from pyruvate.</s><s>Ornithine decarboxylated.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl aminopeptidase and N-acetylglucosaminidase tests positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and β-galactosidase tests negative.</s><s>Acid produced from D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, and glycerol.</s><s>Acid not produced from D-mannitol, Draffinose, ribose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-xylose, xylitol, D-melibiose, and α-methyl-D-glucoside.</s><s>Esculin, β-glucuronidase, L-arginine arylamidase, and L-arginine dihydrolase tests negative.</s><s>Weak hemolysis on sheep blood agar after 2 days.</s><s>Hemolysis on rabbit blood agar not neutralized by antistaphylococcal alpha-toxin serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enterotoxins A, B, and C, TSST-1 toxin, and exfoliatin toxin not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to 25 mg of lysostaphin per ml and resistant to 400 mg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Resistant to vibriostatic compound 01129 and to bacitracin.</s><s>Susceptible to 0.12 μg of novobiocin per ml.</s><s>Susceptibility to the following antibiotics is similar to that of <i>S. aureus</i> ATCC 29213 (minimal inhibitory concentrations are given in parentheses): penicillin G (0.06 μg/ml), oxacillin (0.12 to 0.5 μg/ml), gentamicin (0.12 μg/ml), kanamycin (0.5 μg/ml), amikacin (0.5 to 2.0 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (2 to 4 μg/ml), tetracycline (0.12 Fg/ml), erythromycin (below 0.06 μg/ml), clindamycin (below 0.06 μg/ml), rifampin (below 0.06 μglml), vancomycin (0.5 to 1 μg/ml), pefloxacin (0.5 to 1 μg/ml), fosfomycin (2 to 16 μg/ml), nitrofurantoin (5 to 10 μg/ml), and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole (2 to 4 μg/ml).</s><s>Resistant to 23 <i>S. aureus</i> typing bacteriophages.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall teichoic acids contain glycerol, glucose, and glucosamine.</s><s>Protein A and β-ribitol teichoic acid not present.</s><s>Peptidoglycan is of the L-LYs-Gly<sub>5-6</sub>, type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain N860297 (= ATCC 43809).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain N860297<sup>T</sup> was isolated from an axillary lymph node.</s><s>The type strain has all the characteristics of the species.</s><s>In addition, it has the following properties.</s><s>On P agar, colonies are circular, smooth and glistening, and 3 mm in diameter, with an entire edge.</s><s>A creamy or yellowish orange pigment is produced after 5 days.</s><s>Older colonies show an acuminate center.</s><s>Broth cultures are uniformly turbid with a small deposit.</s><s>Fibrinogen affinity factor is detected on blood agar or nutrient agar cultures.</s><s>Good growth on 10% NaCl, poor growth on 15% NaCl.</s><s>Weak hydrolysis of gelatin.</s><s>Acid produced from lactose, weakly produced from turanose.</s><s>Staphylococcus aureus antigen c<sub>1</sub>/m/o present.</s><s>The base composition of DNA is 32 mol% G+C (thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>