<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1337_nm.4982" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4982" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4982" rank="species">Bacillus smithii</organism><reference id="rid.1337"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blumenstock</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Claus</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of Bacillus coagulans Hammer 1915 with a proposal for Bacillus smithii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>63</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-63</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus smithii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus smithii</i> (smithi.i.L. gen. n. <i>smithii</i> named after Nathan R. Smith, the American bacteriologist who has made fundamental contributions to the taxonomy of Bacillus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rods that measure 0.8 to 1.0 by 5.0 to 6.0 μm and are motile by peritrichous flagellation.</s><s>Oval or cylindrical endospores (0.6 to 0.8 by 1.3 to 1.5 μm) are produced terminally or subterminally in nonswollen sporangia or in some cases slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>The cell walls of vegetative cells contain diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The main menaquinone is MK-7; also present is MK-6.</s><s>Agar colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, thin, smooth, circular, and entire and measure about 2</s></p><p class="description"><s>mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Facultative thermophile.</s><s>Grows at 25 to 60"; most strains grow at 65°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.7; does not grow at pH 4.5 or 7.7 in nutrient broth.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 3% NaCl, 0.001% lysozyme, or 0.02% azide (except two strains).</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, H<sub>2</sub>S, and indole are not produced.</s><s>In Voges-Proskauer broth, the pH ranges between 4.3 and 4.7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Casein, chitin, egg yolk lecithin, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Starch is weakly hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of pullulan and esculin is variable.</s><s>DNA and hippurate are hydrolyzed. <i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl-β-galactosidase is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilization of citrate and propionate is variable.</s><s>Acetate, fumarate, malate, and succinate are utilized.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, phenylalanine and trytophan deaminases, and urease are not produced, Tyrosine is not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Litmus milk is not coagulated or acidified, but is usually alkalized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from D-fructose, D-glucoseand trehalose.</s><s>Acid production from L-arabinose, erythritol, D-galactose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, D-mannose, D-ribose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, and D-xylose is variable.</s><s>A small proportion (10% or less) of the strains metabolize the following substrates: N-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, D- and L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-xyloside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, raffinose, L-sorbose, starch, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant density range for 21 strains was 1.6917 to 1.6940 g/cm<sup>3</sup>, and the G+C contents determined from these values ranged from 38.1 to 40.4 mol%.</s><s>As determined by the thermal melting point method the G+C contents ranged from 38.7 to 39.7 mol% (five strains tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from evaporated milk, canned foods, cheese, and sugar beet juice from extraction installations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NRS-173, which has been deposited as strain NRRL NRS-173 in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection, Peoria, Ill.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics of the species; with respect to the variable characteristics, it ferments L-arabinose, D-galactose, maltose, mannitol, glycogen, D-ribose, and L-rhamnose.</s><s>Citrate and propionate are utilized.</s><s>The G+C content is 40.2 mol%.</s><s>This strain was isolated from cheese.</s></p></content></protolog>