<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8635_nm.13599" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13599" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13599" rank="species">Salinicoccus halodurans</organism><reference id="rid.8635"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus halodurans sp. nov., a moderate halophile from saline soil in China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1537</fpage><lpage>1541</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65467-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599690</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus halodurans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus halodurans</em> (ha.lo.du′rans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt; L. pres. part. <em>durans</em> enduring; N.L. part. adj. <em>halodurans</em> salt-enduring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of strain W24<sup>T</sup> are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming cocci, 0.65–0.90 μm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, tetrads or irregular clumps.</s><s>Colonies on GMH medium are circular, white, opaque and slightly convex, reaching 1.4–2.8 mm in diameter after cultivation at 37 °C for 2 days.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 8–43 °C, and the optimum temperature is approximately 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5–9.0, and maximum growth occurs at pH 7.5.</s><s>Grows well in media without NaCl.</s><s>Also able to grow in the presence of NaCl up to a concentration of 24 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, NH<sub>3</sub> production, methyl red reaction, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, citrate utilization, urease production, and hydrolysis of gelatin and aesculin, but negative for indole production, Voges–Proskauer reaction, and hydrolysis of starch, casein, cellulose, and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Utilizes d-mannitol, erythritol, sorbitol, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose, d-lactose, sucrose, trehalose, cellobiose and l-rhamnose as sole carbon and energy sources, but not lactate, creatine, dodecanoic acids, acetone, ethanol, propanol, pentanol, butanol, iso-amyl alcohol or iso-propyl alcohol.</s><s>Produces acid in the API 50 CH gallery from d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, erythritol, glycerol, d-ribose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose, cellobiose, d-lactose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and 5-ketogluconate, but not from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, l-rhamnose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, melibiose, melezitose, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, raffinose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, xylitol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, amygdalin, arbulin, salicin, inulin, glycogen, gluconate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), novobiocin (5 μg), rifandin (5 μg), vancomycin (30 μg), penicillin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg), but resistant to norfloxacin (10 μg), bacitracin (0.04 U), ciprofloxacin (5 μg) and streptomycin (5 μg).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (21.85 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (17.89 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14.33 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (8.82 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8.62 %).</s><s>Major cellular polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The major lipoquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The cell-wall murein is of l-Lys–Gly<sub>5</sub> type.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, W24<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6501<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19336<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil sample around the Chaerhan salt lakes of Qinghai province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>