<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1562_nm.2831" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2831" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2831" rank="species">Aestuariibacter salexigens</organism><reference id="rid.1562"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aestuariibacter salexigens gen. nov., sp. nov. and Aestuariibacter halophilus sp. nov., isolated from tidal flat sediment, and emended description of Alteromonas macleodii.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>571</fpage><lpage>576</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02798-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023977</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aestuariibacter salexigens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aestuariibacter salexigens</em> (sa.lex′i.gens. L. n. <em>sal salis</em> salt, sea water; L. v. <em>exigo</em> to demand; N.L. part. adj. <em>salexigens</em> sea water-demanding).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are approximately 1·0–1·8 μm long and 0·4–0·6 μm wide.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 35 °C, pH 7–8 and 2–6 % artificial sea salts.</s><s>Colonies are circular, raised, entirely margined, brittle, rough, opaque and white on MA and hard to emulsify.</s><s>Viability is lost rapidly after 7 days on MA at 30 °C.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Decomposes DNA, aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tween 80, but not agar, alginate, casein, cellulose, chitin or egg yolk.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, fluorescein, H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, polyhydroxybutyrate or urease.</s><s>Does not ferment carbohydrates.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but not lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, glycine, inulin, l-arginine, l-ornithine and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>d-Galactose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, ethanol, l-lysine and succinate are utilized weakly.</s><s>Does not utilize acetamide, adenine, benzoate, citrate, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-salicin, d-xylose, inositol, 2-propanol, lactose, l-cysteine, l-rhamnose, sucrose, salicylate or thiamin.</s><s>Cellular fatty acid composition is given in Table 2.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 48 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JC2042<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 14006<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12042<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15300<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the sediment of getbol, the Korean tidal flat.</s></p></content></protolog>