<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6953_nm.5497" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5497" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5497" rank="species">Carnobacterium viridans</organism><reference id="rid.6953"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>T.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peirson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yost</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Carnobacterium viridans sp. nov., an alkaliphilic, facultative anaerobe isolated from refrigerated, vacuum-packed bologna sausage.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1881</fpage><lpage>1885</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02216-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361300</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Carnobacterium viridans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Carnobacterium viridans</i> (vi«ri.dans. N.L. adj. <i>viridans</i> from L. v. <i>viridare</i> to make green, referring to the production of a green colour in cured meat by the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, facultatively anaerobic organism that occurs as slightly curved rods, singly or in pairs, or as straight rods (0.8x3.6±0.6 μm) in chains sometimes 20 μm long.</s><s>Grows satisfactorily in BHI, APT, M5 and CTSI media, but poorly on a variety of media including MRS.</s><s>Does not grow on Rogosa agar.</s><s>It grows over a range of pH from 5.5 to 9.1 and from 2 to 30°C, but the range may be slightly greater.</s><s>No growth at 37°C.</s><s>Does not produce catalase or oxidase and is bhaemolytic on blood-agar base with 0.8% sheep blood.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose, nitrate is not reduced and H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, inulin, mannitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, ribose or D-xylose.</s><s>Thus, the organism differs from the seven described species of <i>Carnobacterium</i>.</s><s>It is capable of acid production/growth on: galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose and tagatose (API 50CHL).</s><s>The organism also metabolizes N-acetyl D-mannosamine, arbutin, dextrin, gentiobiose, glucose 6-phosphate, maltotriose, 3-methyl D-glucose, salicin, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, pyruvic acid and uridine (Biolog AN).</s><s>Negative for all other substrates used in the API 50CHL and Biolog AN panels.</s><s>Does not grow in 4% (w/v) NaCl but will tolerate 26.4% (w/v) NaCl (saturated brine) for long periods at 4°C.</s><s>Does not grow on KF streptococcus agar.</s><s>Produces predominantly L(+)-lactic acid from glucose and the cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-DAP.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain MPL-11<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-336<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14451<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for its 16S rDNA sequence is AF425608.</s></p></content></protolog>