<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6890_nm.4488" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4488" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4488" rank="species">Dethiosulfovibrio peptidovorans</organism><reference id="rid.6890"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Magot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ravot</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Campaignolle</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Crolet</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dethiosulfovibrio peptidovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a new anaerobic, slightly halophilic, thiosulfate-reducing bacterium from corroding offshore oil wells.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>818</fpage><lpage>824</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-818</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226912</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dethiosulfovibrio peptidovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dethiosulfovibrio peptidovorans</i> (pep.ti.do.vo'rans. Gr. adj. <i>peptos</i>, cooked; L. v. <i>voro</i>, to devour; M.L. part adj. <i>peptidovorans</i>, devouring peptides)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative vibrios, 3 to 5 μm by 1 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 20 and 45°C (optimum 42°C) and at pH values between 5.5 and 8.8 (optimum 7.0).</s><s>The organism is slightly halophilic; growth requires NaCl (optimum, 3%), but no growth occurs at 11% NaCl.</s><s>The organism is a strictly anaerobic bacterium using peptides and amino acids as its sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The organism ferments serine and histidine. <i>D. peptidovorans</i> uses alanine, arginine, asparagine, glutamate, isoleucine, leucine, methionine, and valine only in the presence of thiosulfate as an electron acceptor.</s><s>The organism produces acetate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, 2-methylbutyrate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub> from peptides.</s><s>Yeast extract is not required, but improves growth on Casamino Acids and peptides.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for the use of a single amino acid.</s><s>The organism uses elemental sulfur and thiosulfate, but not sulfate, as electron acceptors with peptides.</s><s>The organism does not perform disproportionation of thiosulfate or elemental sulfur.</s><s>The presence of either sulfur or thiosulfate increases the biomass and the growth rate.</s><s>In addition, H<sub>2</sub>S is produced with a concomitant decrease in H<sub>2</sub> when thiosulfate or sulfur is present.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by hydrogen, but this inhibition is partially reversed by the addition of thiosulfate.</s><s>Cells do not contain cytochrome or desulfoviridin.</s><s>The organism is unable to utilize proteins (gelatin and casein), carbohydrates (arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, sorbose, trehalose, and xylose), fatty acids (acetate, propionate, butyrate, citrate, and lactate) as its sole carbon and energy source with added yeast extract, bio-Trypticase, and/or thiosulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition (G+C content) is 56 mol%. <i>D. peptidovorans</i> lives in an oil-producing well in Africa.</s><s>The type strain is SEBR 4207 (=DSM 11002).</s></p></content></protolog>