<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6168_nm.9350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9350" rank="species">Nereida ignava</organism><reference id="rid.6168"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nereida ignava gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel aerobic marine alpha-proteobacterium that is closely related to uncultured Prionitis (alga) gall symbionts</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>631</fpage><lpage>636</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63442-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nereida ignava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nereida ignava</em> (ig.na′va. L. fem. adj. <em>ignava</em> lazy).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, the species has the characteristics described below.</s><s>It does not swarm or luminesce.</s><s>Requires at least 1·36 % (w/v) marine salts and tolerates up to 8 % (w/v) salts, failing to grow at 9 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive growth at 13 and 28 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 4, 37 or 40 °C.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, starch, lecithin, alginate or agar.</s><s>Does not grow in gelatin, DNA or Tween 80.</s><s>Produces negative results in tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulfate, indole production from tryptophan and sulfite oxidation.</s><s>Utilizes the following compounds as carbon and energy sources after 14 days incubation, provided that the medium is supplemented with 0·01 % (w/v) yeast extract (an indication that undetermined growth factors are required): maltose, succinate, fumarate, malate, lactate and sarcosine.</s><s>In the same conditions, it grows weakly on d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, pyruvate, propionate, acetate, citrate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, l-serine, l-ornithine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and citrulline.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: d-ribose, d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-trehalose, l-rhamnose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, d-melibiose, salicin, amygdalin, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, d-sorbitol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, glycerate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, d-saccharic acid, glycine, l-leucine, l-arginine, l-alanine, l-glutamate, l-threonine, l-aspartate, l-lysine, l-tyrosine, l-histidine and putrescine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 2SM4<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5292<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16309<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108404<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49433<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Mediterranean sea water off Valencia (Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>