<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2727_nm.4046" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4046" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4046" rank="species">Clostridium thiosulfatireducens</organism><reference id="rid.2727"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hernández-Eugenio</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macarie</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thiosulfatireducens sp. nov., a proteolytic, thiosulfate- and sulfur-reducing bacterium isolated from an upflow anaerobic sludge blanket (UASB) reactor.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1461</fpage><lpage>1468</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01946-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361247</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium thiosulfatireducens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium thiosulfatireducens</i> (thi.o.sul.fa.ti.re.du'cens. N.L. n. <i>thiosulfas</i> (-<i>atis</i>) thiosulfate ; L. v. <i>reduco</i> to draw backwards, bring back to a state or condition; N.L. part. adj. <i>thiosulfatireducens</i> thiosulfate-reducing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are rods, 0.5-0.6 μm wide and 2-4 μm long, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Gram staining is positive, and electron microscopy of thin sections reveals an atypical Gram-positive cell wall ultrastructure.</s><s>The cells are motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Terminal spores are formed; sporangia are swollen.</s><s>Colonies (1 mm diameter), appearing after 1 day of incubation in peptone-rich medium at 37°C, are arborescent and translucent.</s><s>Growth occurs from 18 to 45°C, the optimum temperature being 37°C.</s><s>It tolerates NaCl concentrations up to 60 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.4, and growth occurs between pH 6.0 and 9.8.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth on amino acids but not for growth on peptides.</s><s>Gelatin, peptone, bio-Trypcase and Trypticase soy are used as carbon and energy sources in the absence of thiosulfate as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>The following amino acids are used as carbon and energy sources in the presence of thiosulfate : alanine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, phenylalanine, serine, threonine and valine.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted to acetate.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: arginine, asparagine, aspartate, cysteine, glutamine, glycine, tryptophan, tyrosine, L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, mannitol, D-ribose, L-xylose, dxylose, formate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, valerate, ethanol, n-butanol, n-propanol, fumarate, lactate, malate and succinate.</s><s>In the presence of thiosulfate, Casamino acids, gelatin, peptone and Trypticase soy are converted mainly to acetate, butyrate, isobutyrate, isovalerate or 2-methylbutyrate, CO<sub>2</sub> and sulfide.</s><s>Acetate is the only fatty acid detected from alanine and threonine oxidation, whereas isoleucine is oxidized to 2-methylbutyrate, leucine to isovalerate, valine to isobutyrate and phenylalanine to phenylacetate.</s><s>In the absence of thiosulfate, acetate is the major end product of the metabolism of proteinaceous compounds (Casamino acids, gelatin, peptone and Trypticase soy).</s><s>The isolate ferments serine to acetate, lysine to acetate and butyrate, methionine to propionate and histidine to an unidentified product.</s><s>It performs the Stickland reaction, using alanine as electron donor and methionine and serine as electron acceptors.</s><s>Thiosulfate and sulfur, but not sulfate, sulfite, nitrate or nitrite, are used as electron acceptors.</s><s>The use of thiosulfate increases the range of amino acids oxidized and has a beneficial effect on growth on peptone.</s><s>Adverse effects on animals and humans are not known.</s><s>Because of the ability of <i>C. thiosulfatireducens</i> to degrade amino acids and peptides, the possibility of harmful effects cannot be excluded.</s><s>Cautious handling and autoclaving of cultures before disposal is recommended.</s><s>The DNA has a G­+C content of 31.4 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from UASB digestors in Mexico treating industrial wastewaters.</s><s>The type strain is strain Lup 21<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13105<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106908<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>