<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.697_nm.3279" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3279" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3279" rank="species">Providencia heimbachae</organism><reference id="rid.697"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swenson</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Providencia heimbachae, a new species of Enterobacteriaceae isolated from animals.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>252</fpage><lpage>256</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-252</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Providencia heimbachae</i> (heim. bach'ae. M . L. gen. fem. n. <i>heimbachae</i> of Heimbach, to honor Friederike Heimbach, who isolated 12 of the strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>For the new species described here we propose the name <i>Providencia heimbachae</i>.</s><s>Strains of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, D-glucose-fermenting, nitrate-reducing, straight rod-shaped organisms that conform to the definitions of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (1) and the genus <i>Providencia</i> (16).</s><s>They grow on Endo agar, MacConkey agar, and other similar selective media.</s><s>Like members of other species of <i>Providencia</i>, strains of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> (particularly fresh isolates) develop a red to brown pigment on media containing aromatic amino acids, as well as a characteristic almondlike smell on phenylalanine agar (17).</s><s>Furthermore, they have the other characteristics of this genus (Table 3).</s><s>They are negative for the following tests: lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase, deoxyribonuclease, lipase (both corn oil and Tween 80), gelatinase, H<sub>2</sub>S production on Kligler and triple sugar iron agars, malonate, mucate, acetate, tartrate, pectate, o-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, Voges- Proskauer, and acid production from L-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, D-lactose, melibiose, α-methylglucoside, raffinose, and D-sorbitol.</s><s>They are positive for the following tests: acid production from D-mannose, methyl red, phenylalanine deaminase, and tyrosine clearing. <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> can be differentiated from other <i>Providencia</i> species by its negative tests for Simmons citrate, growth in the presence of KCN, acid production from trehalose, urease, and indole production and by positive tests for acid production from adonitol, D-arabitol, D-galactose, and L-rhamnose (Table 5).</s><s>Motility at 36°C is variable and weak (46% positive after 2 days; 85% positive after 3 to 7 days), and the gas produced in small amounts from D-glucose, D-galactose, and D-mannose by some strains is like that produced by <i>Providencia rustigianii</i> (often a pinhead- sized gas bubble in a Durham tube).</s><s>Additional characteristics of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> are given in Tables 3 through 5 .</s></p><p class="description"><s>Some biochemical tests give different results when medium ingredients or methods are varied.</s><s>The indole reaction is negative when bacteriological neutralized peptone (Oxoid USA), Polypeptone (BBL), or casein hydrolysate (E.</s><s>Merck AG, Darmstadt, Federal Republic of Germany) is used; however, it is weakly positive after 2 to 7 days when tryptone (Oxoid USA) or peptone is used along with 0.1% tryptophan (2).</s><s>The citrate reaction is negative only under standardized conditions (4).</s><s>Traces of readily metabolized substances, such as peptone or glucose, may lead to falsepositive results.</s><s>The KCN test is negative under standardized conditions, as described previously (5); however, weak positive results are obtained if the test is performed as described by Cowan (3) or Munson (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The similar biochemical reactions of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> and <i>Providencia rustigianii</i>, including weak or delayed motility, weak or no production of gas from sugars, and inability to utilize acetate, citrate, or tartrate, indicate that these two species are phenotypically more similar to each other than to the other three species of <i>Providencia</i>.</s><s>The similarity between <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> and <i>Providencia rustigianii</i> may in part reflect the the common habitat of the two species (i.e., the intestines of healthy penguins [12] and probably also other animals).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type (holotype) strain of <i>Providencia heimbachae</i> is strain MUA 2-110 (=CDC 8025-83=ATCC 35613).</s><s>This strain was isolated from the feces of a penguin (<i>Aptenodytes patagonica</i>) in a West German zoo by F.</s><s>Heimbach.</s><s>Its phenotypic characteristics (Table 3) are essentially those of the species</s></p></content></protolog>