<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12731_nm.22502" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22502" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22502" rank="species">Paracoccus stylophorae</organism><reference id="rid.12731"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus stylophorae sp. nov., isolated from the reef-building coral Stylophora pistillata</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2221</fpage><lpage>2226</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028035-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20935084</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus stylophorae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus stylophorae</em> (sty.lo.pho′ra.e. N.L. gen. n. <em>stylophorae</em> of <em>Stylophora</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a coral belonging to the genus <em>Stylophora</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, short rods (0.9–1.0 µm wide and 1.0–1.2 µm long) and are non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on MA are pale yellow, circular and convex with entire edges, 0.4–0.5 mm in diameter on MA after 24 h incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C, with 0–9 % NaCl and at pH 6.0–10.0.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 35 °C, with 5 % NaCl and at pH 8.0.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granule accumulation is observed.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase and DNase activities.</s><s>Negative for lipase (corn oil) activity and hydrolysis of casein, starch, alginate and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>With API 20 NE, positive for reduction of nitrate, hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate, but negative for production of indole, fermentation of d-glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease and β-galactosidase and assimilation of caprate and adipate.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase, but negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>With GN2 MicroPlates, utilizes Tweens 40 and 80, d-galactonic acid lactone, l-histidine, urocanic acid, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate; all other substrates included in the Biolog GN2 MicroPlate are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to rifampicin, nalidixic acid, kanamycin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, novobiocin, tetracycline, ampicillin and penicillin G, but resistant to streptomycin.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, an unknown aminolipid, an unknown glycolipid and four unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KTW-16<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25392<sup>T</sup>  = BCRC 80106<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the reef-building coral <em>Stylophora pistillata</em>, collected off the coast of southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>