<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12795_nm.22587" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22587" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22587" rank="species">Asanoa hainanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12795"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>Q.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Asanoa hainanensis sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil of Acrostichum speciosum in a mangrove, and emended description of the genus Asanoa</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2384</fpage><lpage>2388</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025825-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21057053</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Asanoa hainanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Asanoa hainanensis</em> (hai.nan.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>hainanensis</em> of or pertaining to Hainan, a tropical province of China, from which the mangrove soil sample was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-reaction-positive, non-motile actinobacteria that form extensively branched substrate hyphae.</s><s>Forms spore chains on tap water agar medium and M8 medium.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, reduces nitrate, liquefies gelatin, coagulates and peptonizes milk and degrades Tweens 20 and 80 but does not produce melanin, urease or hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Grows at 20–37 °C but not at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6–9 and in the presence of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, (+)-d-xylose, d-ribose, d-mannitol, inositol and dulcitol and weakly utilizes (+)-cellobiose, d-galactose, (+)-trehalose, glycerol, l-arabinose, (+)-l-rhamnose, (+)-melibiose, soluble starch, sucrose, dextrin, maltose, α-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid and pyruvic acid but does not utilize adonitol, (+)-melezitose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, meso-erythritol, hippuric acid, l-malic acid, dl-lactic acid or succinic acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilizes l-4-hydroxyproline, l-serine and l-valine and weakly utilizes l-arginine, l-methionine and l-cysteine but does not utilize l-histidine or l-phenylalanine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Contains glutamic acid, glycine, alanine and <em>meso</em>-A<sub>2</sub>pm as cell-wall amino acids.</s><s>Xylose, ribose, glucose and mannose are the whole-cell sugars (peptidoglycan type A1γ).</s><s>The acyl type of the cell-wall muramic acid is glycolyl.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and phospholipids of unknown structure containing glucosamine are present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 210121<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 4.5593<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 45427<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of the mangrove fern <em>Acrostichum speciosum</em> in Hainan Province, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>