<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3428_nm.5295" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5295" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5295" rank="species">Macrococcus bovicus</organism><reference id="rid.3428"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ballard</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Webster</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubner</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Delimiting the genus Staphylococcus through description of Macrococcus caseolyticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Macrococcus equipercicus sp. nov., and Macrococcus bovicus sp. no. and Macrococcus carouselicus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>859</fpage><lpage>877</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-859</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734040</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Macrococcus bovicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Macrococcus bovicus</i> (bov.ic'us. Gr. n. <i>bou</i> cow. L. gen. n. <i>bovis</i> of a cow. M.L. adj. <i>bovicus</i> pertaining to a bovine or cow, from which this organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics of ten strains (Table 1) isolated in 1992-1994 from the skin of a cow, a pony and several horses.</s><s>Colonies grow to 4±1 mm in diameter on P agar and TSA.</s><s>They are slightly convex, entire, butyrous, glistening and opaque, and have a pale-yellow to medium-orange pigmentation.</s><s>Growth is not detected in the anaerobic portion of a semi-solid thioglycollate medium.</s><s>Growth is good at NaCl concentrations up to 7.5 YO.O ptimum growth temperature is 35 "C.</s><s>Culture growth causes a partial haemolysis (greening) of horse and bovine blood.</s><s>The cell wall does not contain teichoic acid.</s><s>Lipoteichoic acid is present.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Pyrrolidonylarylamidase activity is negative.</s><s>All strains are resistant to novobiocin and susceptible to lysostaphin and oxacillin.</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically from D-mannitol, glycerol and β-D-fructose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from a-lactose.</s><s>Characteristics of <i>M. bovicus</i> that are general properties of the genus are listed above.</s><s>The variable characteristics of this species are listed in Table 4.</s><s>Major API STAPHIDENT profiles are 0200 (30%), 4500 (20%)an d 4600 (20%), and major ID32 STAPH profiles are 062200000 (20%), 0623 10200 (20%) and 072300200 (20%).</s><s>The major ribotype pattern type is dd 09344 (40%).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42-44 mol%.</s><s>This species appears to have a preference for perissodactyls (e.g. horses and ponies) and artiodactyls (e.g. cattle).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Type strain is ATCC 51825<sup>T</sup> (=DD 4516<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the skin of a Holstein cow.</s><s>It has all of the general properties of the species and genus described above and also the following characteristics.</s><s>Cells are spherical, 1.2-2.1 μm in diameter, have a slightly irregular surface (SEM), and occur singly and in pairs, tetrads and short chains.</s><s>Colonies on P agar and TSA are circular, 3-5 mm in diameter, entire, slightly convex, and with a glistening surface and butyrous consistency.</s><s>Medium-orange pigmentation.</s><s>Marginally facultatively anaerobic; no visible growth in anaerobic portion of thioglycollate medium.</s><s>Partial haemolysis (greening) of horse and bovine blood.</s><s>Positive DNase activity and latex agglutination.</s><s>Negative aesculin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction and urease activity.</s><s>Acid produced aerobically from D-trehalose, D-mannitol, glycerol and β-D-fructose.</s><s>No acid produced from sucrose, α-lactose, maltose and D-ribose.</s><s>Type dd 04516 ribotype pattern.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan is L-Lys-Gly<sub>3</sub>, L-Ser.</s><s>No detectable teichoic acid.</s><s>Lipoteichoic acid is present.</s><s>G + C content of DNA is 44 mol %.</s></p></content></protolog>