<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7445_nm.12186" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12186" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4578" rank="species">Haloanaerobium kushneri</organism><reference id="rid.7445"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bhupathiraju</surname><given-names>V.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McInerney</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloanaerobium kushneri sp. nov., an obligately halophilic, anaerobic bacterium from an oil brine.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>953</fpage><lpage>960</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-953</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425750</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloanaerobium kushneri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloanaerobium kushneri</i> (kush'ner.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>kushneri</i> named after Donn J. Kushner, in recognition of his contributions to the microbiology of halophilic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight, rod-shaped bacterium with cell dimensions of 0.5-0.8 x 0.7-3.3 μm.</s><s>Growing cells appear singly and in pairs and can be motile.</s><s>The cells stain Gram-negative and are non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on complex medium are circular, entire, opaque, white in colour and 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth in liquid medium is uniform.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, tetracycline and penicillin, but not by cycloheximide or sodium azide.</s><s>Obligately halophilic.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 12%; growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of between 9 and 18%.M agnesium chloride concentrations up to 1 M do not inhibit growth.</s><s>The temperature range is 20-45°C, with optimum between 35-40°C.</s><s>The pH range is 6.0-8.0, with the optimum between 6.5 and 7.5.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Fermentative metabolism.</s><s>The end products of glucose fermentation are ethanol, acetate, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> and, sometimes, formate.</s><s>The following compounds support growth in a basal medium: L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, D-glucose, inulin, maltose, D-mannose, peptone, sucrose and trypticase.</s><s>The utilization of fucose, glucosamine, glycerol, lactose, mannitol, pyruvate, sorbose, and xylose is variable among the strains of <i>H. kushneri</i>.</s><s>The following compounds do not support growth in a basal medium: L-alanine, L-ascorbate, adonitol, betaine, butyrate, cellulose, chitin, crotonate, dulcitol, formate, fumarate, glutamate, glycine, glycogen, inositol, lactate, L-lysine, malate, methanol, methionine, pectin, proline, propionate, starch, succinate, sarcosine and sorbitol.</s><s>Amino acid mixtures such as alanine-glycine, leucine-proline, isoleucine-tryptophan, valine-ornithine, phenylalanine-leucine and histidine-sarcosine are not utilized.</s><s>The specific content of major cellular fatty acids is strain-dependent and primarily C<sub>16:0</sub>, <i>cis</i>-9<sub>16:1</sub>, <i>cis</i>-7 <sub>16:1</sub>, and C<sub>14:0</sub> fatty acids.</s><s>The G+ C content of the DNA is 32-37 mol% and is strain-dependent (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The habitat is hypersaline petroleum reservoir production fluid from Payne County, OK, USA.</s><s>The type strain is VS-751<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700103<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>