<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6559_nm.6328" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6328" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6328" rank="species">Mycobacterium branderi</organism><reference id="rid.6559"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Koukila-Kähkölä</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Böttger</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paulin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jantzen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Katila</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium branderi sp. nov., a new potential human pathogen.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>549</fpage><lpage>553</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-549</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium branderi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium branderi</i> (bran'de.ri. L. gen. n. <i>branderi</i>, of Brander, referring to Eljas Brander, the former head of the Tuberculosis Laboratory of the National Public Health Institute, Finland, who collected the strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains that have the newly described sequence are nonchromogenic and produce smooth, often umbonate, off-white to grayish colonies on Middlebrook 7H11 agar (Fig. 4).</s><s>Growth is equally good at 37 and 45°C and is only slightly delayed at 25°C.</s><s>In acid-fast staining preparations the bacterial cells, which are 1.2 to 3 μm long, are delicate slender rods that are often slightly curved.</s><s>The strains are negative for Tween 80 hydrolysis, catalase, urease, and nitrate reductase activities (Table 1), and niacin.</s><s>They are strongly positive for arylsulfatase activity in 14-day tests and moderately to weakly positive for nicotinamidase and pyrazinamidase activities.</s><s>In susceptibility tests they are resistant to isoniazid, rifampin, pyrazinamide, and cycloserine but susceptible to ethambutol, streptomycin, ethionamide, and capreomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains have a glycolipid pattern unlike the patterns of previously described species (3).</s><s>As determined by thin-layer chromatography, they contain alpha mycolates, ketomycolates, and carboxy mycolates (3).</s><s>When the fatty acid methyl esters, alcohols, and mycolic acid cleavage products are analyzed by GLC, hexacosanoic acid (26:0) is the major mycolic acid cleavage product and 2-eicosanol(2-OH-20:0alc) is the major alcohol.</s><s>A high level (15 to 22%) of tuberculostearic acid (10-Me-18:0) is also present.</s><s>The type strain is strain 52157, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51789.</s></p></content></protolog>