<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5882_nm.5794" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5794" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5794" rank="species">Actinomyces nasicola</organism><reference id="rid.5882"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces nasicola sp. nov., isolated from a human nose</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1445</fpage><lpage>1448</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130031</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces nasicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces nasicola</em> (na.si′co.la. L. masc. n. <em>nasus</em> nose; L. masc. suffix -<em>cola</em> inhabitant of; N.L. masc. n. <em>nasicola</em> inhabitant of the nose, referring to the place of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short, diphtheroid-shaped rods; some branching and coccoid forms occur.</s><s>Non-acid-fast and non-spore-forming.</s><s>After 48 h anaerobic incubation on fastidious anaerobe agar, colonies are pinpoint, white or grey, opaque, shiny, entire and convex.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic; grows in air but grows better under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Acid is formed from fructose and cellobiose but not from amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose or xylose in conventional tests.</s><s>Acetic, lactic and succinic acids are the end-products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase and urease are not produced.</s><s>With API systems, acid is not produced from d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed, indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Activity is detected for alanine arylamidase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, serine arylamidase, valine arylamidase or tyrosine arylamidase.</s><s>Activity may or may not be detected for arginine dihydrolase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cysteine arylamidase, esterase C<sub>4</sub>, ester lipase C<sub>8</sub>, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glycine-tryptophan arylamidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase C<sub>14</sub>, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, phosphoamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin or urease.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-negative.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-9.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated, iso-methyl-branched and anteiso-methyl-branched types, with anteiso-C15, C16 : 0, C18 : 0 and C18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> as the major components.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 66·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R2014<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46092<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107668<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from antrum aspirate.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>