<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2775_nm.4522" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4522" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4555" rank="subspecies">Caldanaerobacter subterraneus subterraneus</organism><reference id="rid.2775"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonilla Salinas</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>L'Haridon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeanthon</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhé</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation from oil reservoirs of novel thermophilic anaerobes phylogenetically related to Thermoanaerobacter subterraneus: reassignment of T. subterraneus, Thermoanaerobacter yonseiensis, Thermoanaerobacter tengcongensis and Carboxydibrachium pacificum to Caldanaerobacter subterraneus gen. nov., sp. nov., comb. nov. as four novel subspecies.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>467</fpage><lpage>474</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02711-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023962</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Caldanaerobacter subterraneus</em> subsp. <em>subterraneus</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Caldanaerobacter subterraneus</em> subsp. <em>subterraneus</em> (sub.ter.ra′ne.us. L. pref. <em>sub</em> less than; L. n. <em>terra</em> earth; L. masc. adj. <em>subterraneus</em> underground, subterranean, describing its site of isolation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods (0·5–0·7×2–8 μm) that occur singly or in pairs and possess laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Spores are not observed under microscopic examination, but cultures exposed to 120 °C for 45 min can be subcultured, indicating the presence of heat-resistant forms.</s><s>Electron microscopic examination reveals a Gram-positive cell wall.</s><s>Round colonies (3 mm in diameter) develop on Phytagel plates or in roll-tubes after 3 days incubation at 70 °C.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and obligately anaerobic member of the domain <em>Bacteria</em>, family ‘<em>Thermoanaerobiaceae</em>’.</s><s>Thermophilic.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 65–75 °C at pH 7·5; temperature range for growth is 40–80 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH is 7·0–7·5; growth occurs between pH 5·7 and 9·2.</s><s>Halotolerant; grows in the presence of up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Yeast extract or bio-trypticase is required for growth on carbohydrates.</s><s>Growth on sugars is highly enhanced by the presence of both yeast extract and bio-trypticase.</s><s>Yeast extract cannot be replaced by vitamins.</s><s>Ferments cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, dl-lactose, dl-maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-ribose, starch, d-xylose, glycerol, mannitol, pyruvate and xylan.</s><s>l-Arabinose, l-rhamnose, sorbose, sucrose, l-xylose and CO are not used.</s><s>Acetate, l-alanine, lactate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> are produced during glucose fermentation.</s><s>Elemental sulfur, thiosulfate and sulfite, but not sulfate, are used as electron acceptors.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 38·4–41 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SEBR 7858<sup>T</sup> (=CNCM I-2383<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13054<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from oilfield waters.</s></p></content></protolog>