<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6474_nm.10572" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10572" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6084" rank="species">Agromyces fucosus</organism><reference id="rid.6474"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zgurskaya</surname><given-names>H.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Voyevoda</surname><given-names>H.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobrovolskaya</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysak</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalakoutskii</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Agromyces and description of Agromyces cerinus subsp. cerinus sp. nov., subsp. nov., Agromyces cerinus subsp. nitratus sp. nov., subsp. nov., Agromyces fucosus subsp. fucosus sp. nov., subsp. nov., and Agromyces fucosus subsp. hippuratus sp. nov., subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>635</fpage><lpage>641</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agromyces fucosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agromyces fucosus</i> (fu.co'sus. N.L. n. <i>fucosum</i>, fucose; N.L. adj. <i>fucosus</i>, containing fucose in the cell wall)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Branching hyphae (width, 0.2 to 0.6 μm) break up into diphtheroid and rodlike, irregular, nonmotile fragments.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract medium are opaque, entire, and convex and sometimes penetrate into the agar.</s><s>Rough colony variants occur.</s><s>Produces a yellow carotenoid pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The whole-cell hydrolysates contain galactose, rhamnose, fucose, mannose, and glucose as major sugars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Organic nitrogen is not required for good growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains grow on media containing D-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, inulin, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucoside, methyl-α-Dglucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or D-xylose as a sole carbon source; dulcitol, i-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, methyl-β-D-arabinopyranoside, and L-sorbose are not used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, and D-xylose.</s><s>No acids are formed from D-glucose and <i>meso</i>-inositol.</s><s>Ascorbate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, citrate, formate, gluconate, oxalate, salicylate, and tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Arginine, methionine, norleucine, phenylalanine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine, and valine are not utilized as N sources.</s><s>Does not deaminate phenylalanine.</s><s>Esculin, arbutin, and starch are decomposed; casein, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, pectin, testosterone, Tween 21, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, urea, and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to bacitracin (10 μg/ml), erythromycin (15 μg/ ml), gentamicin (10 μg/ml), kanamycin (30 μg/ml), neomycin (30 μg/ml), novobiocin (30 μg/ml), rifampin (5 μg/ml), rifampin (50 μg/ml), tetracycline (30 μg/ml), and vancomycin (30 μg/ml) and resistant to clindamycin (2 μg/ml) and nalidixic acid (30 μg/ml).</s><s>No growth occurs on media supplemented with 7% NaCl, 0.01% sodium azide, or 0.0175% potassium tellurite.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following tests are variable: utilization of adonitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, and melibiose; production of acids from cellobiose, D-fructose, inulin, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose; utilization of fumarate, α-ketoglutarate, succinate, truns-aconitate, and valerate; decomposition of hippurate and tyrosine; nitrate reduction; and susceptibility to ampicillin (10 μglml), penicillin (10 μg/ml), and streptomycin (10 μg/ml).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs are 70 to 72 mol% (as determined by the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>A. fucosus</i> is strain VKM Ac-1345.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given above was based on seven strains.</s></p></content></protolog>