<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3_nm.5789" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5789" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5789" rank="species">Actinomyces hyovaginalis</organism><reference id="rid.3"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stubbs</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Molecular taxonomic studies of Actinomyces-like bacteria isolated from purulent lesions in pigs and description of Actinomyces hyovaginalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>471</fpage><lpage>473</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347506</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces hyovaginalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces hyovaginalis</i> (hy.o.va.gi.na'lis. Gr. n. <i>hys</i>, pig; L. n. <i>vagina</i>, sheath, vagina; N. L. masc. adj. <i>hyovaginalis</i>, pertaining to the vagina of a pig)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following morphological and physiological description is based on a study of 14 strains (6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are predominantly diptheroidal, and the rods are arranged in clusters or V or Y forms; coccoid elements may occur.</s><s>Colonies are flat with outrunning edges, a trait which is particularly pronounced after anaerobic incubation or incubation under CO<sub>2</sub> on horse blood agar.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, L- and D-arabinose, N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabitol, galactose, glucose, gluconate, fructose, D-mannose, maltose, D-lyxose, salicin, sucrose, turanose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from cellobiose, inositol, lactose, and β-methylxyloside.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, dulcitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-gentiobiose, inulin, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, D-tagatose, trehalose, L-qlose, and xylitol.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, and leucine arylamidase positive.</s><s>Pyrrolidonylarylamidase, pyrazinamidase, and β-glucuronidase negative.</s><s>Esculin, hippurate, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Arginine, gelatin, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is type A5β (Orn-Lys-Glu).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63 mol% G+C (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is strain NCFB 2983 (= BM 1192/5).</s><s>The habitat is the porcine genital tract.</s></p></content></protolog>