<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3177_nm.4390" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4390" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4390" rank="species">Anaerovibrio glycerini</organism><reference id="rid.3177"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schauder</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerovibrio glycerini sp. nov., an anaerobic bacterium fermenting glycerol to propionate, cell matter, and hydrogen.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>152</volume><fpage>473</fpage><lpage>478</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00446932</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerovibrio glycerini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerovibrio glycerini</i> (gly.ce.ri'ni sp. nov. glycerinum. M.L.n. glycerol, glycerini, of glycerol, referring to utilization of glycerol as sole substrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Curved, spiral-shaped cells, 0.5-2-10 μm in size, with slightly pointed ends, occasionally forming dark inclusion bodies.</s><s>Motile in young cultures, Gram-negative, nonsporeforming.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph, glycerol and diolein, perhaps other glycerolesters used as sole source of carbon and energy.</s><s>Propionate only organic fermentation product.</s><s>In mineral media, small amounts of hydrogen are formed.</s><s>Grows in freshwater medium as well as in the presence of up to 2% (w/v) sodium chloride.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, sulfur, or nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Indole not formed, gelatine or urea not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cytochrome b present, no catalase activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrates that did not support growth included glucose, fructose, mannose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, salicin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, sorbose, rhamnose, trehalose, arabinose, xylose, ribose, lactate, pyruvate, tartrate, malate, fumarate, succinate, aspartate, glutamate, citrate, formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, methanol, ethanol, propanol, ethylene glycol, 1,2-propanediol, 1,3-propanediol, 2,3-butanediol, acetoin, diacetyl, glycolate, glyoxylate, glycolaldehyde, oxalate, malonate, betaine, yeast extract, peptone, casamino acids, H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> (80%/20%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All substrates were given at 10 mM or 0.1% concentration.</s><s>Enrichment from anoxic sediments in mineral medium either in continuous culture or isolation by direct dilution of sediment or sludge material.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 5.0 - 8.5; Temperature range 10-42°C, optimum at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 34.4±1 mol% G+C (thermal denaturation).</s><s>Habitats: anoxic muds of freshwater origin, sewage sludge.</s><s>Type strain: LGS 4, DSM 5192, deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen GmbH, Braunschweig, FRG.</s></p></content></protolog>