<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8414_nm.13521" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13521" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13521" rank="species">Paraliobacillus quinghaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.8414"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paraliobacillus quinghaiensis sp. nov., isolated from salt-lake sediment in China.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>28</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65735-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126718</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paraliobacillus quinghaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paraliobacillus quinghaiensis</em> (quing.hai.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>quinghaiensis</em> pertaining to Qinghai, western province of China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase- and oxidase-positive, obligately aerobic, thin rods (3–5×0.4–0.6 μm), occurring singly, in pairs or in chains, and motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in terminal or subterminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>After incubation for 4–5 days on MMA5 at 37 °C, colonies are circular, translucent with slightly irregular margins, with a tiny raised point at the centre, and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies grown for less than 4 days are creamy white, but become pale yellow after several days.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–50 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 8.0).</s><s>Moderately halophilic, with growth occurring at 1–20 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 5 % NaCl, w/v).</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of starch, but negative for hydrolysis of casein, cellulose, chitin, gelatin, Tween 20, Tween 80 and urea.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive, but the Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Positive for oxidation of arabinose, but negative for citrate utilization and fermentation/oxidation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose and amygdalin (API 20E).</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, maltose and potassium 2-ketogluconate (API 50 CH).</s><s>Oxidizes l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, glycerol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, l-alanine, l-asparagine and l-serine (Biolog GP2).</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are catalase, cytochrome oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM).</s><s>Has MK-7 as the sole respiratory quinone and contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Polar lipid profile consists of phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine and three unknown phospholipids.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids (making up 85.46 % of the total) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM-C158<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17857<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6333<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sediment sample collected from the Dabuxun salt lake in the Qaidam Basin in Qinghai Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>