<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10766_nm.17862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17862" rank="species">Actinoplanes tereljensis</organism><reference id="rid.10766"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsetseg</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daram</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ando</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinoplanes toevensis sp. nov. and Actinoplanes tereljensis sp. nov., isolated from Mongolian soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>919</fpage><lpage>927</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009944-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661505</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinoplanes tereljensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinoplanes tereljensis</em> (te.rel.jen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>tereljensis</em> pertaining to the Mongolian region of Terelj, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Gram-stain-positive.</s><s>Cells grow well on ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 7, Bennett agar and YS medium, forming well-developed, extensively branched and non-fragmented substrate hyphae.</s><s>A pale pinkish brown soluble pigment is produced on ISP 7 and aerial mycelium is not observed.</s><s>Numerous irregular sporangia are formed on the surface of water agar, ISP 3, ISP 4 and Bennett agar media; spores are motile.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is moderate greyish brown to dark brownish red on different agar media.</s><s>Good growth occurs on ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 4, ISP 5, Bennett agar and YG agar at 28 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth is at 20–28 °C; does not grow at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6–9 and tolerates up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Biochemical test results are as follows: catalase is produced; nitrate is reduced; urea and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but not gelatin, starch or Tween 80; and casein and tyrosine are decomposed weakly, but not calcium malate, hypoxanthine, xanthine, arbutin or adenine.</s><s>According to the API ZYM assay: positive for acid phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase; weakly positive for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase lipase (C8) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase; and negative for leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, esterase (C4), valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and trypsin.</s><s>According to the API Coryne assay: positive for nitrate reduction, pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, hydrolysis of gelatin, d-glucose, d-xylose, maltose and sucrose, and catalase; weakly positive for fermentation of d-lactose and glycogen; and negative for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, and fermentation of d-ribose and d-mannitol.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains 3-hydroxy- and <em>meso</em>-DAP; diagnostic sugars are galactose, mannose, ribose, glucose, rhamnose, arabinose and xylose; mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) is the major menaquinone (85 %); a small amount of MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) is also observed (15 %).</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyl-<em>N</em>-methylethylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol, but phosphatidylcholine and phosphatidylglycerol are not detected (phospholipid type PII).</s><s>Major fatty acid methyl esters are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Detailed fatty acid profiles are given in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MN07-A0371<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 105297<sup>T</sup>=VTCC D9-10<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil of Terelj National Park, Töv Province, Mongolia.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>