<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4456_nm.5422" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5422" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5422" rank="species">Lactobacillus psittaci</organism><reference id="rid.4456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wacher</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hansson</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus psittaci sp. nov., isolated from a hyacinth macaw (Anodorhynchus hyacinthinus).</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>967</fpage><lpage>970</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411722</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus psittaci</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus psittaci</i> (psit.ta'ci. L. gen. masc. n. psittaci of the parrot, from which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, coccibacilli to rod-shaped occurring as single cells or in pairs.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>After 24 h incubation on Columbia horseblood agar, colonies are 1-2 mm in diameter, colourless and do not produce an odour.</s><s>α-Haemolytic.</s><s>Gas is produced from glucose (Gibson's semi-solid medium).</s><s>Growth is observed on acetate agar (pH 5.4).</s><s>Optimum pH range is 5.5-7.5.</s><s>Grows in 2% NaCl, but not in 6% NaCl.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose, D-raffinose and sucrose, but not from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, pullulan, D-ribose, sorbitol, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for acid phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, phosphoamidase and valine arylamidase (weak reaction).</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, methyl β-D-glucopyranosidase, pyrazinamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, trypsin and urease.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin or hippurate are not.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Isolated from the lungs of a dead hyacinth macaw (<i>Anodorhynchus hyacinthinus</i>).</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 42378<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106492<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>