<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1987_nm.10976" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10976" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10976" rank="species">Pseudomonas moorei</organism><reference id="rid.1987"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cámara</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strömpl</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pieper</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas reinekei sp. nov., Pseudomonas moorei sp. nov. and Pseudomonas mohnii sp. nov., novel species capable of degrading chlorosalicylates or isopimaric acid</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>923</fpage><lpage>931</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64703-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473234</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas moorei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas moorei</em> (moo′re.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>moorei</em> of/from Moore, named in honour of Edward R. B. Moore, for his important contributions to the study of the genus <em>Pseudomonas</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are circular and white–yellow on LB agar.</s><s>Cells do not produce a fluorescent pigment on King's B medium.</s><s>Cells are oxidase-positive and show hydrolysis of arginine, but do not reduce nitrates or hydrolyse Tween 80.</s><s>Does not show lecithinase, urease or β-galactosidase reactions or hydrolysis of aesculin or gelatin.</s><s>Indole is not produced on tryptophan and there is no glucose fermentation.</s><s>Does not grow at 41 °C or in media supplemented with 5 or 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Results obtained with Biolog GN2 microplates indicate that the following substrates are utilized: l-arabinose, d-galactose, α-d-glucose, d-mannitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid and glycerol.</s><s>Weak utilization is observed of d- and l-alanine, dl-carnitine, putrescine and 2-aminoethanol.</s><s>The other organic substrates included in the Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>Consistent with the chemical properties of the genus, the major respiratory lipoquinone present is ubiquinone 9 (Q9) and the major phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The fatty acids present include 3-OH 10 : 0, 12 : 0, 2-OH 12 : 0, 3-OH 12 : 0, 14 : 0, 16 : 1ω7<em>c</em>, 16 : 1ω7<em>t</em>, 16 : 0, cyclo 17 : 0, 18 : 1ω7<em>c</em>, 18 : 0 and cyclo 19 : 0.</s><s>The level of 14 : 0 does not exceed 1.5 %.</s><s>The 3-OH 10 : 0 and 2-OH 12 : 0 are ester-linked, while the 3-OH 12 : 0 is amide-linked.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is RW10<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12647<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53114<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>