<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2791_nm.7354" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7354" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7354" rank="species">Streptomyces yunnanensis</organism><reference id="rid.2791"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces yunnanensis sp. nov., a mesophile from soils in Yunnan, China.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>217</fpage><lpage>221</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01851-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656176</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Teredinibacter turnerae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Teredinibacter turnerae</i> (tur'ner.ae. N.L. fem. n. <i>turnerae</i> of Turner, named after Ruth D. Turner, malacologist at the Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics of the genus, the species characterization is based on the properties of the type strain (T7902) and three additional strains (T7901, T8402 and T8602<sup>T</sup>) isolated from phylogenetically divergent species and genera of teredinid molluscs collected in distantly separated locations in the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans.</s><s>All isolates grew on cellulose with or without an added source of combined nitrogen and also demonstrated growth on carboxymethylcellulose, cellobiose, fructose, salicin, glutamate,  succinate, pyruvate, pectin, xylan, sucrose, xylose, yeast extract and glucose.</s><s>All but T8604 also grew on acetate.</s><s>Acid was produced by all isolates when grown on sucrose, fructose, xylose, glucose, pectin, salicin, cellobiose and cellulose.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is approximately 20-30 °C, with optimal growth occurring at 30-35 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 15 or 40 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 8.5 and the pH range for growth is 6.0-10.5.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 0.1-0.6 M, and optimal growth occurs at 0.3 M.</s><s>Growth also requires elevated concentrations of Ca<sup>2+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup> that reflect the chemistry of seawater.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>T7902<sup>T</sup> exhibits oxidase and catalase activity.</s><s>No growth was observed under anaerobic conditions on SBM agar with cellulose as the carbon source.</s><s>Colonies are translucent with all growth occurring beneath the agar surface.</s><s>As colonies age a yellow-brown pigment is observed and clearing occurs around the colonies due to cellulose hydrolysis.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 49-51 mol%.</s><s>The type strain T7902<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC39867<sup>T</sup>=DSM15152<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from <i>Lyrodus pedicellatus</i> originally collected from Long Beach, CA, USA, but kept in culture at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution for many years.</s></p></content></protolog>