<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1512_nm.1591" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1591" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1591" rank="species">Methylobacterium rhodesianum</organism><reference id="rid.1512"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Green</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bousfield</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hood</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Three new Methylobacterium species: M. rhodesianum sp. nov., M. zatmanii sp. nov., and M. fujisawense sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>124</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-124</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylobacterium rhodesianum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylobacterium rhodesianum</i> (rhod'es.i.an.um Id. L. neut. adj. <i>rhodesianum</i> named after the British taxonomist Muriel Rhodes-Roberts for her contributions to pseudomonad taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mode of respiration, colony and cell morphology, flagellar arrangement, Gram reaction, and oxidase and catalase as previously described (6).</s><s>Grows at 15 and 30°C but not at 10°C.</s><s>Most strains will also grow at 37°C.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Casein, cellulose, gelatin, lecithin, and DNA are not degraded.</s><s>Urease is produced, but β-galactosidase, indol, H<sub>2</sub>S, Lornithine and L-1 ysine decarboxylases, and L-arginine dihytlrolase are not.</s><s>The methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Some strains reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin, tetracyclines, gentamicin, alhamycin T, streptomycin, and framycetin but resistant to tx-ythromycin, nalidixic acid, oleandomycin, spiramycin, polymyxin B, colistin sulfate, penicillin G, and bacitracin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds serve as sole carbon sources: fructose, glycerol, malonate, succinate, fumarate, 2-oxoglutarate, lactate, malate, acetate, pyruvate, ethanol, propylene glycol, methanol , monome thy lamine, ethylamine, formate, and betaine.</s><s>Does not utilize monosaccharides other than fructose, citrate, sebacate, tartrate, or trimethylamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 69.8 to 71.2 moles percent (mol%) (9).</s><s>We propose</s></p><p class="description"><s>NCIB 12249<sup>T</sup> (<i>Pseudomonas</i> strain 1 [16]), which was isolated from a fermentor operating with formaldehyde as a sole carbon source, as the type strain.</s><s>As a result of recent work, including DNA-DNA homology studies (9), we also propose that the following strains be considered as strains of <i>M. rhodesianum</i>: <i>Pseudomonas</i> sp. strains NCIB 10598 and 10611, strain M159-1 (13), Rhodes-Roberts strain CS51, and NCIB 12440 “<i>Corynebacterium rubrum</i>.” (It should be noted that the National Collection of Industrial Bacteria strain of “<i>C. rubrum</i>” is different from the strain deposited in the DSM as DSM 1857).</s><s>Other strains assigned to this species solely on the basis of phenotypic data are listed in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>