<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10753_nm.17845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17845" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17845" rank="species">Streptomyces ascomycinicus</organism><reference id="rid.10753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Streptomyces hygroscopicus strains as Streptomyces aldersoniae sp. nov., Streptomyces angustmyceticus sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces ascomycinicus sp. nov., Streptomyces decoyicus sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces milbemycinicus sp. nov. and Streptomyces wellingtoniae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>769</fpage><lpage>775</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012161-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656929</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces ascomycinicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces ascomycinicus</em> (as.co.my.ci′ni.cus. N.L. n. <em>ascomycinum</em> ascomycin, an antibiotic; L. masc. suffix -<em>icus</em> adjectival suffix used with various meanings; N.L. masc. adj. <em>ascomycinicus</em> related to ascomycin, referring to the ability of the organism to produce ascomycin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from this and from a previous study (Hütter, 1967).</s><s>Rough spores with spiny surfaces are borne in loops (0.5–0.7×0.5–1.2 μm) with two to three turns.</s><s>Grows well on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are degraded.</s><s>Does not use methanol or propanol as a sole carbon source (at 1 %, v/v).</s><s><em>α</em>-Alanine and d-glycine are used as sole nitrogen sources for energy and growth (at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Sensitive to cephaloridine hydrochloride (32 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chlortetracycline hydrochloride (64 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin, gentamicin sulphate, kanamycin sulphate, lincomycin hydrochloride, neomycin sulphate and novobiocin (4 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and to doxycycline hydrochloride, oleandomycin phosphate, rifampicin, streptomycin sulphate, tetracycline hydrochloride and tobramycin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are mentioned in the text or in Table 1.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 70.2 mol%.</s><s>Produces ascomycin, which has an immunosuppressant action.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSM 40822<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 13981<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil collected in Sannomiya, Kobe City, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>