<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10089_nm.15040" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15040" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15040" rank="species">Lactobacillus similis</organism><reference id="rid.10089"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kitahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus similis sp. nov., isolated from fermented cane molasses</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011551-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648343</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus similis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus similis</em> (si′mi.lis. L. masc. adj. <em>similis</em> similar, resembling, as the type strain is similar to those of <em>L. collinoides</em> and <em>L. paracollinoides</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells cultivated on MRS agar plates are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods.</s><s>Cells are 0.5 μm in width and variable in length, mostly ranging between 2 and 5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, disc-shaped and white when grown on MRS agar plates at 37 °C for 2 days.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at 15 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, produces gas from glucose, and produces d- and l-lactic acids heterofermentatively.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, acid is produced from l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, lactose, melibiose and gluconate.</s><s>Variable reactions with raffinose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α-</em>galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative reactions for alkaline phosphatase, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α-</em>mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content of strain JCM 2765<sup>T</sup> is 48.5 %.</s><s>The type strain is JCM 2765<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23904<sup>T</sup>), isolated from fermented cane molasses at alcohol plants in Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>