<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12507_nm.21349" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21349" rank="genus">Gibbsiella</organism><reference id="rid.12507"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirk</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Palenzuela</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Gibbsiella quercinecans gen. nov., sp. nov., associated with Acute Oak Decline</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>444</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.08.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21115313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gibbsiella</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0095"&#x003E;<em>Gibbsiella</em> (Gibb.si’el.la. N.L. fem. n. <em>Gibbsiella</em> named in honour of British forest pathologist John N. Gibbs for his contributions to forest pathology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0100"&#x003E;Gram-negative short rods (0.9 × 1–1.5 μm), facultatively anaerobic, oxidase negative and catalase positive.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or in groups of four, and possess very fine fimbriae (<a href="#sec0060">Supplementary Fig. S2</a>) but no flagella.</s><s>Colonies are white to cream on nutrient agar, round, convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Strains can grow at temperatures between 10 and 40 °C.</s><s>Positive for β-galactosidase activity but negative for H<sub>2</sub>S, urease, indole, acetoin and gelatinase production.</s><s>Citrate is utilized and nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activity are all negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from: glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, α-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, arbutin, aesculin, ferric citrate, salicin, d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-saccharose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, d-turanose and d-arabitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, inositol, α-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, β-methyl-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid mono-methyl ester, acetic acid, citric acid, d-gluconic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, d,l-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-aspartic acid, glycerol and α-d-glucose-1-phosphate.</s><s>The G + C content ranges from 56.0 to 56.4 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>G. quercinecans</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>