<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1983_nm.10609" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10609" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10609" rank="species">Bacillus decisifrondis</organism><reference id="rid.1983"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus decisifrondis sp. nov., isolated from soil underlying decaying leaf foliage.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>974</fpage><lpage>978</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64440-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473244</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus decisifrondis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus decisifrondis</em> (de.ci.si.fron′dis. L. part. adj. <em>decisus</em> thrown off, dead, died; L. n. <em>frons</em> <em>frondis</em> of/from foliage; N.L. gen. n. <em>decisifrondis</em> from thrown off decayed foliage).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell size is 0.8–1.6 μm×2.6–4.8 μm.</s><s>Electron microscopy of the type strain reveals the presence of peritrichous flagella, round spores, inclusion bodies and a rough outer wall surface.</s><s>Growth is strictly aerobic and occurs at temperatures between 25 and 40 °C (optimum temperature, 30 °C) and at pH values of 7.1 to 9.1 (optimum pH, 8.4).</s><s>Able to metabolize the following in GN2 Biolog plates: pyruvic acid methyl ester, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-proline, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glycerol, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, turanose, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine and 2-aminoethanol.</s><s>Does not metabolize the following in GN2 Biolog plates: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein but not starch and produces catalase but not oxidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41±1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, E5HC-32<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13601<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17725<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil underlying the decaying leaf litter of slash pine forest in south east Queensland, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>