<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3369_nm.4799" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4799" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4799" rank="species">Spiroplasma mirum</organism><reference id="rid.3369"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spiroplasma mirum, a new species from the rabbit tick (Haemaphysalis leporispalustris.)</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>92</fpage><lpage>100</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-92</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spiroplasma mirum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spiroplasma mirum</i> (L. adj. <i>mirus</i> extraordinary)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological and cultural properties.</s><s>In SP-4 broth, or in fluids of infected eggs, organisms of the SMCA group examined by dark-field microscopy were seen as helical filaments 3 to 8 μm long and 0.1 to 0.2 μm in diameter.</s><s>In rapidly growing cultures in the logarithmic phase of growth, a predominance of short helical filaments was noted.</s><s>However, in the stationary phase of growth, or in suboptimal media, the organisms became spheroidal.</s><s>Flexing and twitching of the cells was frequently observed in broth cultures containing helical forms, and some cells exhibited apparent rotatory motility.</s><s>Negatively stained preparations of the organisms not only showed similar structural features but also revealed that one end of the helix was more pointed than the other.</s><s>Neither negatively stained nor sectioned organisms showed periplasmic fibrils or any evidence of cell wall material (37, 38).</s><s>Instead, thin sections showed only a typical unit membrane without evidence of a surrounding envelope.</s><s>Examination of negatively stained preparations of organisms revealed that some cells carried spiroplasma viruses.</s><s>Members of the group have been found to be infected with both the C1 and C3 virus groups (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Primary isolation of the organisms was best achieved in SP-4 medium.</s><s>This formulation, which has also proved useful for primary isolation of other mycoplasmas (33, probably owes its efficacy to the tissue culture supplement (CMRL 1066) incorporated into the medium.</s><s>Omission of the CMRL 1066 component in SP-4 broth, for example, blocked isolation in all of 25 primary isolation attempts in which 0.2 ml of infected allantoic fluids was added to 1.8 ml of incomplete broth.</s><s>In contrast, all 25 specimens of infected egg fluids added to complete SP-4 medium yielded helical forms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Primary isolates of the organism were first evidenced by the appearance of a light turbidity and the presence of short helical filaments in the cultures.</s><s>The organisms were frequently not perfectly helical in early passages, often appearing long and thin or distorted in various ways.</s><s>Primary cultures and early passages were slow to acidify the SP-4 medium.</s><s>Long after growth (in the form of helical filaments) was evident, gradual acidification of the cultures occurred.</s><s>Eventually, the pH of the cultures decreased to about 5.6 but never reached the low pH typically observed in liquid media supporting the growth of most other spiroplasmas.</s><s>All three strains in this group grew in the M1A medium but only after prior adaptation to SP-4 medium.</s><s>SMCA in infected allantoic fluids could not be grown directly in M1A broth medium or in the sorbitol medium used for primary isolation of <i>S. citri</i> (29,35b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although strains of this group formed colonies on SP-4 medium containing 0.8% Noble agar, the colonies were often diffuse and rarely, if ever, resembled the classical umbonate colonies characteristic of most mycoplasmas.</s><s>Colonies on this “soft” agar appeared only after 10 to 14 days of incubation at 30°C in an anaerobic environment (GasPak, BBL Microbiology Systems).</s><s>When 2.25% Noble agar (“hard” agar) was added to either SP-4 or M1A formulations, SMCA colonies were smaller but diffuse.</s><s>Agar plates prepared by substituting 5% bovine serum fraction for the fetal bovine serum in either SP-4 or M1A “hard” agar also yielded colonies after inoculation with SMCA, GT-48, or TP-2 strains.</s><s>Although most colonies on these formulations exhibited a dense core (Fig. lA), the amount of peripheral growth around the core varied considerably, and numerous satellite colonies were observed around the central zone (Fig. 1B).</s><s>The satellite growth suggested that some spiroplasma cells had migrated through the agar from the primary site of growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature requirements for growth.</s><s>The SMCA strain grew readily in SP-4 broth at temperatures between 25 and 37°C and achieved a growth yield of at least lo9 CCU/ml at each temperature (Table 1).</s><s>At 20°C, a growth yield of 10<sup>9</sup> CCU/ml was achieved, but only after incubation for 7 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reversion studies.</s><s>Cultures of the SMCA, GT-48, and TP-2 strains that were maintained in antibiotic-free broth medium for at least five passages did not revert to bacterial forms.</s><s>Cultures examined by dark-field microscopy were characterized by typical helical organisms, with no evidence of walled forms.</s><s>Also, colonies failed to develop when platings were made on 5% sheep blood agar plates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration studies.</s><s>A cloned broth culture of the SMCA strain contained 10<sup>8.5</sup> CCU/ml before filtration through a series of graded membrane filters.</s><s>The numbers of CCU/per milliliter after filtration through membrane filters with average pore diameters of 450, 300, and 220 nm were 10<sup>8.5</sup>, 10<sup>6.5</sup>, and 10<sup>2.5</sup>, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and biological properties.</s><s>Biochemical reactions of the SMCA and TP-2 isolates are summarized in Tables 2 and 3.</s><s>Both strains fermented glucose, but variable fermentation patterns were observed with glycerol, sucrose, trehalose, fructose, and mannose.</s><s>Other carbohydrates tested gave negative reactions.</s><s>Arginine hydrolysis was demonstrated for both SMCA and TP-2 strains, regardless of whether glucose was included in the test medium.</s><s>However, neither fermentation of carbohydrates nor hydrolysis of arginine occurred in M1B medium from which the defined amino acid fraction had been deleted.</s><s>The SMCA and TP-2 strains did not hydrolyze urea.</s><s>Other biological characteristics of these two strains are summarized in Table 4.</s><s>Most notable characteristics are the production of film and spot responses and susceptibility to digitonin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>The results of the modified sterol test are presented in Table 5.</s><s>As noted earlier, the base medium contained a small amount of cholesterol, but significant growth of the SMCA strain was not observed in this serum-free formulation.</s><s>However, increased growth was apparent in medium supplemented with albumin, palmitic acid, and Tween 80.</s><s>It should be noted, however, that the enhanced growth of the SMCA strain observed in this formulation could not be sustained for more than two consecutive passages.</s><s>The addition of 1 μg of cholesterol per ml to the base medium containing fatty acid supplements provided the most significant growth stimulation of the SMCA organism.</s><s>Additional amounts of cholesterol were clearly inhibitory.</s><s>As expected, good growth of the SMCA strain was observed in base medium supplemented with various quantities of fetal bovine serum.</s><s>These results suggest that the SMCA strain could be maintained well on SP-4 medium containing only 1 to 5% fetal bovine serum rather than the usual amount (17%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological tests.</s><s>Sera prepared against SMCA and TP-2 isolates gave zones of growth inhibition ranging from 9 to 18 mm in reciprocal tests (Table 6).</s><s>No growth inhibition was observed in reciprocal tests of the SMCA and TP-2 isolates with any strain representing an established spiroplasma serogroup, including Maroc (=R8A2), the type strain of <i>S. citri</i>.</s><s>Antiserum prepared against the Drosophila sex ratio organism also failed to inhibit the growth of either SMCA or TP-2.</s><s>In previously published work, strains in the SMCA group have also been compared with other established spiroplasma serogroups by both the deformation and metabolism- inhibition tests, and the results confirm the serological distinctiveness of the SMCA group (34, 41, 43).</s><s>Although the serological tests reported here did not include the GT-48 strain, previously reported studies have shown that this strain is closely related to SMCA (38).</s><s>Other published serological tests also support the placement of the SMCA, GT-48, and TP-2 isolates in the genus <i>Spiroplasma</i> and confirm their identity as strains of a new species.</s><s>Complement fixation and precipitin ring tests established the existence of a low-order cross-reaction between antigens in extracts of SMCA and <i>S. citri</i> (37,38).</s><s>Enzyme-linked immunosorbent tests have also confirmed the unique serological position of SMCA in relation to other serogroups (2, 34).</s><s>Thus, available data strongly suggest that the isolates of the SMCA cluster represent a serogroup that is completely distinct from all strains of the <i>S. cirri</i> complex and from other serotypes that may represent putative <i>Spiroplasma</i> species.</s></p></content></protolog>