<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12752_nm.22535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9818" rank="subspecies">Mycobacterium abscessus bolletii</organism><reference id="rid.12752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leao</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Euzéby</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal that Mycobacterium massiliense and Mycobacterium bolletii be united and reclassified as Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. bolletii comb. nov., designation of Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. abscessus subsp. nov. and emended description of Mycobacterium abscessus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2311</fpage><lpage>2313</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023770-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21037035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> (Adékambi <em>et al.</em> 2006a) Leao, Tortoli and Garcia, comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> (bol.le′ti.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>bolletii</em> of Bollet, to honour Claude Bollet, a famous clinical microbiologist and taxonomist).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Mycobacterium bolletii</em> Adékambi <em>et al.</em> 2006a.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on that given for <em>Mycobacterium bolletii</em> by Adékambi <em>et al.</em> (2006a), with the addition of the description given by Adékambi <em>et al.</em> (2006b) for <em>Mycobacterium massiliense</em>.</s><s>As demonstrated by Leao <em>et al.</em> (2009), the characterization of a wide set of isolates clearly showed further within-subspecies variability in this subspecies.</s><s>Thus, the phenotypic characteristics of this subspecies show variation between strains in relation to the characteristics indicated in the first description given by Adékambi <em>et al.</em> (2006a).</s><s>For example, several strains are able to grow in 5 % (w/v) NaCl and others reveal a positive result for urease.</s><s>The variability is even stronger when comparing antimicrobial susceptibility: several strains are susceptible to clarithromycin, in contrast to the resistance described in the initial report.</s><s>It is important to mention that discrepancies in susceptibility tests could be also ascribed to the method used. <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> has the properties given in the emended description of <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em>.</s><s>Additional features that distinguish this subspecies are the PRA-<em>hsp65</em> pattern and the <em>rpoB</em> and <em>hsp65</em> gene sequence differences.</s><s>The PRA-<em>hsp65</em> pattern that characterizes <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> is <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> type 2.</s><s>The trait of 711 bp of the <em>rpoB</em> and the trait of 401 bp of the <em>hsp65</em> nucleotide sequences from <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> show up to 95.6 and 98.5 % similarity, respectively, to <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em>.</s><s>This subspecies includes strains of the species <em>Mycobacterium</em> <em>massiliense</em> described previously (Adékambi <em>et al.</em>, 2004, 2006b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BD<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 50184<sup>T</sup>  = CIP 108541<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 15297<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>