<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1996_nm.10782" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10782" rank="species">Hydrogenophaga caeni</organism><reference id="rid.1996"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenophaga caeni sp. nov., isolated from activated sludge</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1126</fpage><lpage>1130</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64629-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473270</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hydrogenophaga caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hydrogenophaga caeni</em> (ca.e′ni. L. gen. n. <em>caeni</em> of mud, referring to isolation of the type strain from activated sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on R2A agar are white, glistening, translucent, raised and circular with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs optimally at 30 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>On R2A agar at 30 °C, cells are Gram-negative rods (0.8–1.2 μm wide and 1.4–2.0 μm long).</s><s>Motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrogen gas is not produced.</s><s>Thiosulfate is oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>No aerobic chemoautotrophic growth occurs with hydrogen as a substrate.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is observed.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed.</s><s>Tyrosine, aesculin, casein, Tween 20, starch, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-raffinose and <em>myo</em>-inositol, but not from d-lactose, d-mannitol, melibiose, d-glucose, sorbitol, sucrose, rhamnose, amygdalin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-arabinose, arbutin or salicin.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase is produced, but esterase (C4), lipase (C14), acid phosphatase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not produced.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for alkaline phosphatase and esterase lipase (C8).</s><s>The following are utilized (Biolog GN2): Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>Cells contain a large amount of phosphatidylethanolamine and a small amount of diphosphatidylglycerol as the polar lipids.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (27.51 %) and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, 44.77 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.6 mol % (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EMB71<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12613<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17962<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge used for enhanced biological phosphorus removal in a laboratory-scale sequencing batch reactor.</s></p></content></protolog>