<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5911_nm.10099" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10099" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10099" rank="species">Ancylobacter vacuolatus</organism><reference id="rid.5911"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ancylobacter polymorphus sp. nov. and Ancylobacter vacuolatus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1185</fpage><lpage>1188</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64118-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738088</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ancylobacter vacuolatus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ancylobacter vacuolatus</em> (va.cu.o.la′tus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>vacuolatus</em> vacuolate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characters of type strain were originally reported by Nikitin (1971).</s><s>Gram-negative, curved rods, 0.8–1.0 μm in diameter, non-motile, with a capsule and gas vesicles.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, round, entire and 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation on nutrient broth agar plates.</s><s>Can produce pellicles when growing in liquid medium.</s><s>Produces poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Fixes free nitrogen while growing on Döbereiner nitrogen-free medium.</s><s>No growth at 4 or 37 °C or at pH 5.5 or 11.0.</s><s>Optimum growth at 28–30 °C and at pH 7.0.</s><s>Grows in 0–2.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-, catalase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Negative for DNase, phenylalanine deaminase, lipase (Tween 80) and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S or indole.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrates.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin but not starch.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: maltose, l-arabinose, fructose, glycerol, mannitol, sorbitol, starch, adonitol, ribose, mannose, aesculin, amygdalin, sodium gluconate, ketoglutaric acid, alanine, proline, fumaric acid, arginine, sodium acetate, sodium malonate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sodium propionate, sodium lactate, sodium malate and methanol.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates weakly as carbon and energy sources: cellobiose, galactose, glucose, xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, melezitose, sodium formate and salicin.</s><s>Does not utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: rhamnose, dextrin, lactose, inulin, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, sorbose, melibiose, dulcitol, inositol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, sodium tartrate, sodium hippurate and sodium pyruvate.</s><s>Forms acid but no gas from mannose, ribose, glycerol, mannitol, inulin, sorbitol, galactose, cellobiose, rhamnose, salicin, glucose, arabinose, xylose, melibiose, adonitol, fructose and lactose.</s><s>Does not form acid or gas from inositol, raffinose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, maltose, sorbose, trehalose, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol or dextrin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 1277<sup>T</sup> (=AS 1.2807<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil in Russia, previously described as ‘<em>Renobacter vacuolatum</em>’ (Nikitin, 1971).</s></p></content></protolog>