<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4739_nm.9161" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9161" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2502" rank="species">Volcaniella eurihalina</organism><reference id="rid.4739"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valderrama</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bejar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutierrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruiz-Berraquero</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Volcaniella eurihalina gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic nonmotile Gram-negative rod.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>267</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-261</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Volcaniella eurihalina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Volcaniella eurihalina</i> (eu.ri.ha.li‘na. Gr. adj. <i>euris</i>, wide, broad; Gr. adj. <i>halinos</i>, salted; M. L. adj. <i>eurihalina</i>, growing in the presence of a wide range of salt concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are as described above for the genus.</s><s>Colonies on MH medium containing 7.5% (wt/vol) salts are circular, convex, smooth, slightly opaque, and cream with entire margins.</s><s>They are 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 20 h and 4 to 5 mm in diameter and remarkably mucoid after 72 h at 32°C.</s><s>In liquid cultures they grow uniformly.</s><s>The type strain shows a specific requirement for Na<sup>+</sup> cations; sodium can be supplied as NaCl, Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, or NaBr.</s><s>All strains are capable of growth on KCN and reduce nitrate to nitrite but not to gas.</s><s>They hydrolyze tyrosine, gelatin, and urea, grow on MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar, and reduce selenite.</s><s>No strain produces acid from carbohydrates, forms pyocyanine (or fluoresces) or indole, is methyl red or Voges-Prokauer positive, hydrolyzes starch, casein, blood, or lecithovitellin, or oxidizes gluconate.</s><s>Strains are not capable of respiration on nitrate, nitrite, or fumarate.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), colistin (50 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampin (5 μg), sulfonamide (200 μg), and sulfonamide (23.75 μg)-trimethoprim (1.25 μg), and all strains are resistant to ampicillin (100 μg), clindamycin (2 IU), penicillin G (10 IU), streptomycin (10 μg), and tetracycline (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most of the strains utilize a great diversity of organic compounds as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>These include carbohydrates, organic acids, polyols, and amino acids.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized by at least 80% of the strains: L-arabinose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-salicin, acetate, citrate, D-gluconate, DL-lactate, DL-malate, malonate, pyruvate, β-hydroxybutyrate, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-ornithine, and L-serine.</s><s>At least 80% of the strains cannot use esculin, L-sorbose, benzoate, oxalate, starch, D-tartrate, or L-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Eighty percent or more of the strains give positive results for the following tests: H<sub>2</sub>S and phosphatase production, Tween 20 hydrolysis, esculin hydrolysis, and growth at a total salt concentration of 3% (wt/vol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Eighty percent or more of the strains give negative results for the following tests: phenylalanine deaminase and susceptibility to amikacin (30 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), and gentamicin (10 IU).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains were isolated from hypersaline habitats (soils, salt ponds) and from seawater and have DNA G+C contents ranging from 59.1 to 65.7 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>The type strain is strain F9-6 (= ATCC 49336), which has a DNA G+C content of 65.7 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>This strain has all of the characteristics described above for the type species, including those for which 80% or more of strains are positive or negative.</s><s>It was isolated from hypersaline soil located near Alicante in southern Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>