<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1400_nm.7700" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7700" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7700" rank="species">Bifidobacterium merycicum</organism><reference id="rid.1400"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mattarelli</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium ruminantium sp. nov. and Bifidobacterium merycicum sp. nov. from the rumens of cattle.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-163</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1995032</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium merycicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium merycicum</i> (me.ry´ci.cum. Gr, n. <i>meryx</i> [implied by verb <i>merykazo</i>], rumen; N. L. adj. <i>merycicum</i>, pertaining to the rumen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, irregularly shaped rods that are 2.0 to 5.0 μm long and are sometimes arranged in pairs which form angles (Fig. 1 through 8).</s><s>Surface colonies on Trypticase-Phytone-yeast extract agar are soft, smooth, convex, circular with entire margins, cream to white, and glistening (Fig. 13).</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Carbon dioxide has no effect upon oxygen sensitivity, but it enhances anaerobic growth.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 38 to 42°C.</s><s>No growth occurs below 25°C or at 45°C and above.</s><s>The optimum initial pH is 6.5 to 6.9.</s><s>Growth is delayed at pH 6.3 or 7.2.</s><s>No growth occurs at pH 4.5 or 8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arabinose, raffinose, sucrose, glucose, xylose, melibiose, maltose, lactose, starch, galactose, dextrin, and ribose are fermented.</s><s>Mannitol, mannose, melezitose, sorbitol, trehalose, glycerin, rhamnose, gluconate, and lactate are not fermented.</s><s>Salicin and inulin are not fermented or, occasionally, are fermented slowly.</s><s>Fructose is weakly fermented.</s><s>Cellobiose fermentation is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The molar ratio of lactic acid to acetic acid from the fermentation of glucose ranges from 1:2 to 1:5.</s><s>No gas, propionic acid, or butyric acid is produced.</s><s>Catalase or pseudocatalase (hemin) is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 mol% (strains Ru769, Ru915B<sup>T</sup>, and Ru919) or 60 mol% (strain Ru767) (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The DNA of this species exhibits little or no relatedness to the DNA of any other <i>Bifidobacterium</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Ru915B (= ATCC 49391), which was isolated from bovine rumen.</s></p></content></protolog>