<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6904_nm.463" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.463" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.463" rank="species">Thermotoga lettingae</organism><reference id="rid.6904"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Balk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weijma</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stams</surname><given-names>A.J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermotoga lettingae sp. nov., a novel thermophilic, methanol-degrading bacterium isolated from a thermophilic anaerobic reactor.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1361</fpage><lpage>1368</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02165-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148651</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermotoga lettingae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermotoga lettingae</i> (let'tin.gae. N.L. gen. n. <i>lettingae</i> of Lettinga, named after Gatze Lettinga, a Dutch biotechnologist, in recognition of his pioneering work on anaerobic methanol conversion in methanogenic bioreactors)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-negative rods 2-3 μm long x 0.5-1 μm wide.</s><s>Each rod is surrounded by a sheath-like structure, ballooning over the ends.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or, rarely, in chains comprising a maximum of four rods.</s><s>The rods tend to become large spheres in the stationary phase.</s><s>Motile, strictly anaerobic, thermophilic.</s><s>Growth occurs between 50 and 75°C, the optimum being at 65°C; between pH 6.0 and pH 8.5, the optimum being at pH 7.0; and at NaCl concentrations between 0 and 28 g l<sup>-1</sup>, the optimum being at 10 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The doubling time at optimum temperature and salinity at pH 7.0 is 4 h.</s><s>Growth is possible on complex substrates such as yeast extract, peptone, gelatin, biotrypticase or Casamino acids.</s><s>Uses thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, Fe(III) and anthraquinone-2,6-disulfonate, but not sulfate, sulfite, nitrate or cystine, as electron acceptors.</s><s>Grows on methanol, lactate, pyruvate, glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, xylose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, arabinose, ribose, cellobiose, rhamnose, glycerol, pectin, methylamines, starch, xylan, 2-oxoglutarate and serine.</s><s>In the presence of thiosulfate or a methanogen, it can grow on acetate, betaine, leucine, isoleucine and valine.</s><s>In the presence of thiosulfate, it grows on formate and H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> but not on choline, benzoate, mannitol, butanol, isobutanol, 2,3-butandiol, propanol, butyrate or succinate.</s><s>Methanol degradation occurs in syntrophic culture with <i>Methanothermobacter thermautotrophicus</i> ΔH or <i>Thermodesulfovibrio yellowstonii</i>.</s><s>Thiosulfate enhances the growth rate and substrate conversion.</s><s>Isolated from an anaerobic bioreactor.</s><s>The type strain is TMO<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 14385<sup>T</sup> and in the ATCC culture collection as BAA-301<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>