<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4174_nm.2893" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2893" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2893" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas mariniglutinosa</organism><reference id="rid.4174"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhukova</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of 'Alteromonas marinoglutinosa' NCIMB 1770 to Pseudoalteromonas mariniglutinosa sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1105</fpage><lpage>1109</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02564-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892134</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoalteromonas mariniglutinosa</em> sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoalteromonas mariniglutinosa</em> (ma.ri.ni.glu.ti.no′sa. L. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea; L. adj. <em>glutinosa</em> glutinous, slimy; N.L. fem. adj. <em>mariniglutinosa</em> from the sea, forming glutinous, slimy colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, rod-shaped cells, 0·6–0·8 μm in diameter and 1·7–2·0 μm in length, motile by a single, polar, unsheathed flagellum.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> is essential for growth; growth is observed in 1–9 % NaCl.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph.</s><s>Grows at 5–37 °C with optimal growth at 20–28 °C; no growth at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>On complex marine media, smooth, convex, slimy, non-pigmented, whitish or translucent colonies that are depressed into the agar are formed.</s><s>In addition to the phenotypic characters indicated in Table 1, the type strain exhibits the following reactions: acid is produced from sucrose, maltose, l-arabinose and d-mannitol by using Leifson's method; acid is not produced from glucose, lactose, mannose, d-galactose, d-xylose, melibiose, rhamnose or glycerol.</s><s>l-Malate, citrate, propionate and l-serine are utilized, whereas caprate and butyrate are not.</s><s>DNase activity is positive.</s><s>According to the API 20 NE panel, the following tests are positive: aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis, assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose (weakly), mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, malate and citrate.</s><s>The following tests are negative: nitrate reduction, indole production, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-d-galactopyranoside (PNPG) test, gluconate, caprate, adipate and phenylacetate assimilation.</s><s>In API ZYM analysis, strain NCIMB 1770<sup>T</sup> exhibits positive reactions for alkaline phosphatase, esterase-lipase C8 (weakly), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>As shown by Biolog GN MicroPlate tests, the type strain utilizes <em>α</em>-cyclodextran, dextran, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methylpyruvate, mono-methylsuccinate, acetic acid, citric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline (weak) and l-serine.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for utilization of the other organic compounds included in Biolog GN MicroPlate tests.</s><s>Susceptible to streptomycin, polymyxin, gentamicin (weakly), kanamycin, carbenicillin and neomycin, but resistant to ampicillin, oleandomycin, lincomycin, benzylpenicillin, O/129, oxacillin and tetracycline.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>.</s><s>Phospholipids include phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol as main components and diphosphatidylglycerol and <em>bis</em>-phosphatidic acid as minor components.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 40·3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NCIMB 1770<sup>T</sup> (=KMM 3635<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the diatom <em>Chaetoceros lauderi</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>