<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1147_nm.11045" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11045" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5238" rank="species">Staphylococcus carnosus</organism><reference id="rid.1147"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of a new species of the genus Staphylococcus: Staphylococcus carnosus.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>153</fpage><lpage>156</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-2-153</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus curnosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(car.nó sus. L. adj. <i>carnosus</i> pertaining to flesh).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cocci, 0.5 to 1.5 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in pairs and singly.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Colonies were slightly raised, circular, smooth, slightly glistening, and usually gray-white and ranged from about 1 to 3 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grew facultatively anaerobically and produced, under anaerobic growth conditions, equal amounts of D- and L-lactate from glucose.</s><s>The pH of a peptone-yeast extractglucose broth was lowered from 6.8 to 4.2 after 2 days of growth under anaerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grew well at 15 and 45°C and at NaCl concentrations up to 15%.</s><s>All strains reduced nitrate and produced acetoin.</s><s>All failed to produce coagulase and to exhibit hemolysin activity.</s><s>All were negative for the oxidase test and resistant to 50 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Their growth was inhibited by 200 μg of lysostaphin or 1.6 μg of novobiocin per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produced acid aerobically from glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, and glycerol.</s><s>All failed to produce acid from xylose, sucrose, maltose, xylitol, rhamnose, turanose, raffinose, fucose, and melibiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Variable characters of the strains are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The peptidoglycan types of the strains were studied, and all were determined to be L-Lys-Gly<sub>5-6</sub>.</s><s>This type of peptidoglycan was previously found in <i>S. aureus</i>, <i>S. cohnii</i>, <i>S. simulans</i>, and <i>S. xylosus</i>.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of five strains were determined and were found to vary between 35 and 36 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization studies indicated that the strains of <i>S. carnosus</i> are closely related to one another at the species level.</s><s>The DNA homology values with other staphylococci, with the exception of <i>S. simulans</i>, were rather low (10 to 20%) but were significantly higher than the values between the staphylococci and an unrelated gram-positive bacterium of low G+C content, namely, <i>Lactobacillus gasseri</i> DSM 20243.</s><s>The DNA homology values (32 to 39%) between the type strain of <i>S. simulans</i>, ATCC 27848, and the strains of <i>S. carnosus</i> are higher than those between ATCC 27848 and the other staphylococci.</s><s>This indicates that <i>S. carnosus</i> and <i>S. simulans</i> are closely related to each other but not closely enough to justify their union in one species.</s><s>In particular, DNA-DNA homology studies under stringent conditions clearly demonstrated that  <i>S. simulans</i> and <i>S. carnosus</i> belong to separate species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characters for the differentiation of <i>S. carnosus</i>from other staphylococci are listed in Table 4. <i>S. carnosus</i> can be distinguished from all other staphylococci primarily on the bases of its ability to produce acetoin, to reduce nitrate, and to grow on 15% NaCl and of its failure to produce acid from maltose and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain DSM 20501 (originally designated no. 361) is the type of strain of <i>S. carnosus</i>.</s><s>A description of this strain follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spheres, about 1 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in pairs and singly.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile and nonsporeforming.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract-glucose-NaCl-agar were circular, entire, about 1.0 to 2.5 mm in diameter, slightly convex, smooth with glossy surface, white, and opaque.</s><s>Older colonies (16 days) showed a brownish pigment in their centers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic: Metabolism was respiratory and fermentative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and benzidine tests were positive.</s><s>Coagulase negative.</s><s>Bovine or sheep blood was not hemolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature relationships: Growth occurred at 15 and 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on NaCl-agar: Growth occurred with 10 and 15% NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate was reduced.</s><s>Acetoin was produced.</s><s>Acid was produced aerobically from glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, ribose, trehalose, mannitol, and glycerol.</s><s>No acid from xylose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, xylitol, rhamnose, turanose, raffinose, fucose, or melibiose.</s><s>Susceptible to lysostaphin (100 μg/ml) and novobiocin (1.6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fructose-1,6-biphosphate aldolase: class I.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type: L-Lys-Gly<sub>5-6</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell-wall teichoic acid composition: Glycerol, glucose, galactosamine, and traces of glucosamine were present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content of DNA: 36 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>