<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6727_nm.5189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5189" rank="species">Planococcus alkanoclasticus</organism><reference id="rid.6727"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Engelhardt</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daly</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swannell</surname><given-names>R.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Head</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a novel hydrocarbon-degrading, Gram-positive bacterium, isolated from intertidal beach sediment, and description of Planococcus alkanoclasticus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>90</volume><fpage>237</fpage><lpage>247</lpage><source id="178">Journal of Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1364-5072</issn><essn>1365-2672</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11168727</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planococcus alkanoclasticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planococcus alkanoclasticus</i> (al.kan.o.clas'ti.cus. M. L. part. adj. <i>alkanoclastic</i>, breaking down alkanes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods that are 0.4-0.8 μm wide and 1.7-2.6 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Grampositive, though Gram-stain reaction may be variable.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar or nutrient agar with 0.8% NaCl are orange pigmented.</s><s>Chemoorganotroph with respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin and produces DNase and phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce acid from glucose in Hugh and Leifson O-F medium.</s><s>Negative tests were obtained for the utilization of α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, N-acetyl-D-mannosamine, amygdalin, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, D-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, D-gluconic acid, α-D-glucose, <i>m</i>-inositol, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, α-methyl-D-galactoside, β-methyl-D-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-D-gluglucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, palatinose, D-psicose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, seduheptulosan, D-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, D-xylose, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, D-lactic acid methyl ester, L-lactic acid, D-malic acid, L-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, N-acetyl L-glutamic acid, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanyl-glycine, L-asparagine, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-pyroglutamic acid, L-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2'-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine-5'-monophosphate, thymidine-5'-monophosphate, uridine-5'-monophosphate, fructose-6-phosphate, glucose-1-phosphate, glucose-6-phosphate and D-L-α-glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Degrades linear and branched alkanes from C11 to C33.</s><s>Obligate requirement for NaCl but will not grow at NaCl concentrations of 6% or greater.</s><s>Range of temperature for growth is 15-41°C.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are branched iso and anteiso fatty acids with a15:0 being the predominant cellular fatty acid.</s><s>The mol % G + C of the DNA of the type strain is 45.3±0.4% (HPLC, n=4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Type strain is <i>Planococcus alkanoclasticus</i> strain MAE2 (NCIMB 13489<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>