<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7197_nm.6767" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6767" rank="genus">Streptoalloteichus</organism><reference id="rid.7197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tomita</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakakita</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Numata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawaguchi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>New genus of the Actinomycetales: Streptoalloteichus hindustanus gen. nov., nom. rev.; sp. nov., nom rev.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>211</fpage><lpage>213</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptoalloteichus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Streptoalloteichus (Strep'to.al'lo.tei'chus. Gr. adj. <i>streptos</i>, bent, turned; Gr. adj. <i>allos</i>, different; Gr. n. <i>teichos</i>, wall; M.L. masc. n. <i>Streptoalloteichus</i>, streptomycete with different wall)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are aerobic, gram-positive, non-acid-fast , filamentous organisms that form from a mycelium differentiated into a substrate mycelium that penetrates the agar and forms a compact layer on top of the agar, and an aerial mycelium originating from the substrate mycelium.</s><s>The aerial mycelium forms chains of arthrospores at the hyphal tips and branched sporophores.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is not fragmented into short filaments or rods, and capriciously bears small sporangium-like vesicles enveloping one spore or a single row of two to four spores.</s><s>The spores have a single polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall is type III (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid of the wall peptidoglycan and lacking any characteristic sugars).</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern is a variant of type C (D-galactose, D-mannose, and Lrhamnose).</s><s>The phospholipids are type PII (phosphatidylethanolamine as nitrogenous phospholipid).</s><s>The menaquinones contain both MK-9 (H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10 (H<sub>6</sub>) as the major components.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Streptoalloteichus hindustanus</i>.</s><s>The type strain is C677-91<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 31217).</s></p></content></protolog>