<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7197_nm.6768" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6768" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6768" rank="species">Streptoalloteichus hindustanus</organism><reference id="rid.7197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tomita</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakakita</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Numata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawaguchi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>New genus of the Actinomycetales: Streptoalloteichus hindustanus gen. nov., nom. rev.; sp. nov., nom rev.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>211</fpage><lpage>213</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptoalloteichus hindustanus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptoalloteichus hindustanus</i> (hin'du.stan'us. L. adj. of Hindustan, northwest district of India)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Aerial mycelium.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is well-developed and branched, averaging 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Chains of spores are formed only at the tips of the aerial mycelium, either as long, open-coiled (10 to 50 spores in a chain), or short hooked branching spore chains.</s><s>Both types may be found in the same culture.</s><s>The arthrospores in the long chains are oval or cylindrical (0.5 to 2.0 μm in diameter), and the conidiospores in the short chains are mostly barrel shaped.</s><s>Both types of spores have a smooth surface.</s><s>A sclerotium may also be formed on the aerial mycelium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Substrate mycelium.</s><s>The substrate mycelium does not fragment, and occasionally coalesces into a thick rope.</s><s>Single oval or spherical sporangium-like vesicles enveloping one spore, or a single row of two to four spores, are capriciously formed among the vegetative hyphae.</s><s>The sporangia measure 1.5 to 4.5 by 2.7 to 7.0 μm, and the sporangiospores are 0.9 to 1.5 by 1.2 to 4.0 μm, oval or rod shaped with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Globose dense bodies, 3 to 20 μm in diameter, consisting of coalesced vegetative hyphae, are observed on the agar surface.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Chemotaxonomic analysis.</s><s>Purified cell walls of <i>S. hindustanus</i> contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, alanine and glutamic acid, as the wall peptidoglycan and lack any characteristic sugars.</s><s>The whole cell sugar pattern is a variant of type C (D-galactose, D-mannose, and L-rhamnose).</s><s>The phospholipids present are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol, and hence a type PI1 pattern.</s><s>Mass spectra show that the major menaquinones are MK9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK10(H<sub>6</sub>) in roughly equal amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Appearance on various media.</s><s>All agar slants were incubated at 28°C and observed after 21 days.</s><s>The color names were from the ISCC-NBC Centroid color charts (5).</s><s>The growth is good on yeast extract-malt extract agar, inorganic salts-starch agar and tyrosine agar.</s><s>On these agar media, a thick mass of white aerial mycelia are produced turning to pale yellow or pale pinkish yellow after sporulation, and the substrate mycelia are off-white to light yellowish brown.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>On peptone-yeast extract-iron agar, the growth and aerial mycelium formation is scant, and a brownish weakly diffusible pigment is produced in the substrate mycelium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) Physiological characteristics.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 54°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 56°C.</s><s>Melanin is not produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar and tyrosine agar, and the tyrosinase reaction is negative.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied, starch is hydrolyzed, and nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>No growth occurs on media supplemented with more than 7% NaCl.</s><s>D-Fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, maltose, and salicin are utilized, but L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, raffinose, inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, and inulin are not utilized for growth.</s><s>The utilization of sucrose and lactose is questionable.</s></p></content></protolog>