<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2857_nm.10917" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10917" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10917" rank="species">Paenibacillus fonticola</organism><reference id="rid.2857"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus fonticola sp. nov., isolated from a warm spring</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1346</fpage><lpage>1350</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64872-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus fonticola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus fonticola</em> (fon.ti.co′la. L. masc. n. <em>fons fontis</em> a spring, fountain; L. suf. -<em>cola</em> from L. masc. or fem. n. <em>incola</em> an inhabitant of a place, a resident; N.L. n. <em>fonticola</em> an inhabitant of a fountain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, Gram-variable, sporulating, motile, rod-shaped, 0.8–1.0 μm in diameter and 2.0–12.4 μm in length.</s><s>Grows at pH 7–10 and at 20–45 °C.</s><s>Positive (API 20NE and 20E) for catalase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, OPNG test, gelatinase and acid production from arabinose.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, tryptophan deaminase, acetoin production and acid production from glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose and amygdalin.</s><s>In API ZYM enzyme reactions, positive for C4 esterase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, C8 lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (positive in the Biolog GN2 system): dextrin, Tween 80, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon sources (negative in the Biolog GN2 system): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citrate, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconate, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactate, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin (10 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ZL<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17579<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23577<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected from Jhonglun warm spring, Chiayi County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>