<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.628_nm.8424" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8424" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8424" rank="species">Dictyoglomus thermophilum</organism><reference id="rid.628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saiki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawagoe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beppu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dictyoglomus thermophilum gen. nov., sp. nov., a chemoorganotrophic, anaerobic, thermophilic bacterium.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>259</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dictyoglomus thermophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dictyoglomus thermophilum</i> (ther. mo. phil' um; Gr. n. <i>thermus</i> heat; L. adj. <i>philum</i> loving; L. n. <i>thermophilum</i> heat loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods that are 0.4 to 0.6 μm wide by 5 to 20 μm long and occur singly, in pairs, in filaments, and in bundles.</s><s>Several to several dozen cells frequently form large spherical bodies up to 50 to 100 μm in diameter.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming, and nonmotile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic; does not grow in an aerobic atmosphere or in a medium in which the color has become light pink due to the oxidation of resazurin by a trace amount of air.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the late log phase of growth 30 to 50% of the cells are in large bodies (Fig. 1 and 2).</s><s>Cell aggregates in linear arrays consist of two to several cells and share an outer wall membrane.</s><s>There seem to be various intermediate forms during growth from single cells to large spherical bodies.</s><s>The cells may grow and duplicate inside the outer wall membrane.</s><s>Any excess outer wall membrane produced may be pinched off to form small empty spherical bodies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron microscopic observations indicate that the various types of spherical structures are composed of outer wall membrane.</s><s>Electron micrographs of ultrathin sections show that the cell surface structure is of the complex gram-negative type (Fig. 3).</s><s>Flagella are not present, Neither complex membranous structures such as mesosomes nor invaginations of the plasma membrane are observed.</s><s>The outer layer appears to be a definite membranous structure, no portion of which is connected with the underlying innermost layer.</s><s>Electron-dense materials are observed between the outer and inner membranes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large spherical bodies are formed by association of separate filamentous cells, which are surrounded by a membranous structure (Fig. 4d).</s><s>This membranous structure is composed of the outer wall membranes which have partially peeled away from the cell surfaces.</s><s>Figures 4A through C show examples in which two, three and several cells share an outer wall membrane.</s><s>These forms may be observed as bundles or immature spherical bodies under a light microscope (Fig. 1).</s><s>There is evidence from elecron micrograph sections (Fig. 5) that the large spherical bodies are actually three-dimensional structures of associated cells surrounded by an outer wall membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell division profile of strain H-6-12<sup>T</sup> resembles that of gram-negative bacteria, such as <i>Escherichia coli</i> or <i>Thermus aquaticus</i> (4).</s><s>Deep narrow invaginations of the cell envelope are formed (Fig. 6).</s><s>The cell envelope is tripartite (plasma membrane, thin middle layer, and an outer wall membrane).</s><s>The bundles and large spherical bodies consist of associated cells surrounded by an outer wall membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are uniformly round and nonpigmented and grow to a diameter of 2 to 4 mm in 3 to 5 days at 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature range for growth is 73 to 78°C, the maximum temperature is 8O°C, and the minimum temperature is 51°C.</s><s>The doubling time at 77°C in anaerobic culture tubes is about 3.6 h.</s><s>The doubling times at 73°C in anaerobic culture tubes and minijar fermentors are about 4.3 and 2.5 h (Fig. 7 and 8), respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum pH for growth is about 7; no growth is produced above pH 8.9 or below pH 5.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism does not grow in media lacking fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The carbohydrates used as energy sources include amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, fucose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, and insoluble starch of potato.</s><s>Cellulose, merythritol, glycerol, L-inositol, mannitol, pyruvate, rhamnose, sorbitol, xylitol, and insoluble starch from corn and wheat are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain H-6-12<sup>T</sup> ferments 0.5% soluble starch to produce 16 mM acetate, 3 mM lactate, about 12 mM CO<sub>2</sub>, and trace amounts of H<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A very heat stable α-amylase is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The methyl red test, indole production, and nitrate reduction are negative.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Catalase activity is not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is inhibited by 10 fμg of streptomycin per ml, 10 μg of tetracycline per ml, 100 μg of chloramphenicol per ml, 10 μg of neomycin per ml, 100 μg of vancomycin per ml, 100 μg of actinomycin D per ml, 10 μg of tunicamycin per ml, 2% sodium chloride, and 100 μg of sodium dodecyl sulfate per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are resistant to lysozyme and lysozyme plus ethylenediaminetetraacetate.</s><s>Incubation of cells in 50 mM tris (hydroxymethyl) aminomethane hydrochloride buffer (pH 7.6) containing 78 μg of lysozyme per ml and 1 mM ethylenediaminetetraacetate for 20 min at 37°C causes no decrease in absorbance at 550 nm of a cell suspension.</s><s>However, light microscope observations reveal the appearance of partial extrusions like protoplast structures from some long cells.</s><s>After incubation the cells are lysed by the addition of 1% sodium dodecyl sulfate, whereas the addition of the same concentration of sodium dodecyl sulfate does not lyse untreated cells.</s><s>The large spherical bodies are rapidly decomposed to separate filamentous cells by the addition of 0.1% sodium dodecyl sulfate, whereupon each cell become thinner.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from slightly alkaline hot springs (Tsuetate Hot Spring) in Kumamoto Prefecture, Japan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 29 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>HoloType strain: <i>Dictyoglomus thermophilum</i> H-6-12 (=ATCC 35947).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Brock and Edwards reported the production of similar outer wall membrane from cells to form the "empty bodies" observed in most cultures.</s></p></content></protolog>