<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3136_nm.12173" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12173" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3602" rank="species">Desulfocapsa sulfoexigens</organism><reference id="rid.3136"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thamdrup</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Elemental sulfur and thiosulfate disproportionation by Desulfocapsa sulfoexigens sp. nov., a new anaerobic bacterium isolated from marine surface sediment.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>125</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9435068</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfocapsa sulfoexigens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfocapsa sulfoexigens</i> (sul.fo.ex'i.gens. L. n. <i>sulfurum</i>, sulfur; L. v. <i>exigo</i>, to demand; M. L. part. adj. <i>sulfoexigens</i>, demanding sulfur for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative cells that are elongated with slightly pointed ends, 0.5 μm wide and 2 to 4 μm long.</s><s>Multiplication occurs by binary fission.</s><s>Under most conditions, only a few cells are motile.</s><s>Spores are not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in mineral medium without vitamins or organic carbon sources with bicarbonate as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Disproportionation of elemental sulfur, sulfite, and thiosulfate to sulfide and sulfate occurs.</s><s>Growth by sulfur disproportionation occurs only in the presence of a hydrogen sulfide-scavenging agent, like ferric iron.</s><s>Growth by disproportionation of thiosulfate occurs with and without iron.</s><s>No growth occurs by sulfate reduction.</s><s>The pH range is from 6.0 to 8.2 with an optimum of 6.7 to 7.3.</s><s>The temperature range is 4 to 35°C with an optimum of 30°C.</s><s>The habitat is oxidized marine surface sediment.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from marine sediment covered by the eelgrass, <i>Zostera noltii</i>, in the basin of Arcachon, France.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 47.2 ± 0.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain SB164P1, DSM 10523, deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>