<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1781_nm.9564" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9564" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9564" rank="species">Treponema porcinum</organism><reference id="rid.1781"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nordhoff</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taras</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macha</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tedin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wieler</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema berlinense sp. nov. and Treponema porcinum sp. nov., novel spirochaetes isolated from porcine faeces.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1675</fpage><lpage>1680</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63388-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014500</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Treponema porcinum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Treponema porcinum</em> (por.ci′num. L. neut. adj. <em>porcinum</em> pertaining to swine, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells exhibit typical spirochaete morphology and are approximately 6–8 μm in length and 0·3 μm in width with two to three windings.</s><s>Transmission electron microscopy reveals two periplasmic, subterminally inserted flagella.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Best growth is obtained in liquid OMIZ-Pat medium at 37 °C supplemented with 10 % (v/v) BHI and 10 % (v/v) TSYE.</s><s>Growth is independent of glucuronic or galacturonic acid.</s><s>d-Maltose is essential for growth, whereas no growth is observed in the presence of any of the following carbohydrates as the sole carbohydrate source: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-arabinose, l-fucose, d-trehalose, d-sucrose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>Does not grow with pectin as a sole carbon source.</s><s>On supplemented OMIZ-Pat (1·3 % w/v) agar supplemented with 5 % egg yolk, 10 % BHI and 10 % TSYE, the species forms small, greyish, irregular swarms up to 2 mm in diameter, visible after 3–4 days.</s><s>Positive enzyme reactions using the API ZYM and Rapid ID 32A system are obtained for acid phosphatase, esterase C4, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, whereas reactions for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase C8, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, mannose and raffinose fermentation, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase are negative.</s><s>Reduction of nitrates and indole production are not detected.</s><s>In the polar lipid profile, three unknown phospholipids and a highly hydrophobic compound predominate.</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol as well as phospholipids are present in moderate amounts.</s><s>Additionally, a glycolipid and several phospholipids are present in minor amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 14V28<sup>T</sup> (deposited as ATCC BAA-908<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108245<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12342<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from swine faeces in Berlin, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>