<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6131_nm.9325" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9325" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9325" rank="species">Streptococcus castoreus</organism><reference id="rid.6131"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Markopoulos</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus castoreus sp. nov., isolated from a beaver (Castor fiber).</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>843</fpage><lpage>846</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63433-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774672</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus castoreus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus castoreus</em> (cas.to′re.us. L. masc. adj. <em>castoreus</em> pertaining to a beaver, from which the bacterium was originally isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are cocci that occur in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, but grows best under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by rich medium and CO<sub>2</sub>, but is not obligately capnophilic.</s><s>No growth on MRS at 37 °C in air, but there is growth on MRS in CO<sub>2</sub> and in a microaerophilic atmosphere.</s><s>Growth on chocolate medium is superior to growth on blood agar.</s><s>Colonies are <em>β</em>-haemolytic and 0·5 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation on horse blood agar.</s><s>Produces a strong reaction in Oxoid Strep latex with Lancefield group A antisera.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Using API test kits, acid is produced from starch, maltose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, sorbitol, tagatose or trehalose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but hippurate is not.</s><s>Activity is detected for arginine dihydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phosphoamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase; activity for <em>β</em>-mannosidase is variable.</s><s>Activity is not detected for esterase C4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 37·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M605815/03/2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 48115<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108205<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a European beaver (<em>Castor fiber</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>