<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6814_nm.5023" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5023" rank="genus">Geobacillus</organism><reference id="rid.6814"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nazina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poltaraus</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Novikova</surname><given-names>E.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grigoryan</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petrunyaka</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osipov</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Belyaev</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanov</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of aerobic thermophilic bacilli: descriptions of Geobacillus subterraneus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Geobacillus uzenensis sp. nov. from petroleum reservoirs and transfer of Bacillus stearothermophilus, Bacillus thermocatenulatus, Bacillus thermoleovorans, Bacillus kaustophilus, Bacillus thermodenitrificans to Geobacillus as the new combinations G. stearothermophilus, G. th.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>433</fpage><lpage>446</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321089</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Geobacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Geobacillus</i> (Ge.o.ba.cil'lus. Gr. n. <i>Ge</i> the Earth; L. dim. n. <i>bacillus</i> small rod; M.L. masc. n. <i>Geobacillus</i> earth or soil bacillus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on our observations, as well as on previous descriptions of obligately thermophilic species of the group 5 bacilli (Claus &#x0026; Berkeley, 1986; Fahmy et al., 1985; Suzuki et al., 1983; Zarilla &#x0026; Perry, 1987; Priest et al., 1988; Golovacheva et al., 1975, White et al., 1993; Manachini et al., 2000).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rod-shaped and produce one endospore per cell.</s><s>Cells occur either singly or in short chains and are motile by means of peritrichous flagella or non-motile.</s><s>The cell wall structure is Gram-positive, but the Gram-stain reaction may vary between positive and negative.</s><s>Ellipsoidal or cylindrical endospores are located terminally or subterminally in slightly swollen or non-swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colony morphology and size are variable ; pigments may be produced on certain media.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophs.</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Oxygen is the terminal electron acceptor, replaceable in some species by nitrate.</s><s>Obligately thermophilic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 37 to 75°C, with an optimum at 55-65°C.</s><s>Neutrophilic.</s><s>Growth occurs in a pH range of 6.0 to 8.5, with an optimum at pH 6.2-7.5.</s><s>Growth factors, vitamins, NaCl and KCl are not required by most species.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose, fructose, maltose, mannose and sucrose.</s><s>Most species do not produce acid from lactose.</s><s>Most species form catalase.</s><s>Phenylalanine is not deaminated, tyrosine is not degraded, indole is not produced, the Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Oxidase-positive or negative.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-15:0, iso-16:0 and iso-17:0, which make up more than 60% of the total.</s><s>The main menaquinone type is MK-7.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 48.2-58 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The levels of 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity are higher than 96.5% for the members of this genus.</s><s>Most species are widely distributed in nature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Geobacillus stearothermophilus</i> (basonym <i>Bacillus stearothermophilus</i> Donk 1920); the type strain of this species is strain DSM 22<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>