<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8453_nm.13516" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13516" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13516" rank="species">Paenibacillus tarimensis</organism><reference id="rid.8453"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus tarimensis sp. nov., isolated from sand in Xinjiang, China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2081</fpage><lpage>2085</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65445-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus tarimensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus tarimensis</em> (ta.ri.men′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>tarimensis</em> referring to Tarim Basin, China, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic rods, 3.0–6.0 μm in length and 0.5–0.8 μm in width.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, opaque and ivory on TSA plates after 16 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–45 °C; optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Cells grow at pH 6.0–9.0; optimum pH is 7.5.</s><s>Growth is not observed at NaCl concentrations above 3 %.</s><s>Positive for catalase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine decarboxylase (weakly), phenylalanine deaminase (weakly), the Voges–Proskauer reaction, methyl red test and aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for oxidase, urease, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, and hydrolysis of starch, casein, gelatin and Tween 80.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and d-tagatose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, d-lyxose, d-arabitol or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, stachyose, sucrose, l-malic acid, succinamic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-ribose, d-xylose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester and pyruvic acid, but not Tween 40, Tween 80, arbutin, d-sorbitol or <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid (Biolog GP2 plates).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 53.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SA-7-6<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 206108<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19409<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from desert sand of the Tarim Basin, Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>