<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8289_nm.13733" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13733" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13733" rank="species">Kriegella aquimaris</organism><reference id="rid.8289"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kriegella aquimaris gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from marine environments</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2624</fpage><lpage>2628</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65751-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kriegella aquimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kriegella aquimaris</em> (a.qui.ma′ris. L. n. <em>aqua</em> water; L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>aquimaris</em> of seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are motile by gliding, 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 1.2–1.4 μm long.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, shiny with entire edges and dark-orange pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C (optimum 25–28 °C) and with 1–6 % NaCl (optimum 1–2 %).</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Decomposes aesculin and Tween 40.</s><s>Hydrolysis of DNA and Tweens 20 and 80 is strain-dependent.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse agar, casein, gelatin, starch, alginate, cellulose (CM-cellulose or filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Forms acid from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, l-fucose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose and d- and l-xylose, but not from l-sorbose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, citrate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Utilizes d-mannose, but not inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, malonate or citrate.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, activities of esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine and valine arylamidases, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are present, but lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, lincomycin and oleandomycin and resistant to benzylpenicillin, carbenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3665<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22188<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19886<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample from Amursky Bay of the Sea of Japan, also known as the East Sea.</s><s>A reference strain, KMM 3942 (=DSM 15364 =KCTC 22189), was isolated from the green alga <em>Ulva fenestrata</em> in Troitsa Bay, Sea of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>