<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12668_nm.22403" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22403" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22403" rank="species">Sphingomonas xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.12668"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas xinjiangensis sp. nov., isolated from desert sand</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1865</fpage><lpage>1869</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021147-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20817834</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, an autonomous region in north-west China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods (0.5–0.8×0.9–1.9 µm) and are motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Growth is observed on 1/10 TSB agar, R2A agar and full-strength TSB agar.</s><s>Colonies on 1/10 TSB agar are yellow, circular, entire, low-convex and smooth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 17–30 °C (optimum 28 °C), at pH 6.5–7.5 (optimum pH 7) and with 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0 % NaCl).</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin, but not casein, chitin, tyrosine, cellulose, starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Positive for β-galactosidase, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urea hydrolysis (API 20 NE).</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, malic acid, trisodium citrate, melibiose, l-fucose, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, maltose, l-alanine and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, salicin, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-proline, inositol, sucrose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, lactic acid, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-serine.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidases, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidases and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, but negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine and an unknown polar lipid.</s><s>The polyamine pattern contains the predominant compound <em>sym</em>-homospermidine.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 10-1-84<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AB 208035<sup>T</sup>  = NRRL B-51332<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface layer of a desert soil from Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>