<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8490_nm.13528" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13528" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13528" rank="species">Phenylobacterium conjunctum</organism><reference id="rid.8490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macedo</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawelczyck</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny by a polyphasic approach of the order Caulobacterales, proposal of Caulobacter mirabilis sp. nov., Phenylobacterium haematophilum sp. nov. and Phenylobacterium conjunctum sp. nov., and emendation of the genus Phenylobacterium.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1939</fpage><lpage>1949</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65567-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phenylobacterium conjunctum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phenylobacterium conjunctum</em> (con.junc′tum. L. neut. adj. <em>conjunctum</em> adjacent, the <em>Phenylobacterium</em> species which is closely related to the genus <em>Caulobacter</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Phenylobacterium conjunctum</em> is the same as that given for the genus (Lingens <em>et al.</em>, 1985) and emended by Kanso &#x0026; Patel (2004) and in this study, with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>Prosthecate bacteria, colony colour is tan, cells are bacteroid.</s><s>Cells are 1.15–1.60 μm in length and 0.5–0.7 μm in width.</s><s>The cell wall is of Gram-negative architecture and is about 25 nm in width, layered with an S-layer of 7.4 nm thickness.</s><s>Two major fatty acids are summed feature 7 (see Supplementary Table S1) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The minor fatty acids are summed feature 4 (see Supplementary Table S1) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Can grow on peptone-yeast extract media with 0–10 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl, with optimal growth at around 5 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl.</s><s>Tests are positive for the activities of acid and alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and weak activities are detected for cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), trypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>No activity for <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- or <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Able to utilize arabinose, citrate, dextrin, glucose, malonate, maltose, mannose and Tween 40, but not acetate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, adonitol, alaninamide, l- and d-alanine, l-alanylglycine, 2-amino ethanol, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, d-arabitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, 2,3-butanediol, dl-carnitine, cellobiose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, i-erythritol, formate, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, glucose 1- and glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, d-glucuronic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glycogen, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, hydroxy l-proline, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyrate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactate, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, l-leucine, d-mannitol, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, glycyl l-aspartic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, phenylethylamine, l-proline, propionate, psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, d- and l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinic acid, sucrose, Tween 80, trehalose, l-threonine, turanose, thymidine, uridine, urocanic acid or xylitol.</s><s>Does not grow with salt concentrations above 20 g l<sup>−1</sup> NaCl.</s><s>Growth is observed between 20 and 40 °C, with optimal growth at around 30 °C.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FWC 21<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24262<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55074<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a bench-scale rotating biological contactor at the University of British Columbia, Canada.</s></p></content></protolog>