<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12691_nm.22430" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22430" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22430" rank="species">Nocardioides ultimimeridianus</organism><reference id="rid.12691"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides ultimimeridianus sp. nov. and Nocardioides maradonensis sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1933</fpage><lpage>1937</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022715-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833879</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides ultimimeridianus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides ultimimeridianus</em> (ul.ti.mi.me.ri.di.a′nus. L. superl. adj. <em>ultimus</em> farthest, extreme; L. adj. <em>meridianus</em> of or belonging to the south, southern, meridional; N.L. masc. adj. <em>ultimimeridianus</em> of the farthest south, referring to the region in the Republic of Korea where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-reaction-positive, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, non-motile short rods (0.6–1.0×1.0–1.6 µm).</s><s>Colonies are moderately yellow in colour, circular, convex with entire margins and reach 0.2–0.3 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days (on ISP 2 medium at 30 °C).</s><s>Growth does not occur on TSA or NA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–42 °C (optimum 30–37 °C), at pH 5.0–10.1 and in 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, but not cellulose or DNA.</s><s>Does not degrade hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Positive for esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-glucosidase and trypsin (weak response).</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, citrate, dextran, d-fructose, gluconate (weakly), d-glucose, dl-malate, raffinose, d-sorbitol, succinate, sucrose and dl-tartrate as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Does not utilize adonitol, d-arabinose, benzoate, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, formate, glycerol, lactose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl α-d-mannoside, l-sorbose, trehalose, d-xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Data for other physiological and biochemical properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>ll-DAP is the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The polar lipids include phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RP-B26<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 19368<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 19768<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of a cliff-associated plant (<em>Peucedanum japonicum</em> Thunb.) on Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>