<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1355_nm.4887" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4887" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4887" rank="species">Bacillus chondroitinus</organism><reference id="rid.1355"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus alginolyticus sp. nov. and Bacillus chondroitinus sp. nov., two alginate-degrading species.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>284</fpage><lpage>286</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-284</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus chondroitinius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus chondroitinius</i> (chon.dro'i.tinus. M.L. adj. <i>chondroitinus</i>, of chondroitin, pertaining to chondroitin)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped, 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide by 3.0 to 5.0 μm long as measured by phase microscopy, and exist singly and in short chains.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Produce ellipsoidal spores in</s></p><p class="description"><s>swollen sporangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, smooth, circular, entire, and measure from 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter after 3 days at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase not detected.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol (Voges-Proskauer test), indole, and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>pH in Voges-Proskauer broth is higher than 5.5 at 7 days.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, Alginate, starch, Tween 80, and urea are usually decomposed.</s><s>Casein, egg yolk lecithin, and tyrosine are not degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine, lysine, and ornithine are not decomposed.</s><s>Citrate, fumarate, and succinate are not utilized.</s><s>Acetate and malate are utilized by most strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows at pH 5.6 or 5.7.</s><s>Growth is usually inhibited by 3% NaCl and 0.001% lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Litmus milk is not changed in 7 days.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature ranges from 28 to 30°C, the maximum is from 35 to 40°C, and the minimum is from 5 to 10°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Sorbitol is not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA buoyant density (12), 1.7060 to 1.7065 g/cm<sup>3</sup>; G+C content, 47 to 48 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NRRL NRS-1351.</s><s>Except for the ability to degrade desulfated chondroitin, this strain is phenotypically identical to other strains of species.</s></p></content></protolog>