<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3740_nm.9559" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9559" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9559" rank="species">Olleya marilimosa</organism><reference id="rid.3740"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mancuso Nichols</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guezennec</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Olleya marilimosa gen. nov., sp. nov., an exopolysaccharide-producing marine bacterium from the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from the Southern Ocean</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1557</fpage><lpage>1561</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63642-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014481</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Olleya marilimosa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Olleya marilimosa</em> (mar.i.lim.o′sa. L. gen. neut. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; L. adj. <em>limosus -a -um</em> full of slime, slimy; N.L. fem. adj. <em>marilimosa</em> of the sea and slimy).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus with the following additions.</s><s>When incubated on marine agar for 1 week at 20 °C, CAM030<sup>T</sup> forms orange/yellow, translucent colonies 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, convex, with an entire edge and a butyrous consistency.</s><s>Colonies exhibit spreading margin on dilute agar and enhanced mucoid morphology when grown on marine agar supplemented with 3 % glucose.</s><s>Growth occurs in the pH range 5–9 and in the temperature range 4–30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> or sea salts for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs between 0·2 and 0·9 M NaCl with optimal growth occurring at approximately 0·2–0·5 M NaCl.</s><s>Requires yeast extract or peptone for growth.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose, assimilates a range of carbohydrates, but does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Indole, DNase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lipase, urease and acetoin (Vogues-Proskauer reaction) are not produced, but oxidase and catalase are formed.</s><s>Tween 80, elastin, gelatin and tyrosine are degraded, but agar, starch, aesculin, casein, cellulose and xanthine are not.</s><s>Citrate is utilized as a sole carbon source, but uric acid is not.</s><s>Glucose, maltose and mannose are assimilated; arabinose, mannitol, d-gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate and trisodium citrate are not.</s><s>Tests for <em>β</em>-<em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase are positive.</s><s>Tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, proline arylamidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase are negative.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CAM030<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1065<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108537<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Southern Ocean particulate material.</s></p></content></protolog>