<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5974_nm.3162" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3162" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3162" rank="species">Enterobacter pyrinus</organism><reference id="rid.5974"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter pyrinus sp. nov., an organism associated with brown leaf spot disease of pear trees.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>161</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-157</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter pyrinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter pyrinus</i> (pyr'i.nus. N. L. n. <i>pyrus</i>, pear; L. suff. -<i>inus</i>, belonging to; N. L. adj. <i>pyrinus</i>, from pears)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, fermentative rods (0.6 to 1.0 by 1.6 to 2.3 μm that are motile and peritrichous.</s><s>Grows well on nutrient agar, yeast extract-dextrose-CaCO<sub>3</sub> agar, and other common bacteriological media.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, entire, convex, smooth, translucent, and 1.5 to 5.0 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation at 27°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 36°C and in the presence of 5% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>Positive in tests for acetoin production (Voges-Proskauer test), H<sub>2</sub>S production from cysteine, glucoriate oxidation, gas production from D-glucose, KCN tolerance, nitrate reduction, phosphatase activity, reducing substances produced from sucrose, and urease activity.</s><s>Negative in tests for casein hydrolysis, DNase activity, erythromycin susceptibility, gelatin liquefaction, growth factor requirement, indole production, mucoid growth, pectinase activity, phenylalanine deaminase activity, pigment production, potato rot, and tobacco hypersensitivity.</s><s>The strains utilize citrate, formate, lactate, galacturonate, and malonate as sole carbon sources, but not L-tartrate.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, mannose, melibiose, ribose, L-rhamnose, salicin, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, dextrin, dulcitol, inulin, lactose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, palatinose, raffinose, D-sorbitol, and starch.</s><s>Phenotypic tests that are useful for differentiating <i>Enterobacterpyrinus</i> from other <i>Enterobacter</i> and <i>Erwinia</i> species are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>he G+C content of the DNA is 57.5 to 61 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from pear leaves and cause brown leaf spot disease of pear trees (<i>P. pyrifolia</i> Nakai).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Enterobacterpyrinus</i> is strain KCTC 2520 (= CDC 6570 = ATCC 49851).</s><s>This strain was isolated from diseased pear (<i>P. pyrifolia </i> cv. Mansamgil) leaves at Yusung, Korea, in 1988.</s><s>The biochemical characteristics of this strain are identical to those of the species, and the G+C content of its DNA is 57.5 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>