<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.88_nm.4785" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4785" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4785" rank="species">Spiroplasma culicicola</organism><reference id="rid.88"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hung</surname><given-names>S.H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spiroplasma culicicola sp. nov. from the salt marsh mosquito Aedes sollicitans.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>365</fpage><lpage>370</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-365</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spiroplasma culicicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spiroplasma culicicola</i> (cu.li'ci.co.la; M. L. n. <i>Culicidae</i>, family name of mosquitoes, to denote family of insect host)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells pleomorphic, but commonly helical, 1 to 2 μm in length with one to two turns, rarely 3 to 10 μm in length.</s><s>Negatively stained cells of strain AES-1 and photographs of ultrathin sections in electron microscopy are shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>Cells lack true cell walls and periplasmic fibrils.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Typical "fried egg"- shaped colonies are produced on solid R-2 medium prepared with 1% Noble agar.</s><s>Primary colonies usually are surrounded by satellite colonies.</s><s>Grows in R-2 medium with a doubling time of about 66 min; grows well at 25 and 31°C, with optimal growth at 31°C.</s><s>The growth is significantly faster in R-2 than CC-494 medium.</s><s>Viability is lost at 37°C in R-2 broth medium.</s><s>Passes readily through membrane filters with pore diameters of 450 and 220 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth in serum-free medium or in CC-494 defined medium without cholesterol.</s><s>Failure to grow in cholesterol- free CC-494 is contrasted with the ability to grow in the complete medium.</s><s>On inoculated agar plates with digitonin-impregnated filter paper disks, average inhibition zones are 8 to 11 mm.</s><s>Sterol is required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilizes and ferments glucose, fructose, mannose, trehalose, and maltose, but not sucrose, raffinose, galactose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, and starch added as the sole carbohydrate to medium CC-494.</s><s>With arginine as the sole energy source in the medium, no growth is produced in the first subculture, indicating that the arginine dihydrolase pathway is absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the defined CC-494 medium, maximum cell yield is obtained when all 20 amino acids are supplied (Table 3).</s><s>However, good growth is produced in a defined medium supplemented with only two negatively charged polar R group amino acid (aspartic and glutamic acid) or three glucogenic and ketogenic amino acid combinations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth with arginine or urea instead of glucose in the defined CC-494 medium.</s><s>Tellurite is reduced in aerobic and anaerobic cultures.</s><s>After potassium tellurite agar plates are inoculated with an inverted agar block exhibiting dense growth, true black coloration of colonies is observed microscopically.</s><s>Methylene blue is not reduced in either aerobic or anaerobic cultures.</s><s>Phosphatase negative.</s><s>Film and spot reaction positive.</s><s>Agar colonies do not hemadsorb guinea pig erythrocytes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from salt marsh mosquito (<i>Aedes sollicitans</i>) in New Jersey.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is about 26 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>) and 26.7 mol% (buoyant density).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is AES-1 (ATCC 35112).</s></p></content></protolog>