<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10085_nm.15036" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15036" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15036" rank="species">Caldicoprobacter oshimai</organism><reference id="rid.10085"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokoyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>I.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caldicoprobacter oshimai gen. nov., sp. nov., an anaerobic, xylanolytic, extremely thermophilic bacterium isolated from sheep faeces, and proposal of Caldicoprobacteraceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>67</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011379-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648349</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Caldicoprobacter oshimai</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Caldicoprobacter oshimai</em> (o.shi′ma.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>oshimai</em> of Oshima, named after the Japanese microbiologist Tairo Oshima, in honour of his many contributions to our knowledge of thermophiles and their biochemistry).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.5 μm in diameter and 4–14 μm long and appear singly or in pairs.</s><s>Main cell-wall sugars are galactose and mannose.</s><s>Spherical endospores (0.4–0.6 μm in diameter) are formed in a terminal position, causing swelling of the mother cell.</s><s>Non-sporulating cells form protuberances in the stationary growth phase that then become round, spheroplast-like cells that are not viable.</s><s>Extremely thermophilic, growing at 44–77 °C (optimum 70 °C) at pH<sup>70 °C</sup> 7.2 (no growth at or below 42 °C or at or above 79 °C), and neutrophilic, with a pH<sup>70 °C</sup> range for growth at 70 °C of 5.9–8.6 and an optimum at pH<sup>70 °C</sup> 7.2 (no growth at or below pH<sup>70 °C</sup> 5.7 or at or above pH<sup>70 °C</sup> 8.9).</s><s>Tolerates 0–2.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Xylose, glucose, galactose, fructose, mannose, cellobiose, lactose, raffinose and xylan are utilized as carbon and energy sources but not dextran, soluble potato starch, CM-cellulose, cellulose powder, cellulose (filter paper), sorbitol, mannitol, lactate, acetate, ethanol, butanol, peptone, casein, gelatin or Casamino acids.</s><s>Fermentation end products from glucose are lactate, acetate, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JW/HY-331<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21659<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1711<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sheep faeces collected from a farm at the University of Georgia, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>