<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2808_nm.3912" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3912" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3912" rank="species">Clostridium cellulosi</organism><reference id="rid.2808"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Long</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two cellulolytic Clostridium species: Clostridium cellulosi sp. nov. and Clostridium cellulofermentans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>306</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-306</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854643</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium cellulosi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium cellulosi</i> (cellulosi, L. gen. n. of cellulose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, straight or slightly curved rods which usually are 0.3 to 0.6 μm wide by 2.0 to 15.0 μm long.</s><s>Although most young cells are 2.0 to 4.0 μm long, longer ones are common and cells with spores are frequently longer than vegetative cells (Fig. 1).</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs, or in chains and are motile with lophotrichous flagella (Fig. 2).</s><s>Endospores are terminal and spherical and swell the cells.</s><s>Cultures survive 100°C for 20 min.</s><s>Heat shock favors germination of the cultures.</s><s>In cellulose agar medium, clear zones showing digestion of cellulose are observed after 48 h of incubation.</s><s>Tiny colonies range of 40 to 65°C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 35 or 70°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.3 to 7.5, and the pH range is 6.2 to 8.5.</s><s>Ruminal fluid or added vitamins and tryptic peptone are not necessary for growth.</s><s>Nutritional requirements are met by 2 g of yeast extract per liter.</s><s>Only slight growth occurs in PY medium with no fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic medium is required.</s><s>No germination occurs in medium in which traces of dissolved oxygen have been indicated by resazurin turning pink.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, gelatinase, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Sulfate and nitrate are not reduced.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is produced, and milk is curdled.</s><s>The other characteristics of the species are given in Table 1.</s><s>After several transfers in cellobiose broth and repicking of single colonies from cellobiose agar into cellulose medium, cellulolytic activity is still apparent, although there is an increased lag phase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products from cellulose fermentation are hydrogen, carbon dioxide, ethanol, and acetic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from cow manure compost.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA composition is 35 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>C. cellulosi</i> AS 1.1777.</s></p></content></protolog>