<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5344_nm.11736" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11736" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2149" rank="species">Thiorhodococcus minus</organism><reference id="rid.5344"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guyoneaud</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matheron</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caumette</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiorhodococcus minus, gen. nov., sp. nov., A new purple sulfur bacterium isolated from coastal lagoon sediments.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>168</volume><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050464</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9211709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiorhodococcus minus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiorhodococcus minus</i> (mi'nus. L.adj. <i>minus</i> small)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells spherical, 1.0–2.0 μm in diameter; diplococci are formed during binary fission; gram-negative.</s><s>Cells highly motile.</s><s>Color of cell suspension brown-orange.</s><s>Photosynthetic membrane system of the vesicular type.</s><s>Contains bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids of the normal spirilloxanthin series with rhodopin as major pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phototrophic under anoxic conditions in the light; chemolithotrophic and chemoorganotrophic under microoxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Electron donors for photolithoautotrophic growth: H<sub>2</sub>, hydrogen sulfide, thiosulfate, and elemental sulfur.</s><s>During photolithotrophic growth with reduced sulfur compounds, elemental sulfur globules are formed and randomly stored inside the cells.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and hydrogen carbonate, acetate, propionate, lactate, glycolate, pyruvate, malate, fumarate, succinate, fructose, sucrose, ethanol, and propanol are photoassimilated.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic growth occurs with acetate and fructose; chemolithotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and thiosulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain not capable of assimilatory sulfate reduction.</s><s>Optimal pH 7.0–7.2; pH range 6.0–8.0; optimal salinity 2% NaCl, salinity range 0.5-9% NaCl; optimal temperature 30–35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition of the type strain: 66.9 mol% G+C (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: anoxic sediments from coastal lagoons and marine environments rich in sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain CE2203<sup>T</sup> isolated from the brackish lagoons of Certes, Arcachon Bay, France.</s><s>Deposited with the German Collection of Microorganisms in Braunschweig, Germany (DSMZ no. 11518 and with the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC no. 700259).</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence deposited in EMBL under accession no. Y11316.</s></p></content></protolog>