<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7286_nm.5244" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5244" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5244" rank="species">Staphylococcus condimenti</organism><reference id="rid.7286"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Probst</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hertel</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richter</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wassill</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hammes</surname><given-names>W.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus condimenti sp. nov., from soy sauce mash, and Staphylococcus carnosus (Schleifer and Fischer 1982) subsp. utilis subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>651</fpage><lpage>658</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-651</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734019</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus condimenti</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus condimenti</i> (con.di.men'ti. L. n. <i>condimentum</i> spice; L. gen. n. <i>condimenti</i> of the spice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci (diameter 1 μm), facultative anaerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming and occur in pairs, short chains and small clusters.</s><s>Colonies on P-agar are usually opaque, circular and slightly raised, with entire margins.</s><s>After 48 h incubation, colonies are cream-coloured and 1-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>They exhibit catalase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, nitrate reductase, nitrite reductase, β-galactosidase, phosphatase and lipolytic activity.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed; no β-glucuronidase activity is detectable.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, trehalose, mannitol, sorbitol and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from raffinose, ribose, cellobiose, turanose and arabinose.</s><s>Lecithinase and coagulase activity is not detectable.</s><s>Strains grow at 15 and 42°C and on P-agar containing 0.5-15% NaCl.</s><s>Sensitive to lysostaphin (200 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and resistant to lysozyme (400 and 1600 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Variable characteristics are shown in Table 5.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 35.2-36 mol%.</s><s>MK-7 is the major menaquinone, and MK-6 or MK-6 and MK-8 are the minor menaquinones.</s><s>Strains were isolated from soy sauce mash.</s><s>Strain F-2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11674<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain, and its characteristics are those described above.</s><s>Its G + C content is 35.2 mol %.</s><s>MK-7 is the major menaquinone; MK-6 is the minor menaquinone.</s><s>The sequences of the 16s and 23s rRNA have EMBL accession numbers Y15750 and Y15755.</s><s>Strain F-8 (=DSM 11675) is a reference strain that exhibits different physiological characteristics.</s><s>This strain does not grow at 45°C, has a G+C content of 36 mol %, MK-7 as the major menaquinone and MK-6 and MK-8 as the minor menaquinones.</s></p></content></protolog>