<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.349_nm.14" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14" rank="species">Pyrobaculum aerophilum</organism><reference id="rid.349"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Völkl</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drobner</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rachel</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burggraf</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trincone</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stetter</surname><given-names>K.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pyrobaculum aerophilum sp. nov., a novel nitrate-reducing hyperthermophilic archaeum.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>2918</fpage><lpage>2926</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7692819</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pyrobaculum aerophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pyrobaculum aerophilum</i> (a.e.ro'phi.lum. Gr. masc. n. <i>aer</i>; adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. neut. adj. <i>aerophilum</i>, air loving, because of its ability to use oxygen for growth in contrast to all other described species of the genus <i>Pyrobaculum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells usually between 3 and 8 μm long; cylinder-shaped rods with a width of 0.6 μm.</s><s>Motile by monopolar flagellation.</s><s>Cells with terminal spheres occur mainly in the stationary-growth phase, at high nitrite concentrations, or at pH values above 8.</s><s>Spheres can enlarge, producing coccoid cell forms.</s><s>Colonies greyish yellow, round with a rough surface.</s><s>Anaerobically grown, packed cell masses exhibit a deep green color; aerobically grown cells exhibit a brownish yellow color.</s><s>Growth between 75 and 104°C (optimum, 100°C), at pH 5.8 to 9 (optimum, 7.0), and at 0 to 3.6% NaCl (optimum, 1.5%).</s><s>Optimal doubling time, 180 min.</s><s>Heterotrophic growth on yeast extract, meat extract, tryptone, peptone, gelatin, casein, Casamino Acids, propionate, and acetate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth by oxidation of hydrogen or thiosulfate.</s><s>Oxygen, nitrate, and nitrite are possible electron acceptors.</s><s>Nitrite and dinitrogen are products of dissimilatory nitrate reduction (denitrification).</s><s>Growth inhibition by elemental sulfur.</s><s>Aerobically grown cells exhibit catalase-positive reaction.</s><s>Cell wall composed of a protein surface layer, exhibiting p6 symmetry and a center-to-center distance of approximately 30 nm between neighboring protein complexes.</s><s>Core lipids mainly glycerol diphytanyl glycerol tetraethers with varying degrees of cyclization.</s><s>DNA base composition, 52 mol% G+C.</s><s>By 16S rRNA sequence comparisons, 1.6% evolutionary distance to <i>P. islandicum</i>.</s><s>Type strain: <i>Pyrobaculum aerophilum</i> IM2, DSM 7523, Braunschweig, Germany (isolated at Maronti Beach, Ischia, Italy).</s></p></content></protolog>