<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5813_nm.1588" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1588" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1588" rank="species">Methylobacterium lusitanum</organism><reference id="rid.5813"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuznetsov</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium suomiense sp. nov. and Methylobacterium lusitanum sp. nov., aerobic, pink-pigmented, facultatively methylotrophic bacteria.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>773</fpage><lpage>776</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylobacterium lusitanum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylobacterium lusitanum</i> (lu.si.ta'num. L. neut. adj. <i>lusitanum</i> of Lusitania, the Latin name of Portugal)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, asporogenous rods, 1.0-1.2x1.7-2.0 μm, occurring singly or rarely in pairs.</s><s>Cells are motile by a single or two to three polar flagella.</s><s>Slow growth on nutrient agar and PYG agar.</s><s>Colonies on methanol/salt agar are shiny, smooth, raised, entire and pink, 1 mm in diameter after 3 days growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The pink pigment is water insoluble and has absorption maxima at 473, 499 and 532 nm in a mixture of chloroform and methanol (1:1).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Produces indole from tryptophan on medium with nitrate as nitrogen source.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin or starch.</s><s>Does not form ammonia or hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Produces acid oxidatively from D-fructose.</s><s>Catalase-, oxidase-, lipase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Oxidase activity is weak.</s><s>Strict aerobe.</s><s>Chemo-organotroph and facultative methylotroph, assimilating C<sub>1</sub> compounds by the <i>icl<sup>−</sup></i> serine pathway.</s><s>Utilized carbon sources are:methanol, methylamine, ethanol, glycerol, inositol, D-fructose, acetate, acetamide, succinate, malate, fumarate, pyruvate, α-ketoglutarate and propionate.</s><s>The following are not utilized: L-arabinose, D-glucose, galactose, D-xylose, mannose, lactose, maltose, trehalose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, sorbose, sorbitol, mannitol, inositol, soluble starch, tartrate, citrate, alanine, valine, glycine, arginine, aspartate, betaine, N,N-dimethylglycine, sarcosine, glutamate, mono- and dichloromethane, di- and trimethylamine, CO<sub>2</sub>­H<sub>2</sub> and methane.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrate, urea, aspartate, glutamate and alanine are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Optimal growth between pH 6.9 and 7.5 and at 30-37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acid is cisvaccenic acid (C"):"x7; 83.1%).</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>Dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA is 66.5 mol%(<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>The type strain, RXM<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from a sewage station in Portugal as a methanol-utilizing bacterium and has been deposited in the Russian Collection of Microorganisms as VKM B-2239<sup>T</sup>, in the National Collections of Industrial, Food and Marine Bacteria as NCIMB 13779<sup>T</sup> and in the DSMZ as DSM 14457<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>