<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7237_nm.6420" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6420" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6420" rank="species">Nocardia abscessus</organism><reference id="rid.7237"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mendrock</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brzezinka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia abscessus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1487</fpage><lpage>1493</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939654</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia abscessus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia abscessus</i> (abs.ces'sus. L. gen. masc. n. <i>abscessus</i> of or derived from an abscess, referring to the characteristic clinical conditions from which the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The filamentous cells formed in early growth stages are Gram-positive, slightly acid/alcohol-fast and fragment, in a later stage of growth, into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Mature colonies measure 0.5-1.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is well developed and shows an orange colour.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are abundant and white.</s><s>Type of metabolism and chemotaxonomic properties are of the genus <i>Nocardia</i>.</s><s>D-Glucose, maltose, rhamnose (some strains are not able to utilize this sugar), sucrose, trehalose, acetate, citrate and paraffin are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy, but L-arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, lactose, D-melezitose, raffinose, xylose, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butanediol, 1,2-propanediol, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, adipate, benzoate, gluconate and lactate are not utilized.</s><s>Acetamide, L-alanine, gelatin, proline and serine are not utilized as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources.</s><s>Testosterone and urea are hydrolysed but adenine, aesculin, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, keratin, tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>The G­+C content is 67.9±0.2 mol% for the type strain and ranges from 67.5 to 69.8 mol% for the species.</s><s>The type strain of <i>N. abscessus</i> is strain IMMIB D-1592<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44432<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a joint abscess of a 56-year-old man with a complete endoprosthesis of one of his knees.</s></p></content></protolog>