<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1823_nm.6918" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6918" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6918" rank="species">Streptomyces cellulolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.1823"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces cellulolyticus sp. nov., a new cellulolytic member of the genus Streptomyces.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>443</fpage><lpage>445</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-443</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103634</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces cellulolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces cellulolyticus</i> (cel.lu.lo.ly'ti.cus. M. L. n. <i>cellulosum</i>, cellulose; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; M. L. adj. <i>cellulolyticus</i>, decomposing cellulose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore chains are rectiflexibiles, with 20 or more spores per chain.</s><s>The spores are oval and are 2.1 to 2.3 by 2.5 to 2.7 μm.</s><s>The spore surface is warty.</s><s>Mycelia do not fragment into coccoid or bacillary structures.</s><s>The branching substrate mycelium is yellow on yeast extract-malt extract agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, glucose-asparagine agar, and nutrient agar; brown on glycerol-asparagine agar, tyrosine agar, and Czapek’s solution agar; and colorless on oatmeal agar.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is white to pink.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Soluble pigments, including melanin, are not produced.</s><s>The organism is positive for catalase activity and production of H<sub>2</sub>S and negative for oxidase activity and indole production.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Starch, casein, and esculin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Cellulose is decomposed.</s><s>D-Glucose, D-fructose, L-arabinose, sucrose, D-xylose, raffinose, and i-inositol are utilized for growth, but L-rhamnose is not utilized.</s><s>L-Asparagine, L-cystine, and L-threonine can be used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Good growth occurs at pH 7.2, and the optimum temperature is 30°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 10% NaCl.</s><s>Isolate LX<sup>T</sup> is susceptible to penicillin G, but not to dimethylchlortetracycline, vancomycin, kanamycin, rifampin, and aminobenzylpenicillin.</s><s>The cell wall chemotype is chemotype I, and the cell wall contains LL-diaminopimelic acid and glycine; no characteristic sugars are detected as whole-cell sugars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LX, which has been deposited in the China General Microbiological Culture Collection Center as strain AS. 41332.</s></p></content></protolog>