<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12887_nm.22702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22702" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22702" rank="species">Micrococcus lactis</organism><reference id="rid.12887"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chittpurna</surname><given-names>.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pinnaka</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korpole</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Micrococcus lactis sp. nov., isolated from dairy industry waste</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2832</fpage><lpage>2836</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028043-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21239567</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Micrococcus lactis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Micrococcus lactis</em> (lac′tis. L. gen. n. <em>lactis</em> from milk, pertaining to the isolation source ‘dairy waste’).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci with diameter of about 1.0 µm, stain Gram-positive, are non-motile and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Growth is observed between temperatures of 10 and 40 °C but not at 42 °C and between pH 4.5 and 9.5, the optimum being 7.5.</s><s>Growth occurs with between 0 and 4 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase-positive but oxidase-negative.</s><s>Exhibits urease activity.</s><s>Cannot hydrolyse starch, aesculin or Tweens 20, 40, 60 or 80.</s><s>Positive in the Vitek2 system (bioMérieux) for leucine, alanine, l-proline, tyrosine and l-aspartate arylamidases but negative for ala-phe-pro arylamidase.</s><s>Positive for α-glucosidase but negative for arginine dihydrolase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactopyranosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase-mannosidase, phosphatase, and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Exhibits l-lactate alkalinization.</s><s>Cannot utilize d-ribose, raffinose, cyclodextrin, d-sorbitol, lactose, d-mannitol, salicin, d-mannose, sucrose, trehalose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, methyl β-d-glucopyranoside, d-galactose or pullulan.</s><s>Sensitive to novobiocin, optochin, polymyxin and bacitracin.</s><s>Positive for oxidization of the following substrates in Biolog plates: acetate, dextrin, α-hydroxybutyric acid, glycerol, inosine, lactate, pyruvic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-pyroglutamic acid, adenosine, maltose, maltotriose, α-ketovaleric acid, d-ribose, sucrose, succinamic acid, succinic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, turanose, Tween 40, Tween 80 and glycerol.</s><s>Cannot oxidize α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, amygdalin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, glycogen, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl α-d-galactoside, methyl β-d-galactoside, 3-methyl-d-glucose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl β-d-glucoside, methyl α-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, d-tagatose, xylitol, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, lactamide, d-malic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, putrescine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate or α-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan of the type strain is type A4α with l-Lys-Asp.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern includes DPG, PG, PI, PC, an unknown phospholipid and two unknown glycolipids.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H, i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and ai-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 68.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DW152<sup>T</sup> ( = MTCC10523<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23694<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from dairy industry waste.</s></p></content></protolog>