<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3792_nm.4378" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4378" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4378" rank="species">Allisonella histaminiformans</organism><reference id="rid.3792"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Garner</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flint</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Allisonella histaminiformans gen. nov., sp. nov. A novel bacterium that produces histamine, utilizes histidine as its sole energy source, and could play a role in bovine and equine laminitis.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>498</fpage><lpage>506</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/07232020260517625</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12583709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Allisonella histaminiformans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Allisonella histaminiformans</i> (his.ta.min.i.for.mans N.L. neut n. <i>histamini</i> histamine; L. part adj. formans forming; N.L. part adj. <i>histaminiformans</i> histamine forming.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid shaped (0.4–0.8 × 1.0–8.0 μm long), are non-motile and occur in dipliod or chains.</s><s>Spores are absent.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are highly resistant to the ionophore, monensin.</s><s>Facultative anaerobic chemoheterotroph that utilizes histidine, producing histamine and CO<sub>2</sub> as end-products.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium that contains yeast extract, butyrate and histidine.</s><s>The only other amino acid that is utilized is lysine, but lysine alone does not allow growth.</s><s>Carbohydrates and organic acids are not utilized.</s><s>Cellular yield is 1.5 mg protein per mmol of histidine.</s><s>Cells have a 110 min doubling time and grow optimally at 39 °C.</s><s>Volatile fatty acids are not produced and butyric acid is required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular fatty acids profiles are dominated by C16 and C18 mono-unsaturated C16 fatty acids.</s><s>C16:0 saturated fatty acids account for less than 5% of the total.</s><s>The mol % guanine plus cytosine of DNA is 46.8 (thermal denaturation).</s><s>16S rRNA gene comparisons indicated that <i>A. histaminiformans</i> was most closely to Gram-positive bacteria, but these bacteria did not produce histamine. <i>A. histaminiformans</i> can be easily isolated from the rumen of cattle fed grain, but it could not be detected in cattle fed hay. <i>A. histaminiformans</i> can also be isolated at lower numbers from bovine feces and the cecum of a horse.</s><s>The type strain is MR2 (ATCC BAA610, DSM 15230).</s></p></content></protolog>