<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12886_nm.22701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22701" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22701" rank="species">Streptomyces fenghuangensis</organism><reference id="rid.12886"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces fenghuangensis sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2811</fpage><lpage>2815</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.029280-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216916</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces fenghuangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces fenghuangensis</em> (feng.hu.ang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>fenghuangensis</em> pertaining to Fenghuang, where the seawater was collected from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive, catalase-positive actinomycete that forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium which carries aerial hyphae that differentiate into straight to flexuous chains of spores with rough to warty surfaces.</s><s>Milk coagulation, milk peptonization and starch hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>Good growth on yeast extract/malt extract agar (ISP 2), Gause’s synthetic agar medium no. 1, glucose-asparagine agar and Czapek’s solution agar and moderate growth on oatmeal agar (ISP 3), glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP 5) and starch agar.</s><s>Poor growth on inorganic salts/starch agar (ISP 4).</s><s>White aerial mycelium is formed on ISP 2, ISP 3, glucose-asparagine agar and Gause’s synthetic agar medium no. 1.</s><s>Greyish-white, yellowish-white and orange–white aerial mycelium is formed on ISP 5, Czapek’s agar and starch agar, respectively.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is white on Czapek’s agar, yellow on Gause’s synthetic agar medium no. 1 and starch agar, yellowish white on ISP 2, ISP 5 and glucose-asparagine agar, grey on ISP 3 and greyish white on ISP 4.</s><s>Blue diffusible pigment is formed on ISP 5.</s><s>Melanin pigment is not produced on ISP 7.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-fructose, inositol, mannitol and l-arabinose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-DAP (cell-wall type I) and glucose is detected as a diagnostic sugar in the whole-cell sugar hydrolysate.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The type strain contains straight-chain and iso- and anteiso-branched fatty acids and a proportion of unsaturated fatty acids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;4 %) are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>No antimicrobial activity is detected against <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 6538, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> ATCC 6633, <em>Candida albicans</em> ATCC 10231 or <em>Penicillium citrinum</em> AS 3.2788.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.94 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GIMN4.003<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCCM 208215<sup>T</sup>  = NRRL B-24801<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater.</s></p></content></protolog>