<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12331_nm.20355" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20355" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20355" rank="species">Amnibacterium kyonggiense</organism><reference id="rid.12331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amnibacterium kyonggiense gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Microbacteriaceae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018788-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173001</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amnibacterium kyonggiense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amnibacterium kyonggiense</em> (ky.ong.gi.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>kyonggiense</em> of or belonging to Kyonggi University, Republic of Korea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following characteristics in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.15–0.20 μm in width and 0.25–0.30 μm in length.</s><s>After 3 days on R2A agar, colonies are 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter, smooth, yellow-coloured, circular and convex.</s><s>Grows between 10 and 37 °C, but not at 4 °C or 45 °C after 24 h.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30 °C in LB broth.</s><s>The pH growth range is between pH 5.0 and pH 8.0, with an optimum pH of 6.0 in LB broth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 2 % (w/v) NaCl in LB broth.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar and LB agar.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis and weakly positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20NE).</s><s>Adipate, l-arabinose, caproate, citrate, gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucose, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and phenylacetate are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (API 20NE).</s><s>Positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (6-Br-2-naphthyl-<em>β</em> d-glucopyranoside), esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase, weakly positive for acid phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (naphthol-AS-BI-<em>β</em> d-glucuronide), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for acid production from aesculin ferric citrate and potassium 5-ketogluconate, weakly positive for arbutin and d-tagatose, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, starch, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose (bovine origin), d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium gluconate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>β</em>-l-sorbose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylopyranoside, d-xylose and l-xylose (API 50CHB).</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and three unknown phospholipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KSL51201-037<sup>T</sup> (=KEMC 51201-037<sup>T</sup>=JCM 16463<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Anyang stream, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>