<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3465_nm.2848" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2848" rank="genus">Idiomarina</organism><reference id="rid.3465"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matte</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matte</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huq</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maugel</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Idiomarina gen. nov., comprising novel indigenous deep-sea bacteria from the Pacific Ocean, including descriptions of two species, Idiomarina abyssalis sp. nov. and Idiomarina zobellii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>901</fpage><lpage>907</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758902</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Idiomarina</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Idiomarina</i> (I.di.o.ma.ri'na. Gr. adj. <i>idios</i> original, true; L. fem. adj. <i>marina</i> of the sea, marine; M.L. fem. n. <i>Idiomarina</i> pertaining to the peculiar, true marine nature of micro-organisms from the ocean (seawater))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, chemo-organotrophic, oxidase-positive, asporogenous, motile, with single polar flagellum, rod-shaped cells occurring single, sometimes in pairs, about 0.7-0.9 μm in diameter.</s><s>Does not accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product and does not have an arginine dihydrolase system.</s><s>Organic growth factors not required, but sodium ions or seawater are required for growth.</s><s>Temperature of growth is 4-30 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 20-22 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 40°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5-9.5, with optimum growth occurring at pH 7.5-8.0.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Gelatinase, lipase and DNase present but agar and starch not hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes D-arginine and L-tyrosine as a sole source of carbon but not D-arabinose, D-rhamnose, D-mannose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, glycerol, mannitol, L-lysine or L-phenylalanine.</s><s>The following were utilized : α-ketobutyric and α-ketovaleric acids; alaninamide; L-alanine; and L-alanyl-glycine.</s><s>D-Arabinose, D-rhamnose, D-mannose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, glycerol, mannitol, L-lysine and L-phenylalanine were not utilized, according to BIOLOG tests.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin but resistant to kanamycin, ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, lincomycin, tetracycline, oxacillin, oleandomycin, vancomycin and O/129.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are odd-numbered, iso-branched (about 70%), followed by saturated and monounsaturated straight fatty acids.</s><s>DNA G+­C content is 48.0-50.4 mol%, (determined by thermal denaturation).</s><s>A member of a phylogenetically coherent group, including the genera <i>Alteromonas</i>, <i>Colwellia</i> and <i>Pseudoalteromonas</i>, in the γ-<i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The genus contains two species, <i>Idiomarina abyssalis</i> and <i>Idiomarina zobellii</i>, with <i>I. abyssalis</i> as the type species.</s><s>Isolated from the deep sea.</s></p></content></protolog>