<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12798_nm.22592" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22592" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22592" rank="species">Pseudokineococcus lusitanus</organism><reference id="rid.12798"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jurado</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laiz</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ortiz-Martinez</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saiz-Jimenez</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudokineococcus lusitanus gen. nov., sp. nov., and reclassification of Kineococcus marinus Lee 2006 as Pseudokineococcus marinus comb. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2515</fpage><lpage>2519</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026195-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21112988</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudokineococcus lusitanus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudokineococcus lusitanus</em> (lu.si.ta′nus. L. masc. adj. belonging to Lusitania the Latin name for Portugal, where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive cocci that are 1.0–1.5 µm in diameter and occur singly or in pairs, tetrads or clusters.</s><s>Colonies are circular, rough and orange-coloured.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, oxidase-negative, urease-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 6–37 °C (optimum 28–30 °C).</s><s>Grows well at 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl, moderately at 5–6 % and poorly at 7–8 %.</s><s>Produces acid from d-and l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, methyl-α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, sucrose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose and d-lyxose but not from erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl-β-d-xylopyranoside, dulcitol, methyl-α-d-mannopyranoside, inulin, l-arabitol, d-fucose, potassium gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate or l-fucose.</s><s>Acid production from d-tagatose is variable.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C1), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase but not lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase or α-fucosidase.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, l-arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose but does not assimilate mannose, gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, dl-malic acid, citrate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Negative for glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase activities.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and indole tests are negative.</s><s>Sensitive to (µg per disc) chloramphenicol (30), rifampicin (5), tetracycline (30), novobiocin (30), streptomycin (10), carbenicillin (100), framycetin (50), erythromycin (15), doxycycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and kanamycin (30) but resistant to norfloxacin (10), ampicillin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain glucose, ribose, rhamnose and traces of galactose, mannose and xylose.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, an unidentified phospholipid, an unidentified glycolipid and an unidentified phosphoglycolipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, T2A-S27<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 24148<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7306<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23768<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from a roof tile in Oporto, Portugal.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 76.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>