<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12889_nm.22706" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22706" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22705" rank="species">Actinoplanes octamycinicus</organism><reference id="rid.12889"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishisda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.-i.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Descriptions of Actinoplanes ianthinogenes nom. rev. and Actinoplanes octamycinicus corrig. comb. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2916</fpage><lpage>2921</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.030130-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257697</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinoplanes octamycinicus</em> corrig. comb. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinoplanes octamycinicus</em> [oc.ta.my.ci′ni.cus. N.L. n. <em>octamycinum</em> octamycin (name of an antibiotic); L. masc. suff. -<em>icus</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. masc. adj. <em>octamycinicus</em> pertaining to octamycin, in reference to octamycin production].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of this species is based on data reported by Gauze <em>et al.</em> (1979) and data obtained in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colony surface is powdery.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is orange, yellow or brown.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is absent and vegetative mycelium has branched hyphae.</s><s>Sporangia on short sporangiophores arising from the vegetative mycelium, which is formed abundantly on oatmeal agar and humic acid-vitamin agar, are globose with an irregular surface and 3.0–10.0 µm in diameter.</s><s>Sporangial release is observed after rupture of the sporangial wall.</s><s>Subspherical spores are motile.</s><s>Grows at 15–37 °C, at pH 6–9 and in a maximum NaCl concentration of 1 %.</s><s><em>N</em>-Acetylglucosamine, aesculin ferric citrate, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose can be utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, catalase, aesculin hydrolysis, esterase lipase (C8), gelatin hydrolysis, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucine aminopeptidase, nitrate reduction, phosphohydrolase, pyrazinamidase, trypsin and valine aminopeptidase.</s><s>The major fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and the major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown polar lipid as major components but lacks phosphatidylcholine and aminoglycolipids (phospholipid type PII).</s><s>Additionally, moderate amounts of phosphatidylinositol are detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NBRC 14524<sup>T</sup> ( = INA 4041<sup>T</sup> = ATCC 43632<sup>T</sup> = JCM 9649<sup>T</sup> = KCTC 9593<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.1 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>