<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1197_nm.11720" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11720" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8228" rank="species">Sphingobacterium mizutae</organism><reference id="rid.1197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyoshi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium gen. nov., Sphingobacterium spiritivorum comb. nov., Sphingobacterium multivorum comb. nov., Sphingobacterium mizutae sp. nov., and Flavobacterium indologenes sp. nov.: glucose-nonfermenting Gram-negative rods in CDC groups IIK-2 and IIb.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>580</fpage><lpage>598</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingobacterium mizutae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingobacterium mizutae</i> (mi.zu'tae. N.L. adj. referring to Shunsuke Mizuta, Japanese pediatrician, who first reported a case of meningitis in a premature baby from whose spinal fluid the type strain of the species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Sphingobacterium mizutae</i> has the characteristics described above for the genus, and in addition strains of this species tolerate 40% bile and produce acid from rhamnose in oxidation-fermentation medium.</s><s>No acid is produced from ethanol, mannitol, or inulin.</s><s>No growth occurs at pH 5.0.</s><s>Sliding translocation on semisolid agar medium and fumarate respiration are not observed.</s><s>Starch hydrolysis and DNase production are negative.</s><s>Most strains do not oxidize glycogen or hydrolyze urea.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, but the type strain and some other strains reduce nitrite to nitrogen gas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is susceptible to carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, erythromycin, sulfadiazin, and sulfamethoxazole-trimethoprim but is resistant to penicillin, ampicillin, cephalothin, streptomycin, amikacin, kanamycin, gentamicin, clindamycin, colistin, and polymyxin B.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity has not been defined.</s><s>The natural habitat of this organism is not known, but it has been isolated from clinical specimens.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is in the range from 39.0 to 41.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 33299 (=GIFU 1203).</s></p></content></protolog>