<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.17_nm.6812" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6812" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6812" rank="species">Saccharothrix texasensis</organism><reference id="rid.17"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lyons</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharothrix texasensis sp. nov. and Saccharothrix waywayandensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>358</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharothrix texasensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix texasensis</i> (tex. as. en' sis. L. adj. <i>texasensis</i>, referring to the source of the soil samples, the state of Texas, from which the species was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium is dark yellow to brownish yellow.</s><s>Sparse white aerial mycelium is produced, particularly on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>A brown to reddish brown soluble pigment is produced on ATCC medium 172.</s><s>Adenine, casein, esculin, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, starch, Tween 80, and tyrosine are hydrolyzed; cellulose, guanine, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed; hydrolysis of allantoin and hydrolysis of urea are variable.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, lactate, DL-malate, and succinate are assimilated; benzoate, citrate, mucate, oxalate, and tartrate are not assimilated; propionate is variably assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose; no acid is produced from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, raffinose, and D-sorbitol; acid production from D-fructose and β-methyl-D-xyloside is variable.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 3% NaCl but not in the presence of 4% NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 42°C.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 74 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. texasensis</i> is strain NRRL B-16134 (= LL-37U-77).</s></p></content></protolog>