<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7228_nm.535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.535" rank="species">Meiothermus cerbereus</organism><reference id="rid.7228"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Meiothermus cerbereus sp. nov., a new slightly thermophilic species with high levels of 3-hydroxy fatty acids.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1225</fpage><lpage>1230</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1225</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336933</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Meiothermus cerbereus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Meiothermus cerbereus</i> (cer.be.re'us. L. adj. <i>cerbereus</i>, the monstrous dog Cerberus that guarded the mythological Greek Hades, so named because of the difficulty we had in growing the strains of this species in liquid medium)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Meiothermus cerbereus</i> strains have rod-shaped cells of variable length which are 0.5 to 0.8 (strains GY-1<sup>T</sup> and GY-5) μm wide.</s><s>Long filaments are also present.</s><s>Gram stain is negative.The cells are nonmotile, and spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on <i>Themus</i> medium with and without sodium thiosulfate are red-orange pigmented and 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 72 h of growth.</s><s>Cysteine, thiosulfate, or thioglycolate is required for growth of strains GY-1<sup>T</sup> and GY-5 in liquid medium.</s><s>Growth occurs between 35 and 60°C; the optimum growth temperature for strain GY-1<sup>T</sup> is about 55°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is about 7.5; growth does not occur at pH 5.0 or 10.5.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:0 iso and 15:0 anteiso and 17:0 iso and 17:0 anteiso; 3-OH fatty acids are present in higher levels than 2-OH fatty acids when strains are grown in <i>Thermus</i> agar without thiosulfate.</s><s>All strains are oxidase positive and catalase negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. α- and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>Elastin, fibrin, casein, and hide powder azure are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Degradation of arbutin and esculin is positive.</s><s>Strains GY-1<sup>T</sup> and GY-5 utilize D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, D-melibiose, D-cellobiose, D-trehalose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, pyruvate, L-glutamate, and L-proline.</s><s>Strains GY-1<sup>T</sup> and GY-5 do not hydrolyze starch or utilize D-raffinose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, D-xylose, glycerol, ribitol, succinate, malate, citrate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-asparagine, L-serine, L-glutamine, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, and L-arginine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA of strain GY-1<sup>T</sup> has a G+C content of 60.9 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from hot springs in the Geysir area of Iceland.</s><s>Strain GY-1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismeh und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 11376.</s><s>Strain GY-5 (DSM 11377) is a reference strain of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>