<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6836_nm.2702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2702" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2702" rank="species">Pseudomonas trivialis</organism><reference id="rid.6836"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fluorescent pseudomonads associated with the phyllosphere of grasses; Pseudomonas trivialis sp. nov., Pseudomonas poae sp. nov. and Pseudomonas congelans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1461</fpage><lpage>1469</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02567-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas trivialis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas trivialis</em> (tri.vi.a′lis. L. fem. adj<em>. trivialis</em> trivial).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile by one polar flagellum and are 1·6–3·3 μm long and about 0·8 μm wide.</s><s>Oxidase reaction is weak and ice nucleation activity is negative.</s><s>In addition to the general description, the following substances are assimilated: formic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, d-alanine, l-proline, quinic acid, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, d-trehalose and Tween 40.</s><s>None of the strains assimilates <em>i</em>-erythritol, glucose 6-phosphate, glycogen, glycolyl l-aspartic acid or d-psicose.</s><s>Gelatinase, casein hydrolysis and utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, l-rhamnose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, d-serine, dl-carnitine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerolphosphate, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid and d-sorbitol are strain-dependent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P 513/19<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14937<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21464<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses in Paulinenaue (Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>