<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12538_nm.21397" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21397" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21397" rank="species">Paenibacillus tianmuensis</organism><reference id="rid.12538"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus tianmuensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1133</fpage><lpage>1137</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024109-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543152</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus tianmuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus tianmuensis</em> (ti.an.mu.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>Tianmuensis</em> pertaining to Tianmu Mountain National Natural Reserve in Zhejiang Province, China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species description is based on two strains.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-negative, non-motile rods (0.75–1.5×3.0–7.5 µm).</s><s>No flagella are observed.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed at terminal or subterminal positions in swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 48 h on nutrient agar at 30 °C, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, flat, glossy, translucent and pale yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–37 °C, at pH 6–8 and with 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Oxidase is variable, depending on the growth stage.</s><s>Positive for catalase, β-galactosidase and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Negative for urease, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, Voges–Proskauer test, methyl red test and citrate utilization.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, DNA and gelatin are hydrolysed and starch is weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-ribose, d-galactose, d-glucose, methyl α-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol and turanose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from glycerol, cellobiose, starch and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β<em>-</em>d-xyloside, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The diamino acid in the cell wall is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.4–55.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B27<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22342<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 1.8946<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of Tianmu Mountain National Natural Reserve in Zhejiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>