<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3814_nm.12193" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12193" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2510" rank="species">Halomonas magadii</organism><reference id="rid.3814"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Duckworth</surname><given-names>A.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meijer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas magadii sp. nov., a new member of the genus Halomonas, isolated from a soda lake of the East African Rift Valley</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>53</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s007920050007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10741837</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas magadii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas magadii</i> (ma.ga'di.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>magadi</i> of Magadi, named for lake Magadi, a saline soda lake in Kenya)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gramnegative, non-spore-forming motile rods 4.0–6.0 x 0.6-0.8 μm.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase positive, circular, low, convex, opaque cream-colored colonies are formed on agar.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; growth occurs between pH 7.0 and 11.0 with an optimum around 9.5.</s><s>Halotolerant: able to grow at 0% to 20% salts.</s><s>Grows well between 25°C and 40°C with an optimum at 37°C.</s><s>Phosphatase and phenylalanine deaminase negative.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze starch, gelatin, or casein.</s><s>Indole not produced.</s><s>No anaerobic growth in the presence or absence of nitrate.</s><s>Nitrate reduced as far as nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S produced from cysteine.</s><s>Under alkaline conditions, amygdalin, D-cellobiose, esculin D-fructose, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, L-raffinose, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, starch, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, D-glucuronolactone, D-glucosamine, dulcitol, erythritol, ethanol, glycerol, D-mannitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, propanol, D-sorbitol, acetate, N-acetylglucosamine, propionide, quinate, D-saccharate, salicylate, suberate, succinate, tartrate, L-alanine, DL-arginine, L-asparagine, dlaspartic acid, DL-phenylalanine, L-glutamine, L-histidine, α-aminovalerate, aconitate, α-ketoglutarate, butyrate, caprylate, citrate, fumarate, DL-glycerate, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate, glutamate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, hippurate, DL-malate, malonate, oxalate, L-ornithine, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, DL-lysine, L-methionine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, L-tryptophan, L-valine, and pyruvate are metabolized, but not sarcosine, ethionine, creatine, dlaminobutyrate, Tween 80, inulin, or L-rhamnose.</s><s>Sensitive to erythromycin, streptomycin, polymyxin, sulphafurazole, chloramphenicol, and oleandomycin, but insensitive to gentamycin, sulphamethoxazole, kanamycin, nitrofurantoin, trimethoprim, fusidic acid, tetracyclin, rifampicin, bacitracin, ampicillin, penicillin G, methicillin, neomycin, novobiocin, and vancomycin.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidyl glycerol, phosphatidyl glycerol phosphate, diphosphatidyl glycerol, and phosphatidyl ethanolamine with a small amount of an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>Cells contain ubiquinones 6 and 9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the littoral sediments of Lake Magadi, Lake Nakuru, and Lake Bogoria, Kenya.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of the DNA is 62 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is 21M1, deposited at the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria Ltd., 23 St Machar Drive, Aberdeen, AB2 1RY as NCIMB 13595.</s></p></content></protolog>