<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8618_nm.13675" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13675" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13675" rank="species">Vibrio sinaloensis</organism><reference id="rid.8618"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomez-Gil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fajer-Avila</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roque</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio sinaloensis sp. nov., isolated from the spotted rose snapper, Lutjanus guttatus Steindachner, 1869.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1621</fpage><lpage>1624</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65719-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599705</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio sinaloensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio sinaloensis</em> (si.na.lo.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>sinaloensis</em> from the Mexican state of Sinaloa, the source of the first strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, curved bacilli that grow as bright-yellow colonies on TCBS agar, are not luminescent and do not swarm on marine agar or on TSA with 2.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0.35–9 % (w/v) NaCl; no growth without NaCl or with more than 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 15 and 37 °C but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth at 40 °C is variable, being negative for strains CAIM 695, CAIM 793 and CAIM 798.</s><s>Strains are sensitive to the vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10 and 150 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Positive for arginine dihydrolase (Thornley) and tryptophan deaminase (TDA) and negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases (Moeller).</s><s>Ferments glucose without gas formation; positive for ONPG, nitrate reduction, methyl red and gelatinase.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, starch, Tween 80, DNA and blood (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Negative for production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S; negative for citrate utilization, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and urease.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of alginate, agar and lecithin (except CAIM 793).</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as sole sources of carbon: 3-hydroxybutyrate, acetate (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>), cellobiose (weak reaction for most strains), citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>), d-glycerate (weak reaction), d-gluconate, d-glucose, d-mannitol (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup> and CAIM 792), d-mannose, d-ribose, trehalose, fumarate, glycerol (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>), glycine, l-glutamic acid, 4-amino-l-butyric acid, lactate, l-alanine, l-arginine (weak reaction), l-citrulline (weak reaction), l-histidine (except CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>; weak reaction for CAIM 792), l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-threonine, malate (weak reaction; negative for CAIM 752), maltose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, pyruvate, propionate, sucrose, succinate and <em>trans</em>-aconitate (weak reaction).</s><s>Negative for utilization of 2-ketoglutarate, l-aspartic acid, amygdalin, betaine, butyrate, d-galacturonate, d-glucuronate, d-sorbitol, d-xylose, lactose, l-arabinose, l-leucine (except CAIM 648, which presents a weak reaction), l-lysine, l-rhamnose, l-sarcosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol and putrescine.</s><s>Variable results are obtained for melibiose (weak reaction; negative for CAIM 797<sup>T</sup>, CAIM 695 and CAIM 792), salicin (positive for CAIM 750, CAIM 793 and CAIM 798) and l-ornithine (positive for CAIM 695, CAIM 750 and CAIM 792).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CAIM 797<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7298<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain and the reference strains CAIM 648, CAIM 694, CAIM 695, CAIM 750, CAIM 752, CAIM 792, CAIM 793 and CAIM 798 were isolated from cultured spotted rose snapper, <em>Lutjanus guttatus</em> Steindachner, 1869, in Mazatlán, Sinaloa state, Mexico.</s></p></content></protolog>