<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6403_nm.3815" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3815" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3815" rank="subspecies">Campylobacter sputorum mucosalis</organism><reference id="rid.6403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>G.H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leaver</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pettigrew</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rowland</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Some features of Campylobacter sputorum subsp. mucosalis subsp. nov., nom. rev. and their taxonomic significance.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>391</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-385</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>An examination of "<i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i>" strains derived from a variety of sources indicated that this taxon is homogeneous and that strain FS253/72 (=NCTC 11000) is representative of this group. The taxonomic positions of the other biochemically and serologically distinct catalase-negative vibrios isolated from pigs are less certain. We are in favor of retaining the name "<i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i>" for those organisms that can be demonstrated within the cells of adenomatosis lesions and for bacteria that cannot be distinguished from these organisms. Consequently, we propose that the name <i>Campylobacter sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> be revived for the same organism with which the name was associated when it was published originally by Lawson et al. (5, 7). The type strain is FS253/72 (=NCTC 11000). The separation of <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> from <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>sputorum</i> and <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>bubulus</i> can be achieved in the laboratory in most instances relatively easily by salt or glycine tolerance tests or by serological means (7). <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>bubulus</i> is glycine and salt tolerant, and <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>sputorum</i> is glycine tolerant, whereas "<i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> does not grow in 1% glycine but does grow in salt concentrations similar to those in which <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>sputorum</i> grows. Serological cross-reactions among these subspecies have not been reported.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The taxonomic positions of the human oral vibrios and of <i>V. succinogenes</i> are uncertain.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the DNAs of the oral vibrios and of <i>V. succinogenes</i> are between 48 and 50 mol% (15,17); this should exclude them from the genus Campylobacter, in which guanine-plus-cytosine contents are between 30 and 35 mol% (1).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of strains of oral vibrios originally identified as <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>sputorum</i> (9) have not been determined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>During its phase of intracellular parasitism, <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> is thought to multiply primarily within cells.</s><s>Ultrastructural studies of the parasitized mucosa fail to show a bacterial population outside and adjacent to the infected cells, and profiles of dividing bacteria can be seen within the cell cytoplasm (6).</s><s>Presumably, the energy necessary for such bacterial multiplication is derived from the host cells, and an understanding of this relationship may indicate how the bacteria influence a parasitized cell.</s><s>It is believed that hydrogen is produced within the alimentary tract in humans at levels which are detectable in breath.</s><s>The increase in respiratory hydrogen levels after eating indicates that the lower ileum may be the site of origin of this gas (2).</s><s>At the moment, whether hydrogen acts as an important electron donor during the intracellular growth of <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> is highly speculative. <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> can become established in the oral cavity, a site at which hydrogen is likely to be considerably less abundant, except possibly in microclimates.</s><s>This organism also becomes established in gnotobiotic piglets monocontaminated only by members of the genus Bacillus and can survive in the presence of tissue culture systems in which hydrogen enrichment of the gaseous phase is not used.</s><s>Both nitrate and nitrite are reduced by <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i>, and in this way this organism seems to be similar to <i>V. succinogenes</i>, which can grow in a medium in which formate and nitrate are the sole energy sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cytochrome <i>c<sub>553</sub></i> has been identified as the major cytochrome of <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i>.</s><s>The reducibility of this cytochrome by formate suggests that it may act in an electron transport chain concerned with formate oxidation that is similar to the chain present in other organisms (8).</s><s>However, in <i>E. coli</i> and <i>V. succinogenes</i> the electron acceptor for formate dehydrogenase is a type b cytochrome rather than a type c cytochrome (3), and indeed rather few low-spin type c cytochromes are known that have redox potentials comparable to those found in type b cytochromes (12).</s><s>The best-characterized low-spin, low-potential, type c cytochrome is cytochrome c<sub>3</sub> of the sulfate-reducing bacteria.</s><s>However, <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> cytochrome <i>c<sub>553</sub></i> is spectroscopically distinct from these cytochromes in that it has a relatively low soret reduced/soret oxidized spectroscopic ratio and no indication of a weak shoulder to the short wavelength side of the soret reduced peak (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A further comparison of the <i>C. sputorum</i> subsp. <i>mucosalis</i> cytochrome with other type c cytochromes (such as the low-potential cytochrome <i>c<sub>553</sub></i> found in some sulfate-reducing bacteria) would be premature and must await the purification of this cytochrome.</s></p></content></protolog>