<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10097_nm.15051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15051" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15051" rank="species">Polynucleobacter cosmopolitanus</organism><reference id="rid.10097"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Q.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polynucleobacter cosmopolitanus sp. nov., free-living planktonic bacteria inhabiting freshwater lakes and rivers</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>166</fpage><lpage>173</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010595-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Polynucleobacter cosmopolitanus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Polynucleobacter cosmopolitanus</em> (cos.mo.po.li′ta.nus. Gr. adj. <em>kosmopolites</em> an inhabitant of the world, a cosmopolitan; N.L. masc. adj. <em>cosmopolitanus</em> cosmopolitan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Curved, non-motile rods, 0.5–1.4 μm in length and 0.3–0.5 μm in width.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic strains, at least some of the strains are able to grow anaerobically.</s><s>Can be cultivated on NSY, R2A, and Bacto peptone media, and some other complex media at concentrations of ≤3 g l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Colonies grown on NSY agar are unpigmented, circular and convex with smooth surfaces and reach a diameter of 1 mm after 5–10 days at 20−24 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C, four strains also grow at 5 °C and two strains are able to grow at 38 °C.</s><s>Grows without NaCl.</s><s>Maximum NaCl concentration tolerated is strain dependent and ranges from 0.3 to 0.5 % (w/v).</s><s>Utilizes acetate, pyruvate, propionate, oxaloacetate, malate, succinate, fumarate, d-galacturonic acid, d-galactose, l-cysteine and l-alanine when these substrates are provided in a medium containing low amounts of NSY.</s><s>None of the strains utilize formate, glycolate, oxalate, d-lyxose, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-aspartate, l-serine, l-asparagine or betaine.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>No 2-hydroxylated compounds are detected.</s><s>Fractions of natural populations pass through 0.2 μm filters.</s><s>Can be distinguished from <em>P. necessarius</em> by using the <em>P. necessarius</em>-specific FISH probe PnecC-16S-445 (Hahn <em>et al.</em>, 2009), as well as by differences in fatty acid profiles (Table 3).</s><s>In contrast to <em>P. necessarius</em>, exclusively free-living strains and no endosymbiotic strains are reported, however, the existence of endosymbiotic strains cannot be completely excluded at present.</s><s>Tentatively, all strains possessing the oligonucleotide sequence 5′-AA(T/G)CCCT(A/T)AGGGGGAAA-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 181–197) within the 16S rRNA gene shall be assigned to the proposed species.</s><s>In almost all cases (with one known exception), the presence of this diagnostic sequence can be determined by FISH with a mixture of the two probes PnecD1-181 and PnecD2-181 (Hahn <em>et al.</em>, 2005).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MWH-MoIso2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21490<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109840<sup>T</sup>=LMG 25212<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the water column (pelagic zone) of Lake Mondsee located in the Salzkammergut Lake District in Austria (Hahn, 2003).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.9 %.</s><s>Four other reference strains are available: MWH-CaK1 (=DSM 21494), MWH-VicM1 (=DSM 21486); MWH-TaW3 (=DSM 21487) and MWH-NZ8W13 (=DSM 21488).</s></p></content></protolog>