<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1239_nm.8252" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8252" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8252" rank="species">Flexibacter canadensis</organism><reference id="rid.1239"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flexibacter canadensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>429</fpage><lpage>432</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Flexibacter canadensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flexibacter canadensis</i> (ca na denásis. M.L. adj. <i>canadensis</i>,of Canada, source of the soil from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonflagellated, flexible, thin rods or filaments measuring 0.3 by 3 to 60 μm and showing gliding motility and good spreading ability on many dilute media such as Cook cytophaga agar and skim milk-acetate agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Cook cytophaga agar: 5-Day-old colonies are white with a pale blue-green iridescence, irregular with a rough surface and lobate edge, and effuse and transparent with no water-soluble pigment.</s><s>The Munsell color of the colonies is 2.5 Y 8/2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Skim milk-acetate agar: 5-Day-old colonies are whitish with a blue-green iridescence, irregular with a rough surface and lobate edge, and effuse and transparent to opaque with no watersoluble pigment.</s><s>The Munsell color of the colonies is 10 YR 8/2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Plate count agar: 5-Day-old colonies are very pale pinkish gray with a blue-green iridescence, irregular with a smooth surface and lobate edge, effuse to raised and translucent to opaque with no water-soluble pigment.</s><s>The Munsell color of the colonies is 2.5 YR 6/3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Munsell colors observed on various media are 2.5 YR 6/3, 6 YR 6/4,7.5 YR 6/4 and 7/2, 10 YR 7-8/2 and 7/3, and 2.5 Y 7-8/2; no water soluble pigment has ever been observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth culture: Overnight growth in a shaken culture is silky but not viscous or flocculent; there is no surface ring or pellicle produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fruiting bodies and microcysts are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Growth is reduced by 1% and is inhibited by 2% NaCl; the preferred atmosphere for growth is 10% O2; the temperature range is 10 to 40°C, optimum growth occurring at 18 to 30°C; the pH range for growth is 5 to 10, optimum growth occurring at pH 6 to 8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>, glutamate, asparaginate, and various proteins and protein digests (e.g., tryptone, Casitone, gelatin, casein), but not N0<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> or urea, are utilized as sole N sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is stimulated by yeast extract on media containing agar only or chitin and agar only.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is not reduced by 0.01% but is inhibited by 0.1% sodium lauryl sulfate.</s><s>The organism is susceptible to 30 μg of chloramphenicol, 10 μg of dihydrostreptomycin, 300 U ofpolymyxin B, and actinomycin D; it is resistant to 10 U of penicillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacteria and fungi are not lysed, but the possible lysis of actinomycete strain UASM 4441 and of a Chlorella sp. culture was noted.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions.</s><s>The attack on glucose is both oxidative and fermentative.</s><s>Acid is produced from lactose, glucose, cellobiose, and glycerol but not from sucrose or mannitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipolytic activity on tributyrin and on Tweens 20, 40, 60, and 80 has not been detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes starch; weakly hydrolyzes pectate; does not hydrolyze cellulose (filter paper or carboxymethyl cellulose), chitin, agar, or alginate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Liquefies gelatin; peptonizes milk in 2 days; growth and NH<sub>4</sub> produced from Casitone, casein, Casamino Acids, and Penassay broths; grows well on 0.2% tryptone; produces growth but no hemolysis on sheep blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, deoxyribonuclease, catalase, oxidase, and phosphatase are produced; the indole, methyl red, Voges-Proskauer, and citrate tests are negative;there is no growth on McConkey or eosin methylene blue.</s><s>Reduces (denitrifies) NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> and N0<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> to gaseous form; however, much NH<sub>4</sub> is present, the significance of which is under investigation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine plus cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of the deoxYribonucleic acid is 37.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>