<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1771_nm.8026" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8026" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8026" rank="species">Porphyromonas circumdentaria</organism><reference id="rid.1771"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collings</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Briscoe</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Porphyromonas circumdentaria sp. nov. and reassignment of Bacteroides salivosus (Love, Johnson, Jones, and Calverley 1987) as Porphyromonas (Shah and Collins 1988) salivosa comb. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>434</fpage><lpage>438</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-434</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503973</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas circumdentaria</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas circumdentaria</i> (cir.cum.den.ta'ri.a. L. adj. <i>circum</i>, around, about; L. adj. <i>dentaria</i>, pertaining to the teeth; L. adj. <i>circumdentaria</i>, referring to the isolation of organisms from the vicinity of the teeth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, nonsporing, nonmotile, gram-negative rods or coccoid forms.</s><s>In cooked meat-carbohydrate medium (11) and on sheep blood agar plates, cells are 0.3 to 0.6 by 0.8 to 1.5 μm and occur singly and in groups; occasionally filaments up to 10 μm long are present.</s><s>On sheep blood agar plates, surface colonies after 72 h are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, dome shaped, opaque, and greenish brown, changing to creamy brown by day 7.</s><s>By day 14, colonies are brown to black.</s><s>Both colony size and pigment formation are enhanced by growth in the presence of <i>S. epidemidis</i>.</s><s>Colonies exhibit a brick red fluorescence (at 265 nm) after 24 h, which persists up to day 7.</s><s>After incubation at 37°C for 48 h in prereduced broth, cultures exhibit a heavy uniform gelatinous to ropy turbidity.</s><s>Vitamin K and hemin are required for growth.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days, the pH values of media containing a fermentable carbohydrate generally range from 6.3 to 6.5 in all of the media tested.</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentation is not detected in media containing adonitol, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation products in cooked meat-carbohydrate medium are acetic acid (average concentration, 24.5 μmol/ml), butyric acid (average concentration, 35.5 μmol/ml), and isovaleric acid (average concentration, 21.6 μmol/ml).</s><s>Smaller quantities of propionic acid (average concentration, 1.0 μmol/ml), isobutyric acid (average concentration, 8.5 μmol/ml), succinic acid (average concentration, 8.4 μmol/ml), and phenylacetic acid (average concentration, 6.7 μg/ml) are produced.</s><s>Neither lactate nor pyruvate is utilized, and threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>Strains are catalase positive, produce ammonia, liquefy gelatin, and are indole positive.</s><s>Strains produce acid and alkaline phosphatase and small amounts of naphthol as β-1-phosphate.</s><s>Cells do not hemagglutinate sheep, horse, or pig  rythrocytes or produce trypsinlike activity.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, urea is not split, and esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Malate dehydrogenase and glutamate dehydrogenase are present; 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase and glucose 6-phosphate dehydrogenase are absent.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids consist predominantly of 13-methyltetradecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> acid), and there are smaller amounts of the acids shown in Table 1.</s><s>In transmission electron micrographs thin sections of cells reveal a typical gram-negative cell wall, and large numbers of long (up to 0.4-μm), thin, peritrichous fimbriae are observed with negative stains (3).</s><s>Outer membrane vesicles are numerous at the cell surface and in the medium (Fig. 1), and a capsule or slime layer up to 0.5 μm thick is present in preparations from plates and from broth cultures (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains were isolated from soft-tissue infections (abscesses and empyemas), gingival margins, and gingival plaques of felines.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 40 to 42 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation method (14).</s><s>Members of the species exhibit an average intraspecies DNA-DNA homology level of 98%, and strain VPB 3325 exhibited average DNA-DNA homology levels of 9, 16, 11, and 4% with <i>Porphyromonas gingivalis</i> ATCC 33277<sup>T</sup>, <i>Porphyromonas salivosa</i> comb. nov., <i>Porphyromonas gingivalis</i> subsp. <i>felis</i>, and <i>Porphyromonas asaccharolytica</i> ATCC 25269<sup>T</sup>, respectively, and did not react in dot blot hybridization assays with <i>Porphyromonas endodontalis</i> ATCC 35406<sup>T</sup> or the representatives of the genera <i>Bacteroides</i>, <i>Prevotella</i>, <i>Fusobactenum</i>, and <i>Eubacterium</i> included in the assays.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 12469 (= VPB 3329).</s></p></content></protolog>