<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6647_nm.913" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.913" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.913" rank="species">Gluconacetobacter azotocaptans</organism><reference id="rid.6647"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fuentes-Ramírez</surname><given-names>L.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bustillos-Cristales</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tapia-Hernández</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiménez-Salgado</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caballero-Mellado</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel nitrogen-fixing acetic acid bacteria, Gluconacetobacter johannae sp. nov. and Gluconacetobacter azotocaptans sp. nov., associated with coffee plants.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1305</fpage><lpage>1314</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491326</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gluconacetobacter azotocaptans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gluconacetobacter azotocaptans</i> (a.zo.to.cap'tans. N.L. n. <i>azotum</i> nitrogen; L. part. adj. <i>captans</i> catching; N.L. adj. <i>azotocaptans</i> nitrogen-catching, referring to the ability to assimilate atmospheric nitrogen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods with rounded ends, approximately 1.6-2 μm long and 0.5-0.6 μm wide, and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Isolates are Gram-negative, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 29°C, but not at 37°C, in LGI liquid medium at pH 4-7.</s><s>Colonies on potato agar with 5, 10 or 15%cane sugar are beige or very light-brownish, even after 10 d.</s><s>Strains are aerobic and fix atmospheric nitrogen microaerophilically, even in the presence of 10 mM nitrate.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrite, but isolates grow well with ammonium.</s><s>Regardless of the presence of growth factors from yeast extract, very few carbon sources support growth.</s><s>Strains grow and produce abundant acid on sucrose, D-glucose and L-fructose and grow in 30% D-glucose or sucrose.</s><s>Ethanol is oxidized to acetic acid and acetate and lactate are oxidized to CO<sub>2</sub> and water.</s><s>Isolates grow on 0.1 and 0.5% ethanol, but not with 0.1 or 0.5% methanol.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0.25 and 0.5% NaCl, but not with 1.0% NaCl, in LGI liquid medium.</s><s>Single amino acids cannot be used as sole sources of carbon and nitrogen.</s><s>Characteristics that differentiate this species from other N<sub>2</sub>-fixing acetobacteria are shown in Table 2.</s><s>This species can be differentiated from other N<sub>2</sub>-fixing acetobacteria by ARDRA patterns, in addition to DNA-DNA reassociation data, and by means of PCR analysis using specific primers.</s><s>Strain CFN-Ca54<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700988<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13594<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain and has a G+C content of 64.01 mol%.</s><s>This strain was recovered from the rhizospheres of coffee plants.</s></p></content></protolog>