<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3451_nm.6576" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6576" rank="genus">Catenuloplanes</organism><reference id="rid.3451"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catenuloplanes crispus (Petrolini et al. 1993) comb. nov.: incorporation of the genus Planopolyspora Petrolini 1993 into the genus Catenuloplanes Yokota et al. 1993 with an amended description of the genus Catenuloplanes.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1853</fpage><lpage>1860</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1853</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555369</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Catenuloplanes</i> Yokota <i>et al</i>. 1993</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The amended description below is based on data from Yokota <i>et al</i>. (1993), Petrolini <i>et al</i>. (1993a) and this study. Aerobic, Gram-positive and non-acid-fast. Forms non-fragmenting and branched vegetative hyphae. Aerial mycelium is rudimentarily developed or absent. Spores, if produced, are arranged in chains, which arise from the vegetative hyphae or are formed on the rudimentary aerial hyphae. The spore chains are aggregated into clusters and may be enveloped by outer sheaths. The configuration of spore chains is curly or spiral with one or two turns and sometimes branched, The spores are rod-shaped, straight or curved with smooth surfaces, and become motile by peritrichous flagella after release into water. The cell wall peptidoglycan contains glycine, D-glutamate, L-lysine, D-alanine and L-serine in a ratio of 1:1:1:0.8:1 and lacks diaminopimelic acid. The muramic acid in the glycan moiety is N-glycolated. The whole-cell hydrolysate contains xylose, mannose, glucose and ribose, and lacks madurose. The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-11(H<sub>4</sub>) and, in some strains, MK-10, MK- 10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-11(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-11(H<sub>6</sub>) are also present as minor components. The diagnostic phospholipid is phosphatidylcholine. The cellular fatty acid was composed of hexadecanoic, octadecanoic, octadecenoic and 14-methylhexadecanoic acids. Hexadecenoic, heptadecanoic and 14-methylpentadecanoic acids are also detected as major components in some strains. Mycolic acids are absent. The G + C content of the DNA is 70-72 mol%. The type species is <i>Catenuloplanes japonicus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>