<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10579_nm.17829" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17829" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17829" rank="species">Cobetia crustatorum</organism><reference id="rid.10579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cobetia crustatorum sp. nov., a novel slightly halophilic bacterium isolated from traditional fermented seafood in Korea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>620</fpage><lpage>626</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008847-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cobetia crustatorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cobetia crustatorum</em> (cru.sta.to′rum. N.L. part. n. <em>crustatus</em> crustated; N.L. gen. pl. n. <em>crustatorum</em> of shellfish).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-negative and slightly halophilic micro-organism.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.6–1.5 μm in length, 0.6 μm in width, and generally observed as single cells or pairs.</s><s>Cells have 2–5 peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are less than 3 mm in diameter, round, glistening, raised and cream-coloured.</s><s>Grows under a range of conditions: 4–30 °C; 3.5–11.5 % salts; and pH 5.0–10.0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25 °C, at pH 5.0–6.0 and in 6.5 % salts.</s><s>Cells produce exopolysaccharide and accumulate PHB.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses l-tyrosine, DNA and ONPG, but not casein, starch, gelatin, urea or Tweens (80 and 20).</s><s>Oxidative metabolism occurs from d-glucose; indole is not produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are not produced.</s><s>The Simmons citrate, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, phenylalanine deaminase, and hydrogen sulfide production from l-cysteine are negative.</s><s>Respiration on fumarate, nitrate and nitrite is negative.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate to nitrite under aerobic conditions is negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, cellobiose, maltose and d-fucose, but not from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose, sucrose and trehalose in API 50 CH strips, but not erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 MicroPlates, metabolizes l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, turanose, glycerol, d-gluconic acid, lactulose, d-psicose, Tween 80, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, but not glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, xylitol, d-arabinose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, inulin, melezitose, starch, d-tagatose, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and polymyxin B (300 IU).</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JO1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22486<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15644<sup>T</sup>), isolated from ‘Jogae jeotgal’, a type of traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>