<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7263_nm.1178" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1178" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1178" rank="species">Sphingomonas chungbukensis</organism><reference id="rid.7263"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic assignment of an aromatic-degrading Pseudomonas sp., strain DJ77, in the genus Sphingomonas as Sphingomonas chungbukensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1641</fpage><lpage>1647</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939671</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas chungbukensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingomonas chungbukensis</i> (chung.bu.ken'sis. M.L. adj. <i>chungbukensis</i> named after Chungbuk National University)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, mesophilic, asporogenous, curved rods.</s><s>The cell size is 0.5-1x1.5-3 μm.</s><s>Produces visible, circular, smooth, yellow colonies on TSA in 2-3 d.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are positive.</s><s>Indole, urease, β-galactosidase and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>Utilizes a variety of aromatic compounds including biphenyl, naphthalene, phenanthrene, phenol, salicylate, <i>p</i>-cresol, <i>m</i>-xylene, toluene and benzoate.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, larabinose, α-D-glucose, maltose, D-sorbitol, methylpyruvate, formic acid, D-gluconate, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-keto-butyric acid, DL-lactic acid, alaninamide, L-alanyl-glycine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid and L-proline.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated: glucose, L-arabinose, mannose, maltose, gluconate, D-xylose, galactose, D-fructose, aesculin, amidon, D-lyxose and D-fucose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are octadecenoic, 2-hydroxymyristic, cis-9 hexadecenoic and hexadecanoic acids.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone 10.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 63 mol%. <i>Sphingomonas chungbukensis</i> is distinct from its phylogenetic neighbours, namely <i>S. chlorophenolica</i>, <i>S. herbicidovorans</i> and <i>S. yanoikuyae</i>, by low levels of DNA-DNA reassociation, by its ability to produce a great quantity of extracellular polysaccharide and by exhibiting different physiological characteristics.</s><s>Isolated from chemically contaminated freshwater sediment in Taejon, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The type strain of the species is DJ77<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 2955<sup>T</sup>=IMSNU 11152<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>