<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3462_nm.6669" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6669" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6669" rank="species">Marmoricola aurantiacus</organism><reference id="rid.3462"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urzì</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salamone</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marmoricola aurantiacus gen. nov., sp. nov., a coccoid member of the family Nocardioidaceae isolated from a marble statue</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>536</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758857</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Marmoricola aurantiacus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Marmoricola aurantiacus</i> (au.ran.ti'a.cus. M.L. adj. <i>aurantiacus</i> orange-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical occurring singly, in pairs, tetrads and small clusters (0.5-0.7 μm in diameter).</s><s>Nonmotile and non-sporulating.</s><s>No rod/coccus life cycle.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, entire, orange-pigmented, shiny and smooth (2-5 mm in diameter).</s><s>They can become rough and shaped like craters in old cultures.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>No acid production is observed from D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, lactose, D-cellobiose, D-trehalose, D-raffinose, glycerol, D-mannitol or <i>myo</i>-inositol.</s><s>Casein and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Xanthine and tyrosine are not decomposed; hypoxanthine is decomposed.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, Tween 80 is only weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>DNA is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The strain does not grow in the following media: CZ, YMS-Glc, YCSGlc, YG-Glyc, Y-Glyc, agar-H<sub>2</sub>O and M53.</s><s>Growth occurs in Luedemann, PDA and BHIA media.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains LL-A<sub>2</sub>pm as characteristic diamino acid and a single glycine residue as interpeptide bridge (type A3γ).</s><s>The acyl type is acetyl.</s><s>Phospholipids are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile consists of straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated components and TBSA as the only branched chain fatty acid.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetically, it is a member of the family <i>Nocardioidaceae</i>.</s><s>The only known isolation site is a Carrara marble statue (Wagmüller's monument) located in the Nordfriedhof Cemetery in Munich, Germany.</s><s>The type strain is strain BC 361<sup>T</sup> (bacterial collection of the Institute of Microbiology, Messina).</s><s>It has been deposited in the DSMZ - German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures GmbH as strain DSM 12652<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>