<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3222_nm.5777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5777" rank="species">Actinomyces catuli</organism><reference id="rid.3222"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henderson</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces catuli sp. nov., from dogs</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>679</fpage><lpage>682</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces catuli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces catuli</i> (ca'tu.li. L. masc. n. <i>catulus</i> small dog; L. masc. gen. n. <i>catuli</i> of a small dog)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods which stain Gram-positive, are non-acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are tiny, irregular, convex, white and adherent to medium at colony base.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-variable.</s><s>End products of glucose metabolism are acetic, lactic (major) and succinic acids.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose, maltose, lactose, D-raffinose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, mannitol, melezitose, pullulan, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from L-arabinose, melibiose and methyl β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin and hippurate are not.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, ester lipase C8, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and pyrazinamidase are produced.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, valine arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Activities for arginine dihydrolase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, esterase C4 and agalactosidase may or may not be detected.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Isolated from dogs.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 41709<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106507<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>