<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2208" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2208" rank="genus">Xanthomonas</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Xanthomonas</i> Dowson 1939</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on the phenotypic description of Bradbury (7), as revised by Van den Mooter and Swings (46) and Palleroni and Bradbury (36), as well as the results of Yang et al. (58, 60), Auling et al. (2), and this study. G+C content data were obtained from the studies of De Vos and De Ley (14), Vera Cruz et al. (53), Van den Mooter et al. (44,45), and Vauterin et al. (50; this study).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Xanthomonads are plant pathogens or are associated with plants.</s><s>Most xanthomonad strains form yellow mucoid smooth colonies.</s><s>The yellow pigments are mono- or dibromo arylpolyenes called xanthomonadins (l), which are characteristic of the genus.</s><s>The exopolysaccharide xanthan, which is responsible for the mucoid or viscous cultures, is typical of the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram-negative rods which are 0.4 to 0.6 by 1.0 to 2.9 μm.</s><s>They occur mostly alone or in pairs, but chains occur as well.</s><s>Filamentous cells are occasionally seen.</s><s>Cells are usually motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is present, but urease and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Oxidase is absent or only weakly reactive.</s><s>Acetoin is not formed.</s><s>Litmus milk is not acidified.</s><s>There is no growth at pH 4.5 or at 4 or 37°C.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 6% NaCl, 30% glucose, 0.01% methyl green, 0.01% thionin, 0.01% lead acetate, or 0.1% triphenyl tetrazoliumchloride.</s><s>Strains are usually susceptible to erythromycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Small amounts of acid are produced from many carbohydrates but not from L-rhamnose, adonitol, sorbose, D-sorbitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, or <i>meso</i>-inositol.</s><s>Glycine, L-glutamine, and L-asparagine are not utilized as sole carbon and nitrogen sources. <i>Xanthomonas</i> strains are chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>One or more growth factors may be required.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Xanthomonas</i> strains contain the following nine fatty acids: 11:0 iso, 11:0 iso 3OH, 12:0 3OH, 13:0 iso 3OH, 15:0 iso, 16:1 cis-9, 16:0, 17:1 iso F, and 17:0 iso.</s><s>Among these fatty acids, 11:0 iso, 11:0 iso 3OH, and 13:0 iso 3OH are characteristic of the genus and are useful criteria for differentiating <i>Xanthomonus</i> strains from other bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Xanthomonus</i> strains contain spermidine as the major polyamine.</s><s>Spermine is usually present in detectable amounts, whereas 2-hydroxyputrescine, 1,3-diaminopropane, and putrescine are never present.</s><s>Some strains contain cadaverine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As determined by the Biolog GN microplate test, the following carbon compounds are oxidized by at least 94% of the strains (and thus these reactions are characteristic of the genus): D-fructose, α-D-glucose, D-mannose, methylpyruvate, and α-ketoglutaric acid.</s><s>The following carbon compounds are not oxidized by more than 94% of the strains: α-cyclodextrin, adonitol, D-arabitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, xylitol, D-glucosaminic acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, sebacic acid, L-ornithine, L-pyroglutamic acid, D-serine, DL-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, phenyl ethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, and 2,3 butanediol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of members of the genus range from 63.3 to 69.7 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Xanthomonas campestris</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>