<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5865_nm.11821" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11821" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6294" rank="species">Gordona hirsuta</organism><reference id="rid.5865"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Klatte</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altendorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordona hirsuta sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>876</fpage><lpage>880</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-876</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863412</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordona hirsuta</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gordona hirsuta</i> (hir.su'ta. L. adj. <i>hirsuta</i>, shaggy, rough, referring to the rough surface of the colonies)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile, strictly aerobic rods that grow amycelially.</s><s>White to light yellow colonies with irregular margins and flat, rough surfaces are formed on various media.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Hydrolyzes pNβ-phosphorylcholine, but not 2-deoxythymidine-5'-pNβ-phosphatea nd pNβ-β-D-xyloside.</s><s>As determined by MTT reduction, D-galactose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, and 2-oxoglutarate are metabolized, but N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, gluconate, D-glucosaminic acid, citrate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, 2-hydroxyvalerate, phenylacetic acid, pimelate, succinate, quinate, L-alanine, L-aspartate, L-leucine, L-serine, L-proline, L-valine, putrescine, tyramine, D-ribose, D-sucrose, D-turanose, D-arabitol, L-rhamnose, glucarate, and acetamide are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall type is of wall chemotype IV sensu Lechevalier and Lechevalier; <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid is the only diamino acid, arabinose and galactose are major cell wall sugars, and N-glycolated muramic acid moieties of peptidoglycan are present, The predominant menaquinone is menaquinone MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are composed of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Contains major amounts of straight-chain, saturated and unsaturated fatty acids and tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids with 60 to 64 carbon atoms are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 69 mol% (as determined by the HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain was isolated from the packing material (tree bark compost) of a large-scale biofilter used for deodorization of animal-rendering emissions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain K718a (= DSMZ 44140<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>