<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1439_nm.874" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.874" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.874" rank="species">Acetobacter methanolicus</organism><reference id="rid.1439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Uhlig</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karbaum</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steudel</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acetobacter methanolicus sp. nov., an acidophilic facultatively methylotrophic bacterium</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>322</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-317</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetobacter methanolicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetobacter methanolicus</i> (meth. a.nó. li. cus. Lat. n. <i>methanolum</i> methanol; L. adj. <i>methanolicus</i> methanolic, using methanol as a sole carbon source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells ellipsoidal to rod shaped (0.6 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 1.8 μm) and occur singly, in pairs, or rarely in short chains.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Usually motile and peritrichously flagellated.</s><s>Resting stages are not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on methanol-containing mineral agar are circular with entire margins, slightly convex, and weakly glistening, have a moist and smeary consistency, and are white to pale yellowish (rarely pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature optimum, 30 to 32°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at pH values of &#x003C;6.5; optimum pH, 4.0 to 4.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism respiratory, never fermentative.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not formed.</s><s>Methanol is incorporated via the fructose biphosphate variant of the hexulose monophosphate pathway.</s><s>Enzymes of the tricarboxylic acid cycle are present.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction with lactate is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth at pH 4.0 to 5.4 on methanol, glucose, gluconate, glycerol, caproic acid, 2,3-butanediol, and succinic acid.</s><s>Weak to very weak growth on ethanol, acetate, fumaric acid, propionate, pyruvate, and glyoxylate.</s><s>No growth on lactate.</s><s>The utilization of fructose and mannitol by strains differs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ammonium and nitrates are utilized as sole sources of nitrogen in the presence of growth factors when methanol, glucose, and other carbon compounds are used as carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pantothenic acid or yeast extract is required as a growth factor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ethanol is oxidized to acetic acid, but oxidation to CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O occurs only at initial ethanol concentrations of &#x003C;0.5%; lactate is oxidized very weakly.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is formed from glucose, galactose, xylose, L-arabinose, mannose, melibiose, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, and amylalcohol.</s><s>On mannitol different strains produce different reactions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ketogenesis from glycerol (weak), but not from sorbitol and mannitol; 2-, 5-, or 2,5-ketogluconic acid, γ-pyrones, and brown pigments are not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ubiquinone type, Q<sub>10</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, except for the characteristics shown in Table 4.</s><s>The color of the colonies is white to pale yellow.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 62.3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the new species, strain MB58, has been deposited with the Culture Collection of the Institute of Microbiology and Experimental Therapy (IMET) of the Academy of Science of the German Democratic Republic, Jena, as strain IMET 10945<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>