<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3521_nm.6622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6622" rank="species">Propionibacterium microaerophilum</organism><reference id="rid.3521"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Koussémon</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Combet-Blanc</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionibacterium microaerophilum sp. nov., a microaerophilic bacterium isolated from olive mill wastewater</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1373</fpage><lpage>1382</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491335</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionibacterium microaerophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionibacterium microaerophilum</i> (mi.cro.ae.ro'phi.lum. Gr. adj. <i>mikros</i> small, Gr. n. <i>aer</i> air ; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; N.L. neut. adj. <i>microaerophilum</i> slightly air-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on agar plates (basal medium) incubated under an atmosphere ofN<sub>2</sub>/O<sub>2</sub> (95:5%, v/v) are white and lens-shaped with smooth edges and 2-3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, pleomorphic rods with rounded ends, non-motile, non-spore-forming, facultatively anaerobic, microaerophilic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Although growth occurs under anaerobic and aerobic conditions, the optimum O<sub>2</sub> concentration for growth is 5% in the gas phase of the culture.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The strain requires no complex nitrogen nutrients such as yeast extract, amino acids or peptides for growth and can grow with ammonium salts as the only nitrogen source.</s><s>However, yeast extract stimulates growth.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, large amounts of propionate, acetate and CO<sub>2</sub> are produced from glucose or lactate fermentation.</s><s>Lactate, formate and succinate can also be detected from glucose fermentation, depending on the pH or the medium composition.</s><s>Neutrophilic and mesophilic.</s><s>The pH for growth ranges from 4.5 to 9.5, with optimum growth at 7.0.</s><s>The temperature for growth ranges from 20 to 45 °C, with optimum growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The DNA G­C content is 67.7±0.6 mol%.</s><s>Results of 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis indicate that the isolate is related to members of genus <i>Propionibacterium</i> and is closely related to <i>P. acidipropionici</i> (97.5% similarity).</s><s>DNA-DNA hybridization with this species showed 56% reassociation.</s><s>Isolated from the decantation reservoir of olive mill wastewater of an olive oil factory in Raphèle-les-Arles (south of France).</s><s>The type strain is M5<sup>T</sup> (=CNCM I-2360<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13435<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>