<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2013_nm.10678" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10678" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10678" rank="species">Corynebacterium ureicelerivorans</organism><reference id="rid.2013"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium ureicelerivorans sp. nov., a lipophilic bacterium isolated from blood culture.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1200</fpage><lpage>1203</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64832-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium ureicelerivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium ureicelerivorans</em> (u.re.i.ce.le.ri.vo′rans. N.L. fem. n. <em>urea</em> urea; L. adj. <em>celer</em> -<em>eris</em> fast; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>ureicelerivorans</em> fast urea-devouring, referring to the rapid utilization of urea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods.</s><s>Colonies are creamy, circular, dry and approximately 0.1–0.3 mm in diameter on Columbia blood agar after 48 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies are non-haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>The organism is lipophilic.</s><s>Urea (positive reaction in approx. 60 s) and hippurate are hydrolysed, but aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Weak acid production is observed from ribose and d-xylose in the API Coryne and API 20 Strep systems (incubation time, 3 days).</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-raffinose.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are detected: alkaline and acid phosphatases, ester lipase C8, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, leucine arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and pyrazinamidase.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are not detected: arginine dihydrolase, esterase C4, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Positive for acetoin production.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>Long-chain fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types, with C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> predominating; tuberculostearic acid is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMMIB RIV-2301<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45051<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53377<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from blood culture from a patient with signs of septicaemia.</s></p></content></protolog>