<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1493_nm.6043" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6043" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6043" rank="species">Microbacterium dextranolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.1493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of two new species in the genus Microbacterium: Microbacterium dextranolyticum sp. nov. and Microbacterium aurum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>549</fpage><lpage>554</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium dextranolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium dextranolyticum</i> (dex.tra.no.ly'ti.cum. Engl. n. <i>dextran</i>, polysaccharide produced by bacteria; Gr. adj. <i>lyticum</i>, dissolving; <i>dextranolyticum</i>, dextran dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on solid media in air; colonies are 2 to 4 mm in diameter, circular, low convex with entire margins, opaque, and moist.</s><s>A yellow pigment is produced.</s><s>In young cultures, small, slender rods are formed.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at angles, forming V shapes; primary branching is uncommon.</s><s>In older cultures rods are shorter, but a marked rod-coccus growth cycle does not occur.</s><s>Gram-positive rods that are not acid fast and not motile.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is ca. 30°C.</s><s>Good aerobic growth.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from glucose, mannose, fructose, maltose, cellobiose, mannitol, xylose, L-arabinose, galactose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, inulin, arbutin, esculin, ethanol, butanol, melibiose, and melezitose, but not from ribose, D-arabinose, L-sorbose, xylitol, erythritol, adonitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, inositol, methanol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, starch, glycerol, and salicin.</s><s>Pyruvate, fumarate, and succinate are assimilated, but acetate, lactate, malate, α-ketoglutarate, maleate, formate, butyrate, oxalate, pimelate, glycolate, glyoxylate, gluconate, propionate, and hippurate are not assimilated.</s><s>Esculin, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed, but gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer reaction positive.</s><s>Arginine is not decarboxylated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains L-lysine as the diamino acid (variation B1α).</s><s>The glycan moiety of the cell wall contains glycolyl and acetyl residues.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are rhamnose, 6-deoxytalose, galactose, and glucose.</s><s>Mycolic acid is not present.</s><s>The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are primarily anteiso- and iso-methyl branched acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>Unsaturated menaquinones with 11 and 12 isoprene units are present.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and dimannosyldiacylglycerol; an unknown monoglycosyldiacylglycerol and phosphoglycolipid are also present.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 68.3 mol% G+C.</s><s>Source: isolated from soil (8, 13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IFO 14592.</s></p></content></protolog>