<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2246_nm.9507" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9507" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9507" rank="species">Atopococcus tabaci</organism><reference id="rid.2246"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiernik</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Atopococcus tabaci gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel Gram-positive, catalase-negative, coccus-shaped bacterium isolated from tobacco</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1693</fpage><lpage>1696</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63618-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014503</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Atopococcus tabaci</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Atopococcus tabaci</em> (ta.ba′ci. N.L. gen. neut. n. <em>tabaci</em> of/from tobacco).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s><em>α</em>-Haemolytic on horse blood agar.</s><s>Grows aerobically but not under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature on tryptic soy agar is 30 °C.</s><s>Halotolerant, growing in 8–9 % NaCl.</s><s>Using API test kits, acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, ribose, sucrose and trehalose but not from l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, sorbitol, tagatose or d-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin and hippurate are hydrolysed but not gelatin.</s><s>Activity is detected for acid phosphatase, esterase C4, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Activity may or may not be detected for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and urease.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, chymotrypsin, trypsin, phosphoamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl trytophan arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-mannosidase are not detected.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and the Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>The predominant long-chain fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 48253<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108502<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from moist powdered tobacco.</s></p></content></protolog>