<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.986_nm.1681" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1681" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1681" rank="species">Ralstonia paucula</organism><reference id="rid.986"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of Centers for Disease Control group IVc-2 to the genus Ralstonia as Ralstonia paucula sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>663</fpage><lpage>669</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-663</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319489</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ralstonia paucula</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ralstonia paucula</i> (pau'cu.la. L. adj. <i>pauculus rare</i>, very few, to indicate that these strains only sporadically cause human infections)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming and rod- shaped.</s><s>After 24 h growth on Trypticase soy agar at 30°C, the mean cell size was about 0.8 μm in width, and 1.2-2 μm in length.</s><s>Strains produce convex, circular, and beige colonies with entire edge and smooth surface.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Non-pigmented.</s><s>No haemolysis on horse blood agar.</s><s>Grows at 30, 37 and 42°C.</s><s>No acid production from D-glucose, maltose, adonitol, D-fructose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 0.5 and 1.5% NaCl, but not in the presence of cetrimide, 10% lactose, penicillin (10 μg disks) or 3, 4.5 or 6% NaCl.</s><s>Grows on Drigalski agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80.</s><s>No fluorescence on King B medium.</s><s>Negative for lysine or ornithine decarboxylases and for arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>No amylase activity.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>No denitrification.</s><s>Hydrolysis of urea, but not gelatin or aesculin.</s><s>No β-galactosidase or DNase activity.</s><s>No production of indole.</s><s>No production of hydrogen sulfide or acid in triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>No tryptophanase activity.</s><s>Assimilates D-gluconate, caprate, adipate, L-malate, citrate, phenyl acetate and DL-lactate, but not D-glucose, trehalose, L-arginine, DL-norleucine, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, maltose or sucrose.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, and leucine and cystine arylamidases, and phosphoamidase activity are present; valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activity are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ubiquinone-8 was reported to be the respiratory quinone (Ferreira <i>et al</i>., 1996).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from a variety of human clinical sources including blood, wounds, sputum, urine, eye, throat and peritoneal fluid.</s><s>In addition, <i>R. paucula</i> strains have been isolated from pool water (Aspinal &#x0026; Graham, 1989), groundwater (Campbell Wyndham <i>et al</i>., 1994) and bottled mineral water (Manaia <i>et al</i>., 1990).</s><s>It should be noted that <i>R. paucula</i> strains were present in bottled mineral water only at the day of bottling; after 7 d storage, no strains could be recovered, suggesting that they did not survive or were, unlike several other components of the flora of bottled mineral waters, unable to multiply (Ferreira <i>et al</i>., 1996).</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 65-67 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 3244<sup>T</sup> (= CCUG 12507<sup>T</sup> = CDC E6793<sup>T</sup>),which was isolated from a human respiratory tract in the USA.</s><s>Its G + C content is 67 mol%. <i>Ralstonia paucula</i> reference strains are available from the BCCM/LMG and CCUG Culture Collections.</s></p></content></protolog>