<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9084_nm.14265" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14265" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14265" rank="species">Thermotalea metallivorans</organism><reference id="rid.9084"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ogg</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermotalea metallivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a thermophilic, anaerobic bacterium from the Great Artesian Basin of Australia aquifer.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>964</fpage><lpage>971</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004218-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406776</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thermotalea metallivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thermotalea metallivorans</em> (me.tal.li.vo′rans. L. n. <em>metallum</em> metal; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <em>metallivorans</em> metal-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 3.0–3.5×0.6–0.7 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs between 30 and 55 °C (optimum temperature 55 °C) and pH 6.5 to 9 (optimum pH 8.0).</s><s>Grows on yeast extract and tryptone as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Yeast extract or tryptone is required for growth with other substrates.</s><s>Grows with glucose, sucrose, maltose, fructose, arabinose, mannose, cellobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, Casamino acids, serine, and leucine, but not with lactose, galactose, raffinose, xylose, ribose, chitin, starch, acetate, propionate, lactate, formate, pyruvate, ethanol, glycerol, amyl media, arginine, alanine, glycine, threonine, glutamate, isoleucine, methionine, amylopectin, casein or xylan.</s><s>Metabolizes mannan, Tween 40, Tween 80, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, ribose, sedoheptulosan, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-asparagine, l-serine, putrescine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, but not <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, stachyose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine and thymidine 5′-monophosphate.</s><s>End products from glucose fermentation are ethanol and acetate.</s><s>Fe(III), Mn(IV) and elemental sulfur are reduced in the presence of yeast extract, but not sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, nitrate or nitrite.</s><s>Sensitive to chloramphenicol, streptomycin, tetracycline, penicillin, ampicillin, sodium azide and to NaCl concentrations greater than 4 % (w/v).</s><s>Phylogenetically related to <em>Geosporobacter subterraneus</em> DSM 17957<sup>T</sup> (16S rRNA gene sequence similarity value 89.9 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B2-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 5625<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15105<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21119<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a microbial mat sample from the outflow of a GAB bore (New Lorne Bore) in Queensland, Australia.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 48±1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>