<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9710_nm.14860" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14860" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14860" rank="species">Flavobacterium tiangeerense</organism><reference id="rid.9710"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Z.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium tiangeerense sp. nov., a cold-living bacterium isolated from a glacier</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2773</fpage><lpage>2777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007906-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625423</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium tiangeerense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium tiangeerense</em> [ti.an.geer.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>tiangeerense</em> pertaining to the mountain Tiangeer (meaning ‘close to the sky’ in Mongolian language), the location of the China No. 1 glacier, where the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative rods, non-flagellated and 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 2.5–8.5 μm long.</s><s>Gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, smooth, circular and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–26 °C (optimum, 22–23 °C) and at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum, approximately pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Weak growth occurs under microaerobic conditions (approximately 10 % CO<sub>2,</sub> 11 % O<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions (O<sub>2</sub>&#x003C;1 %, 9–13 % CO<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar and trypticase soy agar, but not on seawater agar.</s><s>No brown pigment is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>No precipitate is formed on egg yolk agar.</s><s>Casein and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, tyrosine, chitin, pectin, alginate, DNA, carboxymethylcellulose and Tweens 20 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed by colonies and flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from starch and mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, adonitol, sorbitol, glycerol, melibiose, sorbose, galactose, rhamnose, mannitol, melezitose, sucrose, trehalose, glucose, lactose, glycogen, raffinose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, amygdalin, xylose, inositol, dulcitol, salicin, ribose, fructose, maltose and inulin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN MicroPlate: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, uridine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN MicroPlate are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Menaquinone-6 (MK-6) is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 0563<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6847<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15087<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the China No. 1 glacier (Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, China).</s></p></content></protolog>