<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4656_nm.6826" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6826" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6826" rank="species">Streptomyces aculeolatus</organism><reference id="rid.4656"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amano</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohuchi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sezaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Studies on new antibiotics SF2415. I. Taxonomy, fermentation, isolation, physico-chemical properties and biological activities</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>732</fpage><lpage>739</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3610830</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces aculeolatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces aculeolatus</i> (acu.le.o.la'tus. L. adj. <i>aculeolatus</i> somewhat spiny, referring to the spore surfaces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative mycelium was well developed and branched.</s><s>The hyphae did not fragment into coccoid or bacillary elements.</s><s>Aerial mycelium was simply branched and terminated in open or closed coils.</s><s>Mature spore chains have 10 or more spores per chain.</s><s>This morphologywas observed in sucrose-nitrate agar, glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP medium 5), and inorganic salts-starch agar (ISP medium 4).</s><s>Spores were ellipsoidal in shape, 0.8-1.2 by 1.0-1.6 μm in size.</s><s>Surface irregularities on spores were intermediate between warts and spines (Figs. 1 and 2).</s><s>Sporangia, flagellated spores, and sclerotic granules were not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics of strain SF2415 are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Aerial mass color was in the white, yellow or red color series of Tresner and Backus.</s><s>The reverse side of colonies varied from pale yellow to orange depending on the medium*This orange color was somewhat pH sensitive, changing from orange to reddish with addition of 0.05 n NaOH and from orange to yellowish with addition of 0.05 n HCl.</s><s>Light brownish orange, water-soluble pigment was occasionally produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SF2415 grew within a temperature range of 15°C to 37°C, with an optimum range of26°C to 30°C.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and liquefaction of gelatin were positive.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate, peptonization and coagulation of milk, and formation of melanoid pigment were all negative.</s><s>Strain SF2415 tolerated 3 % NaCl, but no growth occurred on more than 4% NaCl.</s><s>On ISP medium 9 the strain utilized D-glucose, D-fructose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, D-mannitol, raffinose and L-rhamnose, but did not utilized <i>i</i>-inositol and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>LL-Diamino-pimeric acid was detected in whole-cell hydrolysates of the culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on the taxonomic properties described above, strain SF2415 is considered to belong to the genus <i>Streptomyces</i>.</s><s>A comparison of the description of strain SF2415 with those of the <i>Streptomyces</i> species described previously showed that no known species are identical to strain SF2415 based on the following combination of criteria: White, yellow or red color series, spiral spore chain, warty to spiny spore surface, non-chromogenic reaction on ISP media 1, 6 and 7, and carbon utilization pattern.</s><s>Organisms that resemble this strain are <i>Streptomyces arabicus</i> and <i>Streptomyces erythrogriseus</i>.</s><s>As summarized in Table 2, however, strain SF2415 differs clearly from these two species in their aerial mass color and utilization of some carbon sources, such as <i>i</i>-inositol, sucrose and raffinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Therefore, we regard strain SF2415 as a new species, for which we propose the name <i>Streptomyces aculeolatus</i>.</s><s>Strain SF2415, the type strain of <i>S. aculeolatus</i>, have been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, with accession number of JCM6055.</s></p></content></protolog>