<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5700_nm.6551" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6551" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6551" rank="species">Actinoplanes derwentensis</organism><reference id="rid.5700"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical and chemical classification of Actinoplanes and some related actinomycetes</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinoplanes derwentensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinoplanes derwentensis</i> (der. wen-ten'sis. ML adj. <i>derwentensis</i>, pertaining to the Derwent, a river in County Durham, UK, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Orange to dark orange substrate mycelium formed on modified Bennett's agar.</s><s>Spherical sporangia readily formed, spores motile and arranged irregularly within sporangia.</s><s>Degrades arbutin, casein, chitin, DNA, elastin, lecithin, RNA and starch; utilizes adonitol, L-arabinose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-sorbitol, D-xylose and sodium fumarate as sole carbon sources but not methyl α-D-glucoside, D-ribose, catechol, coumarin, m-, o- or p-hydroxybenzoic acid, syringaldehyde, syringic acid or vanillin.</s><s>The organism is tolerant to a number of antibiotics and chemical inhibitors (Table 6).</s><s>It grows at 4 and 30 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>- and hydroxydiaminopimelic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The principal wall sugars are arabinose, galactose, glucose, mannose and xylose.</s><s>The organism also contains complex mixtures of straight- and branched-chain fatty acids, with hexadecanoic, 14-methylpentadecanoic and 14-methylhexadecanoic acids predominating, tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenologue, and major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from river sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Actinoplanes derwentensis</i> LA 107 (IFO 14935; NCIB 12875).</s></p></content></protolog>