<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5633_nm.5242" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5242" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5242" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus cohnii cohnii</organism><reference id="rid.5633"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolfshohl</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus cohnii subspecies: Staphylococcus cohnii subsp. cohnii subsp. nov. and Staphylococcus cohnii subsp. urealyticum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>284</fpage><lpage>289</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-284</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854641</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus cohnii</i> subsp. <i>cohnii</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus cohnii</i> subsp. <i>cohnii</i> (coh'ni.i. M.L. gen. noun of Cohn, named for Ferdinand Cohn, a German botanist and bacteriologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of <i>S. cohnii</i> subsp. <i>cohnii</i> is based on testing of 14 to 25 strains.</s><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci, 0.5 to 1.2 μm in diameter, nonmotile, and nonsporeforming; they occur predominantly singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on P agar (17) are convex, entire, circular, smooth, usually glistening or glossy, opaque, and 4.0 to 6.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are unpigmented or occasionally have a slightly yellowish tint.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase not produced.</s><s>Coagulase, clumping factor, heat-stable nuclease, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, and arginine arylamidase negative.</s><s>No esculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is not produced aerobically from D-turanose, D-xylose, D-cellobiose, L-arabinose, sucrose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, β-melibiose, or α-lactose.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-trehalose, β-D-fructose, D-glucose, and glycerol.</s><s>No acid is produced anaerobically from D-mannitol.</s><s>The variable characteristics of <i>S. cohnii</i> subsp. <i>cohnii</i> are listed in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities.</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin (MIC, 3.1 to 12.5 μg/ml) and slightly resistant to lincomycin (MIC, 21.6 μg/ml), oxacillin (MIC, 0.5 to 4 μg/ml), and penicillin G (MIC, 0.1 to 0.8 μg/ml).</s><s>Forty-four percent of strains are resistant to erythromycin, 8% are resistant to tetracycline, and 4% are resistant to chloramphenicol.</s><s>All strains tested are susceptible to vancomycin, gentamicin, and kanamycin By disk diffusion methods, borderline resistance or resistance is noted for oxacillin and penicillin G.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan and teichoic acid.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is L-Lys-Gly<sub>5-6</sub> (24).</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acid type is poly(glycerolphosphate), with glucose and N-acetylglucosamine as the main substituents (5, 24).</s><s>Additional characteristics.</s><s>Predominantly L-lactic acid (mean = 96%) and only a very small percentage of D-lactic acid are produced following anaerobic growth in a yeast extract-glucose broth (24).</s><s>Supplementation of a basal casein hydrolysate medium with uracil does not promote growth under anaerobic conditions (6).</s><s>Most strains (78%) require both L-arginine and L-proline for growth on a defined medium (4).</s><s>Esterase polymorphism and polytypism are characteristic for this subspecies (25).</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. cohnii</i> subsp. <i>cohnii</i> is ATCC 29974 (DSM 20260, originally designated GH137), the designated type strain of <i>S. cohnii</i> Schleifer and Kloos 1975b, 55 (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain has all the uniform characteristics of the subspecies.</s><s>In addition, it has the following properties (24).</s><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci, 1.0 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in pairs and singly, occasionally in tetrads.</s><s>Agar colonies are circular, entire, about 6.0 mm in diameter, convex to slightly peaked with a flat edge, smooth with a glossy surface, white, and opaque.</s><s>Weak hemolysins are detected.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase negative.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol (acetoin) produced.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Weak acid produced aerobically from maltose and D-mannitol.</s><s>No acid produced from D-mannose, xylitol, or N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin (MIC, &#x003E;150 μg/ml) and susceptible to tetracycline.</s><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 37.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>