<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12854_nm.22661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22661" rank="species">Halomonas rifensis</organism><reference id="rid.12854"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Amjres</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abrini</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas I.</surname><given-names /></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas rifensis sp. nov., an exopolysaccharide-producing, halophilic bacterium isolated from a solar saltern</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2600</fpage><lpage>2605</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027268-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21131498</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas rifensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas rifensis</em> (ri.fen′sis. N.L. adj. <em>rifensis</em> pertaining to the Rif mountains in northern Morocco, where the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative rods, 0.8–1.0×3.0–4.4 µm, that occur either singly or in pairs, are motile by peritrichous flagella, produce exopolysaccharide, accumulate poly-β-hydroxyalkanoate and do not form endospores.</s><s>Forms circular, convex, creamy-white colonies.</s><s>Growth pattern in liquid medium is uniform.</s><s>Moderately halophilic; capable of growth in salt concentrations (mixture of sea salts) of 0.5–20 % (w/v) (optimum 5–7.5 %, w/v); incapable of growing without NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 25–45 °C (optimum 32 °C) and at pH 5–10 (optimum pH 6–9).</s><s>Does not produce acid from any of the sugars or alcohols tested, including l-arabinose, amygdalin, d-glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, melibiose, l-rhamnose, sucrose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and produces catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory with oxygen and nitrate but not with nitrite and fumarate as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and ONPG tests are negative.</s><s>Does not produce hydrogen sulfide from l-cysteine.</s><s>Aerobic nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 20 but not casein, DNA, gelatin, Tween 80 or tyrosine.</s><s>Produces pigment from tyrosine.</s><s>Produces lecithinase, phosphatase and tryptophan deaminase but not amylase, arginine dihydrolase, haemolysin, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or urease.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar and cetrimide agar.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, adonitol, l-arabinose, l-aspartate, benzoate, cellobiose, ethanol, formate, fumarate, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconate, d-glucose, d-glutamate, glycerol, hippurate, dl-β-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, malate, malonate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, propionate, pyruvate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, sorbitol, starch, succinate, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: adipic acid, aesculin, caprylate, citrate, dl-lactate, lactose, phenylacetic acid, 2-propanol, ribose, d-salicin and tartrate. <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-alanine, creatine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine are used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy. l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan and l-valine are not used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg unless stated otherwise) amoxicillin (25), ampicillin (10), cefalothin (30), gentamicin (10), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin G (10), polymyxin B (300 IU), tetracycline (30), tobramycin (10), rifampicin (5) and sulphamide (300) and resistant to erythromycin (15).</s><s>The principal fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is Q-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HK31<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7698<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25695<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a solar saltern in Chefchaouen in the Rif Mountains, Morocco.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.5 mol% (<em>T<sub>m</sub></em> method).</s></p></content></protolog>