<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5685_nm.7132" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7132" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7132" rank="species">Streptomyces macrosporus</organism><reference id="rid.5685"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lacey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Todd</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical classification of thermophilic Streptomycetes</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>133</volume><fpage>3135</fpage><lpage>3149</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces macrosporus</i> (ex Krassilnikov et al., 1968, 66) nom. rev. sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces macrosporus</i> (Ma.cro.spor'us. Gr. adj. <i>makros</i> long, large; Gr. n. <i>spora</i> seed; M.L. adj. <i>macrosporus</i> large-spored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 40 °C on half-strength nutrient and V-8 juice agars good; aerial mycelium in the green colour series near 24 ih (Tresner &#x0026; Backus, 1963), with white flecks, although may be thin and white on half-strength nutrient agar.</s><s>At 25 "C, small colonies only, sometimes with sparse white aerial mycelium.</s><s>Substrate mycelium colourless to dark brown with no distinctive pigments but often crystalline deposits in the agar.</s><s>Melanoid pigments not produced on peptone iron agar.</s><s>No soluble pigments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores mostly in tight spirals of up to six turns and 50 spores but sometimes in short straight chains of only five spores.</s><s>Spores appear warty in transmission electron micrographs but are characteristically wrinkled in scanning electron micrographs, 0.7-1.8 x 0-7-1 -6 μm, sometimes broader than long, mean 1.12 x 0.96 μm (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Degrades aesculin, arbutin, casein, DNA, gelatin, RNA, starch and L-tyrosine; utilizes D-fructose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, trehalose and D-xylose as sole carbon sources, and L-arginine, L-phenylalanine, potassium nitrate and L-threonine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Proteolysis and lipolysis evident on egg yolk agar; pectin hydrolysed; hydrogen sulphide produced but nitrate not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sewage compost and soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type culture: DSM41449 = K44 = A1201 = INMI 2892.</s></p></content></protolog>