<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7229_nm.7297" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7297" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7297" rank="species">Streptomyces thermocarboxydus</organism><reference id="rid.7229"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falconer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces thermocarboxydovorans sp. nov. and Streptomyces thermocarboxydus sp. nov., two moderately thermophilic carboxydotrophic species from soil</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>59</fpage><lpage>68</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-59</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542077</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces thermocarboxydus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces thermocarboxydus</i> (ther.mo.car.box'y.dus. Gr. n. <i>therme</i> heat; L. n. <i>carbo</i> charcoal, carbon; Gr. adj. <i>oxys</i> sharp, acid; L. n. <i>carboxydus</i> pertaining to carbon monoxide)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and earlier studies (7, 32).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, moderately thermophilic, facultatively chemolithotrophic actinomycete with extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelia. <i>Retinaculiaperti</i> chains of warty-surfaced spores are borne on aerial hyphae.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is grey; distinctive substrate mycelium colours are not produced.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on peptone-iron agar.</s><s>The organism oxidizes hydrogen and can use carbon monoxide as a sole source of carbon for energy and growth.</s><s>Positive activity is seen for chemotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, lipase and trypsin but not for α-galactosidase (APIZYM).</s><s>N-Acetyl-β-D-galactosamidase, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosamidase and α-L-arabinosidase are produced but not β-D-cellobiosidase, β-D-fucopyranosidase, α-D-mannosidase or β-D-xylosidase.</s><s>Aesculin, arbutin, DNA, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, testosterone and xanthine are degraded.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced and hydrogen sulphide produced.</s><s>Neither allantoin nor urea are hydrolysed.</s><s>D-Fructose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-lactose, mannitol, trehalose and sodium propionate, but not adonitol, raffinose, sucrose, xylitol, sodium acetate, sodium fumarate or sodium pyruvate, are used as sole carbon sources and L-arginine, D-amino butyric acid, L-cysteine, L-histidine, potassium nitrate, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine, but not L-hydroxyproline or L-methionine, as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20°C and 55°C and in the presence of adenine (0.5%, w/v), crystal violet (0.001%, w/v), phenyl ethanol (0.3%, v/v), potassium tellurite (0.01%, w/v), sodium azide (0.01%, w/v), chloramphenicol (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), chlortetracycline (4 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gentamicin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), neomycin sulphate (2 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), novobiocin (2 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), oleandomycin phosphate (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), penicillin G (16 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), polymyxin B (32 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), rifampicin (4 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (2 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), tobramycin sulphate (8 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and vancomycin (4μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 70.9 ± 0.4 mol% G + C.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain is AT37 (= DSM 44293).</s></p></content></protolog>