<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8306_nm.13353" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13353" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13353" rank="species">Halomonas korlensis</organism><reference id="rid.8306"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas korlensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, denitrifying bacterium isolated from saline and alkaline soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2582</fpage><lpage>2588</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65711-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984697</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas korlensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas korlensis</em> (kor.len′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>korlensis</em> pertaining to Korla, in north-western China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile and non-spore-forming rods or short rods and 0.8–1.0×1.3–1.7 μm.</s><s>No flagella are observed (see Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>Does not accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate and does not produce exopolysaccharides.</s><s>On MH agar, produces circular, convex and orange-coloured colonies.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, capable of growing in salt concentrations of 0.5–25 % (w/v); no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows within the temperature range of 4–43 °C and at pH values between 6.0 and 10.0.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 6.0–10.0 % total salts, 30 °C and pH 8.5–9.0.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, with oxygen, nitrate or nitrite as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Gas is produced anaerobically from nitrate.</s><s>Nitrate can be reduced to nitrite aerobically.</s><s>Cells do not grow anaerobically in the presence of fumarate.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and urease are produced, but not <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Variable reaction for oxidation/fermentation of d-glucose.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed, but not gelatin, casein, starch, Tween 80, DNA, lecithin or aesculin.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative; methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose and d-glucose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose, trehalose or cellobiose.</s><s>A variable reaction is found for d-galactose and sucrose.</s><s>The following compounds can be used as sole carbon and energy sources: d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, ribose, acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, malonate, propionate, succinate, ethanol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, pectin, sucrose, malate, lactate and pyruvate, but not cellobiose, starch, d-xylose or oxalate. d-melezitose, d-salicin, adonitol and d-mannitol are weakly utilized; a variable reaction is noted for aesculin, l-arabinose, lactose, trehalose and sorbitol.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-isoleucine, l-serine and l-valine, but not l-cysteine or l-histidine.</s><s>Variable reaction for l-lysine and l-methionine.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), ampicillin (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), cefoxitin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), cefotaxime (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chloramphenicol (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), kanamycin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), nitrofurantoin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), streptomycin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), sulphamide (250 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and spectinomycin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but not to carbenicillin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), nalidixic acid (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), tobramycin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), neomycin (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), tetracycline (12.5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), bacitracin (30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) or furandantin (50 μg  ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>t</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>t</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C contents are between 65.1–65.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XK1<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6981<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19633<sup>T</sup>) and four other reference strains were isolated from a saline and alkaline soil in Korla, north-western China.</s><s>For the type strain, XK1<sup>T</sup>, acid can also be produced from d-galactose, but not from sucrose.</s><s>l-Arabinose, trehalose and l-lysine are weakly utilized, but not aesculin, lactose, sorbitol or l-methionine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose by fermentation.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>