<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5764_nm.10008" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10008" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10008" rank="species">Sediminicola luteus</organism><reference id="rid.5764"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sediminicola luteus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>841</fpage><lpage>845</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64047-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sediminicola luteus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sediminicola luteus</em> (lu.te′us. L. masc. adj. <em>luteus</em> golden yellow, because the colony colour is golden yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to possessing the characteristics given in the description of the genus, the cells are 0·5–0·7 μm in width and 3–5 μm in length; 7-day-old cells form longer filaments of 5–10 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–30 °C; the optimal growth temperature is 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 10–100 % strength artificial sea water.</s><s>NaCl alone is not sufficient to support growth.</s><s>Positive for catalase and weakly positive for oxidase.</s><s>Positive for degradation of gelatin, casein and starch and for nitrate reduction.</s><s>Urea, chitin, cellulose, CM-cellulose and DNA are not depolymerized.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, dl-lactic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine and glucose 1-phosphate are oxidized.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvic acid, mono-methyl succinic acid, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate are not oxidized.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CNI-3<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 100966<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23246<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediment on the shore of the Sea of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>