<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.646_nm.1950" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1950" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1950" rank="species">Aquaspirillum magnetotacticum</organism><reference id="rid.646"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maratea</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blakemore</surname><given-names>R.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquaspirillum magnetotacticum sp. nov. a magnetic spirillum.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>452</fpage><lpage>455</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aquaspirillum magnetotacticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aquaspirillum magnetotacticum</i> (mag ne to tac'ti cum. Gr. n. <i>magnes</i> magnet, comb. form <i>magneto</i>-; Gr. adj. <i>taktikos</i> showing orientation or movement directed by a force or agent; <i>magnetotacticum</i> capable of orientation with respect to a magnet)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical (clockwise) spirilla, 0.2 to 0.4 by 4.0 to 6.0 μm, with a tendency to form long chains and coccoid bodies in older cultures; the wavelength is 1 to 2 μm.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile by means of a single flagellum at each pole.</s><s>Each magnetotactic cell contains a variable number of enveloped magnetite (Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>) particles arranged in a chain within the cytoplasm; each particle (magnetosome) is approximately 40 to 50 nm on a side.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic granules presumed to be poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are present.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30°C.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Microaerophilic.</s><s>Growth in the presence of KCN is inhibited.</s><s>Cannot grow anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze casein, starch, hippurate, esculin, or gelatin.</s><s>Selenite is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced from cysteine.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, urease, sulfatase, and indole are negative.</s><s>Oxidase test is faintly positive with toluene-treated cells.</s><s>Phosphatase is positive.</s><s>There is no alkaline reaction in litmus milk.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 1% glycine, but growth is inhibited by 1% bile or 1% NaCl.</s><s>No pigment is produced from aromatic amino acids.</s><s>A water-soluble fluorescent pigment is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrous oxide without nitrite accumulation.</s><s>Ammonia is formed during growth in nitrate-containing medium.</s><s>A variety of tricarboxylic acid cycle intermediates are used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Nitrate and ammonium ions are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 64.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: isolated by R.P.B. at the University of Illinois from sediments collected in Cedar Swamp, Woods Hole, Mass.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain MS-1.</s><s>A culture of strain MS-1 has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 31632.</s><s>Since at present the type strain is the only known strain in the species, the description of the type strain is the same as that for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>