<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.325_nm.6508" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6508" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6508" rank="species">Tsukamurella pulmonis</organism><reference id="rid.325"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brzezinka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rifai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seifert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Feldmann</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella pulmonis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>429</fpage><lpage>436</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-429</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934902</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella pulmonis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella pulmonis</i> (pul. mo' nis. L. gen. masc. n.<i>pulmonis</i>, of the lung, referring to the organ from which the bacterium was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, gra<i>m</i>-positive, and slightly acid-alcohol-fast bacilli.</s><s>Most cells are long rods that, at a later stage of growth, fragment into three parts which then separate and grow as independent rods.</s><s>The cells do not form spores, capsules, or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Visible growth from dilute inocula occurs within 2 days; colonies on Loewenstein-Jensen medium and BHI agar are eugonic, creamy colored, and rough.</s><s>Growth occurs at 24, 31, and 37°C, but not at 45°C.</s><s>The organism contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as a wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e., the cell wall chemotype is chemotype IV).</s><s>It has a mycolate pattern of the α, α' type and a type PII phospholipid pattern with significant amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>MK-9 is the major menaquinone, and minor amounts of MK-10 and MK-8 are also present.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not produced on either ISP medium 6 or ISP medium 7.</s><s>Produces acetamidase, allantoinase, catalase, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, urease, and phosphatase but not arylsulfatase (after 3 days), benzamidase, nitrate reductase, and succinamidase.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar without crystal violet and tolerates 5% NaCl and <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoic acid.</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, trehalose, sucrose, mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, gluconate, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butandiol, 1,2-propandiol, and paraffin are utilized as sole carbon sources, but arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, lactose, maltose, raffinose, cellobiose, melezitose, adonitol, erythritol, inositol, benzoate, citrate, lactate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and adipate are not utilized.</s><s>Acetamide, alanine, and proline are utilized as nitrogen and carbon sources, but gelatin and serine are not utilized.</s><s>Urea, esculin, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed, but adenine, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine, casein, gelatin, elastin, guanine, keratin, and testosterone are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, galactose, trehalose, sucrose, mannitol, sorbitol, mannose, and fructose, but not from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, lactose, maltose, raffinose, cellobiose, melezitose, adonitol, inositol, and inulin.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin, isoniazid, ethambutol, rifampin, <i>p</i>-aminosalicylic acid, protionamide, capreomycin, and cycloserine.</s><s>The G + C content is 69.8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>T. pulmonis</i> is strain DSM 44142.</s></p></content></protolog>