<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1372_nm.5602" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5602" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5602" rank="species">Weissella soli</organism><reference id="rid.1372"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Magnusson</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jonsson</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schnürer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roos</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Weissella soli sp. nov., a lactic acid bacterium isolated from soil</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>831</fpage><lpage>834</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02015-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Weissella soli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Weissella soli</i> (so´li. L. n. <i>solum</i> soil ; L. gen. n. <i>soli</i> of the soil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporeforming, catalase-negative rods 0.9x1.2-3.0 μm in size, often thickened at one end and occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>The cells in a pair are often of different size.</s><s>After anaerobic growth at 30 °C for 2 days, colonies on MRS agar are 1 mm in diameter; they are off-white, smooth and convex.</s><s>Growth on MRS agar occurs both in an aerobic and an anaerobic environment.</s><s>Obligately heterofermentative and produces mainly dlactic acid.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 40 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, salicine, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, D-raffinose and D-arabitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-D-xyloside, galactose, D-fructose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, lactose, inulin, melezitose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate or 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed and arginine is cleaved.</s><s>No dextran is produced from sucrose.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 43 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is Mi268<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 20113<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14420<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>