<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5044_nm.3034" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3034" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3034" rank="species">Photobacterium histaminum</organism><reference id="rid.5044"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Okuzumi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium histaminum sp. nov., a histamine-producing marine bacterium.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>631</fpage><lpage>636</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-631</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Photobacterium histaminum sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Photobacterium histaminum (his.ta.mi'num. N.L.n. histaminum, histamine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, asporogenous, short, rod-shaped cells with rounded ends that are 1.0 to 1.2 μm wide and 2.2 to 2.5 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of one to three polar flagella.</s><s>PHB accumulates in cells.</s><s>Colonies on ordinary nutrient agar having an ASW base are entire, smooth, semitranslucent, nonluminescent, and ivory; they are 1.0 to 1.2 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation at 30°C.</s><s>Halophilic and mesophilic.</s><s>Best growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of ca. 2%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is between 30 and 35°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 45°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 4.5 to 9.0, and the optimum pH is 6.0 to 7.0.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic chemoorganotroph having both respiratory and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from D-glucose and many other carbohydrates.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Amylase and chitinase are produced.</s><s>Neither gelatin nor alginate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Histamine is produced.</s><s>Susceptible to vibriostatic agent 0/129 (2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropyl pteridine).</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, succinate, fumarate, D-ribose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, cellobiose, melibiose, trehalose, glycerol, L-aspartate, L-α-alanine, L-glutamate, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, and hippurate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: valerate, isovalerate, DL-lactate, pyruvate, <i>m</i>-malate, L-tartrate, citrate, malonate, D-gluconate, D-glucronate, D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, lactose, salicine, sucrose, D-galacturonate, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, ethanol, n-propanol, D-α-alanhe, <i>p</i>-alanine, L-leucine, L-arginine, γ-aminobutyrate, L-citrulline, glycine, Lhistidine, L-ornithine, and betaine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 41.3 to 41.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: seawater and marine fish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain C-8, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as strain JCM 8968</s></p></content></protolog>