<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.14759" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14759" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11368" rank="species">Rhizobacter fulvus</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobacter fulvus</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobacter fulvus</em> (ful′vus. L. masc. adj. <em>fulvus</em> deep yellow, gold-coloured).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Methylibium fulvum</em> Yoon <em>et al.</em> 2007.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on that given for <em>Methylibium fulvum</em> (Yoon <em>et al.</em>, 2007).</s><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not starch, chitin, xylan, CM-cellulose, casein or DNA.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-fructose, d-lyxose, l-xylose, sucrose (weakly), acetate, 3-hydroxybutylate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamine, l-glutamate, l-phenylalanine and l-proline.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, trehalose, maltose, cellobiose, melibiose, raffinose, d-fucose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, d-ribose, lactose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, xylitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, amygdalin, glycogen, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, dextran, pyruvate, valerate, fumarate, salicin, malic acid, formic acid, propionic acid, tartrate, gluconate, caprate, maleic acid, phenylacetate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, glutarate, itaconate, suberate, oxalate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-cysteine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-threonine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is weakly positive; gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulfide and indole production are negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, d-glucose or amygdalin.</s><s>Additional reactions are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile of the type strain is listed in Supplementary Table S1.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 66.6–66.7 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 322<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12591<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19916<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon province, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>