<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7122_nm.1933" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1933" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1933" rank="species">Neisseria weaveri</organism><reference id="rid.7122"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Costas</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>On</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Neisseria weaveri sp. nov. (formerly CDC group M-5), from dog bite wounds of humans.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>687</fpage><lpage>693</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-687</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240951</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nekseria weaveri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nekseria weaveri</i> (wea'ver.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>weaveri</i>, from Weaver, to honor R. E. Weaver, a bacteriologist at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of <i>N. weaveri</i> are given below.</s><s>The 45 strains which we studied are strictly aerobic, gram-negative, uniformly staining, rod-shaped organisms whose cells have parallel sides and rounded ends.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A total of 62 characteristics are common to all strains (either all positive or all negative).</s><s>There are eight characteristics in which one or more of the strains differ (Table 4).</s><s>All strains are positive for the following characteristics: growth at 37°C, growth at room temperature (18 to 22°C), growth on MacConkey agar, catalase production, oxidase production, and growth at 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are negative for the following characteristics: pigment production; nitrate reduction; indole production (Ehrlich reagent); growth on Simmons citrate; urease production; gelatinase production (stab and plate methods); production of H<sub>2</sub>S in triple sugar iron agar; gluconate oxidation; malonate utilization; production of β-galactosidase; deamination of phenylalanine; arginine dihydrolase production; lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase production; acid and gas production in glucose-peptone-water medium; production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and 10% (wt/vol) lactose; production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, ethanol, fructose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose; production of acid in phenol red broth base under aerobic conditions from glucose and sucrose; reduction of 0.4% (wt/vol) selenite; arginine desimidase production; hydrolysis of Tween 80; production of a brown melaninlike pigment on tyrosine agar; growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (therefore there is also no accumulation of lipids after growth on this medium); esculin hydrolysis; growth on cetrimide agar; fluorescence on King medium B; growth at 5°C; casein digestion; production of extracellular DNase; production of lecithinase; and hydrolysis of starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains contain ubiquinone with eight isoprene units as the major isoprenolog and are characterized by the presence of 3-hydroxylauric (3-OH-12:0) cellular fatty acids (8, 20).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of six strains of <i>N. weaveri</i> range from 50 to 51 mol%; the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 51 mol% (as estimated by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>These values agree well with those previously published for two of the strains included in this study.</s><s>The type strain is NCTC 12742 (= CCUG 4007 = ISL775/91 = LMG 5135).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>N. weaveri</i> strains have been isolated predominantly from the oral cavities of dogs or from human wounds following dog bites.</s><s>Although this organism has been isolated from noninfected wounds by some workers (12), others have reported edema and acute pain within 24 h following a bite (5).</s><s>Certainly, in the case described by Barnham and Holmes (2) the patient had a painful, inflamed, discharging wound within 12 h of being bitten.</s><s>A heavy growth of the organism was obtained, and the patient made a good recovery after treatment with oral erythromycin.</s><s>One of the strains used in this study, ISL718/91, was isolated from the sputum of a diabetic patient.</s><s>Although it may be that the patient had a pet dog from which the isolate was acquired, it is also possible that group M-5 strains can be carried in the human oral cavity.</s><s>Like several other organisms associated with dog bite wounds, group M-5 strains are  susceptible to erythromycin, penicillin, and tetracycline (5, 11).</s><s>The organism appears to be widely distributed geographically as our study (Table 1) included 20 strains from Sweden, 15 strains from the United Kingdom, 5 strains from the United States, 4 strains from France, and 1 strain from Norway.</s></p></content></protolog>