<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1459_nm.7568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7568" rank="species">Thermomonospora formosensis</organism><reference id="rid.1459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanida</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ono</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermomonospora formosensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>20</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-1-20</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermomonospora formosensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermomonospora formosensis</i> (for.mos'en.sis. L. adj. <i>formosensis</i> of Formosa [Republic of China]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Single spores are formed on both aerial and vegetative mycelia.</s><s>Mature spores are heat sensitive, nonmotile, and globose with warty surfaces (diameter, about 1.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies are usually pinkish or light orange, depending on the medium, with or without white aerial mycelium.</s><s>There is little to no soluble pigment.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Type III cell walls and pattern B whole-cell sugars.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 72.0 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Dipicolinic acid is not contained in mature spores.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Cultures hydrolyze gelatin and milk, but not starch.</s><s>No nitrate reductace is produced.</s><s>D-Mannitol, D-glucose, soluble starch, D-galactose, and sucrose are utilized, but D-sorbitol, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, trehalose, lactose, i-inositol, D-xylose, D-fructose, raffinose, D-mannose, and glycerol are not utilized or are poorly utilized.</s><s>Growth occurs on media supplemented with NaCl at a concentration of 2% or less.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain C-36820, the type strain of <i>T. formosensis</i>, has been deposited in the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, Japan, as strain IFO 14204.</s><s>Because the species description given above is based on a single strain, it also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>