<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2213" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2213" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2213" rank="species">Xanthomonas axonopodis</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Xanthomonas axonopodis</i> Starr and Games 1950 emend.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. axonopodis</i> is the same as that of the genus. The following pathovars are distinguished on the basis of phytopathogenic specialization on a wide variety of host plants: <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. axonopodis, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. alfalfae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. bauhiniae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. begoniae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. cajani, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. cassavae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. cassiae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. citri (formerly <i>X. campestris</i> pv. citri group A strains [24]), <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. aurantifolii (formerlyx. campestris pv. citri group B, C, and D strains; reclassified as <i>X. campestris</i> pv. aurantifolii by Gabriel et al. [22]), <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. citrumelo (formerly <i>X. campestris</i> pv. citri group E strains; reclassified as <i>X. campestris</i> pv. citrumelo by Gabriel et al. [22]), <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. clitoriae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. coracanae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. cyamopsidis, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. desmodii, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. desmodiigangetici, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. desmodiilaxiflori, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. desmodiirotundifolii, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. dieffenbachiae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. erythrinae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. glycines, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. lespedezae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. malvacearum, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. manihotis, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. patelii, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. phaseoli, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. phaseoli-fuscans, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. phyllanthi, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. poinsettiicola, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. rhynchosiae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. ricini, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. sesbaniae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. tamarindi, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vasculorum, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vesicatoria, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vignaeradiatae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vignicola, and X, axonopodis pv. vitians, as well as (based on work by Palleroni et al. [37]) <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. betlicola, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. biophyti, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. fascicularis, <i>X. mnopodis</i> pv. khayae, <i>X. mnopodis</i> pv. maculifoliigardeniae, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. martyniicola, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. melhusii, <i>X. mnopodis</i> pv. nakataecorchori, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. pedalii, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. physalidicola, and <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. punicae. The following pathovars include the type A strains of the corresponding former <i>X. campestris</i> pathovars: <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. poinsettiicola, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vasculorum, <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vesicatoria, and <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. vitians. <i>X. axonopodis</i> pv. cassavae includes the type B strains of the former taxon <i>X. campestris</i> pv. cassavae.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. axonopodis</i> can be distinguished from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, cellobiose, gentiobiose, maltose, D-psicose, D-trehalose, monomethylsuccinate, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-glutamic acid, and glycyl-L-glutamic acid and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates β-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucuronic acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, glucuronamide, L-phenylalanine, and thymidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 65.0 to 67.6 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 538 (= NCPPB 457 = ATCC 19312 = ICMP 50 = DSM 3585).</s></p></content></protolog>