<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3852_nm.8213" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8213" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8213" rank="species">Cryomorpha ignava</organism><reference id="rid.3852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mancuso Nichols</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Brumimicrobium glaciale gen. nov., sp. nov., Cryomorpha ignava gen. nov., sp. nov. and Crocinitomix catalasitica gen. nov., sp. nov., novel flavobacteria isolated from various polar habitats.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1343</fpage><lpage>1355</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02553-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130017</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cryomorpha ignava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cryomorpha ignava</em> (ig.na′va. L. fem. adj. <em>ignava</em> lazy, pertaining to the biochemically and nutritionally inert nature of the species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Strains grow at −2 to 25 °C, with temperature optima of about 15 °C.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 1 M NaCl (growth range 0·1–1·0 M NaCl).</s><s>Strong catalase reaction.</s><s>Cytochrome-<em>c</em> oxidase test is negative.</s><s>Requires yeast extract for growth, though some strains can grow weakly on peptone as a sole nitrogen source but not Casamino acids, l-glutamate, nitrate or ammonia salts.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse DNA, casein, starch or chitin.</s><s>Some strains produce urease and esterase (Tween 80 hydrolysis).</s><s>Does not produce alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase or glycosidic enzymes.</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates not detected.</s><s>Does not utilize and is not stimulated by any substrate tested (see description of <em>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi</em> above).</s><s>Produces pinpoint to small orange-pigmented colonies that are smooth, circular, convex in elevation, possess an entire edge and have a viscid consistency when grown on marine 2216 agar (10 °C).</s><s>Other characteristics are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36–37 mol% (thermal denaturation procedure).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1-22<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 647<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21436<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107453<sup>T</sup>), and another strain were isolated from quartz stone sublithic environments of the Antarctic continent, Southern Ocean sea-water particulates and superficial marine sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>