<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2755_nm.5062" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5062" rank="genus">Virgibacillus</organism><reference id="rid.2755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Diaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus carmonensis sp. nov., Virgibacillus necropolis sp. nov. and Virgibacillus picturae sp. nov., three novel species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings, transfer of the species of the genus salibacillus to Virgibacillus, as Virgibacillus marismortui comb. nov. and Virgibacillus salexigens comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Virgibacillus.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>501</fpage><lpage>511</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02371-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710619</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Virgibacillus</em> Heyndrickx <em>et al.</em> 1998</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus</em> (Vir.gi.ba.cil′lus. L. n. <em>virga</em> a green twig, transf., a branch in a family tree; L. dim. n. <em>bacillus</em> from <em>Bacillus</em>, a genus of aerobic endospore-forming bacteria; N.L. n. <em>Virgibacillus</em> a branch of the genus <em>Bacillus</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods (0·3–0·7×2–6 μm) that occur singly, in pairs or short chains or filaments.</s><s>They bear oval to ellipsoidal endospores that lie in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are small, circular, low-convex and slightly transparent to opaque.</s><s>Members of the genus are catalase-positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip and in conventional tests, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative, indole is not produced, citrate is usually not used and nitrate reduction to nitrite is variable.</s><s>Urease and hydrogen sulphide are usually not produced.</s><s>Gelatin, aesculin and casein are usually hydrolysed.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by 4–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth may occur between 5 and 50 °C, with an optimum of about 28 or 37 °C.</s><s>d-Raffinose and d-melibiose can be used as sole carbon sources; no growth on d-arabinose, d-fructose or d-xylose.</s><s>The different members of the genus show a wide range of activities in routine phenotypic tests, and this may reflect undiscovered requirements for growth factors and/or special environmental conditions.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidyl glycerol and phosphatidyl glycerol.</s><s>Five phospholipids and one polar lipid of unknown structure are present in all species of the genus.</s><s>Presence of phosphatidyl ethanolamine and other lipids is variable.</s><s>The main menaquinone type is MK-7, with minor to trace amounts of MK-6 and MK-8.</s><s>In the species tested, the cell wall contains peptidoglycan of the <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid type (Claus &#x0026; Berkeley, 1986; Arahal <em>et al.</em>, 1999).</s><s>The G+C content is in the range 36–43 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Virgibacillus pantothenticus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>