<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12343_nm.20374" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20374" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20374" rank="species">Litoreibacter albidus</organism><reference id="rid.12343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Litoreibacter albidus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Litoreibacter janthinus sp. nov., members of the class Alphaproteobacteria isolated from the seashore</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>154</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019513-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173002</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Litoreibacter albidus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Litoreibacter albidus</em> (al′bi.dus. L. masc. adj. <em>albidus</em> white).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter and 1.8–2.0 μm long.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Produces whitish-pigmented, smooth, shiny colonies with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter, on MA.</s><s>Greenish-violet diffusible pigment is observed during cultivation at 35 °C.</s><s>Bchl <em>a</em> is not produced.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs at 0.5–8 % NaCl (w/v) and is optimal in 2–3 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Grows in/on basal medium containing NaCl alone without any of the sea salts components MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub>, NaNO<sub>3</sub>, K<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>, KCl, NaSO<sub>4</sub>, NaHCO<sub>3</sub>, NaF and FeSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Psychrotolerant; the temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C with an optimum at 25–28 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed above 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–10.0 with an optimum at pH 7.5–8.5.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, DNA, chitin and starch.</s><s>Positive for H<sub>2</sub>S production and hydrolysis of Tween 80 and l-tyrosine.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, melanin-like pigments are not produced but a clearance zone is formed.</s><s>No acid production is observed from d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or d-mannitol.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase (PNPG test) and aesculin hydrolysis and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification under anaerobic conditions, gelatin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In ID32 GN tests, assimilates sodium acetate, d-mannitol, melibiose, propionic acid, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline and does not assimilate l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, d-glucose, salicin, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, l-histidine or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The detailed compositions of fatty acids and polar lipids are given in Table 2.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc unless indicated) ampicillin (10), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100), gentamicin (10), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (30), vancomycin (30), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), ofloxacin (5), polymyxin (300 U), oxacillin (10), erythromycin (15), cephazolin (30), cephalexin (30), tetracycline (30) and chloramphenicol (30) and resistant to lincomycin (15), neomycin (30) and oleandomycin (15).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.4 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KMM 3851<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0773<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16493<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the internal tissues of a marine snail specimen (<em>Umbonium costatum</em>) collected from shallow sediments of the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>