<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7406_nm.3170" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3170" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3170" rank="species">Erwinia billingiae</organism><reference id="rid.7406"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hauben</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of non-pigmented Erwinia herbicola strains from trees as Erwinia billingiae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>377</fpage><lpage>383</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia billingiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia billingiae</i> (bil.ling'i.ae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <i>billingiae</i> of Billing, named after Eve Billing who first isolated these organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data obtained for the 22 strains listed in Table 1.</s><s>The species shows the general characteristics of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Erwinia</i>, as described by Hauben et al. (1998).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive motile rods, and ferment glucose without formation of gas.</s><s>Strains grow at 4°C, rarely at 37°C, but not at 41°C, and have an optimal growth temperature of 28-30°C.</s><s>Colonies grown on nutrient agar are circular, low convex with entire margins, translucent and not pigmented.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and strains exhibit β-galactosidase activity, but not arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease or tryptophan deaminase activities, and rarely deoxyribonuclease activity.</s><s>Citrate and malonate are not utilized and indole and hydrogen sulphide are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied, pectate is not degraded, and Tween 80 is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Tetrathionate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin is usually produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, mannitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, trehalose, gentiobiose and D-gluconate, but not from glycerol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-D-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, amygdalin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, <i>meso</i>-xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose or L-arabitol, or on Jordan's tartrate medium.</s><s>Strains grow on aspartate and D-malate as sole carbon sources, but not on acetate or DL-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Other biochemical and physiological characteristics are given in Table 2 and in the Results.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is given in Table 3. <i>Erwinia billingiae</i> strains were isolated from stem cankers, diseased blossoms and immature fruits mainly of rosaceous trees, often in association with plant pathogens, and are considered as secondary invaders rather than primary pathogens (Billing &#x0026; Baker, 1963).</s><s>The DNA G+C contents of three strains are 54.1-55.1 mol% (Starr &#x0026; Mandel, 1969; J.</s><s>Mergaert, unpublished results).</s><s>The type strain is LMG 2613<sup>T</sup> (= NCPPB 661<sup>T</sup>=Billing E63<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>