<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12421_nm.21251" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21251" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21251" rank="species">Rhizobium vignae</organism><reference id="rid.12421"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sui</surname><given-names>X.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium vignae sp. nov., a symbiotic bacterium isolated from multiple legume species</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>580</fpage><lpage>586</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023143-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382786</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium vignae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium vignae</em> (vi.gna′e. N.L. gen. n. <em>vignae</em> of <em>Vigna</em>, referring to the fact that the majority of strains were isolated from the mung bean, <em>Vigna radiata</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods (0.5–0.7×1.2–2.5 μm), aerobic and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on YMA medium are circular, convex, white and opaque and usually have a diameter of 2–3 mm within 2–3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows on YMA agar supplied with 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl; optimum NaCl for growth is 1 %.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C and at pH 7–10 on YMA plates, the optima are 28 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Catalase, urease and oxidase activities are present, but not phenylalanine 4-monooxygenase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced and reduction of methyl blue and Nile blue are observed.</s><s>Acid production and reduction are observed in litmus milk.</s><s>Resistant to (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>): ampicillin (5), kanamycin sulfate (5), neomycin sulfate (5), streptomycin sulfate (5), bacitracin (300), erythromycin (100), chloramphenicol (5) and gentamicin sulfate (5).</s><s>Grows on YMA supplied with Bismarck brown (0.1 %), Congo red (0.1 %), sodium nitrite (0.1 %) and sodium deoxycholate (0.1 %).</s><s>The type strain utilizes d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-amygdalin, d-xylose, sodium dl-malate, glucose, calcium gluconate, dulcitol, inositol, l-rhamnose, l-proline, l-threonine, raffinose pentahydrate, salicin, sodium citrate, sodium d-gluconate, maltose, sodium pyruvate, sodium succinate, sodium acetate, sodium formate, sucrose, trehalose, syringic acid, vanillic acid, glycine and dl-asparagine as sole carbon sources for growth.</s><s>The type strain uses almost all the sole nitrogen sources tested, including l-aspartic acid, (+)-l-glutamic acid, d-glutamic acid, l-alanine, dl-threonine, hypoxanthine, l-arginine, l-cystine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, l-methionine and l-valine.</s><s>The type strain does not utilize adipic acid, dextrin, inulin, melezitose, melibiose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, calcium malonate, sorbose, soluble starch, sodium tartrate, sodium hippurate, l-methionine or l-arginine.</s><s>The common and/or main fatty acid compounds are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> N alcohol, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, summed feature 4 (C<sub>17:1</sub> iso I/anteiso B and/or C<sub>17:1</sub> anteiso B/iso I) and summed feature 8 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCBAU 05176<sup>T</sup> (=HAMBI 3039<sup>T</sup>=LMG 25447<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a root nodule of <em>Astragalus dahuricus</em> grown in Hebei Province, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>Additional strains were isolated from <em>Astragalus dahuricus</em>, <em>A. oxyglottis</em>, <em>Vigna radiata</em> and <em>Desmodium microphyllum</em> grown in different regions of China.</s></p></content></protolog>