<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12493_nm.21333" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21333" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21333" rank="species">Kordia periserrulae</organism><reference id="rid.12493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kordia periserrulae sp. nov., isolated from a marine polychaete Periserrula leucophryna, and emended description of the genus Kordia</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>864</fpage><lpage>869</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022764-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495038</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kordia periserrulae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kordia periserrulae</em> (pe.ri.ser.ru′lae. N.L. n. <em>Periserrula</em> a scientific generic name, <em>Periserrula</em>; N.L. gen. n. <em>periserrulae</em> of <em>Periserrula</em>, pertaining to a species isolated from the digestive tract of <em>Periserrula leucophryna</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, chemoheterotophic, oxidase- and catalase-positive, non-motile, non-gliding, flexirubin-negative, yellow-pigmented and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Aerobic growth is better than anaerobic growth.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (1.3–3.7×0.4–1.0 µm).</s><s>After 4 days incubation on MA at 30 °C, colonies are circular, convex, shiny, have an entire margin and are 3.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C (optimum, 30 °C), pH 7.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0–8.0) and 0.5–7.5 % NaCl (optimum, 3.0 % NaCl).</s><s>Starch, casein and elastin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse DNA, cellulose, CM-cellulose, chitin or Tween 80.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Absorption spectral peaks of the pigments are observed at 451 nm (major peak) and 478 nm.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis and gelatin liquefaction in API 20NE tests, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation and activities of arginine dihydrolase, urease and PNPG (β-galactosidase).</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities; alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase and β-galactosidase in API ZYM tests, but negative for β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>In API 50CH tests, acids are produced from glycerol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, d-cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-tagatose and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 microplate tests, oxidizes α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, rifampicin, chloramphenicol and vancomycin, but resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (by MIDI 4.5).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-6.</s><s>Polar lipids consist of phosphatidylethanolamine, unidentified aminolipids and unidentified polar lipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1412<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14311<sup>T</sup> = KCTC 22801<sup>T</sup> = NBRC 106077<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine polychaete (<em>Periserrula leucophryna</em>) inhabiting a tidal flat of Donggum Island, Korea (37° 34′ 47″ N 126° 30′ 57″ E).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>