<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1770_nm.4711" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4711" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4711" rank="species">Mycoplasma penetrans</organism><reference id="rid.1770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lo</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayes</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>R.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kotani</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pierce</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shih</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma penetrans sp. nov., from the urogenital tract of patients with AIDS.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>357</fpage><lpage>364</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-357</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503969</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma penetrans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma penetrans</i> (pen'e. trans. L.adj. <i>penetrans</i>, penetrating, a penetrant, referring to the unusual ability of this mycoplasma to penetrate into mammalian cells).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are flask shaped and are divided into two compartments, one with a fine-granule appearance and the other with a coarsegranule appearance.</s><s>The elongated cells grow in broth cultures as chains; branching is rarely observed.</s><s>The cells lack true cell walls and do not produce a cell wall when they are cultured in the absence of penicillin.</s><s>On solid medium typical mycoplasma colonies are formed.</s><s>Growth in broth and growth on solid media occur under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In broth cultures there is a noticeable turbidity, and a pellet is formed in the bottom of each culture tube.</s><s>The cells adhere to glass and plastic surfaces.</s><s>Strong hemadsorption and cytadsorption are observed with colonies</s></p><p class="description"><s>on solid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose is fermented, and arginine is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cholesterol is required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serologically unrelated to previously described species and strains of mycoplasmas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genetically unrelated (as determined by DNA hybridization) to mycoplasmas that have been shown previously to both ferment glucose and hydrolyze arginine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 30.5 mol%, as measured by the melting point for hyperchromatic shift.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain GTU-54-6A1; this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 55252.</s></p></content></protolog>