<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7767" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7767" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7767" rank="species">Chlamydia trachomatis</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>, as previously described (Moulder et al., 1984), comprised two human biovars and a murine biovar. As emended, only strains from the human biovars of <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> are being retained in <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>. Therefore, according to Rule 40b of the International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria, the original <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> epithet is retained by the group of human strains which contain A/Har13<sup>T</sup>, the original type strain (Lapage et al., 1992). As emended, <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> strains have a high degree of sequence conservation. The <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> 16s rRNA genes that have been sequenced to date differ by &#x003C;0.65%. <i>Chlamydia</i> species are readily identified and distinguished from other species by ribosomal signature sequences (Figs 3 and 4) or by inspection of the 16S-23s intergenic spacer (Everett &#x0026; Andersen, 1997). Any of several other gene sequences may also be used to identify <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>. In particular, the gene for the MOMP, ompA (ompl), is widely used to distinguish <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> strains. Many, but not all, <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> strains have the extrachromosomal plasmid, pCT (Table 4). Glycogen accumulation by <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> is readily detected with iodine staining of inclusions. <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> strains are generally sensitive to sulfadiazine and tetracyclines. Most strains of <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> are recognized by mAbs to vs4 core epitopes NPTI, TLNPTI, LNPTIA and LNPTI in MOMP (Batteiger et al., 1996; Peterson et al., 1991). <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> causes trachoma, sexually transmitted disease, some forms of arthritis, and neonatal inclusion conjunctivitis and pneumonia. The type strain for <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> is A/Har-13<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC VR 571B<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The 18 serovars of <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> are clustered into two biovars: trachoma and lymphogranuloma venereum (LGV) (Batteiger, 1996; Moulder et al., 1984).</s><s>These serovars are recognized by specific mAbs and can be distinguished by ompA sequence differences.</s><s>Worldwide, each serovar has only a minor amount of diversity, according to ompA sequence analysis.</s><s>The trachoma biovar currently has 14 serovars designated by the letters A through K, plus Ba, Da and Ia.</s><s>Infection is limited primarily to squamocolumnar cells of mucous membranes.</s><s>Serovars A-C are primarily associated with endemic trachoma and serovars D-K with sexually transmitted infection.</s><s>The LGV biovar consists of four serovars, L1, L2, L2a and L3.</s><s>LGV serovars are sexually transmitted and can invade lymphatic tissue.</s><s>There is a clear separation of these biovars based on pathogenicity and on growth in cell culture and in laboratory animals.</s><s>However, there is not a clear molecular pattern of separation of the LGV biovar from the trachoma biovar.</s><s>Antigenic analyses of MOMP and sequence analyses of the ompA gene that expresses MOMP suggest that L1 and L2 are closely related to the B- and E- trachoma serovars and that L3 is related to the A-, C- and H-trachoma serovars (Fitch et al., 1993).</s><s>Analyses of the extrachromosomal plasmid and of the gene for the 60 kDa cysteine-rich protein, however, indicate that the LGV serovars are similar and that they differ from serovar B.</s><s>The 16s rRNA sequences of serovars A, B and D are closer to each other than they are to the serovar L2 sequence.</s><s>The kdtA sequences in the trachoma biovar, including serovars A, B, Ba, D and E, are also phyletically closer than they are to L2 kdtA.</s><s>The groEL sequence of L2 is phyletically almost as different from the serovar A groEL as it is from <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> MoPn groEL.</s><s>It would be inappropriate, therefore, to attempt to further separate the LGV biovar and the trachoma biovar using molecular criteria at the present time.</s><s>The reference strain for the LGV biovar is L2/434/BU (ATCC VR 902B).</s><s>The reference strain for the trachoma biovar is C/PK-2.</s></p></content></protolog>