<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2497_nm.11430" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11430" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11430" rank="species">Salinicoccus kunmingensis</organism><reference id="rid.2497"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus kunmingensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt mine in Yunnan, south-west China</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2327</fpage><lpage>2332</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64783-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911305</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus kunmingensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus kunmingensis</em> (kun.ming.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kunmingensis</em> pertaining to Kunming, a city in south-west China, near which the sample from which the type strain was isolated was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporulating, catalase- and oxidase-positive, obligately aerobic cocci (0.8–1.2 μm) that occur singly or in pairs, tetrads or clumps.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, yellow-pigmented and non-translucent with shiny, glistening surfaces and entire margins, 2–3 mm in diameter after 3 days on MA supplemented with 8 % (w/v) NaCl at pH 8.0 and 37 °C.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced on any media tested.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–45 °C (optimum 37 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum pH 8.0).</s><s>Moderately halophilic, with growth at 0.5–25 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum 8–10 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Also grows well on MA supplemented with 2–15 % (w/v) MgCl<sub>2</sub> or KCl instead of NaCl.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin, starch and Tween 80, but negative for hydrolysis of casein, chitin, gelatin and Tween 20.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Cells are resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg), but ampicillin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (20 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg) inhibit growth.</s><s>In API 20NE strips, a positive result is obtained for assimilation of potassium gluconate and negative results are obtained for assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid and fermentation of glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-fructose, inositol, d-lactose, d-mannitol and sucrose in API 50CH strips.</s><s>In Biolog GP2 plates, the following substrates are used as sole carbon and energy sources: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, Tween 40, l-alaninamide and l-asparagine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed by the type strain are catalase, cytochrome oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, gelatinase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, trypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase/<em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase (ONPG), tryptophan deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase/<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase (PNPG), ornithine decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>The assumed cell-wall murein type is l-Lys–Gly<sub>5</sub>.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-6, and MK-7 is present in minor amounts.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (28.4 %) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (23.1 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM Y15<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17847<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.6302<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a brine sample collected from the Yipinglang salt mine in Kunming, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>