<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7976_nm.8042" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8042" rank="genus">Prevotella</organism><reference id="rid.7976"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>16S rRNA gene similarities indicate that Hallella seregens (Moore and Moore) and Mitsuokella dentalis (Haapasalo et al.) are genealogically highly related and are members of the genus Prevotella: emended description of the genus Prevotella (Shah and Collins) and description of Prevotella dentalis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>832</fpage><lpage>836</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prevotella</i> emend.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on that given in reference 16. Gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, nonmotile, pleomorphic rods. Surface colonies on blood agar plates vary from minute to 2.0 mm in diameter and are generally circular, entire, convex, shiny, and smooth. Colonies on blood agar are translucent, opaque, and grey, light brown, or black. Hemolysis is variable. Glucose broth cultures are usually turbid with smooth or stringy sediments, and the terminal pH is between 4.5 and 5.2. The level of glucose utilization varies between 30 and 90% in BM broth. The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C, but some strains grow at 25 and 45°C. Growth of most species is inhibited by 6.5% NaCl. Hemin and menadione are required for growth of most species. Growth is inhibited by 20% (wt/vol) bile. The major fermentation products from BM medium or peptone-yeast extract-glucose medium are acetic and succinic acids; occasionally lower levels of isobutyric, isovaleric, or lactic acid are produced. Malate dehydrogenase and glutamate dehydrogenase are present; glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase are absent. Proteolytic activity is variable. Most species have limited abilities to ferment amino acids. Nearly all species are indole negative. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid. Respiratory menaquinones (principally MK-10 to MK- 13) may or may not be present. Both nonhydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated fatty acids are present. The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are composed of predominantly straight-chain saturated, anteiso- and iso-methyl, branched-chain types. Sphingolipids are produced. The DNA base compositions are within the approximate range from 40 to 60 mol% G+C. The type species is <i>Prevotella melaninogenica</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>