<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2009_nm.10735" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10735" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10735" rank="species">Galbibacter mesophilus</organism><reference id="rid.2009"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Galbibacter mesophilus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>969</fpage><lpage>973</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64729-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473243</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Galbibacter mesophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Galbibacter mesophilus</em> [me.so.phi′lus. Gr. adj. <em>mesos</em> middle; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>mesophilus</em> middle (temperature)-loving, i.e. mesophilic].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus with the following additional properties.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.7 μm in width and 1.0–3.0 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies on MA are yellow with irregular margins after 3 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>The edge of some colonies may show swarming growth; however, gliding motility is not observed in hanging-drop preparations.</s><s>Carotenoid-type pigments are produced but flexirubin-type pigments are not.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 42 °C, with optimal growth at 25–30 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 30–70 % (v/v) ASW but not in the absence of seawater.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3–7 % NaCl (w/v) and optimally with 3–5 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Positive for the degradation of starch, aesculin and gelatin, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, and production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase activity and for the degradation of agar, carrageenan, urea, arginine, DNA, chitin, cellulose and CM-cellulose.</s><s>Weakly positive for the production of indole from tryptophan and for casein degradation.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid composition is given in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Mok-17<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 101624<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109219<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sediment sample collected in Okinawa Island, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>