<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6294_nm.7854" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7854" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7854" rank="species">Hollandina pterotermitidis</organism><reference id="rid.6294"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bermudes</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margulis</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Morphology as a basis for taxonomy of large spirochetes symbiotic in wood-eating cockroaches and termites: Pillotina gen. nov., nom. rev.; Pillotina calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx gen. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Hollandina gen. nov., nom.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>302</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hollandina pterotermitidis</i> (ex To et al. 1978) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hollandina pterotermitidis</i> (pter.o.ter.mi.ti.'dis. M.L. gen. <i>pterotermitidis</i>, named for the host termite <i>Pterotermes occidentis</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells oblong in cross section and 0.40 to 0.42 μm (narrowest point) to 0.53 to 0.65 μm (widest point) in diameter.</s><s>The outer membrane is in close proximity to the inner membrane over a wide area for most of the cell length.</s><s>A narrow groove (the sillon) is present toward the center.</s><s>Cells have 15 flagella that are 15 to 16 nm in diameter.</s><s>The angle subtended by the flagella ranges from 110 to 130° (average, 122°).</s><s>The angle of concavity ranges from 170 to 180° (average, 175°).</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane ranges from 17 to 20 nm (average, 19 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness is between 2.6 and 3.0 (average, 2.8).</s><s>The thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane ranges from 2 to 6 nm (average, 4.3 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness is between 0.3 and 0.9 (average, 0.7).</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the inner membrane ranges from 7 to 13 nm (average, 9.5 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane to the inner membrane thickness varies from 0.8 to 2.0 (average, 1.4).</s><s>The oblong protoplasmic cylinder is 0.33 to 0.38 μm (narrowest point) to 0.41 to 0.46 μm (widest point) in diameter.</s><s>The ratio of the protoplasmic cylinder diameter to the cell diameter ranges from 0.78 to 0.93 (average, 0.86).</s><s>The type specimen is from the hindgut of the termite <i>Pterotermes occidentis</i> from the Sonoran Desert in Arizona.</s></p></content></protolog>