<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12777_nm.22560" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22560" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22560" rank="species">Hoeflea anabaenae</organism><reference id="rid.12777"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stevenson</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suflita</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stamps</surname><given-names>B.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hoeflea anabaenae sp. nov., an epiphytic symbiont that attaches to the heterocysts of a strain of Anabaena</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2439</fpage><lpage>2444</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025353-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075905</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hoeflea anabaenae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hoeflea anabaenae</em> (a.na.bae′nae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>anabaenae</em> of <em>Anabaena</em>, a cyanobacterium, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small, irregular club-shaped rods, 0.2×2.0–5.0 µm.</s><s>Colonies grown on PY medium are small (1–2 mm diameter), smooth, flat and opaque with no pigmentation.</s><s>Cultures require aerobic growth conditions and concentrations of sea salts above 5 g l<sup>−1</sup> but below 25 g l<sup>−1</sup> (optimum 15 g l<sup>−1</sup>), temperatures of 18–34 °C (optimum 30 °C) and pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum pH 6.5).</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, fumarate and malate are utilized, but glucose, fructose, sucrose, lactate, glutamate, l-arabinose, butyrate and glycerol are not.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM): alkaline phosphatase, esterase, leucine aminopeptidase, trypsin, β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM): esterase lipase, lipase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Does not produce bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> or photopigments.</s><s>Fatty acids detected in the type strain include (in decreasing order of abundance) C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/ω9<em>t</em>/ω12<em>t</em> or any combination of these, ECL 17.603, ECL 18.846/C<sub>19 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, an unidentified phosphoglycolipid, two different unidentified phospholipids and an unidentified aminolipid.</s><s>The only respiratory ubiquinone detected is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.1 mol%.</s><s>Cells are capable of a specific attached symbiotic relationship, only with <em>Anabaena</em> sp. SSM-00 and only attached to the surface of its heterocystous cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WH2K<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 56626<sup>T</sup>  = NRRL B-59520<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a two-membered culture containing WH2K<sup>T</sup> and <em>Anabaena</em> sp. SSM-00, which itself was isolated from a brackish marsh in Woods Hole, MA, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>