<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.782" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.782" rank="species">Chlorobium limicola</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Chlorobium limicola</em></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The species description is as given by Pfennig &#x0026; Overmann (2001a), with the following modifications.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·7–1·1 μm wide and non-motile.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>c</em> with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid, or in some strains, BChl <em>e</em> with isorenieratene.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and sulfur as photosynthetic electron donors; molecular hydrogen and thiosulfate may be used.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria without a requirement for sodium chloride.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 51–52·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 245<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is Y10113.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is a representative of group 3, according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>In addition to the type strain DSM 245<sup>T</sup>, strains clearly assigned to this species are 1630, 9330, DSM 246 and DSM 1855.</s><s>These include two strains that were formerly known as <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> subsp. <em>thiosulfatophilum</em> (strains 1630 and 9330) and one strain formerly assigned to <em>Chlorobium phaeobacteroides</em> (DSM 1855).</s><s>Because of the conflicting situation with other strains known as <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> subsp. <em>thiosulfatophilum</em> that are no longer considered to belong to the genus <em>Chlorobium</em> (see below), it is proposed to abandon the use of subspecies names for thiosulfate-utilizing strains of this and other species of the green sulfur bacteria.</s><s>Thiosulfate utilization is considered to be a property of some of the strains of <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> (strains 1630, 9330 and DSM 257).</s><s>Although the DNA G+C content and some other properties of strains DSM 247, DSM 248 and DSM 257 fit with the properties of <em>Chlorobium limicola</em>, sequence data are lacking and therefore their assignment to <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> is likely but not secure.</s><s>Excluded from this species are all strains that have a DNA G+C content of &#x003E;54 mol% and belong to group 4 (Table 1).</s><s>Strains UdG 6051, UdG 6046 and UdG 6047 (known as <em>Chlorobium phaeobacteroides</em>; Figueras <em>et al.</em>, 1997) are genetically related to <em>Chlorobium limicola</em>, but further studies are necessary to determine their relationship to <em>Chlorobium limicola</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>