<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9533_nm.14688" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14688" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14688" rank="species">Streptomyces philanthi</organism><reference id="rid.9533"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kaltenpoth</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goettler</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dale</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stubblefield</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herzner</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roeser-Mueller</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strohm</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>‘Candidatus Streptomyces philanthi’, an endosymbiotic streptomycete in the antennae of Philanthus digger wasps</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1403</fpage><lpage>1411</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64117-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738121</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Streptomyces philanthi’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Streptomyces philanthi’ [phi.lan′thi. N.L. n. <em>Philanthus</em> (Hymenoptera, Crabronidae) the generic name of the host organism; N.L. gen. n. <em>philanthi</em> of <em>Philanthus</em>, referring to the association with digger wasps of the genus <em>Philanthus</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The reference strain is ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Streptomyces philanthi triangulum’.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Uncultured, Gram-positive, non-motile, possibly sporulating, filamentous bacteria with sometimes branched cells that can be assigned to the genus <em>Streptomyces</em> on the basis of their 16S rRNA gene sequence.</s><s>A detailed description of the methods used in an attempt to cultivate the endosymbionts can be found as supplementary material in IJSEM Online.</s><s>Cells are 0.38–0.62 μm wide and of highly variable length (5–20 μm).</s><s>The bacteria live as symbionts within specialized antennal glands of female digger wasps of the genus <em>Philanthus</em>.</s><s>They are secreted into the brood cells, taken up by the larva and applied to the cocoon, where they appear to protect the beewolf offspring against fungal infection (Kaltenpoth <em>et al.</em>, 2005).</s><s>Bacteria of different <em>Philanthus</em> species differ in their 16S rRNA gene sequence, but sequence divergence is relatively low (0–1.1 %).</s><s>We propose that endosymbionts of different <em>Philanthus</em> species should be treated as ecotypes of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Streptomyces philanthi’ and named according to the host species.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequences of all ecotypes found so far can be amplified selectively by the specific forward primer Strep_phil_fwd3 (5′-CATGGTTRGTGGTGGAAAGC-3′) in combination with the general actinomycete reverse primer Act-A19 (Stach <em>et al.</em>, 2003).</s><s>The ecotype ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Streptomyces philanthi triangulum’ can be stained with the fluorescent probe SPT 177 (5′-Cy3-CACCAACCATGCGATCGGTA-3′) (Kaltenpoth <em>et al.</em>, 2005).</s></p><p class="description"><s>[(<em>Streptomyces</em>) NC; G+; F; NAS (GenBank accession number DQ375802), oligonucleotide sequence of unique region of the 16S rRNA gene is 5′-TACCGATCGCATGGTTGGTG-3′; S (<em>Philanthus</em>, antennal glands); M].</s><s>Kaltenpoth <em>et al.</em>, this study.</s></p></content></protolog>