<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7987_nm.3002" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3002" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3002" rank="species">Vibrio salmonicida</organism><reference id="rid.7987"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Egidius</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiik</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoff</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hjeltnes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio salmonicida sp. nov., a new fish pathogen.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>518</fpage><lpage>520</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-4-518</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibriosalmonicida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio salmonicida</i> (sal. mon. i. ci' da. N.L.n. <i>salmon</i> salmon; L.v. <i>caedo</i> to kill; N.L. adj. <i>salmonicida</i> salmon killer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain HI 7751T (T = type strain) is a gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, curved, motile rod-shaped organism.</s><s>It is oxidase positive and strongly susceptible to vibriostatic agent 0/129; Na+ is required for growth, and the guanine-plus-cytosine content is 42 mol% (14).</s><s>Growth is oxidative or fermentative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>During initial isolation growth on artificial substrates may take 3 to 5 days.</s><s>After a few passages on such substrates, good growth is obtained within 48 h.</s><s>In many cases apparently pure cultures are obtained directly from the kidneys of moribund or newly dead fish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from 24-h cultures on NBA are curved rods which are 0.5 by 2 to 3 μm.</s><s>When they are isolated, strains may show a high degree of pleomorphism.</s><s>Electron micrographs of cells from 24-h tryptone soy agar plates show the presence of at least nine polar sheathed flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>No lateral flagella are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on NBA are small, smooth with entire edges, and grayish; neither pigmentation nor swarming is observed.</s><s>No hemolysis of either human or sheep blood.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum salinity for growth is 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 0.5 and 4.0% (Fig. 2).</s><s>After 11 days growth is obtained only from cultures containing 3.0, 3.5, and 4.0% NaCl, which may indicate a higher survival capacity at higher salinities.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> is essential for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs between 1 and 22°C; optimum growth occurs at 15°C.</s><s>A slight increase in maximal temperature can occur after many passages on an artificial substrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures are sensitive to vibriostatic agent 0/129, with zones of inhibition up to 30 mm in diameter, and are relatively resistant to novobiocin (diameter of inhibition zone, 18 mm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase are present.</s><s>Citrate cannot be used as the only carbon source; nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin, arginine, H<sub>2</sub>S, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Chitinase, β-galactosidase, gelatinase, lipase, and urease are not present.</s><s>D-Fructose, D- galactose, D-glucose, maltose, ribose, and trehalose are utilized, as are N-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, and mannitol.</s><s>Glycerol is utilized slowly.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D- fucose, L-fucose, β-gentibiose, lactose, D-lycose, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, L- sorbose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, amygdalin, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, esculin, α-methyl-D-glucoside, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, α-methyl mannoside, salicin, sorbitol, starch, xylitol, and β-methyl xyloside.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. salmonicida</i> (type strain HI 7751) has been deposited with the National Collection of Marine Bacteria, Aberdeen, Scotland, as strain NCMB 2262.</s></p></content></protolog>