<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4479_nm.8658" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8658" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8658" rank="species">Lactobacillus gastricus</organism><reference id="rid.4479"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roos</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engstrand</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jonsson</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus gastricus sp. nov., Lactobacillus antri sp. nov., Lactobacillus kalixensis sp. nov. and Lactobacillus ultunensis sp. nov., isolated from human stomach mucosa.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>82</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63083-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus gastricus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus gastricus</em> (gas′tri.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>gastricus</em> from Gr. adj. <em>gastrikos</em> of the stomach).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, catalase-negative rods, 0·9×1·2 μm in size and occurring as single cells or in pairs.</s><s>After anaerobic growth at 37 °C for 48 h, colonies on MRS agar are 2 mm in diameter; they are white, smooth and convex.</s><s>Growth on MRS agar under aerobic conditions is very weak.</s><s>In MRS broth, growth occurs at 25 and 42 °C, but not at 20 or 45 °C.</s><s>Both d- and l-lactate are produced.</s><s>Gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose (one of two strains), ribose (one of two strains), galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine (one of two strains), amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-raffinose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-turanose and gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain Kx156A7<sup>T</sup> is 41·3 mol% and the peptidoglycan type is A4<em>β</em> l-orn–d-Asp.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence places the species in the <em>L. reuteri</em> subgroup of lactobacilli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Kx156A7<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22113<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16045<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 48454<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a biopsy of the healthy human gastric mucosa.</s></p></content></protolog>