<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12903_nm.22722" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22722" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22722" rank="species">Pseudomonas composti</organism><reference id="rid.12903"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gibello</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martín</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mengs</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alonso</surname><given-names>P.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garbi</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas composti sp. nov., isolated from compost samples</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2962</fpage><lpage>2966</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027086-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21278410</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas composti</em> (com.pos′ti. N.L. n. <em>compostum</em> -<em>i</em> compost; N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost, from which strains were first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on two strains.</s><s>Gram-negative and non-spore-forming rods (0.4–0.5 µm wide and 1.5–2 µm long).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive, strictly aerobic and motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia blood agar are circular, creamy, brilliant and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Colonies on LB agar are round, yellow and smooth with irregular edges (1.5–2 mm in diameter).</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C and with 6.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Fluorescent pigment is not produced on King’s B medium.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or nitrite and is negative for arginine dihydrolase, indole production, β-galactosidase and acid production from glucose.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin, urea or aesculin.</s><s>With API 50 CH and API 20 NE, assimilates d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, caprate, l-malate, citrate, glycerol, d-fructose, d-arabitol and gluconate, but not <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, d-adonitol, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, l-arabitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, maltose, adipate or phenylacetate.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for ester lipase (C8), esterase (C4) (weakly), trypsin (type strain weakly), leucine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase (type strain weakly) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (type strain weakly); all other tests are negative.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are a summed feature (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/12<em>t</em>/9<em>t</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, C2<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7516<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 59231<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a compost sample.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>