<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7319_nm.2917" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2917" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2917" rank="species">Shewanella amazonensis</organism><reference id="rid.7319"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Venkateswaran</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dollhopf</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aller</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nealson</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella amazonensis sp. nov., a novel metal-reducing facultative anaerobe from Amazonian shelf muds.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>965</fpage><lpage>972</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-965</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734053</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the <i>Shewanella amazonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Shewanella amazonensis</i> (ama.zo.nen.sis. M.L. n. <i>amazonensis</i> named after the area from which the bacterium was collected)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain are rod-shaped, 2-3 µm in length and 0.4-0.7 µm in diameter, Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, polarly flagellated.</s><s>No endospores nor capsules are formed.</s><s>Peritrichous flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solid media.</s><s>Colonies on LB agar medium are circular, smooth and convex with an entire edge, and beige to pinkish depending on the age of the colonies.</s><s>Cells are able to grow at mesophilic temperatures.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 37 °C.</s><s>Denitrifies nitrate to nitrite and nitrite to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Exhibits cytochrome oxidase, catalase and gelatinase activity, and produces hydrogen sulfide from thiosulfate.</s><s>Haemolyses sheep blood cells and does not grow at NaCl concentrations above 3%.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, succinate, fumarate and citrate as sole carbon sources as well as a few carbohydrates and amino acids.</s><s>Very active in the reduction of iron, manganese and sulfur compounds.</s><s>Strain SB2B<sup>T</sup> was isolated from intertidal sediments.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 51.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, SB2B<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700329<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>