<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4044_nm.3232" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3232" rank="genus">Pantoea</organism><reference id="rid.4044"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verdonck</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Erwinia ananas, synonym, Erwinia uredovora and Erwinia stewartii to the genus Pantoea emend. as Pantoea ananas, Serrano 1928 comb. nov. and Pantoea stewartii, Smith 1898 comb. nov., respectively, and description of Pantoea stewartii subsp. indologenes subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>162</fpage><lpage>173</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-162</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Pantoea</i> Gavini, Mergaert, Beji, Mielcarek, Izard, Kersters, and De Ley 1989.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pantoea</i> (Pan.toe'a. Gr. adj. <i>pantoios</i>, of all sorts and sources; M.L. fem. n. <i>Pantoea</i>, [bacteria] from diverse [geographical and ecological] sources)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the data of Beji et al. (5), Gavini et al. (19), and Kageyama et al. (27) and the data in this paper.</s><s>Gram-negative, noncapsulated, nonsporeforming, straight rods that are 0.5 to 1.3 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Cells are motile and peritrichous or are nonmotile.</s><s>Cultures grow well on nutrient agar at 30°C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, translucent, and more or less convex with entire margins.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, pale beige to pale reddish yellow, or nonpigmented.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and oxidase negative.</s><s>No gas is produced from D-glucose.</s><s>No lysine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, or urease activity.</s><s>Pectate is not degraded, and hydrogen sulfide is not produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-xylose, D-ribose, D-galactose, D-fructose, trehalose, and N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, but not from D-arabinose, L-xylose, L-fucose, or D-turanose.</s><s>Isolated from plants, seeds, fruits, soils, and water, as well as from humans (wounds, blood, urine, internal organs) and animals, in several parts of the world.</s><s>Some strains are (or have been thought to be) phytopathogenic.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 49.7 to 60.6 mol% (9, 17, 19, 25, 27, 43; this study).</s><s>The type species is <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i> (Beijerinck 1888) Gavini, Mergaert, Beji, Mielcarek, Izard, Kersters, and De Ley 1989.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The differential characteristics of <i>Pantoea ananas</i>, <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i>, and <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> are shown in Tables 2 and 4. <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i> and <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> can be further differentiated from <i>Pantoea ananas</i> by the higher percentages of straight-chain octodecenoic acids (C<sub>18:1</sub>) (Table 3, summed in feature 7) in their fatty acid compositions.</s><s>Unlike <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i>, <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i> lacks 2-hydroxytetradecanoic acid (C<sub>14:0 2 OH</sub>) and cyclo-heptadecanoic acid (C<sub>17:0 cyclo</sub>).</s><s>Characteristics useful for differentiation from other <i>Pantoea</i> species, <i>Erwinia</i> species, and other members of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> are shown in Tables 4 through 6, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Data presented above or published previously (5, 19, 34) demonstrate that the API 20E commercial kits are not sufficient for the identification of most <i>Pantoea</i> and <i>Erwinia</i> species.</s><s>An updating of the APILAB identification program is needed, and several other tests, some of which are contained in the API 5OCHE system, have to be used to differentiate <i>Pantoea ananas</i>, <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i>, and <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> from each other and from other taxa (Tables 4 through 6).</s><s>The use of the MIS data base for the identification of the fatty acid profiles seems promising; <i>Pantoea ananas</i> and <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>stewartii</i> were correctly identified, while the newly proposed taxon <i>Pantoea stewartii</i> subsp. <i>indologenes</i> produced an unidentified, unique fatty acid profile.</s><s>Of the 13 DNA hybridization groups of Brenner et al. (7), 5 have been named; group IIIhas been described as <i>Pantoea dispersa</i> (19), group VI has been described as <i>Pantoea ananas</i> (this paper), group XI has been described as <i>Escherichia adecarboxylata</i> (26), group XIII has been described as <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i> (5, 19), and group V has been provisionally classified as <i>Pantoea</i> sp. ( 5 , 19).</s><s>The taxonomic positions of DNA hybridization groups I, II, IV, VII to X, and XII of Brenner et al. (7) remain to be elucidated.</s></p></content></protolog>