<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12430_nm.21263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21263" rank="species">Deinobacterium chartae</organism><reference id="rid.12430"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ekman</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raulio</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fewer</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deinobacterium chartae gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely radiation-resistant, biofilm-forming bacterium isolated from a Finnish paper mill</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>540</fpage><lpage>548</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017970-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382794</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Deinobacterium chartae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Deinobacterium chartae</em> (char′tae. L. gen. fem. n. <em>chartae</em> of/from paper).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Plate-grown cells are 0.8–1.3 μm in width and 1.4–2.5 μm in length, may grow to filaments up to 40 μm in rich liquid medium.</s><s>Stains Gram-negatively, but has features of Gram-positive cells.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase-positive, urease-negative.</s><s>Forms colonies with pale pink pigment on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 12 to 50 °C (optimum 37 to 45 °C) and between pH 6 and 10.3.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in the presence of &#x003E;3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on TSA.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose, fructose and maltose.</s><s>Utilizes as a carbon source: succinic acid, l-aspartic acid, glycerol, l-fucose, d-gluconic acid, d-xylose, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-galactonic acid <em>γ</em>-lactone, l-asparagine, d-aspartic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, l-glutamine, <em>m</em>-tartaric acid, d-glucose 1-phosphate, glycyl l-aspartic acid, citric acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-threonine, fumaric acid, bromosuccinic acid, propionic acid, glycolic acid, l-alanine, acetoacetic acid, methyl pyruvate, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>m</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, glucuronamide, d-galacturonic acid, phenylethylamine, chondroitin sulfate C, <em>γ</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, gelatin, glycogen, d-arabinose, arbutin, 3-<em>O</em>-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosyl-d-arabinose, gentiobiose, lactitol, <em>β</em>-methyl d-galactoside, palatinose, raffinose, salicin, d-tagatose, turanose, butyric acid, caproic acid, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, 5-keto-d-gluconic acid, malonic acid, oxalomalic acid, l-histidine, dihydroxyacetone, melibionic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosaminitol, l-lysine and 3-hydroxy-2-butanone but not malate, cellobiose, d-galactose, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-saccharic acid, trehalose, d-mannose, dulcitol, d-serine, d-sorbitol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, l-glutamic acid, Tween 20, d-fructose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, 1,2-propanediol, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, sucrose, uridine, adonitol, mucic acid, tricarballylic acid, l-threonine, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid, l-galactonic acid <em>γ</em>-lactone, capric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-ornithine, <em>N</em>-acetylneuraminic acid, l-phenylalanine, <em>β</em>-d-allose, sedoheptulosan, citraconic acid, amygdalin, citramalic acid, l-valine, glycine, dl-carnitine, d-arabitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, 2-hydroxybenzoic acid, quinic acid, <em>sec</em>-butylamine, l-arabitol, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, d-ribono-1,4-lactone, l-homoserine, dl-octopamine, xylitol, sebacic acid, l-hydroxyproline, putrescine, inulin, 2-deoxy-d-ribose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronic acid, sorbic acid, i-erythritol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, succinamic acid, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, <em>δ</em>-aminovaleric acid, d-tartaric acid, l-tartaric acid or 2,3-butanone.</s><s>Utilizes as a nitrogen source: l-alanine, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-proline, d-glucosamine, d-galactosamine, d-mannosamine, adenosine, cytidine, guanine, guanosine, thymidine, uridine, inosine, uric acid, alloxan, Ala–Asp, Ala–Gln, Ala–Glu, Ala–His, Ala–Leu, Ala–Thr and Gly–Gln.</s><s>Does not utilize as a nitrogen source: ammonia, nitrite, nitrate, urea, biuret, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, glycine, l-methionine, l-valine, d-valine, l-citrulline, l-homoserine, l-ornithine, <em>N</em>-acetyl dl-glutamic acid, <em>N</em>-phthaloyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, hydroxylamine, methylamine, <em>N</em>-butylamine, ethylamine, ethanolamine, ethylenediamine, putrescine, agmatine, <em>β</em>-phenylethylamine, tyramine, formamide, dl-lactamide, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adenine, cytosine, uracil, parabanic acid, <em>γ</em>-amino-<em>N</em>-butyric acid, ϵ-amino-<em>N</em>-caproic acid or <em>δ</em>-amino-<em>N</em>-valeric acid.</s><s>Utilizes as a phosphorus source: adenosine 5′-monophosphate, guanosine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate and thymidine 5′-monophosphate.</s><s>Does not utilize as a phosphorus source: phosphate, trimetaphosphate, tripolyphosphate, triethyl phosphate, hypophosphite, adenosine 2′-monophosphate, adenosine 3′-monophosphate, adenosine 2′,3′-cyclic monophosphate, adenosine 3′,5′-cyclic monophosphate, guanosine 3′-monophosphate, guanosine 2′,3′-cyclic monophosphate, guanosine 3′,5′-cyclic monophosphate, cytidine 3′-monophosphate, cytidine 2′,3′-cyclic monophosphate, cytidine 3′,5′-cyclic monophosphate, uridine 2′-monophosphate, uridine 3′-monophosphate, uridine 2′,3′-cyclic monophosphate, uridine 3′,5′-cyclic monophosphate, guanosine 2′-monophosphate, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>β</em>-glycerol phosphate, carbamyl phosphate, d-2-phosphoglyceric acid, phosphoglycolic acid, 2-deoxy-d-glucose 6-phosphate, 6-phosphogluconic acid, d-mannose 1-phosphate, d-mannose 6-phosphate, cysteamine-<em>S</em>-phosphate, phospho-l-arginine, <em>O</em>-phospho-d-serine, <em>O</em>-phospho-l-threonine, phosphocreatine, phosphorylcholine, <em>O</em>-phosphorylethanolamine, phosphonoacetic acid, 2-aminoethylphosphonic acid, thymidine 3′-monophosphate, inositol hexaphosphate or thymidine 3′,5′-cyclic monophosphate.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is listed in Table 1.</s><s>MK-8 is the only respiratory quinone.</s><s>The lipid profile consists of three unknown aminophospholipids, of which one is the predominant lipid, one unknown phospholipid, four unknown glycolipids, two unknown aminolipids and one unknown polar lipid.</s><s>Peptidoglycan structure is A3<em>β</em> l-Orn–Gly–Gly and the DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.8 mol%.</s><s>May be grown on R2A or TSA at 45 °C in ambient air.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K4.1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21458<sup>T</sup> =HAMBI 2721<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a biofilm collected from a Finnish paper mill.</s></p></content></protolog>