<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9183_nm.14387" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14387" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14387" rank="species">Winogradskyella echinorum</organism><reference id="rid.9183"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhukova</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Winogradskyella echinorum sp. nov., a marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from the sea urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1465</fpage><lpage>1468</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005421-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502336</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Winogradskyella echinorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Winogradskyella echinorum</em> (e.chi.no′rum. L. masc. n. <em>echinus</em> sea urchin; N.L. gen. pl. n. <em>echinorum</em> of echini, sea urchins, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a sea urchin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods that are motile by gliding, 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 1.2–2.7 μm long.</s><s>On marine agar 2216, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, shiny with entire edges and are pigmented bright yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C and with 1–6 % NaCl.</s><s>Produces oxidase, catalase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Degrades aesculin (weakly), gelatin, casein and DNA.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse agar, starch, Tweens 20, 40 or 80, cellulose (CM-cellulose or filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, inositol, sorbitol or mannitol.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose and d-mannose, but not l-arabinose, d-lactose, maltose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, caprate, citrate, gluconate, malate, phenyl acetate, inositol, mannitol or sorbitol.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, leucine, cystine and valine arylamidases, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present, but lipase C14, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, lincomycin and oleandomycin, but resistant to ampicillin, benzyl penicillin, doxycycline, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine is the only phospholipid detected.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (consisting of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 33.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 6211<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22026<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24757<sup>T</sup>), was isolated at Troitsa Bay in the East Sea (also known as the Sea of Japan) from the sea urchin <em>Strongylocentrotus intermedius</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>