<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4_nm.6192" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6192" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6192" rank="subspecies">Corynebacterium afermentans lipophilum</organism><reference id="rid.4"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minck</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of Corynebacterium Group ANF-1 strains: Proposal of Corynebacterium afermentans sp. nov. containing the subspecies C. afermentans subsp. afermentans subsp. nov. and C. afermentans subsp. lipophilum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>292</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-287</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8494739</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium afermentans</i> subsp. <i>lipophilum</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium afermentans</i> subsp. <i>lipophilum</i> (li.po'phi.lum. Gr. n. <i>lipos</i>, animal fat; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. adj. <i>lipophilus</i>, fat loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The biochemical characteristics of  are similar to those of <i>C. afermentans</i> subsp. <i>afermentans</i> except that growth is not visible in brain heart infusion broth and very small colonies appear after 48 h on sheep blood agar, but on 1% Tween 80-supplemented sheep blood agar, beige colonies are large (2 mm in diameter) and without a mucoid consistency.</s><s>Bacteria are pleomorphic gram-positive, nonsporeforming rods or coccobacilli that sometimes contain metachromatic granules.</s><s>They are nonmotile and arranged in palisades and V shapes.</s><s>They are not acid fast, and no rod-coccus cycle is present.</s><s>They are catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-glucose, glycogen, lactose, sucrose, ribose, D-xylose, D-mannose, D-galactose, trehalose, and D-mannitol or on triple sugar iron.</s><s>Tyrosine, gelatin, DNA, and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The methyl red test is negative, and acetoin, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S (on triple sugar iron agar) are not produced.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase, lipase, and acid phosphatase are produced.</s><s>α-Galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, and β-glucosidase are not produced.</s><s>Cells utilize acetate and lactate.</s><s>Propionate, D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, and phenyl acetate are not utilized.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to ampicillin, mezlocillin, piperacillin, ticarcillin, cephalotin, cefotaxime, gentamicin, netilmicin, amikacin, norfloxacin, ciprofloxacin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, rifampicin, pristimamycin, tetracycline, and fusidic acid, and some strains are susceptible to erythromycin.</s><s>All strains are resistant to fosfomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabiinose, galactose, and corynomycolic acids.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated fatty acids are mainly palmitic and stearic acids.</s><s>Branched saturated fatty acids are heptadecanoic acid.</s><s>Straight-chain unsaturated fatty acids are mainly oleic acid, linoleic acid, and arachidonic acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 68 mol% G+C.</s><s>Bacteria were isolated from human blood cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain T18502 (= CIP 103500).</s><s>It was isolated at Strasbourg (France) from a human blood culture.</s><s>Strain CIP 103500<sup>T</sup> has the characteristics described for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>