<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6778_nm.6370" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6370" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6370" rank="species">Mycobacterium lacus</organism><reference id="rid.6778"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Turenne</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chedore</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolfe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jamieson</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Broukhanski</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>May</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kabani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium lacus sp. nov., a novel slowly growing, non-chromogenic clinical isolate.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2140</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02170-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508880</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium lacus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium lacus</i> (la'cus. L. gen. n. <i>lacus</i> of the lake, where the organism was acquired)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Microscopy shows large acid-fast bacilli with prominent beading.</s><s>Colonies on LJ medium are nonchromogenic and can grow at temperatures between 25 and 42°C, optimally at 37°C.</s><s>A slowly growing organism with features similar to <i>M. gastri</i> by HPLC and biochemical tests, with the exception of positive nitrate and pyrazinamidase test results and the ability to grow at 42°C.</s><s>Positive test reactions are also observed for urease, β-glucosidase activity and tellurite reduction.</s><s>Does not grow on 5% NaCl or MacConkey without crystal violet.</s><s>Arylsulfatase, Tween 80 hydrolysis and acid-phosphatase tests are weak.</s><s>Negative results for the niacin test, semi-quantitative catalase, heat-stable catalase, iron uptake, acetamidase, nicotinamidase and succinamidase.</s><s>Genetic testing confirms the isolate as a unique species, based on a unique PRA pattern and 16S rRNA gene sequence.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene shows signature sequences characteristic of slowly growing mycobacteria and unique sequence characteristics in the hypervariable regions A and B of the gene.</s><s>Phylogenetically closest to <i>M. malmoense</i>, <i>M. marinum</i>, <i>Mycobacterium bohemicum</i>, <i>M. ulcerans</i> and <i>M. tuberculosis</i> complex.</s><s>Susceptible in vitro to all antimicrobial drugs tested [amikacin (MIC 0.1 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), capreomycin (5.0), clarithromycin (≤2.0), ciprofloxacin (2.0), ethambutol (2.0), ethionamide (2.5), isoniazid (0.1), kanamycin (2.5), levofloxacin (≤0.5), o¯oxacin (1.0), rifabutin (≤0.12), rifampin (≤0.5)], except streptomycin, with intermediate susceptibility (4.0 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>The type strain is strain NRCM 00-255<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-323<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44577<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>