<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4519_nm.6135" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6135" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6135" rank="species">Leifsonia rubra</organism><reference id="rid.4519"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia rubra sp. nov. and Leifsonia aurea sp. nov., psychrophiles from a pond in Antarctica.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>977</fpage><lpage>984</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02396-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leifsonia rubra</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leifsonia rubra</em> (rub′ra. L. fem. adj. <em>rubra</em> reddish, referring to the reddish pigment that the bacterium produces).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, convex, smooth, butyrous, opaque, red-pigmented and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile, curved rods.</s><s>The pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits characteristic peaks at 420, 443, 490 and 520 nm in methanol.</s><s>Grows between 0 and 22 °C and between pH 6 and 12 and tolerates up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth is observed at 15 °C, pH 7 and in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase and reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, urease, lipase, gelatinase, phosphatase and indole, gives negative results in methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, is negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production and does not hydrolyse aesculin or starch.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucosamine, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, glucosamine, glycerol, d-mannose, pyruvate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sodium acetate, d-sorbose, trehalose, l-glutamic acid and l-phenylalanine as sole carbon sources, and fails to utilize l-arabinose, adonitol, ammonium acetate, d-cellobiose, cellulose, creatinine, dextran, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycogen, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, inositol, inulin, lactose, lactic acid, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, melezitol, myristic acid, polyethylene glycol, potassium hydrogen phthalate, d-raffinose, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sorbitol, sucrose, d-xylose, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-tyrosine and l-tryptophan.</s><s>Sensitive to novobiocin, cefaperazone, cefazoline, kanamycin, amoxycillin, tobramycin, roxithromycin, vancomycin, cephatoxime, streptomycin, erythromycin, amikacin, ampicillin, lincomycin, tetracycline and rifampicin and resistant to penicillin, colistin, cefuroxime, nitrofurantoin, ciprofloxacin, cotrimoxazole, norfloxacin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains dl-diaminobutyric acid as the diamino acid, along with glycine, glutamic acid and alanine.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose, glucose, ribose and rhamnose.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-11.</s><s>Fatty acid methyl esters are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CMS 76r<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4210<sup>T</sup> =DSM 15304<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107783<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>