<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8464_nm.13196" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13196" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13196" rank="species">Aeromicrobium ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.8464"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromicrobium ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2025</fpage><lpage>2030</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64871-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768598</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromicrobium ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aeromicrobium ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> from ginseng soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, non-motile cocci, 0.5–1.2×0.3–0.4 μm after growth on R2A agar (Difco) at 30 °C for 5 days.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar after 5 days are white and circular.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature and pH are 30 °C and pH 7, with a growth range of pH 5.0–8.5.</s><s>Grows in a salt concentration of 3 %, but growth is weak above 4 %.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite, but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>The test for oxidase activity is positive and the test for catalase activity is negative.</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-glucosidase, protease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but not arginine dihydrolase, cellulase, chitinase, DNase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease or xylanase.</s><s>Assimilates 3-hydroxybutyrate, acetate, fumarate, gluconate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, n-valerate, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, dulcitol, ethanol, glycerol, inositol, l-alanine, l-asparagine, glutamate, glutamine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and inulin.</s><s>Does not assimilate 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 5-ketogluconate, adipate, benzoate, caprate, citrate, formate, glutarate, itaconate, lactate, maleic acid, malonate, oxalate, phenyl acetate, suberate, tartrate, l-fucose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, methanol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, l-arginine, l-aspartate, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-threonine, l-valine, salicin, glycogen or dextran.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.8 mol% as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The predominant quinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids include C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (32.7 %), 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (20.6 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (12.9 %), while minor saturated fatty acids C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (3.2 %), 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (2.4 %) and 10-methyl C<sub>19 : 0</sub> (3.1 %) are also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 098<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19207<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14732<sup>T</sup> =GBS 39<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in Daejeon, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>