<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6888_nm.1149" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1149" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1149" rank="species">Sagittula stellata</organism><reference id="rid.6888"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gonzalez</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moran</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hodson</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitman</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sagittula stellata gen. nov., sp. nov., a lignin-transforming bacterium from a coastal environment.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>773</fpage><lpage>780</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-773</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226910</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sagittula stellata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sagittula stellata</i> (stel.la’ta. L. adj. <i>stellata</i>, starry)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of type strain E-37 are rod shaped (approximately 2.3 μm long, and 0.9 μm in diameter) and have numerous vesicles on their surfaces.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 are light cream colored.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 41°C, and optimal growth occurs at 30°C.</s><s>The optimal pH is 7.5, and the pH range is 5.5 to 8.5.</s><s>The organism is a strict aerobe and does not denitrify.</s><s>It accumulates polyhydroxybutyrate.</s><s>It utilizes various carbohydrates and amino acids and some aromatic compounds, such as <i>p</i>-coumarate, cinnamate, ferulate, and vanillate, and it exhibits oxidase, catalase, and cellulase activities.</s><s>During growth on glucose, cells are able to partially transform synthetic lignin.</s><s>Growth without vitamins or yeast extract is slow.</s><s>Capsules are produced in liquid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, penicillin G, streptomycin, tetracycline, and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography is 65.0 mol%.</s><s>On the basis of its 16s rRNA sequence, E-37<sup>T</sup> belongs to the α subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is related to <i>Sulfitobacter pontiacus</i> and <i>Roseobacter</i> spp.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a marine enrichment community that was growing on pulp mill effluent as the sole carbon source and was originally inoculated with seawater from a salt marsh on the coast of Georgia.</s><s>Type strain E-37 has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700073.</s></p></content></protolog>