<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2467_nm.11383" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11383" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11383" rank="species">Methylibium aquaticum</organism><reference id="rid.2467"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylibium aquaticum sp. nov., a betaproteobacterium isolated from a eutrophic freshwater pond.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2125</fpage><lpage>2128</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65179-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylibium aquaticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylibium aquaticum</em> (a.qua′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>aquaticum</em> living in water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative and non-motile.</s><s>Cells are short rods (0.8–1.9×0.4–0.7 μm).</s><s>After 4 days incubation, colonies on R2A agar are circular, umbonate, beige-milkish, smooth with entire margin and 0.5–2.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–42 °C and pH 6–10 and in 0–1 % NaCl; optimal growth is observed at 30 °C, pH 7.0 and in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Contains PHB granules.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic and facultatively aerobic.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is much slower than aerobic growth.</s><s>Catalase-negative and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Gelatinase activity and aesculin hydrolysis are weakly positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are negative (API 20NE).</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase activities are positive; esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are negative.</s><s>Of the 47 different carbon sources in the custom-made 48-well plate assay, the following carbon substrates are utilized: methanol, glycerol, d-ribose, d-galactose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, rhamnose, adonitol, d-xylitol, gluconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>However, methylamine, ethanol, dl-glyceraldehyde, d-arabinose, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-glucosamine, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, arabitol, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, citric acid, glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-glycine, l-leucine, l-lysine and l-ornithine are not utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg) chloramphenicol (25), erythromycin (15), streptomycin (10), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), penicillin G (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Resistant to (μg) ampicillin (10), rifampicin (50) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (43.1 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (20.3 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (13.4 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (7.3 %), cyclo C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (4.2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (1.5 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.4 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.4 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.0 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (0.9 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0.8 %) and 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (0.6 %).</s><s>The major quinone type is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.2±0.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1728<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42364<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102349<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an artificial freshwater pond located inside Inha University, Incheon, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>