<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2838_nm.4280" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4280" rank="species">Eubacterium xylanophilum</organism><reference id="rid.2838"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van der Toorn</surname><given-names>J.J.T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium uniforme sp. nov. and Eubacterium xylanophilum sp. nov., fiber-digesting bacteria from the rumina of sheep fed corn stover.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>323</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-323</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium xylanophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium xylanophilum</i> (xy. lan. o. phil'um. <i>xylan</i> xylan; Gr. part. <i>philo</i> loving; L. neut. adj. <i>xylanophilum</i> xylan loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, and motile, exhibiting a rapid corkscrew-like motion.</s><s>Flagella are observed by transmission electron microscopy, but their points of insertion and their number (one or two per cell) have not been determined with certainty.</s><s>After growing for 16 h on xylan agar medium, fewer than one-half of the cells stain gram positive.</s><s>The cells are straight rods, or sometimes they are coccoid with rounded ends (Fig. 2).</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, and sometimes in short chains.</s><s>The cell width varies from 0.4 to 0.6 μm, and the cell length varies from 0.5 to 2.0 μm (sometimes up to about 3 μm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies in roll bottles containing xylan (3%) agar medium incubated for 3 days are 2 to 4 mm wide, circular, entire, smooth, white, and irridescent in obliquely transmitted light.</s><s>Submerged colonies are lenticular and 0.5 to 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Clearings due to solubilization of xylan surrounding surface colonies vary in diameter from 6 to 20 mm.</s><s>Xylan is extensively degraded within the clearings.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rumen fluid is not required for growth, but growth is slightly enhanced in the presence of carbon dioxide and bicarbonate.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by deletion of reducing agent provided that the medium remains reduced with respect to resazurin.</s><s>Injection of 5 ml of sterile air into 30-ml bottles containing 4 or 10 ml of medium oxidizes (at least partially) the resazurin indicator and causes complete inhibition of growth.</s><s>There is no growth at either 22 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the substrates which have been tested, only xylan and cellobiose are fermented when the inoculum for the tests is grown on xylan agar slopes (Table 2).</s><s>However, when the inoculum is grown on cellobiose agar slopes, esculin is also (but poorly) fermented (pH drop of 0.2 to 0.3 U) by all three strains.</s><s>The final pH in poorly buffered medium containing xylan or cellobiose does not drop below 5.6.</s><s>These bacteria utilize cellobiose but not glucose or xylose, which suggests that they may utilize xylobiose derived from xylan.</s><s>None of the strains produces indole or α-methylindole.</s><s>The strains do not liquefy gelatin, reduce nitrate, produce catalase, or hydrolyze starch.</s><s>Only strain X10D63 produces hydrogen sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation products are formic, acetic, and butyric acids (Table 3).</s><s>Gas and acetylmethylcarbinol are also produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39 mol% for the type strain X6C58 and for strain X10D63.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain X6C58 (= ATCC 35991), which was isolated from the rumen of a sheep.</s></p></content></protolog>