<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8672_nm.13366" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13366" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13366" rank="species">Hydrogenophaga bisanensis</organism><reference id="rid.8672"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenophaga bisanensis sp. nov., isolated from wastewater of a textile dye works.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>393</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65271-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218937</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hydrogenophaga bisanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hydrogenophaga bisanensis</em> (bi.san.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>bisanensis</em> of Bisan, Daegu, Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods (0.4–0.6×1.0–5.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on NA are circular to slightly irregular, raised, smooth, glistening, moderate yellow in colour and 1.5–3.0 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>The optimal temperature range for growth is 30–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15 and 46 °C, but not at 10 or 47 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH range for growth is 7.0–8.0; growth occurs at pH 6.5 and 9.5, but not at pH 6.0 or 10.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on NA, but does occur on NA supplemented with potassium nitrate.</s><s>Weakly positive for catalase.</s><s>Casein, hypoxanthine, xanthine, l-tyrosine, urea and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>In the API 20NE and API 50CH systems, adipate, glycerol, glucose and gluconate are utilized, but caprate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate are not utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to lincomycin.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.8 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K102<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12980<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 54518<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wastewater of a textile dye works at Bisan, Daegu city, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>