<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12431_nm.21264" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21264" rank="genus">Oceanotoga</organism><reference id="rid.12431"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jayasinghearachchi</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lal</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oceanotoga teriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a thermophilic bacterium isolated from offshore oil-producing wells</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>554</fpage><lpage>560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018036-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382783</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Oceanotoga</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Oceanotoga</em> (O.ce.a.no.to′ga. Gr. n. <em>okeanos</em> the ocean; L. fem. n. <em>toga</em> a covering, garment; N.L. fem. n. <em>Oceanotoga</em> an ocean toga, referring to the isolation of the organism from the ocean and the presence of a ‘toga’ sheath-like outer cover).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped with a sheath-like outer structure.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, no spores are formed.</s><s>During the stationary phase of growth, the rods form spherical structures that are still surrounded by the sheath.</s><s>Growth is anaerobic, moderately thermophilic and moderately halophilic.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and able to ferment a broad spectrum of carbohydrates and various proteinaceous substances.</s><s>Able to reduce thiosulfate and elemental sulphur to H<sub>2</sub>S, but these compounds are not essential for growth.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain of the type species is 26.8 mol%.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence comparisons place the genus <em>Oceanotoga</em> in the bacterial domain within the order <em>Thermotogales</em>, close to the <em>Geotoga</em> lineage.</s><s>The type species is <em>Oceanotoga teriensis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>