<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6153_nm.3365" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3365" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3365" rank="species">Yersinia rohdei</organism><reference id="rid.6153"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aleksic</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bockemühl</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huntley-Carter</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Yersinia rohdei sp. nov. isolated from human and dog feces and surface water.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>332</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-327</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Yersinia rohdei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Yersinia rohdei</i> (roh de. i. M.L. gen. n. <i>rohdei</i>, of Rohde)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Yersinia rohdei</i> is named in honor of the late Rolf Rohde, who founded the National Reference Centre for Salmonella in Hamburg, Federal Republic of Germany, and who made many significant contributions to the diagnostic and serological identification of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>, especially in the genus <i>Salmonella</i>.</s><s>Strains of <i>Y. rohdei</i> are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, fermentative, nonpigmented rods with the general characteristics of the family Enterobacteriaceae and of the genus Yersinia (Table 2).</s><s>They are motile at 25 to 28°C but not at 36°C.</s><s>All <i>Y. rohdei</i> strains give positive results in tests at 25 to 28°C for methyl red, citrate utilization (Simmons [may be delayed positive] and Christensen), urea hydrolysis (may be delayed positive), L-ornithine decarboxylase (Moeller) (may be delayed positive) tartrate fermenation (Jordan) (may be delayed positive), <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, and acid from fermenation of D-glucose, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose (may be delayed positive), glycerol (may be delayed positive), D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>All <i>Y. rohdei</i> strains give negative results after 48 h of incubation at 25 to 28°C in tests for indole production, the Voges-Proskauer reaction, H<sub>2</sub>S production (triple sugar iron agar and peptone iron agar), phenylalanine deaminase, L-lysine decarboxylase (Moeller) , L-arginine dihydrolase (Moeller), gelatin hydrolysis, malonate utilization, esculin hydrolysis, acid from mucate, acetate utilization, lipase (corn oil), deoxyribonuclease, tyrosine clearing, gas from D-glucose, and acid from the fermentation of adonitol, D-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, i(<i>myo</i>)-inositol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, and salicin.</s><s>Six of our seven strains produce acid from fermentation of lactose and maltose.</s><s>Strains vary in reactions for growth in KCN and acid production from fermentation of raffinose and melibiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains formed 2 biogroups on the basis of positive (biogroup 1) or negative (biogroup 2) reactions for both raffinose and melibiose.</s><s>Tests that differentiate <i>Y. rohdei</i> from other <i>Yersinia</i> species are shown in Table 3. <i>Y. rohdei</i> strains were resistant to or showed intermediate susceptibility to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, and penicillin and were susceptible to the other antimicrobial agents tested (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Y. rohdei</i> strains had G+C content of 48.7 to 49.4 mol%. <i>Y. rohdei</i> strains were isolated from the feces of dogs and humans and from surface water.</s><s>The clinical significance of <i>Y. rohdei</i> as a diarrheal agent in humans and animals is uncertain and requires further study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Y. rohdei</i> is strain H271-36/78(= 3022-85 = ATCC 43380).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Y. rohdei 3022-MT exhibits the characteristics of the species as given in Tables 2, 4, and 5.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 49.1 mol%.</s><s>It was isolated from dog feces in Germany in 1978.</s></p></content></protolog>