<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3414_nm.2865" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2865" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2865" rank="species">Microbulbifer hydrolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.3414"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moran</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hodson</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitman</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbulbifer hydrolyticus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Marinobacterium georgiense gen. nov., sp. nov., two marine bacteria from a lignin-rich pulp mill waste enrichment community.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>376</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-369</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103623</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbulbifer hydrolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbulbifer hydrolyticus</i> (hy.dro.ly'ti.cus. Gr. n. <i>hydor</i>, water; Gr. adj. lytikos, dissolving, splitting; M. L. adj. hydrolyticus, splitting with [by] water, referring to the hydrolytic activity of the bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of type strain IRE-31 are rod shaped (1.1 to 1.7 μm long and 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide in exponential-phase growth in glucose medium) and have numerous vesicles on their surfaces.</s><s>Cells are gram negative and nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 are cream colored.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 41°C, and optimal growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 0.1 to 1 M, and optimal growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 0.1 and 0.5 M.</s><s>The optimal pH is 7.5, and the pH range is 6.5 to 8.5.</s><s>The organism is a strict aerobe and does not denitrify or accumulate polyhydroxybutyrate.</s><s>It utilizes a limited number of carbohydrates and is able to grow only on glucose, xylose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, and cellobiose.</s><s>Amino acids and some aromatic compounds, such as vanillate and ferulate, are used.</s><s>Exhibits oxidase, catalase, cellulase, xylanase, chitinase, gelatinase, amylase and Tweenase activities.</s><s>Growth factors are not required, although a complex vitamin solution or a low concentration of yeast extract is stimulatory.</s><s>Capsules are produced in liquid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are resistant to penicillin G, streptomycin, and vancomycin and susceptible to tetracycline, kanamycin, chloramphenicol, and ampicillin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography is 57.7 mol%.</s><s>On the basis of its 16s rRNA sequence, IRE-31<sup>T</sup> belongs to the γ subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and forms a deep branch related to the pseudomonads sensu stricto.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a marine enrichment community growing on pulp mill effluent as the sole carbon source.</s><s>The original inoculum was from a salt marsh on the coast of Georgia.</s><s>Type strain IRE-31 has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700072.</s></p></content></protolog>