<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1606_nm.11344" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11344" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11344" rank="species">Rhodococcus kyotonensis</organism><reference id="rid.1606"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Furihata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>L.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus kyotonensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1956</fpage><lpage>1959</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64770-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766854</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodococcus kyotonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodococcus kyotonensis</em> (kyo.to.nen′sis. N.L masc. adj. <em>kyotonensis</em> pertaining to Kyoto, the source of soil from which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming and acid-fast actinomycete that forms non-branching hyphae which fragment into short rod-to-coccus elements.</s><s>Colonies on TSA medium are yellow–orange-pigmented, smooth and opaque.</s><s>Growth occurs well over a pH range (6.0–8.0) on the ISP2 medium; the optimal pH for growth is around 7.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C; with optimal growth temperature of 27–30 °C, growth cannot occur at 40 °C.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is up to 9 %.</s><s>Catalase activity is positive, whereas oxidase activity is negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Gelatin hydrolysis, citrate utilization, activities of ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, production of hydrogen sulfide and indole, and reduction of nitrate and nitrite are negative.</s><s>Positive results for the activities of esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, hydrolysis of aesculin and Voges–Proskauer test, but negative results for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C4), trypsin, chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, glucose, ribose, galactose, fructose, sorbose, rhamnose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol, d-arabitol, and gluconate as the sole carbon and energy sources, but erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, mannose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, 2-keto-gluconate and 5-keto-gluconate are not utilized.</s><s>Diamino acid in the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-DAP; arabinose and galactose dominate in the whole-cell hydrolysates (wall type IV).</s><s>The percentage of major menaquinone MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) is 94.6 %, minor menaquinones MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) is 2.8 and 2.6 %, respectively.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present, which co-migrate with those of the type strain of <em>R. rhodochrous</em>.</s><s>The fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (40.8 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (18.1 %), 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (17.5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (7.2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (5.5 %) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (2.1 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DS472<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15415<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB206088<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the soil in Kyoto city, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>