<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.335_nm.4146" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4146" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4146" rank="species">Pseudobutyrivibrio ruminis</organism><reference id="rid.335"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudobutyrivibrio ruminis, gen. nov., sp. nov., a butyrate-producing bacterium from the rumen that closely resembles Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens in phenotype.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>559</fpage><lpage>563</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-559</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudobutyrivibrio ruminis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudobutyrivibrio ruminis</i> (ru'mi.nis. L. neut. gen. n. <i>ruminis</i>, of the rumen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, curved rods, often with tapering ends.</s><s>Spores are not produced.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Cell width varies from 0.3 to 0.5 μm.</s><s>The length of most cells varies between 1 and 3 μm (Fig. 2A), while very long cells often occur, particularly when grown on agar medium (Fig. 2B).</s><s>When bacteria are mixed with rumen fluid-yeast extract-glucose-agar medium and cultured in roll bottles for 24 h, the colonies produced are convex, round with a smooth edge, and opaque with striations radiating from the center which cover about two-thirds of the inner area of colonies.</s><s>Colony diameters vary from 1.5 to 2 mm.</s><s>Submerged colonies are lens-shaped discs with diameters of about 0.5 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> ferments the following carbohydrates (final pH in parentheses): arabinose (5.1), cellobiose (5.1), fructose (5.0), galactose (5.1), glucose (5.0), lactose (5.3), maltose (5.1), mannose (5.4), sucrose (5.1), trehalose (5.1), and xylose (5.1).</s><s>Glycerol is weakly fermented (5.9), and the following do not support growth: mannitol, ribose, sorbitol, soluble starch, xylan, lactate, succinate, fumarate, oxalate, pyruvate, malonate, malate, aspartate, and glutamate.</s><s>Glucose (50 mM) is fermented to formate (29 mM), butyrate (19 mM), lactate (40 mM), and a small amount of acetate (less than 1 mM).</s><s>Types and amounts of gases produced were not determined.</s><s>The maximum optical densities (600 nm, in tubes of 13.5 mm [inside diameter]) reached in medium containing rumen fluid (40%), yeast extract (0.5%), and glucose (50 mM) and in similar media from which either rumen fluid, yeast extract, or glucose was omitted were 1.8, 1.2, 0.5, and 0.2, respectively.</s><s>Hourly optical density measurements in medium containing 50 mM glucose, 40% rumen fluid, and 0.5% yeast extract with an inoculum constituting 4% of the total volume indicated that the shortest doubling time occurred within the first 2 h of incubation and was about 20 min.</s><s>The maximum optical density was reached after about 6 h.</s><s>Values for growth in medium prepared anoxically are similar, irrespective of whether reducing agent (cysteine plus sulfide) is added, but when air (2 ml per 5 ml of medium in 13-ml tubes) is added to medium without a reducing agent there is practically no growth.</s><s>There is very little growth at 45°C and hardly any growth at 22°C relative to that at 39°C, at which temperature there is good growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characterization tests and G+C content.</s><s>Strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> does not liquefy gelatin or produce hydrogen sulfide; neither does it reduce nitrate, hydrolyze urea, or produce catalase.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40.5 mol% (mean for four separate determinations; standard error of the mean, 0.64).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The major components of the cellular fatty acids of strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> grown in medium without rumen fluid or volatile fatty acid mixture are saturated straight-chain C<sub>14:0</sub> and C<sub>16:0</sub> fatty acids and aldehydes (Table 3).</s><s>Odd-chain and iso- and/or anteiso-fatty acids were found only in cells grown in media with rumen fluid (40% [vol/vol]) or the volatile fatty acid mixture of Caldwell and Bryant (3).</s><s>Thus, strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> differs significantly in its fatty acid composition from <i>Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens</i> type strain D1, which has been reported to contain major amounts of C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>cis</i> 11 aldehydes (16) or C<sub>18:1</sub> fatty acids (12% of total) (10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> is the type strain and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 9787<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comments.</s><s>As mentioned earlier, the older definitions of <i>B. fibrisolvens</i> would have included <i>P. ruminis</i>.</s><s>It has long been recognized that bacteria classified as <i>B. fibrisolvens</i> include a wide variety of biotypes (1, 2, 6, 9, 25).</s><s>Thus, it is considered very likely that more strains, currently classified as <i>B. fibrisolvens</i>, will be found to differ significantly from the type strain and that they will be placed in other species or genera.</s><s>The phenotypical characteristics which differentiate <i>B. fibrisolvens</i> and <i>P. ruminis</i> are that <i>P. ruminis</i> does not grow on xylan or starch and is not proteolytic (does not liquefy gelatin).</s><s>Whereas <i>B. fibrisolvens</i> cells contain major amounts of C<sub>18</sub> fatty acids, <i>P. ruminis</i> cells do not.</s><s>The tendency to produce very long cells, particularly when grown on agar media, is characteristic of <i>P. ruminis</i> but not of <i>B. fibrisolvens</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A12-1<sup>T</sup> was isolated from a 10<sup>-8</sup> dilution of rumen ingesta, which suggests that <i>P. ruminis</i> could contribute meaningfully to fermentation in the rumen.</s><s>The strain was obtained from a culture capable of fermenting succinate with the production of propionate.</s><s>It remains to be seen whether succinate-fermenting isolates, morphologically similar to A12-1<sup>T</sup>, can be obtained from the succinate-fermenting culture.</s></p></content></protolog>