<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11777_nm.19884" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19884" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19884" rank="species">Paenalcaligenes hominis</organism><reference id="rid.11777"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Langer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenalcaligenes hominis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new
member of the family Alcaligenaceae</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1537</fpage><lpage>1542</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016576-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684310</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><em>Description of Paenalcaligenes hominis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenalcaligenes hominis</em> (ho′mi.nis. L. gen. n. <em>hominis</em> of a man, of a human being, named because the type and only known strain is of human origin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as for the genus, with the following additions.</s><s>On NA, colonies are beige and circular with an entire margin.</s><s>Grows at 30, 37 and 42 °C; no growth at 4 °C.</s><s>l-Alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) is hydrolysed, on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, bis-pNP phenylphosphonate, bis-pNP phosphorylcholine, l-aniline pNA, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA and l-proline pNA.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole sources of carbon on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991): acetate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, pyruvate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate and dl-lactate.</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-gluconate, maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, glutarate, itaconate, l-malate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, propionate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>No acids are produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s>Exhibits the chemotaxonomic characteristics listed in the genus description.</s><s>In addition, two unidentified aminolipids (AL1, AL2) and three unidentified lipids (L1, L2, L3) are detectable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 53761A<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7698<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human blood from an 85-year-old man in Göteborg, Sweden.</s></p></content></protolog>