<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3866_nm.11788" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11788" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8833" rank="species">Salipiger mucescens</organism><reference id="rid.3866"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martínez-Cánovas</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>del Moral</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salipiger mucescens gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium isolated from hypersaline soil, belonging to the alpha-Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1735</fpage><lpage>1740</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63166-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388737</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salipiger mucescens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salipiger mucescens</em> (mu.ces′cens. L. masc. ppl. adj. <em>mucescens</em> slimy).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the traits reported for the genus, the species grows on MY solid medium in the form of circular, convex, cream-coloured, mucoid colonies.</s><s>In liquid medium its growth pattern is uniform.</s><s>The cells are encapsulated.</s><s>It is moderately halophilic, capable of growing in salt concentrations (mixture of sea salts) from 0·5 to 20 % w/v, the optimum range being between 3 and 6 % w/v.</s><s>Nevertheless, if NaCl is substituted for sea salts, the concentration required for optimum growth reaches values of 9 to 10 % w/v.</s><s>It grows within the temperature range of 20 to 40 °C and at pH values of between 6 and 10.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Selenite reduction, gluconate oxidation and phosphatase are positive.</s><s>Urea and Tween 20 are hydrolysed.</s><s>It does not produce acids from the following sugars: adonitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose and d-trehalose.</s><s>O/F, ONPG, indole, methyl-red and Voges–Proskauer are negative.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase is not produced.</s><s>Tyrosine, Tween 80, starch, aesculin, gelatin, DNA, lecithin and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Growth on either MacConkey or cetrimide agar is unviable.</s><s>Blood is not haemolysed.</s><s>Neither nitrate nor nitrite is reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are not acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-salicin, acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, glycerol, lactate, malonate, propionate and succinate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>It is susceptible to (μg) amoxicillin (25), ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefotaxime (30), cefoxitin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), rifampicin (30), sulfonamide (250), tobramycin (10) and trimetoprim/sulphametoxazol (1·25/23·7), and is resistant to nalidixic acid (30) and polymixin B (300).</s><s>The major fatty acids (%) are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (78·0), 16 : 0 (12·4), 12 : 1 3-OH (2·3), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (2·3), 18 : 0 (2·0) and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/15 : 0 iso 2-OH (1·3).</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 64·5 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain A3<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5855<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22090<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16094<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a hypersaline soil taken from a solar saltern in Calblanche (Murcia, south-eastern Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>