<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12257_nm.20257" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20257" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20257" rank="species">Cohnella xylanilytica</organism><reference id="rid.12257"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khianngam</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akaracharanya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cohnella xylanilytica sp. nov. and Cohnella terrae sp. nov., xylanolytic bacteria from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2913</fpage><lpage>2917</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017855-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20097800</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cohnella xylanilytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cohnella xylanilytica</em> (xy.la.ni.ly′ti.ca. N.L. neut. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lytica</em> from Gr. masc. adj. <em>lytikos</em> able to loose, dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>xylanilytica</em> xylan-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive, rod-shaped (0.3–0.5×1.4–3.5 μm), facultatively anaerobic and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Central ellipsoidal endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 2 days of incubation on C agar medium, colonies are 1–3 mm in diameter, circular, flat and white.</s><s>Grows in 3 % (w/v) NaCl (weakly), at pH 6–9, at 20–45 °C and at 50 °C (weakly) and under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Does not grow in 5 % (w/v) NaCl, at pH 5 or at 10, 15, 55 or 60 °C.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase activity, hydrolysis of aesculin, DNA, starch, Tween 80 and gelatin (weak), assimilation of l-arabinose, d-glucose, malic acid, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and potassium gluconate.</s><s>Negative for citrate utilization, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production, MR and VP reactions, nitrate reduction and urease activity, hydrolysis of l-arginine, casein and l-tyrosine and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, capric acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-glucopyranoside, glucose, glycogen, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, <em>β</em>-xylopyranoside, xylitol and d-xylose.</s><s>No acid production from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, gluconate, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, <em>α</em>-mannopyranoside, melezitose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose and l-xylose.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and lysyl-phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Unknown phospholipids and aminophospholipids are present.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MX15-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22294<sup>T</sup> =PCU 309<sup>T</sup> =TISTR 1891<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>