<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8721_nm.13436" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13436" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13436" rank="species">Microbacterium hatanonis</organism><reference id="rid.8721"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bakir</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium hatanonis sp. nov., isolated as a contaminant of hairspray.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>654</fpage><lpage>658</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65160-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319473</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium hatanonis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium hatanonis</em> (ha.ta.no′nis. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>hatanonis</em> of Hatano, in honour of Dr Kazunori Hatano, for his contribution to the understanding of the genus <em>Microbacterium</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, non-motile, Gram-positive organism.</s><s>Microaerophilic; does not grow on TSA under an anaerobic atmosphere (CO<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Typically, cells are rods, approximately 0.8 μm wide and 1.7 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex with entire margins, moist, shiny and light yellow.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, with optimal growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0, with optimal growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>No growth occurs at NaCl concentrations above 2 %; optimal growth occurs without the addition of NaCl.</s><s>Demonstrates positive results for catalase, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, maltose and potassium gluconate.</s><s>Weakly positive for malate assimilation.</s><s>Gives positive results for the production of esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Shows negative results for oxidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis, utilization of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid and for the production of alkaline phosphatase, lipase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 69.0 mol%, the major isoprenoid quinones are MK-12 (37.5 %) and MK-11 (34.8 %) and the major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (48.1 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (34.7 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (10.5 %).</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are rhamnose and galactose.</s><s>Diamino acid ornithine is present in the cell-wall hydrolysates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FCC-01<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14558<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19179<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from hairspray.</s></p></content></protolog>