<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5916_nm.10116" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10116" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10116" rank="species">Flavobacterium segetis</organism><reference id="rid.5916"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium weaverense sp. nov. and Flavobacterium segetis sp. nov., novel psychrophiles isolated from the Antarctic</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1239</fpage><lpage>1244</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64164-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium segetis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium segetis</em> (se.ge′tis. L. gen. n. <em>segetis</em> of the soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive and psychrophilic.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped with rounded ends, approximately 1.1–2.3×0.2–0.3 μm and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are convex, translucent, glistening, butyrous, orange, circular with entire margins and become mucoid after prolonged incubation on R2A or AOA.</s><s>Does not glide or adhere to agar plates.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Congo red is not adsorbed.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A, AOA, MA, NA and TSA, but not on cetrimide or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Grows well under aerobic conditions, weakly under microaerobic conditions (with 5–15 % O<sub>2</sub> and 5–12 % CO<sub>2</sub> created by use of the CampyPack Plus system) and poorly under anaerobic conditions (with 4–10 % CO<sub>2</sub> created by use of the GasPack Plus system).</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–11 (optimum pH 7) and with 0–3 % NaCl (optimum 0 %).</s><s>Grows at 5.0–21.8 °C with notional minimum, optimum and maximum growth temperatures of −29.7, 14.3 and 18.9 °C, respectively.</s><s>Minimum doubling time is 6.8 h.</s><s>Decomposes starch and Tween 80, but not alginate, chitin or elastin.</s><s>Negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, urease, l-phenylalanine deaminase, indole production and alkalinization on Christensen's citrate agar.</s><s>Produces acid from d-cellobiose, d-glucose, d-trehalose, maltose and sucrose, but not from d-fructose, d-mannitol, d-raffinose, d-salicin, d-xylose, l-arabinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>Produces acid from lactose after prolonged incubation (4 weeks).</s><s>In API ZYM kits, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present; weak esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, trypsin and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities are present; and esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine (weakly) and maltose as sole carbon sources in API 20NE kits, but not arabinose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 2.</s><s>Maximum absorption peak of pigment is at 472 nm and the next shoulder is at 452 nm.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (containing C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH); the full fatty acid profile is given in Table 1.</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AT1048<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 14050<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12224<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12385<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample of a penguin habitat near the King Sejong Station on King George Island, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>