<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14701" rank="species">Rhodoluna limnophila</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhodoluna limnophila’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhodoluna limnophila’ [Rho.do.lu′na. Gr. adj. <em>rhodeos</em> rosy; L. fem. n. <em>luna</em> the moon; N.L. fem. n. <em>Rhodoluna</em> rosy (red) moon, referring to the red pigmentation and the selenoid morphology of the first strain. lim.no′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>limnos</em> lake; N.L. fem. adj. <em>phila</em> from Gr. fem. adj. <em>philê</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>limnophila</em> lake-loving]. Represented by the aerobic, red-pigmented strain MWH-VicMua1, which was isolated from Lake Victoria (East Africa). The strain is contained in a mixed culture with only a small fraction of non-actinobacterial cells. Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-VicMua1 (GenBank accession no. AJ565417) and the combined presence of the two oligonucleotide sequences 5′-GTTCCATTCCACGGAATCC-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 836–852) and 5′-AATACCGCAAGGTGGAGCGAATCCCATAA-3′ (<em>E. coli</em> positions 1260–1288) within the 16S rRNA gene. This trait is also present in four environmental sequences (Supplementary Fig. S2), which were obtained from a freshwater reservoir in the Czech Republic (two clones), Lake Niegocin in Poland (Warnecke <em>et al.</em>, 2004) and an upland stream in Germany (Beier <em>et al.</em>, 2008). These four environmental sequences and the strain MWH-VicMua1 form together a cluster with sequence similarities &#x003E;98.8 % (Supplementary Fig. S2).</s></p></content></protolog>