<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1051_nm.24362" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.24362" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6284" rank="species">Dietzia natronolimnaios</organism><reference id="rid.1051"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Duckworth</surname><given-names>A.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meijer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dietzia natronolimnaios sp. nov., a new member of the genus Dietzia isolated from an east African soda lake</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>359</fpage><lpage>366</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9783184</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dietzia natronolimnaios</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dietzia natronolimnaios</i> (na. tro. no. lim.na.ios. Gr. n. <i>natrum</i> soda, salt; Gr. adj. <i>limnaois</i> of a lake; Gr. gen. <i>natronolimnaois</i> of the soda lake)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive nonmotile nonspore-forming rods, 0.9-1.1 μm by 1.2-2.3 μm.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Short, rod-shaped cells exhibit snapping division and produce V forms.</s><s>Cells in liquid culture form micro-colonies of up to 50-60 cells.</s><s>Growth occurs on Brain Heart Infusion Agar and alkaline agar media.</s><s>Circular, convex, glistening colonies with entire margins are formed on agar.</s><s>Colonies initially orange in color, becoming coral red with age.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; growth occurs at between pH 6 and 10 with an optimum around pH 9.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the peptidoglycan is meso-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Grows well at between 20°C and 40°C with a temperature optimum around 30°C.</s><s>Grows slowly at 10°C and 45°C; no growth at 50°C.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids are present (34-38 carbon atoms).</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are predominantly saturated and monounsaturated fatty acids (C16:0, C18:0, C18:1, C20:0).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tuberculostearic acid (10-methyloctadecanoic acid) is present.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Menaquinone MK8 (H<sub>2</sub>) is the major isoprenoid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Under neutral conditions, acetate, fructose, fumarate, glutamate, succinate, mannitol, D-glucose, propionate, suberate, valerate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, citrate, glycogen, L-serine, L-proline, L-asparagine, L-arginine, methionine, phenylalanine, L-glycine, and L-valine are utilized for growth, but not D-galactose, lactose, D-sucrose, rhamnose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-ribose, inositol, itaconate, malonate, DL-lactate, salicin, D-melibiose, L-fucose, D-sorbitol, L-arabinose, caprate, 5-ketogluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, L-alanine, L-histidine, or L-lysine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from littoral sediments of Lake Oloidien (Little Lake Naivasha), Kenya.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of the DNA is 66.1% ± 0.4 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is 15LN1, deposited as CBS 107.95 at the Central Bureaux Schimmel Cultures, Baarn, The Netherlands.</s></p></content></protolog>