<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10768_nm.17864" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17864" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17864" rank="species">Planococcus salinarum</organism><reference id="rid.10768"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>K.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.-K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planococcus salinarum sp. nov., isolated from a marine solar saltern, and emended description of the genus Planococcus</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>754</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013136-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656937</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Planococcus salinarum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Planococcus salinarum</em> (sa.li.na′rum. L. pl. gen. n. <em>salinarum</em> of salterns).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive and non-motile, occurring as cocci, short rods or rods (0.4–0.8×0.8–5.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, raised to slightly convex, glistening, smooth, pale yellow in colour and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 38 °C, but not at 39 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 7.5; growth occurs at pH 6.0, but not at pH 5.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs in 0–13.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> ions are required for growth.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA or on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Casein and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, xanthine and l-tyrosine are not.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose or d-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G and streptomycin, but not to polymyxin B or tetracycline.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, leucine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase are present and esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are weakly present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-8 and MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ISL-16<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13584<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 57753<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a marine solar saltern of the Yellow Sea, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.3 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>