<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7101_nm.6785" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6785" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6785" rank="species">Actinokineospora inagensis</organism><reference id="rid.7101"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayakawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nonomura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Four new species of the genus Actinokineospora: Actinokineospora inagensis sp. nov., Actinokineospora globicatena sp. nov., Actinokineospora terrea sp. nov., Actinokineospora diospyrosa sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>371</fpage><lpage>378</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinokineospora inagensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinokineospora inagensis</i> (in.ag.en'sis. M. L. adj. <i>inagensis</i>, pertaining to Lake Inaga, the lake from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Actinokineospora inagensis</i> is a gram-positive, non-acid-fast, aerobic organism with branching hyphae.</s><s>Nonfragmenting, yellow to tan vegetative mycelia are present.</s><s>Spores are formed in chains containing several members and are motile.</s><s>The spores are oval or short rods (diameter, 1.3 to 2.0 μm) and exhibit motility when they are suspended in sterile distilled water.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 14 to 33°C, and good growth occurs at temperatures between 22 and 27°C.</s><s>The organism grows well on Bennett's agar.</s><s>In general, the vegetative mycelia are yellow to tan, and the aerial mycelia are white to gray.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction negative.</s><s>Does not hydrolyze starch.</s><s>Does not decompose calcium malate.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 2% NaCl.</s><s>Peptonization of milk is negative.</s><s>Fructose and rhamnose are slightly utilized as carbon sources, but inositol, arabinose, sucrose, xylose, mannitol, raffinose, mannose, maltose, galactose, lactose, and glucitol are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain glutamic acid, glycine, alanine, and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid (molar ratio, ca. 1:1:2:1).</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is type A (probably Alγ) according to the classification of Schleifer and Kandler (12).</s><s>Arabinose and galactose are the characteristic whole-cell sugars.</s><s>iso-Hexadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> is the major cellular fatty acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 69.1 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H4), and a small amount of MK-7(H<sub>4</sub>) is also present.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine is the diagnostic phospholipid, and phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, and an unidentified phospholipid are absent (type PII).</s><s>Habitat: fallen leaves.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IFO 15663 (=YU4-1).</s></p></content></protolog>