<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7776" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7776" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7776" rank="species">Chlamydophila caviae</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> sp. nov., including guinea pig inclusion conjunctivitis isolates previously belonging to <i>Chlamydia psittaci</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> (ca'vi.ae. L. gen. fem. n. <i>caviae</i> of the guinea pig (<i>Cavia cobaya</i>) because the type strain was isolated from <i>Cavia cobaya</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> was first recovered from the conjunctiva of guinea pigs and the description of this species is identical to that of the isolate GPIC (Gordon et al., 1966; Murray, 1964; Prain &#x0026; Pearce, 1989).</s><s>There are five known <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> isolates, and the ompA (ompl) sequences of these isolates are identical (Zhao et al., 1993).</s><s>Analyses of signature sequences (Figs 3 and 4) or other gene sequences, including 16s rRNA, can be used to distinguish this species.</s><s>GPIC contains an extrachromosomal plasmid, pCpGP1 (Lusher et al., 1989).</s><s>The natural site of <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> infection is the conjunctiva, however, it is possible to infect the genital tract of guinea pigs with <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> and elicit a disease that is very similar to human genital infection. <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> is markedly specific for guinea pigs, as attempts to infect mice, hamsters, rabbits and gerbils have been unsuccessful, except for one experimentally infected gerbil. <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> infects primarily the mucosal epithelium and is not invasive.</s><s>The type strain for <i>Chlamydophila caviae</i> is GPIC<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC VR 813<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>