<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1493_nm.6040" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6040" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6040" rank="species">Microbacterium aurum</organism><reference id="rid.1493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of two new species in the genus Microbacterium: Microbacterium dextranolyticum sp. nov. and Microbacterium aurum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>549</fpage><lpage>554</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium aurum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium aurum</i> (au'rum. L.n. <i>aurum</i>, gold)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on solid media in air; colonies are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, low convex with entire margins, opaque, and moist.</s><s>A golden yellow pigment is produced.</s><s>In young cultures, small, slender rods are formed.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at angles, forming V shapes; primary branching is uncommon.</s><s>In older cultures rods are shorter, but a marked rod-coccus growth cycle does not occur.</s><s>Gram-positive rods that are not acid fast and not motile.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is ca. 30°C.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from glucose, mannose, fructose, maltose, cellobiose, mannitol, galactose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, and inulin, but not from D-xylose, L-arabinose, D-arabinose, glycerol, arbutin, esculin, salicin, ethanol, butanol, melibiose, melezitose, ribose, L-sorbose, xylitol, erythritol, adonitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, inositol, methanol, and α-methyl-D-glumside.</s><s>Acetate, α-ketoglutarate, and succinate are assimilated, but pyruvate, lactate, malate, maleate, formate, butyrate, oxalate, pimelate, glycolate, glyoxylate, gluconate, propionate, and hippurate are not assimilated.</s><s>Esculin, starch, and Tween 60 are hydrolyzed, but Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 80, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer reaction negative.</s><s>Arginine is not decarboxylated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine as the diamino acid (variation B1β).</s><s>The glycan moiety of the wall contains glycolyl and acetyl residues.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are fucose, galactose, and glucose.</s><s>Mycolic acid is not present.</s><s>The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are primarily anteiso- and isomethyl branched acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>Unsaturated menaquinones with 11 and 12 isoprene units are present.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and dimannosyldiacylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 69.2 mol% G+C.</s><s>Source: isolated from commercially available corn steep liquor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IFO 15204</s></p></content></protolog>