<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2012_nm.10731" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10731" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10731" rank="species">Frondicola australicus</organism><reference id="rid.2012"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Frondicola australicus gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from decaying leaf litter from a pine forest.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1177</fpage><lpage>1182</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64560-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551025</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Frondicola australicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Frondicola australicus</em> (aus.tra′li.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>australicus</em> pertaining to Australia, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following properties in addition to those given in the description of the genus.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming, aerobic, irregular, short rods (0.5–1.0×0.2–0.4 μm) that stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Cell wall appears to be made of a protein subunit layer and inclusion bodies are present.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperature between 15 and 37 °C (optimum temperature, 25 °C) and at pH 6.0–9.5 (optimum, pH 9.1).</s><s>The type strain metabolizes dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, maltose, d-melibiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid and urocanic acid.</s><s>Does not metabolize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>The type B2<em>β</em> {Gly} [l-hsr] d-glu–d-Orn peptidoglycan contains the amino acids ornithine, alanine, glycine, homoserine and glutamic acid in a molar ratio of 1.0 : 0.9 : 1.7 : 0.5 : 1.0, respectively.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (78 %) and the major menaquinones detected are MK-8 (76 %) and MK-7 (24 %).</s><s>The glycolipids disphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and three unidentified phospholipids are present.</s><s>The DNA base content is 71±1 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain E1HC-02<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13598<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17894<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the decaying leaf litter of a slash pine forest located in southeast Queensland, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>