<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5956_nm.8601" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8601" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8601" rank="species">Haemophilus pittmaniae</organism><reference id="rid.5956"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nørskov-Lauritsen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bruun</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Multilocus sequence phylogenetic study of the genus Haemophilus with description of Haemophilus pittmaniae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>449</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63325-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653917</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haemophilus pittmaniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haemophilus pittmaniae</em> (pitt.ma′ni.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>pittmaniae</em> of Pittman, named in honour of Margaret Pittman for her substantial contributions to <em>Haemophilus</em> research).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-motile, facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, small, pleomorphic rods, with occasional long, filamentous forms.</s><s>Colonies on chocolate agar are greyish white and reach a diameter of 1–2 mm after 24 h at 35 °C.</s><s>A distinct <em>β</em>-haemolytic zone is produced around the colonies on horse or sheep blood agar.</s><s>Depends on V-factor for growth on brain heart infusion agar plates, but is capable of growth on blood plates due to release of V-factor from lysed blood cells.</s><s>Positive in the porphyrin test, negative or weakly positive in catalase and oxidase tests.</s><s>Negative in the indole and urease tests.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, sucrose, d-mannose, d-galactose and maltose.</s><s>A small amount of gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from lactose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, sorbose, melibiose, inulin, aesculin or amygdalin.</s><s>Negative in lysine and ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase tests.</s><s>Negative for IgA1 protease.</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG), alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase and leucine arylamidase, but not <em>β</em>-glucosidase (NPG), <em>α</em>-glucosidase (PNPG), <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase (GNAC), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (PGUA) or <em>α</em>-fucosidase (ONPF).</s><s>Of the nine strains analysed, six are positive for <em>γ</em>-glutamyl transferase (GGT) activity and one is positive for <em>β</em>-lactamase activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HK 85<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 48703<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13334<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human saliva.</s><s>The species is part of the normal flora of the oral mucous membranes of man.</s><s>It is an opportunistic pathogen and has been isolated from various sites of infection, including blood and bile.</s></p></content></protolog>