<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6133_nm.10260" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10260" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10260" rank="species">Pedobacter aquatilis</organism><reference id="rid.6133"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter aquatilis sp. nov., isolated from drinking water, and emended description of the genus Pedobacter</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1853</fpage><lpage>1858</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64176-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902020</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter aquatilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter aquatilis</em> (a.qua.ti′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>aquatilis</em> aquatic, growing in water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 0.8–1×2–6 μm in size, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells are non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on TSA plates are pale pink, round and convex and 1–2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 28 °C.</s><s>Pigments do not give the typical flexirubin reaction with 20 % KOH.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of ≥2 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 4 and 30 °C (optimal temperature 25–28 °C) and at pH 5–9 (optimal pH 6–7).</s><s>Good growth occurs in R2A and TSA media but not on MacConkey agar medium.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase activities.</s><s>Negative for urease activity.</s><s>Negative for indole and in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S from thiosulfate.</s><s>Starch, aesculin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed but casein, DNA and gelatin are not.</s><s>Negative result in the Simmons' citrate test.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acid is not produced oxidatively from d-galactose, d-mannose, d-glucose, d-arabinose, fructose or d-maltose.</s><s>Negative for glucose fermentation.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, gentiobiose and d-turanose are used as carbon sources.</s><s>Glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inulin, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid are not used as carbon sources.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not present.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), ampicillin (10), neomycin (10), nalidixic acid (30), streptomycin (10) bacitracin (10 U), penicillin (10 U), kanamycin (30), cefazolin (30) and gentamicin (10).</s><s>Shows an intermediate reaction to the following antibiotics (μg per disc): chloramphenicol (30), tetracycline (30), erythromycin (15) and rifampicin (30).</s><s>The fatty acid composition is shown in Table 2.</s><s>Sphingolipids are present.</s><s>MK-7 is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain AR107<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7347<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7114<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13454<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from drinking water.</s></p></content></protolog>