<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6300_nm.8724" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8724" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8724" rank="species">Mycobacterium saskatchewanense</organism><reference id="rid.6300"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Turenne</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thibert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burdz</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>V.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolfe</surname><given-names>J.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cockcroft</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kabani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium saskatchewanense sp. nov., a novel slowly growing scotochromogenic species from human clinical isolates related to Mycobacterium interjectum and Accuprobe-positive for Mycobacterium avium complex</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>659</fpage><lpage>667</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02739-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143004</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium saskatchewanense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium saskatchewanense</em> (sas.kat.che.wa.nen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>saskatchewanense</em> pertaining to Saskatchewan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid–alcohol-fast, long, beaded rods.</s><s>Grows at 25–37 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>The organism shows a bright yellow pigment under both light and dark conditions.</s><s>Strains with an identical 16S rRNA gene sequence to that of 00-250<sup>T</sup> are MAC AccuProbe positive.</s><s>Negative for acid phosphatase, arylsulfatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, niacin, nitrate reductase, pyrazinamidase and urease and does not grow on 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Some strains show a thin film of growth on MacConkey agar without crystal violet.</s><s>Other variable test results include semi-quantitative catalase and tellurite reduction.</s><s>Most isolates are strongly positive for Tween 80 hydrolysis and all isolates have heat-stable catalase activity.</s><s>Mycolic acids of the cell wall produce a single-cluster pattern by HPLC, typical of <em>M. kubicae</em>, <em>M. palustre</em> and some documented clinical strains of <em>M. interjectum</em>.</s><s>Sequencing of the 16S rRNA, <em>hsp65</em> gene and ITS1 region reveals unique data that are crucial in the differentiation of this species from selected NTM species.</s><s>Isolates are susceptible <em>in vitro</em> to amikacin, clarithromycin, ciprofloxacin, linezolid, levofloxacin, moxifloxacin, rifabutin, rifampicin, streptomycin and sulfamethoxazole and are resistant to isoniazid.</s><s>Eighty-six per cent of isolates are susceptible to ethambutol, with a resistance breakpoint of 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from human respiratory samples and were proven to be clinically significant in our case study.</s><s>Strain MB54784 may constitute a distinct species, since it shows significant <em>hsp65</em> and ITS1 sequence variation; however, due to phenotypic and 16S rDNA similarities, this is difficult to establish at this time.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 00-250<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-544<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44616<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108114<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the sputum of a patient with bronchiectasis.</s></p></content></protolog>