<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12566_nm.21811" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21811" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21811" rank="species">Serinicoccus chungangensis</organism><reference id="rid.12566"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Traiwan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serinicoccus chungangensis sp. nov., isolated from tidal flat sediment, and emended description of the genus Serinicoccus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1299</fpage><lpage>1303</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025635-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20639223</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Serinicoccus chungangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Serinicoccus chungangensis</em> (chung.ang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>chungangensis</em> of or belonging to Chung-Ang University, where the taxonomic studies on this species were performed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, moderately halophilic, non-sporulating, strictly aerobic, non-motile cocci.</s><s>Colonies are yellow with convex and entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–40 °C (optimum 30 °C), at pH 5.0–11.0 (optimum pH 9.0) and in the presence of 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 13 %).</s><s>Positive in tests for catalase, nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis and assmilation of ferric citrate and capric acid.</s><s>Positive in tests for enzyme activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone MK8 (H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain mainly glucose and ribose.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol and an unknown lipid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CAU 9536<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 19774<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 59777<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat sediment sample collected from Seogmo Island in the Yellow Sea, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>