<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5856_nm.6195" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6195" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6195" rank="species">Corynebacterium appendicis</organism><reference id="rid.5856"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium appendicis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1165</fpage><lpage>1169</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02141-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148623</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium appendicis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium appendicis</i> (ap.pen'di.cis. L. fem. gen. n. <i>appendicis</i> of the appendix, pertaining to appendicitis, from which the patient from whom the clinical material was taken for isolation of the organism was suffering)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive and non-acid-alcohol-fast.</s><s>Cells are thin, non-motile, non-spore-forming and pleomorphic coryneform.</s><s>On Columbia blood agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood, dry, very small (diameter &#x003C;0.5 mm), slightly greyish colonies are formed after 2 days incubation at 37 °C; these colonies are non-haemolytic.</s><s>Larger, slightly creamy colonies are obtained when the organism grows on BHI agar and on trypticase soy agar supplemented with 1% Tween 80.</s><s>Grows facultatively anaerobically and is catalase-positive.</s><s>Contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e. cell-wall chemotype IV).</s><s>Corynemycolic acids are present and the fatty acid profile contains saturated, unsaturated and tuberculostearic acids.</s><s>Type PI phospholipid pattern with no nitrogen-containing compounds.</s><s>Produces acid from glycerol.</s><s>Acid production from glucose and maltose is positive using the MINITEK (incubation time 3 days) and API CORYNE (incubation time 7 days) systems.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, arabitol, cellobiose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, pullulan, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose or xylose.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin, gelatin, hippurate or starch.</s><s>Displays urease, alkaline phosphatase and pyrazinamidase activities but not acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), lipase (C14), α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin or nitrate reductase.</s><s>Acetoin production is positive but indole production is negative.</s><s>Produces lactate as the major product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>TheG­C content is 65.8 mol% for the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain IMMIB R-3491<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44531<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24151<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an abdominal swab of a patient with appendicitis accompanied with abscess formation.</s></p></content></protolog>