<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6724_nm.5521" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5521" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5521" rank="species">Trichococcus flocculiformis</organism><reference id="rid.6724"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKenzie</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Trichococcus, description of Trichococcus collinsii sp. nov., and reclassification of Lactosphaera pasteurii as Trichococcus pasteurii comb. nov. and of Ruminococcus palustris as Trichococcus palustris comb. nov. in the low-G+C gram-positive bacteria.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1113</fpage><lpage>1126</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02085-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148615</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Trichococcus flocculiformis</i> (Scheff et al. 1984b)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>T. flocculiformis</i> is a previously described organism, originally isolated from bulking sludge in Germany (Scheff et al., 1984a). Results in this study suggest that `<i>N. limicola</i>' I (strains Ben 200, Ben 201 and Ben 77) and `<i>C. allantoicus</i>' NDP should be merged into this species, even though some of these strains exhibit morphologies which may differ from the original descriptions of cocci in chains. Under certain culture conditions, <i>T. flocculiformis</i> Echt<sup>T</sup> grows as single cells or as paired, rod-shaped cells. In addition to the properties given in the genus description above and the original species description, members of this species have the following characteristics. Cells are spherical to ovoid; some strains grow as olive-shaped cells. Colonies on SR2A agar are white, opaque, circular and convex. All strains show no growth with L-tartrate. Only some strains grow on allantoin and L-malate. Only some produce acid from inositol, sorbitol, mannitol, raffinose and adonitol; only some reduce nitrate and are urease positive. Fatty acid composition is C<sub>14:0</sub> (8-14%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (12-24%), C<sub>16:1</sub> (39-50%), C<sub>iso-17:1</sub> (1-4%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (1-3%) and C<sub>18:1(<i>ω</i>9<i>c</i></sub> (14-23%). The G+C content is 47-49 mol%. Isolated from activated sludge in different parts of the world or from duckpond sediment in the USA. The type strain of <i>Trichococcus flocculiformis</i> is Echt<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 2094<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>