<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.641_nm.5540" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5540" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5540" rank="species">Enterococcus hirae</organism><reference id="rid.641"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus hirae, a new species that includes amino acid assay strain NCDO 1258 and strains causing growth depression in young chickens.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>75</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-1-73</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus hirae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus hirae</i> (hir.ae. L.gen.s.n. <i>hirae</i> of the intestine or gut)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid and occur mostly in pairs or short chains.</s><s>The cells are gram positive and nonmotile.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood or nutrient agar are circular, smooth, and entire.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 45°C, in 6.5% NaCl, and at pH 9.6.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>L-Lactic acid is the major end product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze esculin, are Voges-Proskauer, arginine dehydrolase, β-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, and pyrrolidonylarylamidase positive, and proddce acid from amygdalin, arbutin, N-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, β-gentiobiose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>All strains fail to produce acid from adonitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycogen, gluconate, inositol, inulin, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, D-lyxose, mannitol, amethyl- D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methylxyloside, rhamnose, sorbose, sorbitol, xylital, D-xylose, and L-xylose, do not hydrolyze hippurate, and are alkaline phosphatase and β-glucuronidase negative.</s><s>Variable results are obtained for glycerol (one strain positive), melezitose (one strain positive), raffinose (two strains positive), starch (three strains positive), D-tagatose (one strain positive), and D-turanose (one strain positive).</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield group D antisera.</s><s>Group A type peptidoglycan based upon lysine (type LYS-D-ASP).</s><s>Menaquinones are absent.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are predominantly of the straightchain saturated, monounsaturated, and cyclopropane ring types.</s><s>The major fatty acids are hexadecanoic, octadecenoic, and <i>cis</i>-11,12-methylenoctadecanoic acids (Table 3).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 37 to 38 mol%, as determined by melting temperature.</s><s>The strains form a distinct homology group, as determined by DNA-DNA hybridization.</s><s>Isolated from chicken crops and pig intestines.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 1258 (= E.E.</s><s>Snell strain R = ATCC 8043 = CCM 2423 = DSM 20160).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain is α-galactosidase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from starch and D-tagatose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, melezitose, raffinose, or D-turanose.</s><s>The type strain has complex nutritional requirements and is of industrial importance in the assay of a plethora of amino acids, vitamins, and other compounds (1). <i>Enterococcus hirae</i> is distinguished from <i>Enterococcus casseliflavus</i>, <i>Enteroroccus durans</i>, and <i>Enterococcus faecium</i> by the tests shown in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>