<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12749_nm.22530" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22530" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22530" rank="species">Actinomadura apis</organism><reference id="rid.12749"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Promnuan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohkuma</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chantawannakul</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura apis sp. nov., isolated from a honey bee (Apis mellifera) hive, and the reclassification of Actinomadura cremea subsp. rifamycini Gauze et al. 1987 as Actinomadura rifamycini (Gauze et al. 1987) sp. nov., comb. nov</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2271</fpage><lpage>2277</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026633-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952541</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomadura apis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomadura apis</em> (a′pis. L. gen. <em>apis</em> of/from a honey bee, the genus name of the true honey bee <em>Apis mellifera</em> (Linnaeus, 1758), a hive of which was the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic Gram-reaction-positive actinomycetes that form a branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>Aerial mycelium at maturity forms short branched spore chains with 3–5 spores.</s><s>Spore shape is oval and the spore surface is warty at maturity.</s><s>On ISP 2 agar, colonies are lacking in aerial mycelia and have a cartilaginous appearance.</s><s>Good growth occurs on glucose–yeast extract agar and moderate growth occurs on ISP 2, 3, 4, 5 and 7 media, Bennett agar, glucose–asparagine agar, Hickey–Tresner agar, oatmeal–nitrate agar and nutrient agar.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are dark-olive to light-brown on various agar media.</s><s>Aerial mycelia and sporulation are found on ISP3, 4, 5 and 7 media, Hickey–Tresner agar and oatmeal–nitrate agar.</s><s>A soluble greenish-black pigment is produced on ISP 2 and ISP 7 media.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–45 °C and pH 6–12 and moderate growth occurs in the presence of 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>d-Glucose, l-arabinose and rhamnose are utilized as sole carbon sources but sucrose, d-xylose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-fructose and raffinose are not.</s><s>Negative for the production of melanoid pigments.</s><s>The dominant diaminopimelic acid isomer in the cell wall is <em>meso</em>-2,6-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Fucose, galactose, glucose, madurose, mannose and ribose occur in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Polar lipids detected include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>); minor amounts of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) are also present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by the presence of significant amounts (&#x003E;7 % of the total) of C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IM17-1<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16576<sup>T</sup>  = TISTR 1980<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a honey bee (<em>Apis mellifera</em>) hive in Chiang Mai Province, Thailand.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>