<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9136_nm.14232" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14232" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14232" rank="species">Prosthecomicrobium consociatum</organism><reference id="rid.9136"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vasil'eva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Semenov</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giniyatullina</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of soil bacteria of the genus Prosthecomicrobium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>250</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prosthecomicrobium consociatum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prosthecomicrobium consociatum</i> (con.so.cia.tum - the Latin name meaning growth in a community with cellulose degrading bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are short thick rods, 0.5-1.0 μm in diameter and 0.8-1.35 μm long, single or in pairs.</s><s>Stationary (nonmotile) prosthecae are closely located in five rows along the cell.</s><s>The prosthecae size is 0.20-0.25 μm.</s><s>They have the following distinctive feature; 5 rows of prosthecae as a five-pointed star are well seen along the cell axis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They reproduce by budding, prosthecae in the daughter cell are located at an angle to mother cell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are aerobes, catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are gray, rounded, prominent, of a thick consistency, up to 1 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is a chemoorganotroph utilizing some monosaccharides as a sole source of carbon and energy (Tables 2 and 3).</s><s>Di-, tri-, polysaccharides and amino acids are not utilized (except for lactose by strain II).</s><s>Several sugar alcohols, organic acids of the Krebs cycle, methanol and monomethylamine can be utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract or vitamins of the B group are required for bacterial growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolytic activity is absent.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28-30°C, pH-neutral.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is extremely sensitive to penicillin.</s><s>MPK from 0.09 to 0.7 μg/ml [6].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacterium is widespread in soils and composts where the degradation of organic material is rapid.</s><s>The organism has been isolated from compost.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is present in the communities of cellulose degrading bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The GC-content of DNA is about 66.0-68.5 mol% (as determined by heat denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The typical strain 11 has been deposited with the Institute of Microbiology, the USSR Academy of Sciences, Moscow, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>