<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4911" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4911" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4911" rank="species">Bacillus gibsonii</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus gibsonii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus gibsonii</i> (gib.so'ni.i, L gen. n. from Gibson, named after the British bacteriologist Thomas Gibson, who made fundamental contributions to the taxonomy of <i>Bacillus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from the current study for strains of DNA hybridization group 11.</s><s>Colonies are yellow and circular with an entire margin and a smooth, shiny surface.</s><s>Cells are usually stout rods (0.6-1.0 x 2.0-3·0 μm) with ellipsoidal spores (0.6-1.0 x 0.8-1.6 μm) situated subterminally and in ageing cells paracentrally to sometimes lateral.</s><s>Spores do not cause swelling of the sporangium.</s><s>Strains of this species hydrolyse casein, gelatin and MUG.</s><s>Some strains, but not the type strain, hydrolyse Tween 40 and 60.</s><s>No hydrolysis of starch or pullulan is observed, phenylalanine is not deaminated and reduction of nitrate is variable among strains.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7.0, with an optimum at about pH 8.0.</s><s>Strains grow in the temperature range from 10 to 37°C, with the type strain failing to grow at 37°C.</s><s>All strains tolerate up to 9% NaCl, while strain PN-111 grows at 12% NaCl.</s><s>Carbohydrate utilization pattern shows growth on lactose, but not on glycogen or N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 40.6 and 41.7 mol % G +C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-109 (= DSM 8722).</s></p></content></protolog>