<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2757_nm.4428" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4428" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4428" rank="species">Selenomonas lacticifex</organism><reference id="rid.2757"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leuteritz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidel-Rüfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of anaerobic, gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria from breweries: emended description of Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus and description of Pectinatus frisingensis sp. nov., Selenomonas lacticifex sp. nov., Zymophilus raffinosivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., and Zymophilus paucivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-19</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1699594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i> (lac.ti'ci.fex. M. L. n. <i>acidum lacticum</i>, lactic acid; L. suffix <i>fex</i>, a maker; L.n. <i>lacticifex</i>, a maker of lactic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on four strains that were isolated from pitching yeast.</s><s>These organisms are obligately anaerobic, usually motile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods.</s><s>The cells are curved and crescent shaped and occur predominantly as single cells or (rarely) in pairs.</s><s>They are 0.6 to 0.9 by 5 to 15 μm.</s><s>Colonies on modified MRS agar medium are smooth, opaque, circular, yellowish, and 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 3 days at 30°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30°C.</s><s>Glucose is fermented to acetic, lactic, and propionic acids.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the different group IV strains are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cadaverine and rarely putrescine are found as characteristic components of cell wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is directly cross-linked <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Lipid F is also found as a characteristic cellular compound.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 51 to 52 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain DSM 20757 (= VB4b).</s><s>The phenotypic properties of the type strain are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The differentiation of <i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i> from the previously described <i>Selenomonas</i> species is shown in Table 4. <i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i> is distinguished from most other <i>Selenomonas</i> species by its ability to ferment glucose not only to acetic and propionic acids but also to lactic acid as major products.</s><s>Moreover, the G+C content of its DNA is distinctly lower.</s><s>Only <i>Selenomonas ruminantium</i> subsp. <i>lactilytica</i> also produces major amounts of lactic acid and has a DNA G+C content similar to that of <i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i>. <i>Selenomonas lacticifex</i> can be distinguished from this subspecies by its inability to utilize mannitol and dulcitol.</s></p></content></protolog>