<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7044_nm.6401" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6401" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6401" rank="species">Mycobacterium shottsii</organism><reference id="rid.7044"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rhodes</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kator</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kotob</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Berkum</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaattari</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vogelbein</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quinn</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ottinger</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium shottsii sp. nov., a slowly growing species isolated from Chesapeake Bay striped bass (Morone saxatilis).</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>421</fpage><lpage>424</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02299-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710607</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium shottsii</em> (shott′si.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>shottsii</em> of Shotts, named after Emmett Shotts, an American fish bacteriologist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid-fast coccobacilli (0·4–0·6×0·8–1 μm) that may form cell aggregates in culture.</s><s>Spores and cell branching are not present.</s><s>Colonies on Middlebrook 7H10 agar are dysgonic, rough, non-pigmented and typically flat with an irregular margin, becoming umbonate upon ageing.</s><s>Smooth colonies with an entire margin are seen less frequently.</s><s>Visible colonies from a dilute inoculum are observed after 4–6 weeks incubation at 23 °C.</s><s>Little or no growth occurs at 30 °C and none at 37 °C or above.</s><s>Isolates do not grow on MacConkey agar or Löwenstein–Jensen medium with 5 % NaCl, are negative for arylsulfatase (14 days), β-galactosidase, nitrate reductase, pyrazinamidase (7 days), semiquantitative catalase, Tween 80 hydrolysis and Tween opacity and have variable reactions for acid phosphatase and catalase at 68 °C.</s><s>Positive pyrazinamidase reactions occur when incubation is extended to 14–21 days.</s><s>Positive for urease and niacin production.</s><s>Colonies do not produce pigment following exposure to light for several hours or upon prolonged exposure for several days.</s><s>Tolerates isoniazid at 1 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> (but not at 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), thiacetazone and TCH.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in media containing hydroxylamine.</s><s>Resistant to <em>p</em>-aminosalicylic acid and isoniazid but susceptible to ethambutol, ethionamide, kanamycin, rifampicin and streptomycin in disc susceptibility tests.</s><s>The mycolic acid HPLC pattern consists of a single cluster of eight peaks resembling reference patterns for species of the <em>M. tuberculosis</em> complex but the peaks elute more rapidly.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence is unique among species of <em>Mycobacterium</em> and is most similar to those of <em>M. ulcerans</em> and <em>M. marinum</em>.</s><s>The type strain, isolate M175<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700981<sup>T</sup> =NCTC 13215<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from granulomatous lesions in splenic tissue from a striped bass (<em>Morone saxatilis</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>