<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4395_nm.903" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.903" rank="genus">Acidomonas</organism><reference id="rid.4395"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yamashita</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchimura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the genus Acidomonas Urakami, Tamaoka, Suzuki and Komagata 1989.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>865</fpage><lpage>870</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02946-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143037</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Acidomonas</em> Urakami <em>et al.</em> emend. Yamashita, Uchimura and Komagata</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acidomonas</em> (A.ci.do.mo′nas. Gr. adj. <em>acid</em> acid; Gr. n. <em>monas</em> unit, monad; N.L. fem. n. <em>Acidomonas</em> acidophilic monad).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods with rounded ends, measuring 0·5–0·8×1·5–2·0 μm, and are occasionally up to 4 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or (rarely) in short chains and are either motile by a single polar flagellum or non-motile.</s><s>Cells with polar tuft flagella are found very rarely.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on PYM agar (pH 4·5) are shiny, smooth, circular, convex, entire, beige to pink and 1–3 mm in diameter after 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Pellicles are produced in PYM medium, but they are not real cellulose.</s><s>Acetic acid is produced from ethanol.</s><s>Dihydroxyacetone is not produced from glycerol.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-glucose, glycerol, n-propanol, n-butanol, 2-methyl propan-1-ol, ethanol and methanol, but not from l-rhamnose, d-fructose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, raffinose, trehalose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, dulcitol or soluble starch.</s><s>Production of acid from d-arabinose, d-ribose, melibiose and 2-methyl propan-1-ol varies with strains.</s><s>Methanol, ethanol, d-glucose, d-mannose, glycerol and succinic acid are utilized as sole sources of carbon, but d-fructose, l-arabinose, maltose, trehalose, inositol and d-mannitol are not utilized.</s><s>Acetate is oxidized, but lactate is not or is only weakly oxidized.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Pantothenic acid is an essential requirement for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at the same extent between pH 3·0 and 8·0; acidotolerant.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30 °C, but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 30 % glucose and 0·35 % acetic acid.</s><s>Gluconic acid is produced from glucose, but 2-keto-, 5-keto- and 2,5-diketogluconic acids do not accumulate in culture media.</s><s>DNA G+C content ranges from 62 to 63 mol%.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and major hydroxy acids are 2-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and 3-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>Distributed in activated sludge.</s><s>The type species is <em>Acidomonas methanolica</em> (Uhlig <em>et al.</em>) Urakami <em>et al.</em> emend. Yamashita, Uchimura and Komagata.</s></p></content></protolog>