<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2593_nm.11542" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11542" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11542" rank="species">Lapillicoccus jejuensis</organism><reference id="rid.2593"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lapillicoccus jejuensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinobacterium of the family Intrasporangiaceae, isolated from stone</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2794</fpage><lpage>2798</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64911-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048726</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lapillicoccus jejuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lapillicoccus jejuensis</em> (je.ju.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>jejuensis</em> of Jeju, Republic of Korea, referring to the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are circular, flat, undulate and bright yellow in colour.</s><s>Temperature and pH ranges for growth are 20–37 °C and pH 4.1–11.1, with optima at 30 °C and pH 7.1.</s><s>No growth occurs below 10 °C, above 42 °C or at pH 12.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2 % NaCl, but not with 3 % NaCl.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase is present, but urease and arginine dihydrolase are absent.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin degradation is observed, but indole production, glucose fermentation and gelatin hydrolysis are not.</s><s>d-Arabinose, d-mannitol and malate are assimilated or weakly assimilated, but the following substrates are not assimilated: d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate (API 20NE).</s><s>Protease, cellulase and amylase activities are present.</s><s>DNA is hydrolysed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine are degraded.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, the results for leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are positive.</s><s>Results for esterase lipase (C8) and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin are weakly positive.</s><s>Results for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (21.2 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (15.5 %) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (13.7 %).<sub>.</sub> The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 74.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R-Ac013<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19200<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18607<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a small stone collected from an agricultural field in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>