<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12852_nm.22659" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22659" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22659" rank="species">Acidovorax radicis</organism><reference id="rid.12852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rothballer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmid</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Esperschütz</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidovorax radicis sp. nov., a wheat-root-colonizing bacterium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2589</fpage><lpage>2594</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025296-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21131505</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acidovorax radicis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acidovorax radicis</em> (ra′di.cis. L. gen. n. <em>radicis</em> of a root, the source of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Root-colonizing bacterium without apparent phytopathogenic potential.</s><s>In contrast, it exhibits plant-growth-promoting activity.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, straight rods, 1.5–2 µm long and 0.3–0.5 µm in diameter.</s><s>Forms rough colonies after 48 h growth on NB agar at 30 °C and flocculates in liquid NB medium after overnight growth at 30 °C.</s><s>One polar flagellum can be detected with scanning electron microscopy.</s><s>The type strain undergoes phenotypic variation in NB medium, showing smooth colonies on NB agar, no flocculation in liquid NB medium and no flagellum.</s><s>Oxidase-positive, catalase-negative and grows at 10–35 °C (optimum 30 °C), 0–2 % NaCl (optimum 0 %) and pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Glyceryl tributyrate can be hydrolysed, but casein is not.</s><s>Produces siderophores.</s><s>The following sugars, alcohols, fatty acids and amino acids can be metabolized: Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, α-d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-threonine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid and glycerol.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/<em>t</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/<em>t</em>.</s><s>The type strain can be differentiated from the type strains of its phylogenetically closest neighbours, <em>A. defluvii</em>, <em>A. facilis</em>, <em>A. delafieldii</em>, <em>A. temperans</em>, <em>A. soli</em>, <em>A. caeni</em>, <em>A. valerianellae</em>, <em>A. anthurii</em> and <em>S. metamorpha</em>, through DNA–DNA relatedness analysis, fatty acid composition and by the utilization of different substrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, N35<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23535<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25767<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface-sterilized roots of wheat (<em>Triticum aestivum</em>).</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 64.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>