<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9100_nm.14288" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14288" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14288" rank="species">Roseovarius pacificus</organism><reference id="rid.9100"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseovarius pacificus sp. nov., isolated from deep-sea sediment.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1116</fpage><lpage>1121</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002477-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406803</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseovarius pacificus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseovarius pacificus</em> (pa.ci′fi.cus. M.L. adj. <em>pacificus</em> pertaining to the Pacific Ocean from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, non-spore-forming, Gram-negative and ovoid to rod-shaped, 0.48–0.58×0.94–1.74 μm.</s><s>Actively motile; at least one subpolar flagellum may be present.</s><s>On HLB agar plates, small, wettish, smooth, faint pink colonies develop in 3–5 days.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 25 °C, salinities of 2–12 % and pH between 6.2 and 8.5.</s><s>There is an absolute requirement for sodium ions.</s><s>Does not contain Bchl <em>a</em>.</s><s>Cells are positive for oxidase and catalase, and negative for nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of starch and gelatin liquefaction.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>In assays with the API 20E system, lysine decarboxylase is present, but <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Oxidizes the following substrates: methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, ethanol and glycerol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized weakly: Tween 40, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, d-saccharic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, dl-carnitine and urocanic acid.</s><s>Susceptible to fortum, cefuroxime, cephradin, cefazolin, cefalexin, piperacillin, carbenicillin, ampicillin, penicillin G, minomycin, vibramycin, tetracycline, neomycin, kanamycin, gentamicin, amikacin, cefobid, rocephin, polymyxin B, ofloxacin, midecamycin, ciprofloxacin, norfloxacin and chloromycetin, but not to oxacillin, erythromycin, vancomycin, furazolidone, co-trimoxazole or clindamycin.</s><s>The major fatty acid (&#x003E;70 % total fatty acids) is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 81-2<sup>T</sup> (=MCCC 1A00293<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.7083<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24575<sup>T</sup>), isolated from deep-sea sediment of the Western Pacific Ocean.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.3 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>