<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8591_nm.13286" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13286" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13286" rank="species">Comamonas composti</organism><reference id="rid.8591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yen</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comamonas composti sp. nov., isolated from food waste compost.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>251</fpage><lpage>256</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65277-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175717</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Comamonas composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Comamonas composti</em> (com.pos′ti.N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>After 24 h of growth on nutrient agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is 0.5 μm in width and 1.0–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25–35 °C, 0–1 % NaCl and pH 6–8.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, strain YY287<sup>T</sup> shows positive results for oxidase (weak), catalase, nitrate reduction and assimilation of gluconate, adipate and malate reactions, and negative results for indole production, hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, citrate and phenyl acetate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive results are recorded for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, while negative results are recorded for cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase reactions.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN2 microtitre test system: i-erythritol, acetic acid, bromosuccinic acid, urocanic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, itaconic acid, succinamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, citric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, l-leucine, glycogen, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, Tween 40, Tween 80, dl-lactic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, propionic acid, l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, succinic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid and l-asparagine.</s><s>It cannot oxidize melibiose, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-histidine, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, d-fructose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, inosine, dextrin, l-fucose, d-psicose, glucuronamide, uridine, d-galactose, raffinose, l-alaninamide, l-ornithine, thymidine, gentiobiose, l-rhamnose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-alanine, l-phenylalanine, phenyethylamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-sorbitol, d-galacturonic acid, l-alanine, l-proline, putrescine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sucrose, d-gluconic acid, malonic acid, l-alanylglycine, 2-aminoethanol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, trehalose, d-glucosaminic acid, d-serine, 2,3-butanediol, adonitol, lactulose, turanose, d-glucuronic acid, quinic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-serine, glycerol, l-arabinose, maltose, xylitol, d-saccharic acid, l-threonine, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, d-arabitol, d-mannitol, glycyl l-aspartic acid, dl-carnitine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-cellobiose, d-mannose, glycyl l-glutamic acid, d-glucose 6-phosphate and <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid.</s><s>Strain YY287<sup>T</sup> is resistant to streptomycin and gentamicin but sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, rifampicin, penicillin G, sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 16 : 0 (33.3 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (12.9 %) and summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 : 0 iso 2-OH; 40.8 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 62.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain YY287<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17659<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24008<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from food waste compost, Kinmen County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>