<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8833_nm.13227" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13227" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13227" rank="species">Azonexus hydrophilus</organism><reference id="rid.8833"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azonexus hydrophilus sp. nov., a nifH gene-harbouring bacterium isolated from freshwater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>946</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65434-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398200</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Azonexus hydrophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Azonexus hydrophilus</em> [hy.dro′phi.lus. Gr. n. <em>hudor</em> (or <em>hydor</em>) water; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>hydrophilus</em> water-loving, referring to its source of isolation].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, slightly curved rods (0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 1.1–2.2 μm in length), motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are round with umbonate elevation and semi-transparent with irregular edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.3–0.6 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 48 h incubation at 35 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 35–40 °C, 0–1 % NaCl and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Cells grow under anaerobic conditions, but growth is weaker than under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Positive for catalase, cytochrome oxidase, and hydrolysis of starch (weak), Tween 40 and Tween 60.</s><s>Negative for DNase, lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of skimmed milk and Tween 20.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for nitrate reduction and malate assimilation and negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Urease and gluconate assimilation are strain-dependent.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Acid phosphatase activity is strain-dependent.</s><s>The results for carbon source oxidation and antimicrobial susceptibility tests are presented in Table 1.</s><s>Oxidation of the following compounds is strain-dependent: itaconic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, l-asparagine and l-aspartic acid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub> isomers.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64–66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, d8-1<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24005<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17657<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected from a spring located in Nature Valley, Hsinchu County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>