<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.579_nm.5005" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5005" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5005" rank="species">Bacillus vireti</organism><reference id="rid.579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanparys</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Felske</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus novalis sp. nov., Bacillus vireti sp. nov., Bacillus soli sp. nov., Bacillus bataviensis sp. nov. and Bacillus drentensis sp. nov., from the Drentse A grasslands.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02723-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus vireti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus vireti</em> (vi.re′ti. L. gen. n. <em>vireti</em> of the field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, motile, slightly curved, round-ended rods (0·6–0·9 μm in diameter) occurring singly and in pairs (Fig. 3b).</s><s>Cells do not produce endospores on TSA supplemented with MnSO<sub>4</sub>, but sporulate on <em>B. fumarioli</em> agar at pH 7 after 48 h.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, lie in central, paracentral and sometimes subterminal positions and may swell the sporangia slightly; the ends of the sporangia may be slightly tapered.</s><s>After 3 days growth on TSA, colonies are up to 4 mm in diameter, circular, raised, with entire edges and dark-cream in colour.</s><s>The surface has an eggshell-like texture and the biomass is of loose consistency.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C and the maximum growth temperature is 40–45 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth is 4·0–5·0 and the optimum and maximum pH values for growth are in the range 7·0–7·5.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, gelatin is hydrolysed and nitrate reduction is positive; ONPG hydrolysis is variable; reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and the Voges–Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive in the API 50CH gallery.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50CH gallery, using the CHB suspension medium: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, l-fucose (weak), galactose (weak), d-glucose, glycogen, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside (weak), ribose (weak), starch, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s><s>The following reactions are variable between strains and, when positive, are usually weak: gluconate, <em>meso-</em>inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, glycerol, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl d-xyloside, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol and d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, respectively present at about 47 and 34 %.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present to at least 1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>For the strains tested (Table 4), the G+C content is 39·8–40·3 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil (Drentse A agricultural research area, The Netherlands).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain, LMG 21834<sup>T</sup> (=R-15447<sup>T</sup>=IDA3632<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15602<sup>T</sup>), was weak for gluconate and methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside and negative for <em>meso</em>-inositol and rhamnose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is ∼40·2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>