<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.714_nm.9408" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9408" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9408" rank="species">Brevibacillus levickii</organism><reference id="rid.714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Allan</surname><given-names>R.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buchanan</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacillus levickii sp. nov. and Aneurinibacillus terranovensis sp. nov., two novel thermoacidophiles isolated from geothermal soils of northern Victoria Land, Antarctica</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1039</fpage><lpage>1050</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63397-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879231</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacillus levickii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacillus levickii</em> (le.vic.ki′i. N.L. adj. <em>levickii</em> of Levick, named after G. Murray Levick, surgeon and biological scientist of Captain R. F. Scott's Northern Party, the first scientific expedition to visit the vicinity of Mt Melbourne in 1912).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, becoming Gram-negative after 48 h, motile, round-ended rods (0·7–0·8×2·0–5·0 μm) occurring singly, in pairs and in chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, occurring subterminally or terminally in swollen or slightly swollen sporangia (Fig. 4a).</s><s>After 48 h incubation at 40 °C on 1/2 BFA (pH 5·5), colonies are circular, flat, up to 3·0 mm in diameter and cream-coloured with a matt appearance.</s><s>Colony consistency becomes tough and difficult to break with a loop.</s><s>Minimum growth temperature lies between 15 and 20 °C, with optimum growth temperature of 40–45 °C and maximum growth temperature of 50–55 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 4·5 and 6·5 and the optimum pH for growth is pH 5·0–5·5.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 2–3 % NaCl.</s><s>The organisms are microaerophilic and weakly catalase-positive.</s><s>Horse blood agar is partially haemolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed in 24 h and starch hydrolysis is weakly positive.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is weakly positive or negative.</s><s>In the API 20E strip reactions, arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization and the Voges–Proskauer reaction are positive.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed and nitrate reduction is variable.</s><s>Reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and indole production are negative.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in the API Biotype 100 system: <em>α</em>-d-glucose, adonitol, aesculin, <em>α</em>-lactose, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-arabitol, l-aspartate, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, d-galacturonate, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, l-glutamate, dl-glycerate, glycerol, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, dl-lactate, d-malate, l-malate, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-proline, putrescine, quinate, l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinate, sucrose and <em>trans</em>-aconitate.</s><s>Utilization of the following substrates is variable: dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, d-galactose, <em>β</em>-gentobiose, mucate, d-ribose, d-saccharate, d-trehalose and l-tryptophan.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: i-erythritol, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-valerate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, benzoate, betaine, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, caprate, caprylate, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, ethanolamine, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, gentisate, d-glucosamine, glutarate, histamine, l-histidine, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, itaconate, lactulose, d-lyxose, malonate, maltitol, <em>m</em>-coumarate, d-melezitose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl-d-glucopyranose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, propionate, protocatechuate, d-raffinose, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d-tartrate, l-tartrate, tricarballyate, trigonelline, tryptamine, d-turanose, l-tyrosine, xylitol and d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates in API Biotype 100 produce alkaline reactions when inoculated with a suspension in 1/2 BFB prepared without yeast extract or (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, but containing 0·006 % phenol red: 2-oxoglutarate, l-aspartate, fumarate, d-galacturonate, d-gluconate, l-glutamate, d-malate, l-malate, malonate, mucate, quinate, d-saccharate, succinate, d-tartrate, l-tartrate and tricarballyate.</s><s>Alkaline reactions for the following substrates are variable: 2-keto-d-gluconate, l-alanine, caprylate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, citrate, d-glucuronate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, l-histidine, itaconate, dl-lactate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, propionate, l-serine, <em>trans</em>-aconitate and l-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, accounting for approximately 74 % total fatty acid content.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts (at least 1 %): iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (detailed fatty acid data are given in Supplementary Table A).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 48·3–50·3 mol% and the G+C content of the type strain (Logan B-1657<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22481<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108307<sup>T</sup>) is 50·3 mol%.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain is weakly positive for casein hydrolysis and it utilizes dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, d-galactose, d-ribose, d-trehalose and l-tryptophan; alkaline reactions are observed for d-glucuronate, itaconate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate and l-tryptophan.</s></p></content></protolog>