<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4414_nm.3946" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3946" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3946" rank="species">Clostridium hiranonis</organism><reference id="rid.4414"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kitahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takamine</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium hiranonis sp. nov., a human intestinal bacterium with bile acid 7alpha-dehydroxylating activity.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>39</fpage><lpage>44</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211270</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium hiranonis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium hiranonis</i> (hi.ra.no'nis. N.L. masc. gen. n. <i>hiranonis</i> of Hirano, after the Japanese microbiologist Seiju Hirano for his contributions to the study of the isolate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the characteristics given below is based on the results of studies with the two strains, TO-931<sup>T</sup> and HD-17.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells cultivated on EG blood agar plates are Gram-positive, spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>The straight or slightly curved rod-shaped cells are 1.6-10 μm x 0.8 μm in size and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on EG blood agar plates are approximately 1.0-2.0 mm in diameter, disc-shaped and greyish white to grey.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is approximately 37 °C, and the optimum pH for growth is between 7.5 and 8.0.</s><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>All strains produce acid from glucose, fructose, mannose and sucrose.</s><s>Neither strain produces acid from adonitol, amygdalin arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, galactose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Nitrate and sulfate are not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced.</s><s>All strains give positive reactions on N-acetyl-β-D-glucosamidase and proline aminopeptidase in the ANI-DENT test.</s><s>Moderate amounts of acetic acid and iso-valeric acid are produced as the end products in peptone-yeast-extract medium supplemented with glucose; minor amounts of propionic acid and iso-butyric acid are also produced.</s><s>The G­+C content of strain TO-931<sup>T</sup> is 31.1 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain TO-931<sup>T</sup>, isolated from the faeces of a healthy human, and has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Japan, as strain JCM 10541<sup>T</sup>, and also in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Germany, as strain DSM 13275<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>