<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1442_nm.4884" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4884" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4884" rank="species">Bacillus centrosporus</organism><reference id="rid.1442"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>DNA relatedness of Bacillus brevis Migula 1900 strains and proposal of Bacillus agri sp. nov., nom. rev., and Bacillus centrosporus sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>20</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-20</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus centrosporus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus centrosporus</i> (cen.tro.spor'us. L. n. <i>centrum</i>, the center; M. L. n. <i>spora</i>, spore; M. L. adj. <i>centrosporus</i>, with a central spore)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods that are 0.5 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 6.0 μm.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Elllipsoidal spores are produced in swollen sprangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, thin, smooth, circular, entire, and 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, hydrogen sulfide, and indole are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth (test for acetylmethylcarbinol production) is higher than 7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Casein, egg yolk lecithin, starch, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Citrate, but not propionate, is utilized by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is inhibited at pH 5.6 or 5.7 and by 3% NaCl, 0.001% lysozyme, and 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature is 28°C, the maximum growth temperature is 40°C, and the minimum growth temperature is 10°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from cellobiose, glucose, maltose, mannitol, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Arabinose, fructose, galactose, lactose, mannose, melibiose, salicin, sorbitol, and xylose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant density is 1.7025 to 1.7045 g/cm<sup>3</sup>; the G+C content is 49 to 51 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain NRRL NRS-664, has been deposited in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection at the National Center for Agricultural Utilization Research, Peoria, III.</s></p></content></protolog>