<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8650_nm.13401" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13401" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13401" rank="species">Lysobacter spongiicola</organism><reference id="rid.8650"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchino</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter spongiicola sp. nov., isolated from a deep-sea sponge.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>370</fpage><lpage>374</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65391-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218933</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter spongiicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter spongiicola</em> [spon.gi.i.co′la. L. n. gen. <em>spongia</em> sponge; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> (from L. n. <em>incola</em>) inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>spongiicola</em> sponge inhabitant].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, oxidase- and catalase-positive rod-shaped bacteria (0.5–0.6 μm wide and 1.3–1.5 μm long), motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Cells grown on agar media can be observed as non-motile because of their tendency to lose flagella easily.</s><s>On R2A agar and trypticase soy agar, colonies are yellowish in colour, transparent, smooth and shiny, have regular edges and are 3–4 mm in diameter; on MA or media supplemented with NaCl or natural seawater, colonies are yellow-brownish or brown-reddish in colour.</s><s>Grows at 5–41 °C, with an optimum at 25–28 °C, but does not grow at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Growth is observed in 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.5–9.5, with an optimum at pH 6.5–8.5.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase and phenylalanine deaminase are not produced.</s><s>Starch, chitin, DNA, adenine, guanine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, Tweens 80, 40 and 20 and tyrosine.</s><s>Positive for haemolysis.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, arabinose, mannose, rhamnose, galactose, maltose, fructose, lactose, d-xylose, inositol, mannitol or glycerol.</s><s>Results from other phenotypic and biochemical tests are listed in Table 1.</s><s>In addition, in API 50 CH tests, positive results were obtained for the utilization of potassium 5-ketogluconate and d-arabitol and negative results were obtained for the utilization of glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melezitose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, starch, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, l-arabitol, gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In the API ID 32GN test, the assimilation of potassium 5-ketogluconate was weakly positive.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): erythromycin (15), carbenicillin (100), oleandomycin (15), streptomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), polymyxin B (300 U), ofloxacin (5), rifampicin (5), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), nalidixic acid (30) and cephazolin (30).</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): benzylpenicillin (10 U), oxacillin (10), lincomycin (15), gentamicin (10) and cephalexin (30).</s><s>Contains the following fatty acids: 16 : 0 iso (32.5 %), 15 : 0 iso (23.0 %), 11 : 0 iso 3-OH (15.5 %), 17 : 1 iso (13.2 %), 11 : 0 iso (9.5 %), 14 : 0 iso (3.3 %) and 17 : 0 iso (2.8 %).</s><s>On R2A agar, the following phospholipids are present: phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.0 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 329<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0728<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14760<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sponge specimen (<em>Pachastrella</em> sp.) collected from the Philippine Sea at a water depth of 750 m.</s></p></content></protolog>