<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9174_nm.14374" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14374" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14374" rank="species">Psychrobacter fulvigenes</organism><reference id="rid.9174"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter fulvigenes sp. nov., isolated from a marine crustacean from the Sea of Japan.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1480</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007195-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychrobacter fulvigenes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychrobacter fulvigenes</em> (ful.vi.ge′nes. L. adj. <em>fulvus</em> brown; Gr. v. <em>gennaio</em> to produce; M.L. adj. <em>fulvigenes</em> brown pigment-producing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmented, non-spore-forming and ovoid (1.6–1.9 μm long and 0.7–0.9 μm in diameter).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on NA are beige, circular with an entire margin, convex and 2–4 mm in diameter.</s><s>Produces black–brown pigments when grown on and in standard media, including TSA, TSB, MA, MB, NA, NB and R2A.</s><s>Black–brown pigment is produced on MA supplemented with 1 % l-tyrosine.</s><s>Hydrolyses l-tyrosine weakly.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–12 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is −5 to 37 °C with optimum growth at 25–28 °C; no growth occurs at 39–40 °C.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin, Tween 80, starch, chitin and DNA are not.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 40 is variable; the type strain reaction is positive.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, rhamnose, galactose, maltose, cellobiose, d-xylose or mannitol.</s><s>Other physiological properties and biochemical test results are given in Table 2.</s><s>In API ID32 GN tests, positive for assimilation of malonate, lactic acid, l-fucose, propionic acid, valeric acid and 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, but negative for assimilation of l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, melibiose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, capric acid and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, negative for indole production, acid production from glucose, hydrolysis of arginine dihydrolase, aesculin and gelatin, and for assimilation of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, glucose, arabinose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, mannitol, caprate and adipate; positive for nitrate reduction and for the assimilation of urease, gluconate, malate and citrate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase, weakly positive for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, and negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Test for cystine arylamidase was variable between strains; the reaction of the type strain was positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KC 40<sup>T</sup> (=KMM 3954<sup>T</sup>=NRIC 0746<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15525<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a specimen of the marine crustacean <em>Paralithodes camtschatica</em>, collected from Peter the Great Bay of the Sea of Japan.</s><s>Strain KC 65, isolated from the same specimen, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>