<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4544_nm.10573" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10573" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6088" rank="species">Agromyces rhizospherae</organism><reference id="rid.4544"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces luteolus sp. nov., Agromyces rhizospherae sp. nov. and Agromyces bracchium sp. nov., from the mangrove rhizosphere.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1529</fpage><lpage>1537</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491355</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agromyces rhizospherae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agromyces rhizospherae</i> (rhi.zo'spher.ae. M.L. <i>rhizo</i> root; Gr. adj. <i>sphera</i> sphere; M.L. n. <i>rhizospherae</i> within the sphere of the root)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, irregular rods that form ®laments (0.2-0.4 by 1.5-3.0 μm) or show elementary branching in the early growth phase and fragment into short rods (0.2-0.4by 0.8-1.5 μm) during exponential growth phase.</s><s>Colonies on PY agar medium are yellow, opaque, entire and convex, and sometimes penetrate into the agar.</s><s>Grows optimally at 20-30 °C, but does not grow at 10 or 37 °C.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from amidon, cellobiose, fructose, gentiobiose, glucose, maltose, mannose, salicin, but is not produced from adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, galactose, gluconate, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylose or xylitol.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Urease is not produced.</s><s>DAB is the principal amino acid of the cell wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The cell wall is of an acetyl type.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinones are MK-12 and MK-11.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 71.2-73.3 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil of or roots in rhizosphere of mangrove on Iriomote Island, Japan.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 16236<sup>T</sup> (=VKM Ac-2086<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The other strain is IFO 16237 (=VKM Ac-2087).</s></p></content></protolog>