<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4057_nm.7751" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7751" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7751" rank="species">Planctomyces guttaeformis</organism><reference id="rid.4057"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Starr</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planctomyces stranskae (ex Wawrik 1952) sp. nov., nom. rev. and Planctomyces guttaeformis (ex Hortobágyi 1965) sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>477</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planctomyces guttaeformis</i> (ex Hortobagyi 1965) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planctomyces guttaeformis</i> (gutt.ae.form'is. L. gen. noun <i>gutta(e)</i> a drop; L. suffix -<i>formis</i> in the form or shape of; M.L. adj. <i>guttaeformis</i> drop shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are relatively large (2.9 to 3.0 μm in length, 1.15 to 1.3 μm in diameter at the globose end, and 0.6 to 0.7 μm in diameter at the cylindical end) and bulbiform (i.e., bulb shaped; a cylinder blending into a spherical terminal dilatation; shaped like a common screw-in incandescent light bulb).</s><s>A prominent multifibrillar appendage, a spike, extends from the globose (spherical) end of the cell.</s><s>The spike is not a stalk, as it lacks the function of connecting the cell to other cells or to a substrate via a terminal holdfast.</s><s>Division is by budding, with a mirror-image bud formed at the globose end of the cell.</s><s>The bud is often slightly off-center with respect to the longitudinal axis of the mother cell, whereas the spike is usually exactly polar.</s><s>Numerous crateriform surface structures and fine pili are present on the globose end of the cell.</s><s>The fine structure is that of a typical bacterium, except for the rather thin cell envelope, the crateriform surface structures, and the spike and its basal attachment site.</s><s>Resistant to beta-lactam antibiotics.</s><s>Occur in rosettes, consisting of as many as 12 cells attached via holdfasts at the narrower ends of the several cells.</s><s>Neither motility nor flagella have been observed.</s><s>Common in eutrophic freshwater habitats, usually accompanying phototrophs (algae and cyanobacteria).</s><s>Has not been cultivated axenically, although blooms occur in laboratory enrichments.</s><s>The type material consists of the present description and illustrations (Pg in Fig. 1; Fig. 3 made from Hortobagyi’s preserved type material; and Fig. 4; see also Fig. 2 of reference 18 and Fig. 2 of reference 20).</s><s>The type locality is a eutrophic manmade pond in a residential district (The Lakes) in Tempe, Ariz.</s><s>Frequently confused with <i>Planctomyces stranskae</i> (ex Wawrik 1952) sp. nov., nom. rev., from which it can be distinguished on the basis of cellular size and shape, the presence of a multifibrillar spike in <i>P. guttaeformis</i> and its absence in <i>P. stranskae</i>, and the absence of numerous multifibrillar bristles in <i>P. guttaeformis</i> and their presence in <i>P. stranskae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>