<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.318_nm.3601" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3601" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3601" rank="species">Desulfocapsa thiozymogenes</organism><reference id="rid.318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuhmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bak</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Disproportionation of inorganic sulfur compounds by the sulfate-reducing bacterium Desulfocapsa thiozymogenes gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>166</volume><fpage>184</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050374</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfocapsa thiozymogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfocapsa thiozymogenes</i> (thi.o.zy.mo´ge.nes. Gr. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; Gr. n. <i>zyme</i> leaven, ferment; Gr. v. <i>gennaio</i> to produce; ML. adj. <i>thiozymogenes</i> causing a fermentation of sulfur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are round-ended rods, 0.8–0.9 μm wide and 2–3.5 μm long.</s><s>The cells are motile by means of a single, subpolarly inserted flagellum.</s><s>The mol% G+C content of the genomic DNA is 50.7.</s><s>Cytochromes are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ethanol, propanol, and butanol are used as electron donors with sulfate as electron acceptor and are oxidized to their respective fatty acids.</s><s>Volatile fatty acids, organic and amino acids, and sugars are not utilized.</s><s>Amorphous ferric hydroxide, fumarate, and nitrate are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Thiosulfate and sulfite are disproportionated to sulfate and sulfide, concomitant with growth.</s><s>Sulfur is disproportionated to sulfate and sulfide, and in the presence of ferric iron this reaction can support growth.</s><s>Fermentative growth with organic compounds is not possible.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs within a pH range of 6.8–8.0, with an optimum of 7.3–7.5.</s><s>Growth is possible at 20–30°C, but not at 15 or 35°C.</s><s>NaCl concentrations of 15 g l<sup>–1</sup> and higher inhibit growth.</s><s>Vitamins are not required.</s><s>When the cells grow by disproportionation of inorganic sulfur compounds, carbon dioxide can act as the sole carbon source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Bra2, was isolated from a freshwater lake in Århus, Denmark, and has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (Braunschweig, Germany) under accession number DSM 7269.</s></p></content></protolog>