<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2333_nm.714" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.714" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.714" rank="species">Prochlorothrix hollandica</organism><reference id="rid.2333"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Burger-Wiersma</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stal</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mur</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prochlorothrix hollandica gen. nov., sp. nov., a filamentous oxygenic photoautotrophic procaryote containing chlorophylls a and b: Assignment to Prochlororales Florenzano, Balloni, and Materassi 1986, with emendation of the ordinal description.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>250</fpage><lpage>257</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-250</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prochlorothrix hollandica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prochlorothrix hollandica</i> (hol. lan' di. ca. L. adj. <i>hollandica</i>, pertaining to Holland, part of The Netherlands)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filamentous organism composed of cylindrical cells that are 0.5 to 1.5 μm wide and 3 to 10 μm long.</s><s>Unfavorable growth conditions may increase both the cell length and the cell diameter.</s><s>The straight undifferentiated trichomes are composed of 2 to more than 100 cells, depending on the degree of shearing that occurs as a result of stirring liquid cultures.</s><s>The trichomes lack sheaths, do not possess differentiated end cells, and are nonmotile.</s><s>The cell wall is characterized by both gram-positive and gram-negative features.</s><s>Periodic constrictions along the trichomes mark the locations of cross walls between adjacent cells.</s><s>The cross walls are formed by invagination of the cytoplasmic membrane and the peptidoglycan layer of the cell wall.</s><s>The outer layer of the cell wall does not participate in cross wall formation (Fig. 6).</s><s>Reproduction occurs by trichome fragmentation; motile hormogonia are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The thylakoid membranes are arranged in parallel layers at the periphery of the cytoplasm around a thylakoid-free central body (2).</s><s>The thylakoid membranes show lateral heterogeneity (Miller et al., in press).</s><s>Refractile cell inclusions of indefinite nature may be present.</s><s>Gas vacuoles are present at the polar ends of the cells.</s><s>Carboxysomes seem to be restricted to the center of the cells in the vicinity of the thylakoid membranes.</s><s>The nuclear region is located in the center of the cells (2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The primary photosynthetic pigments, chlorophylls a and b, have a ratio of chlorophyll a to chlorophyll b ranging from 7:1 to 19:1.</s><s>Zeaxanthin and β-carotene are the major carotenoids; α-carotene, lutein, and echinenon are absent.</s><s>Dinitrogen fixation does not occur in media devoid of combined nitrogen, nor can nitrogenase activity be induced under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Salt sensitive; 25 mM NaCl inhibits growth, and no growth occurs at 100 mM NaCl.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is between 20 and 30°C, and the optimum pH is 8.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a shallow, highly eutrophic freshwater lake in The Netherlands.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 53 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method (one strain).</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Culture Collection of Algae and Protozoa (Cumbria, United Kingdom) as strain CCAP 1490/1.</s></p></content></protolog>