<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2868_nm.9103" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9103" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1376" rank="species">Rochalimaea vinsonii</organism><reference id="rid.2868"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dasch</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Differiential characteristics of strain of Rochalimaea: Rochalimaea vinsonii sp. nov., the canadian vole agent.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>305</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-305</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rochalimaea vinsonii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rochalimaea vinsonii</i> (The name is in honor of J. William Vinson, who, in collaboration with Henry S. Fuller, first established that the genus <i>Rochalimaea</i> can be cultivated axenically and initiated the investigation of this genus by conventional microbiological methods.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic characteristics of this organism are as follows: <i>Rochalimaea vinsonii</i> is a small, gram-negative, nonflagellated, nonmotile bacterium that can be grown on blood agar or in a liquid medium containing amino acids, YE, and hematin or FCS.</s><s>Succinate, pyruvate, glutamine, and glutamate can serve as sole sources of energy, but glucose is not metabolized.</s><s>When grown in fibroblast cell cultures, the organism adheres to the surfaces of the cells but does not grow intracellularly.</s><s>Its ecology is largely unknown, since it has been isolated only from voles on a small Canadian island.</s><s>It closely resembles <i>Rochalimaea quintana</i> with the following exceptions: added CO<sub>2</sub> is not required for growth; glutamate is catabolized as the sole substrate about as well as glutamine, succinate, and pyruvate, whereas <i>Rochalimaea quintana</i> requires another substrate for significant glutamate utilization; and ornithine decarboxylase activity is inducible, whereas it is constitutive in <i>Rochalimaea quintana</i>. <i>Rochalimaea vinsonii</i> also tends to autoagglutinate and settle to the bottom in liquid media, but this may be a strain characteristic rather than a species characteristic.</s><s>Final identification of an isolate as <i>Rochalimaea vinsonii</i> requires appropriate serological methods and is aided by comparative studies of protein migration patterns and DNA polynucleotide base sequences.</s><s>The type and only presently available strain was isolated by Baker in 1943 and is maintained as the 45th yolk sac passage by the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC VR-152).</s></p></content></protolog>