<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2208_nm.5961" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5961" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5961" rank="species">Cellulomonas hominis</organism><reference id="rid.2208"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual Ramos</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of some clinical strains of CDC coryneform group A-3 and A-4 bacteria as Cellulomonas species and proposal of Cellulomonas hominis sp. nov. for some group A-3 strains.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>2091</fpage><lpage>2097</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7559954</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellulomonas hominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellulomonas hominis</i> (ho'mi.nis L. gen. n. <i>hominis</i>, of man, indicating that the two isolates included in the present study are derived from humans and not from the environment)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are short (1 μm), thin gram-positive rods without irregular branching.</s><s>No spores formed.</s><s>The cells are motile.</s><s>The colonies are circular, smooth, convex, and whitish initially but with yellowish pigmentation in about 3 days.</s><s>The colony size is about 1 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation at 378C in 5% CO<sub>2</sub> .</s><s>The organism is catalase positive.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are hydrolyzed, but urea is not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, xylose, and β-methylxyloside.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, 2-ketogluconate, or mannitol.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are detected: DNase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, and α-mannosidase.</s><s>Valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, and α-fucosidase are not present.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 73 to 76 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain DMMZ CE40 has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung für Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen under accession number DSM 9581.</s><s>This strain has the characteristics described for the species, and its G+C content is 76 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>