<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1626_nm.10615" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10615" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10615" rank="species">Bacillus panaciterrae</organism><reference id="rid.1626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aslam</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus panaciterrae sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2861</fpage><lpage>2866</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17158988</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus panaciterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus panaciterrae</em> (pa.na.ci.ter′rae. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name for ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panaciterrae</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, rod-shaped, 0.5–0.8 μm in diameter and 3.0–5.0 μm in length, non-motile and occur singly or in chains.</s><s>Central ellipsoidal endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C and the growth temperature range is between 20 and 45 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 5.0 and 5.5, the optimum pH is 6.5–7.0 and the maximum pH lies between 8.0 and 8.5.</s><s>Tolerates 1 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 2 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse chitin, but not starch, cellulose, DNA, olive oil or xylan.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-fructose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, pyruvate, acetate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, fumarate, salicin, citrate, lactate, malate, succinate, tartrate, sucrose, d-trehalose, gluconate, inositol (weakly), d-mannitol, xylitol, glycerol, inulin, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-histidine and l-proline.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-galactose, d-mannose, d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d- and l-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, d-xylose, formate, propionate, caprate, maleate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, glutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, amygdalin, methanol, glycogen, dextran, l-cysteine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-threonine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis and negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and urease production.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-melibiose, d-glucose and amygdalin.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (42.4 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (17.4) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (9.7 %).</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA is 47.8 mol%.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 1517<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13929<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52470<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23408<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>