<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1632_nm.11382" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11382" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11382" rank="species">Streptomyces durmitorensis</organism><reference id="rid.1632"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Savic</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bratic</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vasiljevic</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces durmitorensis sp. nov., a producer of an FK506-like immunosuppressant</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2119</fpage><lpage>2124</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64913-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces durmitorensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces durmitorensis</em> (dur.mi.tor.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>durmitorensis</em> pertaining to Durmitor, Serbia and Montenegro, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast streptomycete that produces a yellowish-grey and a greenish-grey substrate mycelium and a greenish-yellow aerial spore mass on yeast extract-malt extract and glycerol-asparagine agars.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not formed on oatmeal, yeast extract-malt extract or glycerol-asparagine agars, while dark-grey pigment is formed on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not formed on peptone/yeast extract/iron or tyrosine agars.</s><s>Spore chains are <em>rectiflexibiles</em>, with 10 or more rod-shaped, smooth-surfaced spores (0.5–0.9×1.0–1.5 μm) per chain.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C with an optimum between 28 and 32 °C.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-DAP.</s><s>Cellobiose, dextran, d-(−)-fructose, d-(+)-galactose, d-(+)-glucose, glycerol, d-(−)-mannitol, d-(+)-mannose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, d-(+)-raffinose, l-(+)-rhamnose, sucrose, <em>α</em>-trehalose and d-(+)-xylose are utilized for growth, but l-(+)-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>β</em>-lactose, maltose and d-sorbitol are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-methionine, l-proline and l-valine are utilized as sole nitrogen sources, but l-asparagine, l-lysine, ornithine hydrochloride, l-phenylalanine and thiamine are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, gelatin is liquefied, xanthine is degraded, starch is not hydrolysed and aesculin and DNA are not degraded.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction, catalase, extracellular protease, haemolysin (<em>β</em>-haemolysis) and urease.</s><s>Negative for lecithinase and H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl (9 %, w/v) and thallous acetate (0.001 %, w/v), but not sodium azide (0.01 %, w/v), phenol (0.1 %, w/v) or potassium tellurite (0.001 %, w/v).</s><s>Susceptible to apramycin (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), kanamycin (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), gentamicin (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), tetracycline (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), thiostrepton (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chloramphenicol (35 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and spectinomycin (90 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but resistant to ampicillin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and FK506 (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The type strain, MS405<sup>T</sup>, produces an immunosuppressant with an FK506-like mechanism of action.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72 mol%.</s><s>The type strain shows antimicrobial activity against <em>Micrococcus luteus</em> NCIMB 196 and <em>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</em> FAV 20, but not against <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> NCIMB 3610<sup>T</sup>, <em>Candida albicans</em> CBS 562, <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 27853, <em>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</em> FAS 20 or <em>Staphylococcus aureus</em> ATCC 25923.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MS405<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41863<sup>T</sup> =CIP 108995<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample taken at the Durmitor National Park, Serbia and Montenegro.</s></p></content></protolog>