<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5869_nm.5872" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5872" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5872" rank="species">Arthrobacter roseus</organism><reference id="rid.5869"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter roseus sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from an antarctic cyanobacterial mat sample.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1017</fpage><lpage>1021</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054218</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter roseus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter roseus</i> (ro.se'us. L. adj. <i>roseus</i> red-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-coccus growth cycle with irregular rods in the exponential phase and predominantly coccoid cells (~1.0 μm in diameter) in the stationary phase.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and non-motile; colonies on peptone/yeast extract medium are round, smooth, convex, 0.2-1 mm in diameter and red-pigmented.</s><s>Pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits four absorption maxima, at 437, 467, 494 and 524 nm.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs between 5 and 30 °C and pH 6 and 12 and cells tolerate up to 5.8% NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth is observed at 22 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Catalase, phosphatase, gelatinase and nitrate-reduction tests are positive; oxidase, urease, lipase, b-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, indole production, methyl red test, Voges-Proskauer test and levan formation are negative.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for utilization of mannose, galactose, maltose, fructose, glucose, arabinose, ribose, xylose, rhamnose, raffinose, trehalose, succinic acid, fumaric acid, citric acid, mannitol, sorbitol, adonitol, sucrose, inulin, pyruvate, acetate, alanine, leucine, isoleucine, valine, serine, arginine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, asparagine, glutamine, proline and phenylalanine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: dulcitol, inositol, melibiose, lactose, nicotine, cellulose, glycine, threonine, cysteine, methionine, lysine, tyrosine, histidine and tryptophan.</s><s>No acid or gas from glucose, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, fructose, galactose, mannose, lactose, maltose or sucrose.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin, chlortetracycline, chloramphenicol, oxytetracycline, tetracycline, erythromycin, nitrofurantoin, bacitracin, nitrofurazone, leucomycin, rifampicin, nystatin, cotrimoxazole, trimethoprim, ampicillin, carbenicillin, gentamicin, amoxycillin, tobramycin and polymyxin B but resistant to furazolidone, colistin, furoxone and kanamycin.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is Lys-Gly-Ala<sub>3</sub> (variation A3α) and the major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Cell-wall sugars are galactose, glucose, ribose and rhamnose.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>14:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>, C<sub>18:0</sub> and C<sub>18:2</sub>.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, cardiolipin and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 66-69 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a cyanobacterial mat sample from McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica (77°32'18" S, 160°45' E).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CMS 90r<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 3712<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14508<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>