<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4256_nm.2033" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2033" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2033" rank="species">Azospira oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.4256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold-Hurek</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the taxonomic structure of the diazotrophic genus Azoarcus sensu lato and description of three new genera and new species, Azovibrio restrictus gen. nov., sp. nov., Azospira oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Azonexus fungiphilus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>659</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azospira oryzae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azospira oryzae</i> (o'ry.zae. L. fem. n. <i>Oryza</i> genus name of rice ; L. gen. n. <i>oryzae</i> from rice, referring to its frequent occurrence in association with rice roots)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On VM ethanol medium, colonies are translucent, pinkish to salmon coloured, smooth, convex with an entire margin; on Congo red medium, colonies are translucent orange, shining with otherwise similar characteristics.</s><s>In addition to those described for the genus, can use D-tartrate, isovalerate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, L-glutamate and L-aspartate as sole carbon source.</s><s>Growth optimum at 40 °C.</s><s>Source is surface-sterilized roots of gramineae such as Kallar grass [<i>Leptochloa fusca</i> (L.) Kunth] or several species of rice (<i>Oryza</i>), grown in the Punjab of Pakistan or Nepal, Philippines and Italy, respectively, or resting stages (sclerotia) of a basidiomycete (Pakistan).</s><s>Type strain is 6a3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 9096<sup>T</sup>), which has a G+­C content of 65.2 mol% and was isolated from Kallar grass.</s><s>It has no requirement for cobalamine.</s></p></content></protolog>