<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5767_nm.10010" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10010" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10010" rank="species">Salegentibacter agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5767"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shevchenko</surname><given-names>L.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krasokhin</surname><given-names>V.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salegentibacter agarivorans sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from the sponge Artemisina sp.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>883</fpage><lpage>887</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64167-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585710</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salegentibacter agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salegentibacter agarivorans</em> (a.ga.r.i.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>agarum</em> agar, algal polysaccharide; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour, to digest; N.L. part. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-digesting).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, chemo-organotrophic, asporogenic rods 0·5–0·7 μm wide and 2·0–4·7 μm long and motile by gliding.</s><s>Oxidase-, catalase-, <em>β</em>-galactosidase- and alkaline phosphatase-positive.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, slimy, shiny with entire edges, sunken into the agar and 1–3 mm in diameter on marine agar 2216.</s><s>Produces yellow, carotenoid, non-diffusible pigments.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 1–18 % NaCl; growth optimum observed at 2–4 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth detected at 4–41 °C, with an optimum at 28–32 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5·7–10·0, with optimum growth occurring between pH 7·5 and 8·3.</s><s>Hydrolyses agar, gelatin, starch, alginic acids, DNA and Tweens 20, 40 and 80, but not casein, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper), chitin or urea.</s><s>Forms acid from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, dl-xylose, d-lactose, d-maltose, l-raffinose, d-sucrose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, but not from l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, sorbitol or mannitol.</s><s>Utilizes d-mannose, but not inositol, sorbitol, mannitol, citrate or malonate.</s><s>In the Microlog GN2 plate, KMM 7019<sup>T</sup> utilizes <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-lactose, sucrose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-threonine and urocanic acid.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabitol, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, KMM 7019<sup>T</sup> produces <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but not esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites under oxic conditions.</s><s>Does not produce indole or acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction).</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, doxycycline, erythromycin, kanamycin, neomycin, oleandomycin and streptomycin.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, carbenicillin, lincomycin, gentamicin, tetracycline and polymyxin B.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 1</sub> iso (12·1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso (12·3 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso (7·1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (5·6 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH (9·8 %) and summed feature 3 (12·2 %), comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 39·2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 7019<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12560<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23205<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sponge (<em>Artemisina</em> sp.) collected near Onecotan Island, Kuril Islands, Sea of Okhotsk, Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>