<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6947_nm.2640" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2640" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2640" rank="species">Pseudomonas mediterranea</organism><reference id="rid.6947"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Catara</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutra</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morineau</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and genomic evidence for the revision of Pseudomonas corrugata and proposal of Pseudomonas mediterranea sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1749</fpage><lpage>1758</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02174-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361283</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas mediterranea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas mediterranea</i> (me.di.ter.ra.ne'a. M.L. adj. <i>mediterranea</i> mediterranean, referring to the fact that most strains of this species were isolated in Mediterranean countries)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is based on results presented in this study and in previous studies (Catara et al., 1997, 2000; Sutra et al., 1997). <i>P. mediterranea</i> is a Gram-negative, non spore-forming rod.</s><s>This species have the same general characteristics as <i>P. corrugata</i>.</s><s>Colonies on YPGA are wrinkled or smooth.</s><s>Yellow to brown pigments are frequently produced.</s><s>Motile by means of multiple polar flagella.</s><s>It is strictly aerobic, non-fluorescent on King's B medium, oxidase-positive, does not produce levan, is not pectolytic, and reduces nitrates into nitrites.</s><s>Most strains (seven out of eight tested) are arginine dihydrolase-positive after 15 days incubation, and few (two out of eight tested) produce hypersentivity on tobacco leaves.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 80 and gelatin is variable (seven and six positive strains out of eight tested, respectively).</s><s>Acid is produced from sucrose and mannitol but not from erythritol and sorbitol. <i>P. mediterranea</i> utilizes N-acetylglucosamine, D-and L-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, D-arabitol, L-arabinose, L-aspartate, cis-aconitate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, citrate, ethanolamine, D-fructose, fumarate, D-galactose, D-galacturonate, gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, D-glucuronate, L-glutamate, glycerol, p-hydroxybenzoate, DL-bhydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, DL-lactate, D-lyxose, L-malate, malonate, D-mannitol, D-mannose, mucate, myo-inositol, L-proline, propionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, D-ribose, D-saccharate, sucrose, L-serine, succinate, D-trehalose, trans-aconitate, trigonelline, L-tyrosine and D-xylose.</s><s>In contrast, it does not hydrolyse DNA or aesculin and does not utilize adonitol, L-arabitol, benzoate, D-cellobiose, <i>m</i>-coumarate, dulcitol, erythritol, DL-fucose, gentisate, gentobiose, L-histidine, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, hydroxyquinoline β-glucuronide, itaconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, lactulose, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, 1-O-methyl a-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, L-tartrate, tricarballylate, L-tryptophan, D-turanose or xylitol.</s><s>Utilization of the following substrates is variable : D-malate, glutarate and tryptamine. <i>P. mediterranea</i> utilizes histamine, 2-ketogluconate and meso-tartrate, whereas <i>P. corrugata</i> does not.</s><s>It uses DL-glycerate but not D-tartrate, whereas the assimilation of these two substrates is variable for <i>P. corrugata</i>. <i>P. mediterranea</i> can be clearly distinguished from <i>P. corrugata</i> by 16S rDNA analysis, by means of REP-and BOX-PCR profiles (this study) and by using fingerprints generated by random-primed PCR (random amplified polymorphic DNA) (Catara et al., 2000).</s><s>Type I primers (PC5/1 and PC5/2) and type II primers (PC1/1 and PC1/2) designed by Catara et al. (2000) allow the PCR identification and detection of <i>P. corrugata</i> and <i>P. mediterranea</i>, respectively.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 60.2 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is strain CFBP 5447<sup>T</sup> (=ICMP 14184<sup>T</sup>). <i>P. mediterranea</i> strains were isolated from pith necrosis on tomatoes and peppers, mainly in Italy, Spain and France.</s></p></content></protolog>