<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.460_nm.3360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3360" rank="species">Yersinia kristensenii</organism><reference id="rid.460"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bercovier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ursing</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carter</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mollaret</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Yersinia kristensenii: a new species of Enterobacteriaceae composed of sucrose-negative strains, formerly called atypical Yersinia enterocolitica or Yersinia enterocolitica-like.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>219</fpage><lpage>224</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02605860</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Yersinia kristensenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Yersinia kristensenii</i> (named in honor of the Danish microbiologist M. Kristensen, who first isolated this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Y. kristensenii</i> is 105 (=CIP 80-30) = Frederiksen P226 = Kristensen MK 1O4) isolated from human urine in Denmark [12].</s><s>The biochemical reactions of strain 105 are given in Table 1.</s><s>It is a serogroup O11 strain [18].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Trehalose-positive, sucrose-negative, Voges-Proskauer-negative <i>Yersinia kristensenii</i> strains have the following properties that are characteristic of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>They are Gram-negative, peritrichously flagellated rods that grow on ordinary media (nutrient agar), reduce nitrates to nitrites, ferment D-glucose, and are oxidase negative and catalase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The physiology of these bacteria was detailed elsewhere [2].</s><s>They grow at temperatures from 4°C to 41°C but they grow better at 28°C than at 37°C.</s><s>Strains isolated from the environment hardly grow at 37°C when first subculture.</s><s>Compared to <i>Y. enterocolitiea sensu stricto</i>, growth at 41°C is very scant.</s><s>The size of the colonies after 24 h incubation at 28°C or 37°C on nutrient agar is similar to those of <i>Y. enterocolitica sensu stricto</i> strains [4].</s><s>They very often produce a strong odor characterized by Wauters [17] and Bottone and Robin [6] as "musty" or "cabbagelike."</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical tests were done on 115 strains from the collection of the Centre National des Yersinia (Institut Pasteur, Paris), as shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The reactions most useful in differentiating <i>Y. kristensenii</i> from other yersiniae are: sucrose, Voges-Proskauer, trehalose, rhamnose, melibiose, raffinose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, sorbose, sorbitol, ornithine decarboxylase, and cellobiose.</s><s>Its negative rhamnose reaction alone is sufficient to distinguish <i>E. kristensenti</i> from <i>Y. intermedia</i>, <i>Y. frederiksenii</i>, <i>Yersinia</i> biotype X2, and <i>Y. pseudotuberculosis</i>.</s><s>Negative reactions in melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside and rallinose also separate <i>Y. kristensentii</i> from <i>Y. intermedia</i>; and negative sucrose and Voges-Proskauer reactions help to separate <i>Y. kristensenti</i> from <i>Y. frederiksenii</i>.</s><s>Positive cellobiose and sorbose reactions, and a negative Voges-Proskauer reaction also distinguish <i>Y. kristensenii</i> from <i>Yersinia</i> biotype X2.</s><s>Positive ornithine decarboxylase, cellobiose and sorbose reactions separate <i>Y. kristensenii</i> from <i>Y. pseudotuberculosis</i>. <i>Y. enterocolitica</i>, <i>Yersinia biotype</i> X1, and <i>Y. kristensenii</i> are all rhamnose negative, Its negative sucrose and Voges-Proskauer reactions serve to differentiate <i>Y. kristensenii</i> from biotypes 1 through 4 of <i>Y. enteroeolitica</i>.</s><s>Its reactions for trehalose (+), sorbitol (+), and Voges-Proskauer (-) separate <i>Y. kristensenii</i> from biotype 5 of <i>Y. enteroeolitica</i>.</s><s>Positive reactions for sorbose, sorbitol, and ornithine decarboxyfase separate <i>E. kristensenii</i> and <i>Yersinia</i> biotype X1.</s></p></content></protolog>