<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3843_nm.1892" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1892" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1892" rank="species">Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</organism><reference id="rid.3843"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shooner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bousquet</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tyagi</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation, phenotypic characterization, and phylogenetic position of a novel, facultatively autotrophic, moderately thermophilic bacterium, Thiobacillus thermosulfatus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>409</fpage><lpage>415</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-409</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934899</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> (ther. mo. sul. fa' tus. Gr. n. <i>thermus</i>, heat; L. n. <i>sulfatus</i>, sulfur; L. adj. <i>themrosulfatus</i>, organism that produces sulfate and grows at high temperatures)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> below is based on the type strain, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51520.</s><s>Cells are gram negative, motile by means of a single polar flagellum, and rod shaped (1.3 to 2.3 by 0.9 μm).</s><s>The cells contain polyphosphate inclusions (typically two or three inclusions) and polyhedral bodies.</s><s>Colonies on autotrophic solid medium (medium A) are round and small (diameter, &#x003C; 1 mm); they are translucent or have sulfur deposits in the center. <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> is strictly aerobic and grows autotrophically on thiosulfate, tetrathionate, and sulfur and heterotrophically on yeast extract, succinate, and glutamate. <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> does not grow on carbohydrates, pyruvate, acetate, or formate.</s><s>When thiosulfate is used as the primary energy source, tetrathionate, trithionate, and sulfate are produced.</s><s>During growth on elemental sulfur and thiosulfate, the pH decreases from neutrality to around pH 2.5.</s><s>During elemental sulfur oxidation, a considerable amount of sulfate (up to 6,000 mg/liter) is produced, depending on the pH buffering capacity of the medium.</s><s>The cells adhere to elemental sulfur by means of a glycocalyx, as judged by the extensive production of a glycocalyx during growth on this substrate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth on thiosulfate occurs between pH 4.3 and 7.8 and at temperatures of 34 to 65°C; optimum growth occurs at pH 5.2 to 5.6 and 50 to 52.5°C.</s><s>Ubiquinone QS is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61 2 1 mol%.</s><s>No denitrification occurs under autotrophic and heterotrophic conditions.</s><s>As determined by a 16s rRNA gene sequence analysis, <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> belongs to the beta subdivision of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is closely related phylogenetically to <i>Thiobacillus perometabolis</i> and <i>Thiobacillus thioparus</i>.</s><s>Its 16s rRNA sequence is most similar to the 16s rRNA sequence of <i>Thiobacillus perometabolis</i> (level of similarity, 95.4%).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the complete 16s rRNA gene sequence of <i>Thiobacillus thermosulfatus</i> is U27839.</s></p></content></protolog>