<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.647_nm.4404" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4404" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4404" rank="species">Mitsuokella dentalis</organism><reference id="rid.647"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Haapasalo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ranta</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ranta</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lounatmaa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mitsuokella dentalis sp. nov. from dental root canals.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>566</fpage><lpage>568</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-4-566</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mitsuokella dentalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mitsuokella dentalis</i> (demta'lis. Lat. fem. adj. <i>dentalis</i> pertaining to the teeth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is based upon our study of strains ES2772, KR11, and ES2645 (5).</s><s>Nonmotile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods approximately 0.7 μm wide by 1 to 2 μm long.</s><s>Cells from agar are blunt-ended, oval rods which occur singly.</s><s>Thinly sectioned cells studied by electron microscopy show an outer membrane structure typical of gram-negative bacteria.</s><s>Numerous fimbriae and a thick capsulelike zone around the cell are present.</s><s>For ultrastructural details see reference 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Cells grow better on blood agar media with hemolysed blood than in liquid media, where growth is poor.</s><s>No growth on kanamycin-vancomycin-laked blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies after 3 days of incubation on enriched horse blood agar (hemolysed blood) are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, convex, irregular in shape, translucent, wet, and mucoid.</s><s>The colonies have a water drop appearance, which is a distinctive characteristic of this species.</s><s>α-Hemolysis on horse and sheep blood agar plates is usually seen after 7 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ferments arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, and raffinose in prereduced anaerobically sterilized peptone-yeast extract broth.</s><s>Melibiose and sucrose are weakly fermented (5.5 &#x003C; pH &#x003C; 5.7); erythritol, mannitol melezitose, rhamnose, salicin, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>As determined by using the API 20A system the fermentation reactions are negative.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole negative.</s><s>The esculin hydrolysis test is positive when a chromogenic enzyme substrate for the detection of a constitutive enzyme is used with cells harvested from an agar plate, but negative when esculin broth for anaerobes is used, The major end products of metabolism are acetate and succinate.</s><s>Malate dehydrogenase is present, and glutamate dehydrogenase is present only in minor amounts.</s><s>α-Arabinosidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase , β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, and alanineaminopeptidase are present.</s><s>Hydrolyzes indoxyl acetate.</s><s>α-Fucosidase, α-mannosidase, and β-xylosidase are absent.</s><s>Leucine, proline, tyrosine, arginine, histidine, phenylalanine, and glycine aminopeptidases and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>Arginine is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to kanamycin and colistin, while vancomycin is inhibitory at concentrations above 5 μg/ml.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, penicillin, rifampin, and metronidazole.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sensitive to oxgall and brilliant green.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is based upon <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid; glycine, alanine, glutamic acid, and aspartic acid are present.</s><s>Hydroxylated and nonhydroxylated long-chain fatty acid methyl esters are present in whole-cell methanolysates.</s><s>The major hydroxylated fatty acid is 3-hydroxy-hexadecanoic acid (3-OH-C<sub>16:0</sub>).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are hexadecanoic (C<sub>16:0</sub>) and 12-methyltridecanoic (iso-C<sub>14:0</sub>) acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 56 to 60 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human dental root canals.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ES2772 (= DSM 3688)</s></p></content></protolog>