<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1329_nm.7818" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7818" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7818" rank="species">Borrelia burgdorferi</organism><reference id="rid.1329"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmid</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hyde</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Borrelia burgdorferi sp. nov.: Etiologic agent of lyme disease.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>496</fpage><lpage>497</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-496</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Borrelia burgdorferi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(burg.dorf er.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>burgdorferi</i> in honor of Willy Burgdorfer, who first discovered the organism in <i>I. dammini</i> ticks at the Rocky Mountain Laboratories, National Institutes of Health, Hamilton, Mont.).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Borrelia burgdorferi</i> possesses the basic phenotypic characteristics of the genus <i>Borrelia</i>; R.</s><s>C.</s><s>Johnson, F.</s><s>W.</s><s>Hyde, and C.</s><s>M.</s><s>Rumpel, Yale J.</s><s>Biol.</s><s>Med., in press).</s><s>The spirochetes are flexible helical cells with dimensions of 0.18 to 0.25 by 4 to 30 μm.</s><s>The organism is motile with both rotational and translational movements; the coiling of the cell is regular.</s><s>On the average, seven periplasmic flagella are located at each cell end, and these flagella overlap at the central region of the cell.</s><s>A multilayered outer envelope or membrane surrounds the protoplasmic cylinder, which consists of the peptidoglycan layer, cytoplasmic membrane, and the enclosed cytoplasmic contents.</s><s>The diamino acid present in the peptidoglycan is ornithine.</s><s>Cytoplasmic tubules are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram negative and stain well with Giemsa and Warthin-Starry stains.</s><s>Unstained cells are not visible by bright-field microscopy but are visible by dark-field or phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 34 to 37°C, and the organism has a generation time of 11 to 12 h at 35°C (A.</s><s>G.</s><s>Barbour, Yale J.</s><s>Biol.</s><s>Med., in press).</s><s>The cells are catalase negative and microaerophilic.</s><s>The spirochetes are chemoorganotropic, when carbohydrates such as D-glucose are used as energy and carbon sources.</s><s>D-Glucose is fermented to lactic acid (Johnson et al. , in press).</s><s>In contrast to the antigenic variability of the relapsing fever borreliae, this organism is antigenically stable.</s><s>It is pathogenic for humans and animals.</s><s>Infections are acquired from several tick species of the genus <i>Ixodes</i> which are parasitized by the spirochete.</s><s>Transovarial transmission of the spirochete in ticks is infrequent and inefficient (W.</s><s>Burgdorfer, Yale J.</s><s>Biol.</s><s>Med., in press).</s><s>The type strain of <i>B . burgdorferi</i> is strain ATCC 35210.</s><s>The guanine-pluscytosine content of <i>B . burgdorferi</i> DNA is 27.3 to 30.5 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>B. burgdorferi</i> is strain B31 (= ATCC 35210).</s><s>This strain was the first isolate of <i>B . burgdorferi</i> and was isolated from a tick (<i>I. dammini</i>) collected on Shelter Island, N.Y.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of this strain is 29.0 to 30.5 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method in two separate studies.</s></p></content></protolog>