<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12776_nm.22559" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22559" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22559" rank="species">Rhizobium pseudoryzae</organism><reference id="rid.12776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sui</surname><given-names>X.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium pseudoryzae sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of rice</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2425</fpage><lpage>2429</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026146-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075907</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium pseudoryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium pseudoryzae</em> [pseud.o.ry′zae. Gr. adj. <em>pseudes</em> false; L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> of rice and also the name of a bacterial specific epithet; N.L. gen. n. <em>pseudoryzae</em> not the true (<em>Rhizobium</em>) <em>oryzae</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-stain-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods (1.0–1.23×2.3–4.3 µm).</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>No flagellum is detected.</s><s>Colonies are circular and pearl white when grown on YMA at 28 °C, which is the optimal growth temperature.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–11 (optimum pH 7–8).</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 40 °C.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase and urease.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl concentrations up to 5 % (w/v) (optimal 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>l-Phenylalanine ammonia-lyase is not detected.</s><s>Does not produce 3-ketolactose from lactose.</s><s>On GN2 microplates (Biolog), utilizes the following 64 compounds among 95 different carbon sources: dextrin, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, formic acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, uridine, l-proline, l-asparagine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, α-d-lactose, lactulose, methyl β-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are summed feature 8 (comprising C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, 46.7 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, J3-A127<sup>T</sup> ( = ACCC 10380<sup>T</sup> = KCTC 23294<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the roots of fresh rice plants (<em>Oryza sativa</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>