<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.263_nm.201" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.201" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.201" rank="species">Methanogenium organophilum</organism><reference id="rid.263"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Widdel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rouviere</surname><given-names>P.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolfe</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of secondary alcohol-utilizing methanogens including a new thermophilic isolate.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>150</volume><fpage>477</fpage><lpage>481</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00422290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanogenium organophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanogenium organophilum</i> or.ga.no'phi.lum. M. L. pref. <i>organo</i> pertaining to organic substance, from Gr. n. <i>organon</i> organ; Gr. v. <i>philein</i> like, love; M. L. adj. <i>organophilum</i> that likes organic compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Irregular coccoid, nonmotile cells, 0.5-1.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>In agar, smooth yellowish colonies are formed.</s><s>Cultures are easily lysed by detergents, e.g. by ≤0.1% sodium dodecyl sulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>H<sub>2</sub>, formate, 2-propanol, 2-butanol, ethanol and 1-propanol serve as hydrogen donors for CO<sub>2</sub> reduction to methane.</s><s>Methanol or acetate are not used for methanogenesis.</s><s>Secondary alcohols are oxidized to ketones, primary alcohols to monocarboxylic acids.</s><s>Acetate has to be added as a carbon source for growth on substrates other than ethanol.</s><s>4-Aminobenzoate, biotin and B<sub>12</sub> are required as growth factors, tungstate but not molybdate is needed as trace mineral.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature optimum is at 30-35°C, the maximum at 39°C The pH range for good growth is 6.4-7.3. 20 g NaCl and 3 g MgCl<sub>2</sub> ⋄ 6 H<sub>2</sub>O per l are necessary for optimum growth.</s><s>Complex supplements such as yeast extract or Trypticase peptone are not required but may stimulate growth somewhat.</s><s>The doubling time of cells stimulated with the complex supplements is around 6 h on H<sub>2</sub> and around 11 h on 2-propanol as hydrogen donor.</s><s>Cysteine (1 mM) and more than about 10 μM ferrous iron may have adverse effects on growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 46.7 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Methanogenium organophilum</i> has been isolated from marine mud.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Methanogenium organophilum</i> CV, DSM 3596, deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, FRG.</s></p></content></protolog>