<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5272_nm.1673" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1673" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1673" rank="species">Ralstonia basilensis</organism><reference id="rid.5272"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steinle</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stucki</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stettler</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanselmann</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aerobic mineralization of 2,6-dichlorophenol by Ralstonia sp. strain RK1.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>2566</fpage><lpage>2571</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9647831</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ralstonia basilensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ralstonia basilensis</i> (from <i>basilea</i>, Latin for Basel, Switzerland, where the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The substrate spectrum of strain RK1 includes nonhalogenated aromatic compounds, like benzene, toluene, and phenol, as well as chlorobenzene and all mono- and dichlorophenols with a chloride substituent(s) in the <i>ortho</i> and/or <i>para</i> position.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydroxylation in the <i>ortho</i> position, which produces chlorocatechol, has been reported to be the first step in the aerobic degradation of mono- and dichlorophenols (9, 12).</s><s>The initial steps used by <i>R. basilensis</i> RK1 for ring cleavage must be different from the pathway described by Don et al. (9).</s><s>2,4-DCP hydroxylase cannot act on the <i>ortho</i> positions of 2,6-DCP, because both of these positions are occupied by chlorine atoms.</s><s>In addition, <i>R. basilensis</i> RK1 also lacks the ability to degrade 2,4-dichlorophenoxyacetic acid.</s><s>Further investigations are in process to evaluate the 2,6-DCP degradation pathway.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lengthening of lag phases with increasing initial substrate concentrations may be interpreted as a consequence of metabolic inhibition by 2,6-DCP at concentrations above 300 μM, since 2,6-DCP and other chlorophenols can act as uncoupling agents in biological membranes (7, 21, 29).</s><s>Escher et al. (10) reported that the concentration required to inhibit the NAD<sup>+</sup> reduction rate by 50% was 8.9 μM for 2,6-DCP.</s><s>In our experiments, which were performed with concentrations that were 10 times lower, the bacterial cell yield remained unchanged, while the lag phase increased from up to 3 days at 2,6-DCP concentrations below 300 μM to 16 days at 1,200 μM 2,6-DCP.</s><s>The prolonged lag phase at high initial 2,6-DCP concentrations may reflect slow growth of the bacteria due to large energy dissipation from simultaneous chlorophenol degradation and uncoupling.</s><s>The lower growth rates at high initial 2,6-DCP concentrations also reflect substrate inhibition.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Under comparable conditions, a mixed culture from reactor 1 degraded 2,6-DCP faster and with a higher cell yield than a pure culture of <i>R. basilensis</i> RK1.</s><s>Our observation that the maximum growth rate of an enriched, specialized pure culture is only one-half the maximum growth rate of a mixed culture (0.076 versus 0.15 h<sup>-1</sup>) is in contrast to observations made with phenol-degrading strains of <i>Acinetobacter calcoaceticus</i> and <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> (19).</s><s>There are several possibilities which might account for our experience.</s><s>Community synergism based on 2,6-DCP products might prevent the buildup of metabolic intermediates and thus minimize feedback regulation of the consumption of 2,6-DCP.</s><s>Alternatively, the community might contain other bacterial populations that are able to degrade 2,6-DCP, which we were not able to isolate on nutrient agar plates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>With the fixed-bed reactors used in this study we were able to demonstrate the practicability of eliminating chlorophenols in water through biological degradation.</s><s>The ability to degrade high concentrations of 2,6-DCP demonstrated with reactor 1 opens up new possibilities for treating wastewater from chemical soil washing without further dilution.</s><s>Elimination of 46 mmol of 2,6-DCP per liter of reactor volume per day (at a 2,6-DCP concentration of 720 μM) consumed 750 ml of mineral medium, 62 ml of hydrogen peroxide (30%), and very little energy for pumping.</s><s>With fixed-bed reactor 2, we treated a simulated groundwater containing low concentrations of 2,4- DCP, 2,6-DCP, and 2,4,6-TCP.</s><s>The concentrations of all three isomers were reduced to below the detection limits with an HRT of 20 min and were reduced 95% with an HRT of 8.2 min.</s><s>Longer adaptation times might improve reactor performance.</s></p></content></protolog>