<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2818_nm.3164" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3164" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3164" rank="species">Enterobacter taylorae</organism><reference id="rid.2818"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riddle</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asbury</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lowery</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Escherichia fergusonii and Enterobacter taylorae, two new species of Enterobacteriaceae isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3968204</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter taylorae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter taylorae</i> ("<i>taylorae</i>" (pronunciation [with a classical Latin pronunciation of the ending], tay' lohr eye) is a neo (modern) Latin genitive (feminine) form of taylor to honor the British bacteriologist Joan Taylor, who for many years was chief of the Salmonella Reference Laboratory, Central Public Health Laboratory, Colindale, London, England, and who has made many contributions to our knowledge of the family <i>Enterobacteriacea</i>, particularly on <i>Salmonella</i>, <i>Shigella</i>, and the role of certain <i>Escherichia coli</i> strains in infantile diarrhea. The name also honors Welton Taylor, an American clinical microbiologist who has also made many contributions to our knowledge of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>, particularly the development of XLD agar and the isolation of Shigella and other bacterial pathogens from feces.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>Enterobacter taylorae</i> have the following properties typical of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>: they are gram-negative rods, oxidase negative, catalase positive, and usually motile, reduce nitrate to nitrite, and ferment D-glucose.</s><s>They have the following properties typical of the genus <i>Enterobacter</i>: they are Voges-Proskauer positive, grow in the presence of KCN, are susceptible to çolistin, and are resistant to cephalothin.</s><s>Other biochemical reactions for <i>Enterobacter taylorae</i> are given in Table 4 and include the following: positive tests for citrate and malonate utilization, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, and gas production during fermentation.</s><s>Negative results were found for indole production, methyl red, H<sub>2</sub>S production on triple sugar-iron agar, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, gelatin hydrolysis, and production of a distinct pigment. <i>Enterobacter taylorae</i> ferments many of the sugars and polyhydroxyl alcohols used for the identification of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>More details on these biochemical results which form the species description are given in Table 4.</s><s>Strains were generally susceptible to colistin (94% susceptible), nalidixic acid (100% susceptible), sulfadiazine (97% susceptible), gentamicin (97% susceptible), kanamycin (97% susceptible), chloramphenicol (100% susceptible), and tetracycline (81% susceptible).</s><s>They were resistant to penicillin (0% susceptible) and cephalothin (3% susceptible).</s><s>Susceptibility was more variable for streptomycin (50% susceptible), ampicillin (53% susceptible), and carbenicillin (69% susceptible).</s><s>The type strain (holotype) is designated as ATCC 35317, which has biochemical reactions typical of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>