<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5343_nm.5608" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5608" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5608" rank="species">Streptococcus adjacens</organism><reference id="rid.5343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus defectivus sp. nov and Streptococcus adjacens sp. nov., nutritionally variant streptococci from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>294</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus adjacens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus adjacens</i> (ad'ja.cens. L. adj. <i>adjacens</i>, adjacent, indicating that this organism can grow as satellite colonies adjacent to other bacterial growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on seven human clinical isolates (3-5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Nonmotile, nonsporulating , catalase negative, and oxidase negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic with complex growth requirements.</s><s>Grows as satellite colonies adjacent to <i>Staphylococcus epidermidis</i> on horse blood- Trypticase-soy agar and on stored sheep blood agar.</s><s>α-Hemolytic on sheep blood agar.</s><s>Tiny colonies up to 0.2 mm in diameter are formed on fresh sheep blood agar or on blood agar supplemented with 10 mg of pyridoxal hydrochloride per liter or 100 mg of L-cysteine per liter.</s><s>Grows in Todd- Hewitt broth enriched with 10 mg of pyridoxal per liter or 100 mg of cysteine per liter.</s><s>Grows in CDMT semisynthetic medium (4) and produces a red chromophore visualized by boiling the bacteria at pH 2 for 5 min.</s><s>The morphology depends upon the conditions of growth; the organism is pleomorphic with chains including cocci, coccobacilli, and globular and rod-shaped cells when it is grown in cysteine- or pyridoxal-supplemented broth.</s><s>Small ovoid cocci (diameter, 0.40 to 0.60 μm) occur singly, in pairs, or in chains of variable length in CDMT semisynthetic medium.</s><s>Some tendency toward rod formation is observed in the stationary phase.</s><s>Lactic acid is the ,predominant acid produced.</s><s>Resistant to optochin and susceptible to vancomycin.</s><s>No production of exopolysaccharide on 5% sucrose.</s><s>Ungroupable in the Lancefield system.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces pyrrolidonyl-arylamidase and does not produce alkaline phosphatase. α- and β-Galactosidases are not produced.</s><s>Trehalose and starch are not fermented.</s><s>Some strains produce β-glucuronidase.</s><s>Inulin is fermented by some strains.</s><s>Leucine aminopeptidase is produced.</s><s>Arginine and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>D-Ribose, L-arabinose, D-mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, D-raffinose, and glycogen are not fermented.</s><s>β-Glucosidase is produced by some strains.</s><s>The PBP pattern includes four major bands at 85, 83, 72 to 75, and 68 to 70 kilodaltons.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Streptococcus adjacens</i> has been isolated from the throat flora, urine, and blood of patients with endocarditis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36.6 to 37.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain GaD (= ATCC 49175 = CIP 103243).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain GaD<sup>T</sup> was isolated from the cardiac valves of a patient with bacterial endocarditis.</s><s>This strain was first described by Cayeux et al. (10) and was used to produce experimental endocaritis in rabbits (2, 21).</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics of the species.</s><s>In addition, it has the following properties: β-glucuronidase and β-glucosidase are produced, and inulin is fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 36.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>