<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12429_nm.21261" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21261" rank="species">Hydrotalea flava</organism><reference id="rid.12429"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrotalea flava gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the phylum Bacteroidetes and allocation of the genera Chitinophaga, Sediminibacterium, Lacibacter, Flavihumibacter, Flavisolibacter, Niabella, Niastella, Segetibacter, Parasegetibacter, Terrimonas, Ferruginibacter, Filimonas and Hydrotalea to the family Chitinophagaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>518</fpage><lpage>523</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023002-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382796</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hydrotalea flava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hydrotalea flava</em> (fla′va. L. fem. adj. <em>flava</em> golden-yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as for the genus with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>On NA, colonies are orange–yellow and circular with an entire margin.</s><s>Good growth on R2A agar and NA; moderate growth on tryptone soy agar; no growth on MacConkey's agar.</s><s>Grows at 20, 25, 28, 30 and 37 °C; no growth at 4, 10, 15 and 40 °C. l-Alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phenyl-phosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline, l-aniline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide are hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991). <em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, melibiose and l-rhamnose are used as sole carbon sources (weak positive results after 72 h incubation) on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-gluconate, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, pyruvate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, adipate, azelate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, glutarate, itaconate, l-malate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, propionate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>No acids are produced from d-glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl-d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol and d-mannose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 51397<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7760<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample in southern Sweden.</s></p></content></protolog>