<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.339_nm.6908" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6908" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6908" rank="species">Streptomyces capillispiralis</organism><reference id="rid.339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higgens</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces capillispiralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>124</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-116</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces capillispiralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces capillispiralis</i> (ca.pil.li.spi.ra'is; L. n. <i>capillus</i> hair; L. adj. <i>spiralis</i> spiral or spiraled; M.L. adj. <i>capillispiralis</i> hairy-spiraled)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological characteristics.</s><s>Strain A49492 produced well-developed, coiled, aerial mycelia, and it was therefore placed in the <i>Spirales</i> (S) section of the classification of Pridham et al. (9).</s><s>This morphology was readily observed on all media which support formation of aerial mycelia.</s><s>Oatmeal agar (ISP no. 3)) ISP no. 7, tomato-paste oatmeal agar, and tap-water agar provided excellent observation of spiral morphology (Figs. 1 and 2).</s><s>The spirals were simple, open, loose coils of two to three turns.</s><s>The sporophores bore chains of 10 to 50 spores.</s><s>Scanning electron micrographs indicated that the spore shape was oval to globose (Fig. 3).</s><s>The spore size ranged from 0.96 to 1.19 μm by 0.54 to 0.71 μm.</s><s>The average size was 1.05 by 0.62 μm.</s><s>The spore surface ornamentation was hairy (Fig. 4).</s><s>Coremia were observed on yeast-malt extract agar (ISP no. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>The aerial mycelium was in the gray (GY) color series of Tresner and Backus (12, 13); light brownish-gray was the predominant shade.</s><s>Strain A49492 produced a nonfragmenting substrate or primary mycelium which varied from yellow-brown to brownishblack, depending on the medium.</s><s>A brown, water-soluble pigment was occasionally produced.</s><s>The strain did not produce melanoid pigments.</s><s>Physiological Characteristics.</s><s>The physiological characteristics of strain A49492 are as follows.</s><s>Catalase, phosphatase, and urease were positive; casein, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, and xanthine were decomposed.</s><s>Liquefaction of gelatin, hydrolysis of starch, reduction of nitrate, peptonization of milk, resistance to lysozyme, and decomposition of esculin were negative.</s><s>Acetate, D-arabinose, melibiose, raffinose, salicin, and sucrose were not utilized.</s><s>Growth of A49492 occurred within a temperature range of 10 to 45°C, with an optimum of 30°C.</s><s>A49492 tolerated a pH range of 6 to 9.5, levels of NaCl up to 6%, and sucrose concentrations up to 35%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Analysis of cell wall hydrolysates by paper chromatography demonstrated the presence of LL-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>No <i>meso</i> isomer was detected.</s><s>Sugar determinations indicated that only glucose and ribose were present.</s><s>This information indicates a type I cell wall and a type C sugar pattern (4).</s><s>The morphological and chemical characteristics of strain A49492 permit a clear assignment of the organism to the genus <i>Streptomyces</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A comparison of the characteristics of strain A49492 with the published descriptions of the currently recognized <i>Streptomyces</i> species indicated which species are most closely related (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The six <i>Streptomyces</i> species listed in Table 1 were reported as belonging in the (GY) color series (13), with spiral (S) (9) sporophore morphology, hairy spore surface ornamentation, and a carbon utilization pattern similar to that of A49492.</s><s>These reference strains were grown simultaneously with culture A49492 to obtain laboratory comparisons.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The similarity coefficients for each of the reference strains when compared with strain A49492 are given in Table 1.</s><s>Ns<sup>+</sup> is the number of positive similarities, Ns<sup>-</sup> is the number of negative similarities, and Nd is the number of dissimilarities.</s><s>The total units of measurement (Ns<sup>+</sup> + Ns<sup>-</sup> + Nd) were 152.</s><s>This figure was composed of morphological and physiological characters.</s><s>When only morphological characters were used, "<i>S . flavoviridis</i>" ATCC 19903 had the highest coefficient of similarity, but when both morphological and physiological characters were used, "<i>S. malachitofuscus</i>" ATCC 25471 had the greater number of common characters of similarity to A49492, as is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 2 lists in brief the similarities and differences among strain A49492, "<i>S. flavoviridis</i>" ATCC 19903, and "<i>S. malochitofuscus</i>" ATCC 25471.</s><s>The growth characteristics and pigmentation of all of the strains studied are presented in Table 3.</s><s>The color notations are from the ISCCNBS Centroid color charts (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A49492 was also compared with six <i>Streptomyces</i> species with respect to carbohydrates utilization patterns and antibiotic susceptibility.</s><s>The data for carbohydrate utilization are presented in Table 4, and the antibiotic susceptibilities of these strains are given in Table 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A49492 (7).</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited at the Northern Regional Research Center, Peoria, Ill., under the accession number 12279.</s></p></content></protolog>