<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12469_nm.21299" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21299" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21299" rank="species">Bacillus nanhaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.12469"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus nanhaiensis sp. nov., isolated from an oyster</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>888</fpage><lpage>893</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus nanhaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus nanhaiensis</em> (nan.hai.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nanhaiensis</em> pertaining to Nanhai, the Chinese name for the South China Sea, the source of the sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, aerobic, straight rods, approximately 0.4–0.6 µm wide and 4.0–6.0 µm long, occurring singly, as pairs or as short chains, producing oval endospores that lie in subterminal unswollen sporangia.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow-pigmented, flat and translucent, have glistening surfaces and circular/slightly irregular margins, and are 2–3 mm in diameter on NA.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Slightly halophilic and facultatively alkaliphilic; growth occurs in 0–18 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0.5–4.0 %), at pH 6.0–10.5 (optimum pH 8.0) and at 15–45 °C (optimum 30 °C).</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Negative for methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production tests.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose, DNA, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, and urea are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-glucose, glycogen, maltose, starch and sucrose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>d-Glucose, maltose, dextrin, d-mannitol, l-alanine and l-histidine are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy; l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, d-salicin, acetate, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, succinate, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine are not utilized.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8); α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities are not observed.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone and diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine as the predominant polar lipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JSM 082006<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23009<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 13712<sup>T</sup>), isolated from homogenates of an oyster collected from Naozhou Island in the South China Sea, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.2 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p></content></protolog>