<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1822_nm.1233" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1233" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1233" rank="species">Sandaracinobacter sibiricus</organism><reference id="rid.1822"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yurkov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buss</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vermeglio</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beatty</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of the genus Erythromicrobium: description of Erythromicrobium sibiricum as Sandaracinobacter sibiricus gen. nov., sp. nov., and of Erythromicrobium ursincola as Erythromonas ursincola gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1172</fpage><lpage>1178</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1172</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336925</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sandaracinobacter sibiricus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sandaracinobacter sibiricus</i> (si.bi'ri.cus. L. adj. <i>sibiricus</i>, isolated in Siberia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, yellow-orange-pigmented, thin, long rods, 0.3 to 0.5 by 1.5 to 2.5 μm or more.</s><s>Motile by means of subpolar flagella (up to three).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain Bchl <i>a</i> and carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Carotenoids give main absorption peaks at 424, 450, and 474 nm in vivo.</s><s>The cytoplasmic membranes contain an RC and LHI with absorption peaks at 750,799, and 857 nm for RC and 867 nm for LHI.</s><s>Tetraheme cyt <i>c</i> of 44.0 kDa is tightly bound to RC and is its immediate electron donor.</s><s>Additionally contain soluble cyt <i>c</i> of 14.0 kDa and membrane-bound cyt <i>c</i> of 30.0 kDa (cyt of <i>bc</i><sub>1</sub> complex).</s><s>Contains quinones Q<sub>9</sub> and Q<sub>10</sub>.</s><s>Menaquinone</s></p><p class="description"><s>is not found (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic chemoorganotroph and facultative photoheterotroph.</s><s>The best growth substrates are butyrate, sucrose, casein hydrolysate, and yeast extract.</s><s>Good growth is observed on acetate and maltose; weak growth on media containing glucose, fructose, pyruvate, propionate, or glycerol.</s><s>No utilization of ribose, sorbitol, benzoate, fumarate, formate, succinate, citrate, malate, methanol, or ethanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria; salinity above 1.0% NaCl/liter of media strongly inhibits growth.</s><s>The pH optimum is 7.5 to 8.5.</s><s>The bacteria exhibit oxidase activity and lack catalase activity.</s><s>Hydrolyze Tween 60 and do not hydrolyze gelatin or starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to chloramphenicol, fusidic acid, streptomycin, amikacin, bacitracin, kanamycin, neomycin, and novobiocin.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin, ampicillin, tetracycline, polymyxin B, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, lincomycin, mycostatin, aureomycin, and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Demonstrate a high level of resistance to tellurite.</s><s>Tellurite resistance depends on medium composition, particularly on organic carbon source.</s><s>The highest tellurite concentration tolerated is 1,200 μg/ml in media containing acetate or yeast extract as a sole organic source.</s><s>Tellurite can be reduced and transformed into metallic tellurium accumulated inside cells (42).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Storage compounds: polyphosphates, polysaccharide, and poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: freshwater algobacterial mat near hydrothermal sulfide-containing vents along the river bottom.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is RB16-17.</s></p></content></protolog>