<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6731_nm.2021" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2021" rank="genus">Azoarcus</organism><reference id="rid.6731"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold-Hurek</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azoarcus gen. nov., nitrogen-fixing proteobacteria associated with roots of kallar grass (Leptochloa fusca (L.) Kunth), and description of two species, Azoarcus indigens sp. nov. and Azoarcus communis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>574</fpage><lpage>584</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-574</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azourcas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azoarcus</i> (A.zo'ar.cus. Fr. n. <i>azote</i>, nitrogen; L. masc. n. <i>arcus</i>, arch, bow; M. L. masc. n. <i>Azoarcus</i>, nitrogen [-fixing] bow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods that occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cell pairs often appear to be slightly S shaped (Fig. 1a).</s><s>Cells range from 0.4 to 1.0 μm wide by 1.1 to 4.0 μm long.</s><s>In most strains, elongated cells (8 to 12 μm) occur rarely in late-log or stationary-phase cultures on semisolid or liquid SM medium supplemented with combined nitrogen (Fig. 1b).</s><s>The cells are all motile; strain BH72 is usually motile by means of a single polar flagellum (Fig. 1b); rarely there are two flagella.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>On nitrogen-free, semisolid media the strains exhibit microaerophilic growth; first veil-like pellicles are developed several millimeters below the medium surface, and later the pellicles move to the surface.</s><s>On Congo red agar, opaque pink colonies with translucent or whitish entire margins are formed; these colonies have a round, convex shape and a smooth texture.</s><s>Colonies develop a nondiffusible yellowish pigment, particularly on VM agar supplemented with ethanol instead of potassium malate.</s><s>Yellow pigmentation is less pronounced in strains belonging to groups C and D.</s><s>Chemoorganoheterotrophic.</s><s>Strictly respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>No denitrification.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>The presence of dissimilatory nitrate reductase and urease varies among strains.</s><s>Except for one species, no growth factor is required.</s><s>Capable of growth on atmospheric nitrogen (N<sub>2</sub>) and reduction of acetylene to ethylene.</s><s>Grows well on salts of organic acids like L-malate, acetate, proprionate, succinate, fumarate, DL-lactate, and pyruvate and on ethanol.</s><s>Growth on amino acids is restricted to L-glutamate and a few other amino acids and amines which can be used by some strains.</s><s>No growth occurs on mono- or disaccharides (Table 5).</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is between 37 and 40°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45°C.</s><s>N<sub>2</sub>-dependent growth occurs at 41°C.</s><s>Not halophilic.</s><s>Growth is not enhanced by addition of moderate concentrations of NaCl(0.25 to 0.75%).</s><s>Strains grow well at a neutral pH.</s><s>All strains have cis-9 16:1, 16:0, and 18:1 as their major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is between 62 and 68 mol%.</s><s>The members of this genus belong to the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Some characteristics which differentiate them from other morphologically similar diazotrophs are shown in Table 6.</s><s>The genus <i>Azoarcus</i> consists of five groups (Table 5) which differ at least at the species level.</s><s>Below we describe two groups that consist of several members and are located at the top of the rRNA branch as named species: <i>Azoarcus indigens</i> and <i>Azoarcus communis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>