<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7206_nm.5690" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5690" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5690" rank="species">Streptococcus thoraltensis</organism><reference id="rid.7206"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alvarez</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus hyovaginalis sp. nov. and Streptococcus thoraltensis sp. nov., from the genital tract of sows</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1073</fpage><lpage>1077</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1073</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336908</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus thoraltensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus thoraltensis</i> (thor.al.ten'sis. L. gen. n. <i>thoraltensis</i>, from Thoraltum, L.name of Torhout, the town where the strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Strains are capnophilic and are positive in Voges-Proskauer tests and tests for leucine arylamidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase (often weak), β-glucoside, and acidification of ribose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, saccharose, trehalose, gentiobiose, methyl- β-D-glucopyranoside, L-arabinose, inulin, starch, and pullulan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain S69 has been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Culture Collection as strain LMG 13593.</s><s>Strain S69<sup>T</sup> was isolated from the intestine of a pig in 1984.</s><s>Its characteristics are the same as those indicated above for the species.</s><s>In addition, S69<sup>T</sup> is positive for the following reactions which are variable in the species: α-galactosidase, hippurate, alkaline phosphatase, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, sorbitol, raffinose, D-xylose, amygdalin, and melibiose.</s><s>The G+C content of LMG 13593<sup>T</sup> is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>The two species described here are associated with pigs and appear to occur most frequently in pig vaginal fluids.</s><s>However, the number <i>S. hyovaginalis</i> strains studied was very low, and <i>S. thoraltensis</i> was also found in pig intestines.</s><s>Although the strains were isolated from postmortem specimens or from diseased animals, their possible involvement in pathological processes is not evident.</s></p></content></protolog>