<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8837_nm.13228" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13228" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13228" rank="species">Azospirillum rugosum</organism><reference id="rid.8837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siering</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hung</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azospirillum rugosum sp. nov., isolated from oil-contaminated soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>959</fpage><lpage>963</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65065-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398202</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Azospirillum rugosum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Azospirillum rugosum</em> (ru.go′sum. L. neut. adj. <em>rugosum</em> wrinkled, as the form of the colonies on the agar changes to a wrinkled appearance).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods and motile.</s><s>Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Ageing cells contain intracellular granules.</s><s>On tryptone soy agar, nutrient agar and BHI agar, light-orange colonies are formed that are initially smooth with entire margins, becoming wrinkled and irregular with age.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Grows at 22–37 °C and tolerates 2.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Has the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of the genus <em>Azospirillum</em>.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists mainly of straight-chain saturated and unsaturated fatty acids, with n-C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> as the major fatty acid, as well as 3-OH hydroxylated fatty acids.</s><s>The respiratory quinone consists of ubiquinone with ten isoprene units (Q-10).</s><s>Gelatin, hippurate and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Adipic acid, d-fructose, glycerol, potassium gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, malic acid and d-xylose are assimilated, but arbutin, d-glucose, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, phenylacetic acid and trisodium citrate are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose and d-xylose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, starch, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, citrate, dulcitol, inositol, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, gluconate, d-galactose, d-glucose, d- and l-fucose, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, d-lactose, d-lyxose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reductase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, 2-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, 4-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, pyrazinamidase and urease activities, but negative for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine aminopeptidase, tryptophan deaminase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase activities.</s><s>Positive for acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer), but negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IMMIB AFH-6<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53966<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19657<sup>T</sup>), isolated from oil-contaminated soil.</s></p></content></protolog>