<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7368_nm.3846" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3846" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3846" rank="species">Helicobacter mesocricetorum</organism><reference id="rid.7368"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Simmons</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riley</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Besch-Williford</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franklin</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter mesocricetorum sp. nov., A novel Helicobacter isolated from the feces of Syrian hamsters.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>1811</fpage><lpage>1817</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10790105</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter mesocricetorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter mesocricetorum</i> (the species name describes the monotypic genus from which this bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is a gram-negative, non-spore-forming, spirally curved rod-shaped bacterium (0.4 to 0.6 by 2 to 3 μm) with singular nonsheathed bipolar flagella.</s><s>Bacteria grew as pinpoint colonies or as a thin spreading film in microaerobic environments at both 37 and 42°C.</s><s>No growth was noted in a microaerobic environment at 25°C, and no growth occurred in aerobic or anaerobic environments at 37°C.</s><s>There is no growth in the presence of 1% glycine or 1.5% sodium chloride.</s><s>The bacterium has the enzymes catalase and alkaline phosphatase but lacks urease and 𝛾-glutamyltransferase.</s><s>The bacterium does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S and does not hydrolyze hippurate; however, it does reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Cells are resistant to cephalothin but sensitive to nalidixic acid.</s><s>The bacterium has been isolated from the feces of asymptomatic Syrian hamsters (<i>Mesocricetus auratus</i>).</s><s>The type strain is MU 97-1514.</s></p></content></protolog>