<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6728_nm.5778" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5778" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5778" rank="species">Actinomyces coleocanis</organism><reference id="rid.6728"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces coleocanis sp. nov., from the vagina of a dog.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1201</fpage><lpage>1203</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148628</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces coleocanis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces coleocanis</i> (co.le.o.can'is. Gr. n. <i>koleos</i> vagina; L. gen. n. <i>canis</i> of the dog; N.L. gen. n. <i>coleocanis</i> of the vagina of a dog)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, some of which exhibit branching.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-aciD-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Succinic acid and lactic acid are the main end products of glucose metabolism.Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose, glycogen, maltose, lactose and pullulan.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, N-acetyl β-glucosamine, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase and pyrazinamidase (weak reaction) are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, β-mannosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Respiratory menaquinones are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain M343/98/2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 41708<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106873<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the vagina of a cocker spaniel dog.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>