<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7323_nm.2899" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2899" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2899" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas prydzensis</organism><reference id="rid.7323"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas prydzensis sp. nov., a psychrotrophic, halotolerant bacterium form Antarctic sea ice.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1037</fpage><lpage>1041</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-1037</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734061</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoalteromonas prydzensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas prydzensis</i> (prydz.en.sis M.L. neut. adj. <i>prydzensis</i> pertaining to Prydz Bay, Antarctica, the site of sea ice samples from which the species was derived)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming, motile organism (0.5-0.7 µm in width and 1.0-2.5 µm in length).</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, translucent, convex, irregular to circular in shape with a lobate to circular edge, 3-7 mm in diameter and mucoid consistency.</s><s>Psychrotrophic, growing from 0°C to 30°C (optimum growth is 22-25°C), no growth occurs at 35°C or higher.</s><s>Requires sodium ions for growth, growing on media with a salinity ranging from 0.5 to 15% NaCl.</s><s>Tolerates 5% ox bile salts, 100 µg vibriostatic agent 0/129 ml<sup>-1</sup> and 20 µg ampicillin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 80, starch, chitin, casein and gelatin.</s><s>Strains may also hydrolyse aesculin and urea.</s><s>Agar, alginate, dextran, DNA, urate and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, L-tryptophan and L-phenylalanine deaminase, indole from L-tryptophan, hydrogen sulfide from L-cysteine, ONPG (β-galactosidase), nitrate reduction and denitrification tests are negative.</s><s>Strictly oxidative.</s><s>No growth occurs anaerobically by fermentation or by respiration with the following electron acceptors: ferric oxide, ferric pyrophosphate, nitrate and trimethylamine <i>N</i>-oxide (with acetate and DL-lactate as electron donors).</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from L-arabinose, D-glucose, D-mannose, maltose, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid may also be formed from cellobiose.</s><s>Acid is not formed from dextran, D-fructose, D-galactose, lactose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, adonitol, glycerol, D-mannitol, m-inositol, or D-sorbitol.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates for carbon and energy: glycogen, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, L-arabinose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, sucrose, trehalose, D-mannitol, glycerol, D-gluconate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, succinate, citrate, aconitate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, L-malate, fumarate, pyruvate, oxaloacetate, L-glutamate, L-proline, hydroxy-L-proline, L-serine and γ-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Some strains can also utilize cellobiose, D-galactose, m-inositol, α-glycerophosphate, valerate, isovalerate, octanoate, malonate, azelate, L-phenylalanine and L-tyrosine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: D-xylose, D-fructose, L-rhamnose, lactose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, D-arabitol, D-sorbitol, D-ghcuronate, saccharate, hexanoate, heptanoate, nonanoate, adipate, glutarate, pimelate, 2-oxoglutarate, DL-lactate, L-alanine, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-threonine, putrescine and urate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38-39 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 16:1ω7c, 16:0, 18:1ω7c and 17:1ω8c.</s><s>Isolated from sea ice.</s><s>The type strain is ACAM 620<sup>T</sup> (isolated from sea ice, Prydz Bay, Antarctica).</s></p></content></protolog>