<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4732_nm.3226" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3226" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3226" rank="species">Moellerella wisconsensis</organism><reference id="rid.4732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huntley-Carter</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saitoh</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moellerella wisconsensis, a new genus and species of Enterobacteriaceae found in human stool specimens.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>460</fpage><lpage>463</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6715516</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moellerella wisconsensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moellerella wisconsensis</i> (Since six of the nine isolates were from Wisconsin, we chose the specific name <i>wisconsensis</i> (pronounced Wis-kahn-sehn'-sis), a modern Latin feminine adjective)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Moellerella </i> is proposed for the group of strains formerly referred to as enteric group 46.</s><s>Strain 2896-78 (ATCC 35017) is proposed as the type strain.</s><s>There is presently only one species in the genus, so the description for the species is the same. <i>M. wisconsensis</i> is the type species for this genus.</s><s>A complete description of <i>M. wisconsensis</i> is given in Tables 2 through 6. <i>M. wisconsensis</i> has the general characteristics of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (Table 2).</s><s>It can be differentiated from other <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> because it gives negative tests for indole, Voges-Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urea, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase, gas production from D-glucose, motility, and acid production from trehalose and positive tests for methyl red, citrate (Simmons), and acid production from lactose and raffinose (Table 6).</s><s>All strains were resistant (no zone of inhibition) to colistin (Table 5).</s><s>They were all susceptible to cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, and nalidixic acid.</s><s>Only 22% were susceptble to ampicillin and carbenicillin.</s></p></content></protolog>