<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10107_nm.15064" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15064" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15064" rank="species">Pontibacter xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.10107"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pontibacter xinjiangensis sp. nov., in the phylum ‘Bacteroidetes’, and reclassification of [Effluviibacter] roseus as Pontibacter roseus comb. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011395-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648348</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pontibacter xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pontibacter xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, an autonomous region in north-west China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped and non-motile (0.4–0.6×1.2–2.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on 0.3× MA are circular, convex, shiny, pink and smooth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C (optimum 30 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0.</s><s>NaCl concentrations for growth are 0–5 % (w/v).</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, aesculin, starch and casein, but not tyrosine, chitin or cellulose.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, citrate utilization, indole production, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase and urease are negative.</s><s>According to API ZYM, the type strain is positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 microplates, the type strain is positive for dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, trehalose, l-leucine, d-gluconic acid, l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, d-arabinose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, melibiose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-histidine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid or 2-aminoethanol.</s><s>The major fatty acids of the type strain are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, summed feature 3 (containing C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>) and summed feature 4 (comprising anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B and/or iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I).</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 47.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 311-10<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207200<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-51335<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>