<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5278_nm.555" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.555" rank="species">Chloroflexus aggregans</organism><reference id="rid.5278"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chloroflexus aggregans sp. nov., a filamentous phototrophic bacterium which forms dense cell aggregates by active gliding movement.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>676</fpage><lpage>681</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-676</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547286</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chloroflexus aggregans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chloroflexus aggregans</i> (ag'gre.gans. L. v. <i>aggregare</i>, to flock or band together; L. pres, part. <i>aggregans</i>, assembling, aggregating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells-form unbranched multicellular filaments of indefinite length.The filaments are clearly septate.</s><s>The diameters of cells range from 1.0 to 1.5 μm.</s><s>Cells have no flagella but are motile by gliding.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Cultures grow by forming mat-like aggregates in liquid that have the appearance of green balls.Cell aggregates reform rapidly whenever a culture is shaken to produce a uniform suspension under growth conditions.</s><s>Photosynthetic cultures are green to greenish brown.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophylls <i>a</i> and <i>c</i> are present in phototrophically grown cells(under anaerobic conditions) and to a certain extent in chemotrophically grown cells under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Chlorosomes are present.</s><s>The major carotenoid components are γ-carotene and OH-γ-carotene glucoside fatty acid esters; there is also a trace amount of β-carotene.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thermophilic facultative phototrophs that grow optimally at 55°C.</s><s>Aerobic growth in the dark occurs at full atmospheric oxygen tension.</s><s>Thiamine and folic acid are required as growth factors.</s><s>Good carbon sources are yeast extract and CasaminoAcids.</s><s>Simple organic compounds such as intermediates of the citric acid cycle, glutamate, and aspartate are utilized as sole carbon sources only under phototrophic conditions.</s><s>The major quinone is menaquinone 10.</s><s>A trace amount of menaquinone 4 is also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: bacterial mats with cyanobacteria in freshwater of hot springs (50 to 67°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 56.7 to 57.0 mol% (as determined by the HPLC method).The type strain is strain MD-66 (= DSM 9485).</s></p></content></protolog>