<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9584_nm.14772" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14772" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14772" rank="species">Vogesella lacus</organism><reference id="rid.9584"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vogesella lacus sp. nov., isolated from a soft-shell turtle culture pond</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2629</fpage><lpage>2632</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009266-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625439</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vogesella lacus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vogesella lacus</em> (la′cus. L. gen. n. <em>lacus</em> of a lake or pond, referring to the source of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are accumulated.</s><s>After 48 h growth on R2A agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is about 0.8 μm in width and 1.5–2.3 μm in length.</s><s>Forms visible, round, entire, convex and colourless colonies.</s><s>The colony size is approximately 1.0–2.0 mm diameter on R2A agar after 48 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at 10, 15, 25, 30, 37 and 42 °C, 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl and pH 7–9.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–30 °C, 0.5 % NaCl and pH 7.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, lipase (corn oil), DNase (weak) activities.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein and Tweens 40 (weak), 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of starch and Tween 20.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are listed in Table 2.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, strain GR13<sup>T</sup> shows positive reactions for nitrate reduction, indole production and for the assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, citrate and malate.</s><s>Gives a negative reaction for d-glucose acidification, activities of l-arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, protease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and for the assimilation of l-arabinose, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, phenylacetate, gluconate and caprate.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN2 test system: <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, dl-lactic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, citric acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-alanine, l-proline, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine and l-alanyl glycine.</s><s>Strain GR13<sup>T</sup> is unable to oxidize maltose, cellobiose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, d-galactose, raffinose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, trehalose, lactulose, turanose, d-sorbitol, 2,3-butanediol, i-erythritol, adonitol, xylitol, d-arabitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, sucrose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, acetic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, bromosuccinic acid, urocanic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, itaconic acid, succinamic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, glucuronamide, l-leucine, l-serine, l-threonine, d-serine, d-alanine, phenylethylamine, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, dl-carnitine, d-alaninamide, 2-aminoethanol, putrescine, uridine, thymidine, inosine, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-gluconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-glucuronic acid, quinic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-saccharic acid, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, sebacic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, succinic acid monomethyl ester, succinic acid and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to tetracycline, kanamycin, rifampicin, gentamicin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, streptomycin, ampicillin and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GR13<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17836<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24504<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a freshwater pond used for the culture of soft-shell turtles (<em>Trionyx sinensis</em>), Pingtung County, Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>