<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9698_nm.14844" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14844" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14844" rank="species">Chitinilyticum litopenaei</organism><reference id="rid.9698"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>S.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>Y-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>T.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinilyticum litopenaei sp. nov., isolated from a freshwater shrimp pond, and emended description of the genus Chitinilyticum</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2651</fpage><lpage>2655</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005090-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620355</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinilyticum litopenaei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinilyticum litopenaei</em> (li.to.pen.ae′i. N.L. n. <em>Litopenaeus</em> the scientific name of a genus of shrimp; N.L. gen. n. <em>litopenaei</em> of <em>Litopenaeus</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a culture pond for Pacific white shrimp, <em>Litopenaeus vannamei</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 3.0–4.5 μm long and 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>They occur singly and are motile by single polar flagella.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are present.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on CB medium are surrounded by a large clear zone, derived from degradation of chitin.</s><s>Grows well by using chitin as the sole carbon, nitrogen and energy source under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C, pH 7.0–11.0 and 0–0.75 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase but negative for oxidase activity.</s><s>API 20NE tests show positive reactions for nitrate reduction, assimilation of mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and gluconate and negative reactions for glucose fermentation and gelatin hydrolysis, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of arabinose, mannitol, maltose, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, shows positive reactions for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and negative reactions for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, C8 lipase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, trypsin and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (positive in the Biolog GN2 system): dextrin, glucose, d-fructose, glycogen, maltose, sucrose, cellobiose, mannose, trehalose, turanose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, methyl pyruvate and gentiobiose.</s><s>The following substrates are not oxidized (negative in the Biolog GN2 system): gluconate, d-glucuronic acid, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactate, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, glucose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, arabinose, lactulose, psicose, melibiose, itaconic acid, l-fucose, inosine, <em>α</em>-lactose, d-galactose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, mannitol, xylitol, glycerol, arabitol, i-erythritol, d-galacturonic acid, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, 2-aminoethanol, monomethyl succinate, citrate, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, malonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, urocanic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, d-glucosaminic acid, phenylethylamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-aspartic acid, l-leucine, l-threonine, l-phenylalanine, l-asparagine, l- and d-alanine, l- and d-serine, l-proline, hydroxy-l-proline, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, dl-carnitine, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-alanyl glycine, putrescine, alaninamide, glucuronamide, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>Sensitive to amikacin (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), penicillin G (10 U) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acid components are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, c1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17609<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21440<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water of an aquaculture pond containing Pacific white shrimp (<em>Litopenaeus vannamei</em>) at Pingtung in southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>