<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7614_nm.14044" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14044" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14044" rank="species">Gaetbulibacter marinus</organism><reference id="rid.7614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gaetbulibacter marinus sp. nov., isolated from coastal seawater, and emended description of the genus Gaetbulibacter.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>315</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65382-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218924</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gaetbulibacter marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gaetbulibacter marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, chemoheterotrophic and obligately aerobic and show no flagellar or gliding motility.</s><s>Cells in exponential phase are rods, 0.8–1.9 μm long and 0.6–0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent (KOH test-negative).</s><s>The yellow pigments (absorption peaks at 478 and 451 nm) are probably of carotenoid type.</s><s>After 5 days incubation, colonies on MA are circular, convex, entire, smooth, yellow-coloured and 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 3–37 °C (optimum, 25 °C), at pH 8–11 (optimum, pH 9) and with 0.5–4.0 % NaCl (optimum, 1.0–1.5 %).</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, acid production from glucose, hydrolysis of urea, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities and gelatin liquefaction (API 20NE strips).</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed, but starch, elastin, CM-cellulose and chitin are not.</s><s>Other enzyme activities determined by using API ZYM strips are given in Table 1.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are oxidized (Biolog GN2 microplates): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, propionic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are not oxidized: glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), penicillin G (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and rifampicin (50 μg), but resistant to vancomycin (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (Table 2).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 38.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1914<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42380<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102040<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater off Deokjeok-do, Yellow Sea, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>