<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5667_nm.9910" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9910" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9910" rank="species">Chryseobacterium soldanellicola</organism><reference id="rid.5667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Do</surname><given-names>J.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium soldanellicola sp. nov. and Chryseobacterium taeanense sp. nov., isolated from roots of sand-dune plants</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>433</fpage><lpage>438</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63825-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium soldanellicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium soldanellicola</em> (sol.da.nel′li.co.la. N.L. n. <em>soldanella</em> the species epithet of a plant belonging to the genus <em>Calystegia</em>; L. suff. verbal n. <em>cola</em> dweller; N.L. masc. n. <em>soldanellicola</em> dweller of <em>Calystegia soldanella</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Good growth is observed on R2A agar, TSA and nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Grows at 5 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish, circular and shiny.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5–7 and that for optimal growth is pH 5.</s><s>Growth occurs aerobically, but not anaerobically.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–4 % (w/v) NaCl within 14 days.</s><s>The most abundant cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0 and iso-C17 : 0 3-OH.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Positive for cytochrome oxidase but negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, tryptophan deaminase and urease.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing aesculin and gelatin.</s><s>Weakly assimilates glucose, arabinose, mannose and maltose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, l-arabinose (weakly), d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose, turanose, mono-methyl succinate, acetic acid, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, 2,3-butanediol (weakly) and glycerol (weakly).</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-l-lactose, lactulose, mannitol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Results from API ZYM tests are given in Table 3.</s><s>The G+C content is 28·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>API ZYM profiles of strains PSD1-4<sup>T</sup> and PHA3-4<sup>T</sup> and other species of the genus <em>Chryseobacterium</em></s></p><p class="description"><s>Species: 1, <em>C. soldanellicola</em> (strain PSD1-4<sup>T</sup>); 2, <em>C. taeanense</em> (strain PHA3-4<sup>T</sup>); 3, <em>C. taichungense</em>; 4, <em>C. balustinum</em>; 5, <em>C. daecheongense</em>; 6,<em>C. defluvii</em>; 7, <em>C. formosense</em>; 8, <em>C. gleum</em>; 9, <em>C. indologenes</em>; 10, <em>C. indoltheticum</em>; 11, <em>C. joostei</em>; 12, <em>C. scophthalmum</em>.</s><s>All species showed positive reactions for 2-naphthyl phosphate, 2-naphthyl caprylate, l-leucyl 2-naphthylamide, l-valyl 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl phosphate and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate and showed negative reactions for 6-Br-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside.</s><s>Data for strains PSD1-4<sup>T</sup> and PHA3-4<sup>T</sup> and <em>C. taichungense</em> were obtained in this study; those for other reference species were taken from Hugo <em>et al.</em> (2003), Kim <em>et al.</em> (2005) and Young <em>et al.</em> (2005).</s><s>The intensity of the developed colour was measured on scale from 0 to 5 and interpreted as negative (−) when values ranged between 0 and 1 and positive (+) for values between 2 and 5 (Mudarris <em>et al.</em>, 1994).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PSD1-4<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12382<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100864<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the roots of <em>Calystegia soldanella</em> growing on a coastal area in Tae-an, Korea.</s><s>The type strain displays antifungal activity against <em>Fusarium oxysporum</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>