<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1236_nm.812" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.812" rank="genus">Rhodospirillum</organism><reference id="rid.1236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rearrangements of the species and genera of the phototrophic "purple nonsulfur bacteria."</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>340</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Rhodospirillum</i> Molisch 1907 (emend. van Niel 1944).</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Type species: <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> Molisch 1907. Other species: <i>Rhodospirillum photometricum</i> Molisch 1907, <i>Rhodospirillum fulvum</i> van Niel 1944, <i>Rhodospirillum molischianum</i> Giesberger 1947, <i>Rhodospirillurn salexigens</i> Drews 1982. Species removed from this genus: <i>Rhodospirillum tenue</i> Pfennig 1969.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spiral shaped, 0.5 to 1.5 μm wide, and motile by means of polar flagella and contain intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes as vesicles, lamellae, or stacks, but not as finger-like intrusions of the cytoplasmic membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell shape and polar flagellation are the main common properties of this genus, which is in other aspects rather heterogeneous.</s><s>All species have different growth factor requirements. <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> and <i>Rhodospirillum salexigens</i> grow well under aerobic conditions in the dark, whereas the other species are very sensitive to oxygen.</s><s>Three different types of intracytoplasmic membranes are present in the different species. <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> and <i>Rhodospirillum photometricum</i> have a large type of cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub>; the other species have a small type.</s><s>The major quinones are the same in <i>Rhodospirillum fulvum</i> and <i>Rhodospirillum molischianum</i> (ubiquinone and menaquinone with a side chain of nine isoprenoid units), but different in all other species.</s><s>Sulfate is reduced via 3'-phosphate adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate in <i>Rhodospirillum rubrum</i> and <i>Rhodospirillum fulvum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The heterogeneity of this genus may call for further separation into several genera.</s><s>However, this seems inappropriate until more strains of each species are studied in detail and more data become available to justify the establishment of new genera.</s></p></content></protolog>