<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5842_nm.10061" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10061" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10061" rank="species">Flavobacterium soli</organism><reference id="rid.5842"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium soli sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>997</fpage><lpage>1000</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64119-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627644</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic rods (0.3–0.6 μm×1.0–3.0 μm).</s><s>No flagella are detected.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, slightly convex, smooth, glistening, cream–yellow in colour and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25 °C; growth occurs at 4 and 33 °C, but not at 34 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.0; growth occurs at pH 6.5 and 8.0, but not at pH 6.0 or 8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0–0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No anaerobic growth occurs on plain TSA and on TSA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Congo red absorption is negative.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are positive, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are negative.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin G, chloramphenicol, cephalothin, novobiocin, tetracycline, lincomycin and oleandomycin, but not to polymyxin B, streptomycin, ampicillin, gentamicin, carbenicillin, kanamycin or neomycin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: l-arabinose, glucose, mannose, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, starch, gentiobiose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, fructose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 36.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DS-6<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12542<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108840<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>