<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5694_nm.3951" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3951" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3951" rank="species">Clostridium hydroxybenzoicum</organism><reference id="rid.5694"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium hydroxybenzoicum sp. nov., an amino acid-utilizing, hydroxybenzoate-decarboxylating bacterium isolated from methanogenic freshwater pond sediment.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>214</fpage><lpage>222</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-214</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186087</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium hydroxybenzoicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium hydroxybenzoicum</i> (hy. drox. y. ben. zo' i. cum. Gr. n. <i>hydro</i>, water; Gr. n. <i>oxys</i>, acid; N. L. n. <i>hydroxy</i>, water acid; Ger. and Fr, n. <i>benzoin</i>, frankincense of Java; Ger. n. <i>benzoesäure</i>, resin obtained from the tree <i>Styrax benzoin</i>; N. L. adj, <i>hydroxybenzoicum</i>, pertaining to the organic acid hydroxybenzoic acid, referring to the characteristic feature of this organism, the reversible decarboxylation of 4-hydroxybenzoate and 3,4-dibydroxybenzoate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two differently induced decarboxylases are responsible for the reversible decarboxylation of 4-hydroxybenzoate and the decarboxylation of 3,4-dihydroxybenzoate.</s><s>The use, however, of the decarboxylation products, e.g., phenol and catechol, as a carbon or energy source by <i>C. hydroxybenzoicum</i> was not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. hydroxybenzoicum</i> cells are strictly anaerobic, slightly curved rods that are 0.35 to 0.76 μm in diameter and 2.5 to 5.1 μm long, depending on the growth conditions and the growth stage.</s><s>The organism is nonmotile, and no flagella have been observed in negatively stained cells by use of an electron microscope.</s><s>Sporulating cells elongate to between 5.0 and 8.d μm long and produce terminal swollen sporangia (drumstick type).</s><s>Spores are round to slightly oval (diameter, 0.8 to 1.1 μm).</s><s>The Gram reaction of the cells from the early to late exponential growth phase is negative.</s><s>However, lipopolysaccharides are not detected, indicating that the organism is gram positive.</s><s>The cell wall type is A1α (L-LYS direct).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH supporting growth ranges from 6.1 to 10, and the optimal pH is 7.2 to 8.2.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 12 to 41°C, and the optimal temperature is 33 to 34°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. hydroxybenzoicum</i> requires yeast extract for growth.</s><s>Acetic acid and sodium ions at concentrations of up to 10 and 200 mM, respectively, stimulate growth, whereas 5% NaCl completely inhibits growth.</s><s>Neither CO<sub>2</sub>-HCO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> nor sulfide is required for growth; addition of nitrate, sulfate, or thiosulfate has no effect on growth.</s><s>During growth in mineral medium containing 1.5% yeast extract and 200 mM acetate, 5 mM butyrate, 4 mM isovalerate, 1 mM propionate, 1 mM isobutyrate, 0.2 mM isopentanol, and traces of valerate are formed, but H<sub>2</sub> is not formed.</s><s>Addition of 0.1% each of glycine, arginine, and lysine to yeast extract-containing medium stimulates growth three- to fivefold.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented; there is no significant acid formation from carbohydrates by resting cells.</s><s>Addition of H, plus CO,, ethanol, propanol, isobutanol, propionic acid, butyric acid, isobutyric acid, valeric acid, pyruvic acid, lactic acid, uric acid, adenine, hypoxanthine, guanine, or xanthine does not stimulate growth.</s><s>Tests for catalase activity, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, lipase activity, gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of starch, glycogen, or esculin, and lecithinase activity are negative; tests for indole and sulfide formation are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 35.5 mol% G+C (as determined by the chemical method).</s><s>So far, <i>C. hydroxybenzoicum</i> has been enriched and isolated only from methanogenic sediment from a freshwater pond in Athens, Ga.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain JW/Z-1 is the type strain of <i>C. hydroxybenzoicum</i> ATCC 51151 = DSM 7310.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of this strain is 35.5 mol%, and the accession number of its 16s rRNA is L11305.</s><s>The properties of the type strain are the same as those described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>