<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.129_nm.8114" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8114" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8114" rank="species">Flavobacterium spiritivorum</organism><reference id="rid.129"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Owen</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium spiritivorum, a new species isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>165</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium spiritivorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium spiritivorum</i> (spi.ri.ti'vo.rum. L. noun <i>spiritus</i> spirit; L. adj. suffix <i>-vorus</i> devouring, eating; M.L. adj. <i>spiritivorus</i> spirit-devouring, intended to refer to the ability of the organism to attack spirits, i.e., alcohol, producing acid in the process)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the type strain, E7288 (= NCTC 11386), also listed in Tables 2 through 6, are as follows: Gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods, 1.O μm in length, of regular shape with rounded ends.</s><s>Nonmotile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular, low convex, smooth, and opaque colonies developing on nutrient agar after 2 days; colonies nonhemolytic on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar; on nutrient agar, a yellow, nonfluorescent pigment is produced.</s><s>There is no production of brown pigment on tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 37°C but not at 5 or 42°C.</s><s>Optimal temperature: about 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of catalase, cytochrome oxidase, and deoxyribonuclease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of urease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No toleration of KCN at a concentration of 0.0075% (wt/vol).</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 20 and Tween 80.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of nitrate to nitrite; no reduction of nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of indole or hydrogen sulfide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on Mac-Conkey agar, but not on cetrimide agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No digestion of casein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of esculin, gelatin, and tributyrin, but not starch or tyrosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No utilization of citrate and malonate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No oxidation of gluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of arginine desimidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, or ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of 3-ketolactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No reduction of selenite and no deamination of phenylalanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of phosphatase and β-D-galactosidase (when tested, respectively, by method 1 of Cowan and the method given by Holmes et al.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, cellobiose, glycerol, ethanol, fructose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, ratfinose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from adonitol, arabinose, dulcitol, inositol, rhamnose, or sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of acid, but not gas, from glucose in peptone-water medium; production of acid in only the open tube of Hugh and Lesson oxidation-fermentation glucose medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of the following enzymes (using various API ZYM galleries): alkaline phosphatase, N-benzoyl-DL-arginyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase , acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, α-D-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminidase, α-L-arabinofuranosidase, β-D-cellobiosidase, L-lysyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-histidyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-L-aspartyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-arginyl-2-naphthylamideh hydrolase, L-alanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-L-prolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-leucyl-glycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-lutaminyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-L-glutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-L-arginyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No production of the following enzymes (using various API ZYM galleries): esterase (C-4), esterase-lipase (C-8), lipase (C-14), L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-cystyl-2-naphthylarnide hydrolase, N-glutaryl-L-phenylalanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, α-D-galactosidase, β-D-galactosidase, β-D-glucuronidase, β-D-glucosidase, α-D-mannosidase, α-L-fucosidase, exo-1,4-β-D-xylosidase, phosphatase, α-D-xylosidase, β-D-fucosidase, β-L-fucosidase, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminidase, lactosidase, arylsulfatase, L-tyrosyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-pyroglutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-phenyldanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-hydroxprolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, γ-L-glutamyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, S-benzyl-L-cysteyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-methionyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-glycyl-glycyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, glycyl-L-phe-nylal-alanyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-seryl-tyrosyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, N-carbobenzoxy-L-arginyl-4-methoxyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-isoleucyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-ornithyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-prolyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-seryl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase, L-threonyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase,</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-tvptophyl-2-naphthylamide hydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, amikacin, gentamicin, kanamycin, tobramycin, chloramphenicol, and tetracycline.</s><s>Susceptible to rifampin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content of DNA: 41.0 mol% (thermal denaturation temperature estimation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: isolated from an intrauterine specimen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two additional strains of <i>F. spiritivorum</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type Cultures: A14/65 as NCTC 11387 and CL48/80 as MCTC 11388.</s></p></content></protolog>