<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2368_nm.11198" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11198" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11198" rank="species">Pelagicoccus mobilis</organism><reference id="rid.2368"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yasumoto-Hirose</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nozawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pelagicoccus mobilis gen. nov., sp. nov., Pelagicoccus albus sp. nov. and Pelagicoccus litoralis sp. nov., three novel members of subdivision 4 within the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia', isolated from seawater by in situ cultivation</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1377</fpage><lpage>1385</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64970-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625161</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pelagicoccus mobilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pelagicoccus mobilis</em> (mo.bi′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>mobilis</em> movable, mobile, referring to the ability to move by means of flagella).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are obligately aerobic cocci that are 0.5–0.7 μm in diameter.</s><s>Motile by means of single or multiple flagella.</s><s>Appendages are found on some cells.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/2 strength R2A agar medium with 75 % artificial seawater are circular, convex and white.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C, the optimal temperature is between 28 and 30 °C, but no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 7.0–9.0.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth; tolerates up to 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of ampicillin (1–1000 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and penicillin G (1–1000 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Catalase reaction is negative, oxidase reaction is positive.</s><s>Aesculin and urea are hydrolysed, but agar, DNA, starch and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for acetoin, ONPG, tryptophan deaminase, citrate utilization, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide and indole production.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose, but not from glycerol, galactose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 5-ketogluconate, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, glucose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannnopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, maltose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Tests for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are positive, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The usual components of bacterial cell walls such as muramic acid and diaminopimelic acid can not be detected.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (29.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (23.3 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (15.1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (5.9 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (5.8 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2.3 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (2.1 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2.1 %).</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 02PA-Ca-133<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08004<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15422<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 13126<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater.</s></p></content></protolog>