<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.580_nm.5129" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5129" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5129" rank="species">Paenibacillus favisporus</organism><reference id="rid.580"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Miguel</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poza</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Villa</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus favisporus sp. nov., a xylanolytic bacterium isolated from cow faeces.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>59</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02709-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742459</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus favisporus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus favisporus</em> (fa.vi.spo′rus. L. n. <em>favus</em> a honeycomb; Gr. n. <em>spora</em> a seed, spore; N.L. masc. adj. <em>favisporus</em> referring to the honeycomb form of spores).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-variable, motile, aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, chemo-organotrophic, xylanolytic bacteria.</s><s>Colonies on YED medium are circular, convex, white with a central brown spot, translucent and usually 1–3 mm in diameter within 48 h at 37 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C; optimal growth pH is 7.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Spore-forming rods, 2–3 μm long and 0·5–0·7 μm wide.</s><s>Spores slightly swell the sporangia and they are in subterminal position in cells.</s><s>Spores have a ornamentation similar to that of honeycomb.</s><s>This species is phylogenetically most closely related to <em>P. azoreducens</em>.</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53 mol%.</s><s>The main fatty acid is anteiso-branched C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Gas is not produced from d-glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, sucrose, d-mannose, lactose, raffinose, rhamnose, melibiose, maltose, xylose and mannitol.</s><s>Xylan, CM-cellulose and starch are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>By contrast, no growth occurs in l-arabinose, citrate, inositol, sorbitol, glucitol or xylitol as carbon sources.</s><s>Xylanases, cellulases, gelatinase, urease, amylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are produced actively, but caseinase, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, tyrosinase, indole, dihydroxyacetone, hydrogen sulfide, acetylmethylcarbinol and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer medium) are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, penicillin, oxacillin, bacitracin, piperacillin, gentamicin and cefoxitin; resistant to tobramicin, cephalexin and dibekacin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GMP01<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 20987<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5760<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from old cow dung in Salamanca, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>