<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8485_nm.13189" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13189" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13189" rank="species">Acinetobacter beijerinckii</organism><reference id="rid.8485"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nemec</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Musílek</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maixnerová</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Baere</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van der Reijden</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dijkshoorn</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acinetobacter beijerinckii sp. nov. and Acinetobacter gyllenbergii sp. nov., haemolytic organisms isolated from humans</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>118</fpage><lpage>124</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001230-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126734</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acinetobacter beijerinckii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acinetobacter beijerinckii</em> [bei.je.rin′cki.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>beijerinckii</em> of Beijerinck, named in honour of Martinus Willem Beijerinck (1851–1931), the Dutch microbiologist and botanist].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the characterization of 15 strains (Supplementary Table S1 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics correspond to those of the genus (Baumann <em>et al.</em>, 1968), i.e. cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, non-motile coccobacilli, capable of growth in mineral media with acetate as the sole carbon source and ammonia as the sole source of nitrogen but incapable of dissimilative denitrification.</s><s>Positive in the transformation assay of Juni (1972).</s><s>Colonies on tryptone soya agar after 24 h incubation at 30 °C are approximately 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter, circular, convex, smooth and slightly opaque with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures ranging from 25 to 37 °C, but not at 41 °C.</s><s>Sheep and horse erythrocytes are lysed in 24 h at 30–37 °C.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose; gelatin is hydrolysed by some (13 %) strains.</s><s>Acetate, ethanol, citrate (Simmons'), 4-aminobutyrate, l-aspartate, l-histidine, d-malate and malonate are utilized as sole sources of carbon, with growth becoming visible after 2 days incubation.</s><s>No growth occurs on dl-lactate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, glutarate, azelate, <em>β</em>-alanine, histamine, l-phenylalanine, phenylacetate, levulinate, citraconate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, l-tartrate, l-ornithine, l-arginine, d-glucose, d-gluconate, d-ribose, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, benzoate, adipate, gentisate, tryptamine, trigonelline, tricarballylate or putrescine within 10 days.</s><s>l-Leucine is utilized by most (93 %) strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains studied were isolated from human (sputum, peritoneal dialysis fluid, gall, throat swab, perineal swab, faeces) and equine (airways) clinical specimens, from a hospital environment and staff (skin), and soil and water (Supplementary Table S1 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The type strain, NIPH 838<sup>T</sup> (=LUH 4759<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 51249<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7266<sup>T</sup>=58a<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in 1980 from the wound of a patient at the hospital in Malmö, Sweden (Tjernberg &#x0026; Ursing, 1989).</s><s>The type strain grows weakly on l-leucine and does not hydrolyse gelatin after 2 days incubation.</s></p></content></protolog>