<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2103_nm.2913" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2913" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2913" rank="species">Psychromonas profunda</organism><reference id="rid.2103"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rüger</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Kegel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glansdorff</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychromonas profunda sp. nov., a psychropiezophilic bacterium from deep Atlantic sediments.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>527</fpage><lpage>532</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02227-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710622</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychromonas profunda</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychromonas profunda</em> (pro.fun′da. L. fem. adj. <em>profunda</em> from the deep).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, either isolated or in pairs, 0·9–1·2 μm wide and 2·0–5·5 μm long, motile by means of a single, unsheathed and polar flagellum.</s><s>On peptone/yeast extract/sea-water agar, colonies are smooth, colourless, translucent, irregular, punctiform and flat with an intact margin.</s><s>Moderately halophilic (no growth observed in the absence of NaCl, normal growth with half-strength sea-water), strictly psychrophilic and moderately piezophilic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 2 °C (or less, not tested) to 12–13 °C (14 °C on plates).</s><s>Maximal growth is observed at 3–4 °C under atmospheric pressure.</s><s>Growth is influenced favourably by pressure, with a maximum at 15–20 MPa at 6 °C and about 25 MPa at 10 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and prototrophic (with possible vitamin dependency, not tested) chemo-organotroph capable of both respiratory and fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but no gas is produced.</s><s>Indole and ONPG tests are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from cysteine.</s><s>Susceptible to discs (Oxoid) containing 150 μg O/129, 2 U penicillin G, 10 μg tetracycline, 10 μg chloramphenicol, 50 μg furazolidone and 300 U polymyxin B.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are C14 : 1, C16 : 0 and C16 : 1.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively and fermentatively from glucose, lactose, cellobiose, dulcitol (weakly), fructose, galactose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and xylose; no acid from adonitol, arabinose, melibiose, raffinose or sorbitol.</s><s>Within 4 weeks at 4 °C, utilizes cellobiose, galactose, gluconate, maltose, salicin, sucrose (weakly), trehalose, xylose, fumarate, succinate, mannitol (weakly), citrate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, glutamate and putrescine as sole carbon and energy sources but not arabinose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, mannose, ribose, propionate, adipate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, sorbitol, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate or quinate.</s><s>Acetate, dl-lactate and glycerol are utilized only after prolonged incubation for up to 6 weeks.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed only weakly and gelatin not at all.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed and the DNase test is positive.</s><s>Lipase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type and only strain, strain 2825<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21260<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11437<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the upper layer of deep Atlantic sediments at a depth of 2770 m off the West African coast.</s></p></content></protolog>