<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7022_nm.2332" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2332" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2332" rank="species">Thiomicrospira frisia</organism><reference id="rid.7022"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brinkhoff</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muyzer</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wirsen</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thiomicrospira kuenenii sp. nov. and Thiomicrospira frisia sp. nov., two mesophilic obligately chemolithoautotrophic sulfur-oxidizing bacteria isolated from an intertidal mud flat.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>392</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-385</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319459</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiomicrospira frisia</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiomicrospira frisia</i> (fri'.si.a. M.L. fem. adj. <i>frisia</i> pertaining to Frisia, a coastal region in the north-west of Germany and the Netherlands)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile and bent-rod shaped (0.3-0-5 x 1-0-2.7 μm).</s><s>During late-exponential growth cells have a strong tendency to clump and to form aggregates. <i>T. frisia</i> is strictly aerobic and grows autotrophically on thiosulfate, tetrathonate, sulfur and sulfide, but not on sulfite or thiocyanate.</s><s>The organism does not grow heterotrophically.</s><s>When thiosulfate is used as the primary energy source small amounts of sulfur and sulfite are produced.</s><s>During growth on reduced sulfur compounds the pH decreases from neutrality to around 3-5.</s><s>Thiosulfate is completely oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth on thiosulfate occurs between pH 4.2 and 8.5 and at a temperature of 3-5-39°C; optimum growth occurs at pH 6-5 and at 32-35°C.</s><s>The optimal Na<sup>+</sup> concentration for growth is 470 mM; growth is possible between a Na<sup>+</sup> concentration of 100 and 1240mM.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> is fixed by means of ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>Nitrate is not used as terminal electron acceptor, On thiosulfate agar, cells produce white to yellowish, smooth, entire colonies (diameter on 1.2 %, w/v, agar is 2-5 mm) in which sulfur is deposited and acid is produced.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-S is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39.6 mol%.</s><s>As determined by a 16s rRNA gene sequence analysis, <i>T. frisia</i> belongs to the gamma subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is closely related to previously described members of the genus <i>Thiomicrospira</i>.</s><s>The type strain of the species is JB-A2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12351<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the nearly complete 16s rRNA gene sequence of <i>T. frisia</i> is AF013974.</s></p></content></protolog>