<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7502_nm.4555" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4555" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter subterraneus</organism><reference id="rid.7502"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacter subterraneus sp. nov., a novel thermophile isolated from oilfield water.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2141</fpage><lpage>2149</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155990</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter subterraneus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter subterraneus</i> (sub.ter.ra'ne.us. L. pref. <i>sub</i> less than; L. n. <i>terra</i> earth; L. adj. <i>subterraneus</i> under the earth, describing its site of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods (0.5-0.7x2-8 μm), occur singly or in pairs and possess laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Spores are not observed under microscopic examination but cultures exposed to 120 °C for 45 min could be subcultured, suggesting the presence of heat-resistant forms.</s><s>Electron microscopic examinations reveal a Gram-positive cell wall.</s><s>Round colonies (3 mm diam.) develop in Phytagel roll tubes after 3 d incubation at 70°C.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and obligately anaerobic member of the domain Bacteria.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 65 °C at pH7.5; temperature range for growth is 40-75°C.</s><s>Optimum pH is 7.5; growth occurs between pH 6.0 and 8.5.</s><s>Halotolerant, growing in the presence of up to 3% NaCl.</s><s>Yeast extract or Bio-trypticase is required for growth on carbohydrates.</s><s>Growth on sugars is highly enhanced by the presence of both yeast extract and Bio-trypticase.</s><s>Yeast extract cannot be replaced by vitamins.</s><s>Ferments cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, DL-lactose, DL-maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, D-ribose, starch, D-xylose, mannitol, pyruvate and xylan.</s><s>Glycerol is poorly utilized and L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, sorbose, sucrose and L-xylose are not used.</s><s>Acetate, L-alanine, lactate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> are produced during glucose fermentation.</s><s>Elemental sulfur, thiosulfate and sulfite, but not sulfate, are used as electron acceptor.</s><s>The DNA G­C content is 41 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from oilfield water.</s><s>Type strain is SEBR 7858<sup>T</sup> (=CNCM I-2383<sup>T</sup>, DSM 13054<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>