<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3639_nm.2300" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2300" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2300" rank="species">Thioploca ingrica</organism><reference id="rid.3639"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maier</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Thioploca ingrica sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>344</fpage><lpage>345</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-344</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thioploca ingrica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thioploca ingrica</i> (Thi.o.plo'ca. Gr. neut. n. <i>thion</i> sulfur; Gr. fem. n. <i>ploke</i> a braid, a twist: M.L. fem. n. <i>Thioploca</i> a sulfur braid; in'gri.ca. M.L. adj. <i>ingrica</i> pertaining to Ingria, ancient district of Leningrad, Russia.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Flexible trichomes made up of numerous cells, generally with numerous sulfur inclusions, occur in parallel or braided fascicles, which are enclosed by a common sheath of xariable width.</s><s>The number of trichomes within a sheath is variable.</s><s>The sheath is frequently encrusted with detritus.</s><s>Individual trichomes show independent gliding movement, and they may emerge from the ends of sheaths or from breaks in a sheath.</s><s>The long trichomes are of uniform diameter, and their terminal segments are often tapered.</s><s>Trichome diameters are 2.0 to 4.5 μm.</s><s>Cell length, exclusive of the terminal cell, varies from 1.5 to 8.0 μm.</s><s>Microaerophilic.</s><s>Identified from sediments of fresh and brackish waters of various localities in Central Europe and Lake Erie.</s><s>Not isolated in pure culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A descriptioh of nutritional and physiological characteristics must await procurement of pure cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiation between <i>T. schmidlei</i> and <i>T. ingrica</i> is based exclusively on trichome diameters, which are 5.0 to 9.0 and 2.0 to 4.5 μm, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics which qualify <i>T. ingrica</i> for inclusion in the genus <i>Thioploca</i>.</s><s>The following characteristics qualify <i>T. ingrica</i> for inclusion in the genus <i>Thioploca</i>: flexible, uniseriate, multicellular, independently gliding trichomes with sulfur inclusions, enclosed by a common sheath: uniform diameter’of trichomes except for terminal segments; found in the upper layers of sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics essential for membership in the species <i>T. ingrica</i>.</s><s>The following characteristics are essential for membership in the species <i>T. ingrica</i>: trichome diameter, 2.0 to 4.5 μm; isolated from sediments of fresh and brackish waters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Diagnostic characteristics.</s><s>The following characteristics are diagnostic: uniform trichome diameter of 2.0 to 4.5 μm; common sheath; sulfur inclusions; independent gliding movement; lack of obvious pigments; isolated from fresh or brackish water sediments</s></p></content></protolog>