<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5853_nm.6568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6568" rank="species">Asanoa ishikariensis</organism><reference id="rid.5853"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal to transfer Catellatospora ferruginea and 'Catellatospora ishikariense' to Asanoa gen. nov. as Asanoa ferruginea comb. nov. and Asanoa ishikariensis sp. nov., with emended description of the genus Catellatospora.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>967</fpage><lpage>972</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02011-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054264</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Asanoa ishikariensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Asanoa ishikariensis</i> (ish.i.ka.ri.en'sis. N.L. deriv. adj. <i>ishikariensis</i> of Ishikari-gun, Hokkaido, Japan, the origin of the soil sample from which the type stain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Originally described as `<i>Catellatospora ishikariense</i>'.</s><s>Utilizes D-arabinose, L-arabinose, dextran, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, methyl a-dglucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, starch, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, dulcitol and D-mannitol as carbon sources.</s><s>No growth on inulin, D-melezitose, salicin, L-sorbose, butanol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, ethanol, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, 2-propanol, 1-propanol, D-sorbitol or D-xylitol.</s><s>Does not decompose adenine, hippurate, hypoxanthine, DL-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, gelatin and starch but not DNA or elastin.</s><s>Grows on 0.001% brilliant green.</s><s>No growth on 0.0001% crystal violet, 3% NaCl or 0.01% lysozyme.</s><s>Susceptible to 50 μg gentamicin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 5 μg neomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 100 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 10 μg tetracycline ml<sup>-1</sup> but resistant to 50 μg novobiocin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 20 μg vancomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>No growth at 37 °C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71.1 mol%.</s><s>The phospholipid profle consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>A trace amount of phosphatidylglycerol is also detected.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by significant amounts of anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> (24.5%), C<sub>17:1</sub> (23.8%), iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> (15.8%) and C<sub>17:0</sub> (11.8%) acids.</s><s>Small amounts of iso-C<sub>17:0</sub> (6.3%), iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> (4.4%), C<sub>15:0</sub> (2.8%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (1.8%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (1.1%) and C<sub>19:0</sub> (1.0%) acids are also present.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain is strain IMSNU 22004<sup>T</sup> (=IFO 14551<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>