<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5268_nm.940" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.940" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.940" rank="species">Roseococcus thiosulfatophilus</organism><reference id="rid.5268"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yurkov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuerst</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hugenholtz</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Golecki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gad'on</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drews</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic positions of novel aerobic, bacteriochlorophyll a-containing bacteria and description of Roseococcus thiosulfatophilus gen. nov., sp. nov., Erythromicrobium ramosum gen. nov., sp. nov., and Erythrobacter litoralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>427</fpage><lpage>434</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-427</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520734</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Roseococcus thiosulfatophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Roseococcus thiosulfatophilus</i> (thi.o.sul.fa.to'phi.lus. M. L. adj. <i>thiosulfatophilus</i>, thiosulfate liking)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species below is based on the original description of Yurkov and Gorlenko (45) and new data.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, pink cocci that are 0.9 to 1.3 by 1.3 to 1.6 μm and are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Cells contain Bchl <i>a</i> and carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Membranes isolated from cells grown semiaerobically in the dark have absorption maxima at 478, 501, and 505 nm (carotenoids) and at 800 and 855 nm (Bchl).</s><s>The major carotenoid is C<sub>30</sub> carotenedioate.</s><s>Aerobic, chemoorganotrophic, and facultatively photoheterotrophic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs on yeast extract and when succinate, acetate, pyruvate, citrate, lactate, malate, or glutamate is used as a sole carbon source; weak growth occurs with glucose, maltose, and glycerol.</s><s>Fructose, sucrose, ribose, arabinose, butyrate, formate, fumarate, propionate, benzoate, tartrate, methanol, ethanol, mannitol, glycolate, and methanol are not used.</s><s>Casein is hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells can oxidize thiosulfate to sulfate in the presence of organic compounds.</s><s>Ribulose diphosphate carboxylase activity is not detected.</s><s>The cells are susceptible to tetracycline, streptomycin, polymyxin B, erythromycin, amikacin, kanamycin, neomycin, aureomycin, vancomycin, chloramphenicol, and fusidic acid, but resistant to gentamicin, lincomycin, nystatin (Mycostatin), bacitracin, and penicillin.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The storage material consists of polysaccharides, poly-β-hydroxybutyrate, and polyphosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: freshwater cyanobacterial mat of a thermal alkaline sulfide spring (54°C; pH 9.3; 7.4 mg of sulfide per liter; 1.6 mg of oxygen per liter).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is RB3 (= DSM 8511).</s></p></content></protolog>