<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6798_nm.5817" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5817" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5817" rank="species">Arcanobacterium phocae</organism><reference id="rid.6798"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pascual Ramos</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of the genus Actinomyces based on 16S rRNA gene sequences: description of Arcanobacterium phocae sp. nov., Arcanobacterium bernardiae comb. nov., and Arcanobacterium pyogenes comb. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>46</fpage><lpage>53</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-46</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995800</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arcanobacterium phocae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Arcanobacterium phocae (phoc'ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>phocae</i>, of Phoca, because the organism has been isolated from seals [the genus <i>Phoca</i>])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of morphological and physiological characteristics is based on the results of studies of six strains.</s><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, non-spore-forming, non-acid-fast coccobacilli and short rods that occur singly, in pairs, or in clusters; primary branching is not observed.</s><s>Short diphtheroid forms may occur.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar (incubated for 24 h) are white, tiny, circular, low convex and surrounded by a zone of β-hemolysis which may be two to three times the diameter of the colony.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth is not enhanced by increased concentrations of CO<sub>2</sub> (5 to 10%).</s><s>The catalase reaction is variable.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly fermentative.</s><s>Acid but not gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, ribose, galactose, glucose, fructose, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, lactose, saccharose, starch, glycogen, D-turanose, and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Most strains ferment mannose, inositol, trehalose, and melezitose, and a few strains ferment mannitol, D-xylose, D-tagatose, and gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, cellobiose, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-D-xyloside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, melibiose, inulin, D-raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, and 2-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Gelatin, esculin, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, esterase (C4), esterase-lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, and leucine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Production of trypsin is variable.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase are not produced (Table 3). <i>Arcanobacterium phocae</i> has been isolated from various tissues and fluids of common seals (<i>Phoca vitulina</i>) and grey seals (<i>Halichoerus grypus</i>), for which its pathological significance is unclear, but it has been recovered in mixed cultures from pneumonic and septicemic seals.</s><s>Type strain M1590/94/3 has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10002.</s><s>The type strain possesses the characteristics of the species except that it is catalase positive and produces trypsin.</s><s>M1590/94/3<sup>T</sup> ferments inositol, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, trehalose, and D-xylose but does not ferment D-tagatose and gluconate.</s></p></content></protolog>