<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8856_nm.13610" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13610" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13610" rank="species">Sphingobacterium canadense</organism><reference id="rid.8856"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mehnaz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weselowski</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lazarovits</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium canadense sp. nov., an isolate from corn roots.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>30</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>519</fpage><lpage>524</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2007.06.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17629434</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobacterium canadense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobacterium canadense</em> (ca.na.den'se. N.L. neut. adj. canadense, pertaining to Canada; region of isolation, referring to its isolation from Canada)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram negative, short rods, 0.8–1.0×1.0–1.9 μm in size, non-motile.</s><s>Growth occurs on LB at 20–37 °C but not at 41 °C, at pH 5–10 and concentrations of 0.5–3% NaCl are tolerated.</s><s>After 24–48 h growth on LB, colonies are circular, entire, low convex, smooth, off-white and turn yellow (non- fluorescent pigment) after a few days.</s><s>Bacterial cultures are positive for IAA production and negative for phosphate solubilization.</s><s>Dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melbiose, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, succinic acid mono-methyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-keto valeric acid, propionic acid, l-asparagine, l-proline and glycerol are oxidized but d-mannitol, l-arabinose, l-fucose, myo-inositol, maltose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, citric acid, d, l-lactic acid, malonic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, potassium gluconate, trisodium citrate, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-serine and l-threonine are not oxidized.</s><s>Positive for acid production from d- and L-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl alpha d-glucopyranoside, esculin ferric citrate, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, d-turanose and l-fucose.</s><s>Negative for glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl beta d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl alpha d-mannopyranoside, arbutin, d-trehalose, <em>N</em>-acetyl glucosamine, amygdalin, glycogen, xylitol, gentibiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, urease, nitrate reduction, <em>ß</em>-glucosidase, <em>ß</em>-galactosidase, gelatine hydrolysis and negative for indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 16:0, 15:0 iso, 17:0 iso 3-OH and summed feature 3 (16:1 ω7c/16:1 ω6c).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CR11<sup>T</sup> (=NCCB100125 <sup>T</sup>=LMG 23727 <sup>T</sup>), was isolated from roots of corn (<em>Zea mays</em>) in London, Ontario, Canada.</s></p></content></protolog>