<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5654_nm.8005" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8005" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8005" rank="species">Anaerophaga thermohalophila</organism><reference id="rid.5654"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denger</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Warthmann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerophaga thermohalophila gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately thermohalophilic, strictly anaerobic fermentative bacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>173</fpage><lpage>178</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837300</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerophaga thermohalophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerophaga thermohalophila</i> (ther.mo.ha.lo'phi.la. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i> warm, hot; Gr. masc. n. <i>hals</i>, halos salt ; Gr. masc. n. <i>philos</i> friend, loving; M.L. fem. adj. <i>thermohalophila</i> heat and salt loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slender flexible rods with rounded ends, 0.3x3.8 μm in size.</s><s>Formation of spheres and spore-like structures in ageing cultures.</s><s>Strict anaerobe, catalase and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Cytochromes of β-type present.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, arabinose, xylose, cellobiose, mannose, trehalose, raffinose, galactose, starch and (contrary to a previous report) lactose used for growth.</s><s>Hexoses and pentoses fermented to equal molar amounts of acetate, propionate and succinate.</s><s>No growth with ribose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, mannitol, glycerol, glycerate, tartrate, malate, glycolate, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, methanol, ethanol, ethylene glycol, acetoin, alanine, serine, threonine, glutamate, aspartate, proline, cellulose, arabinogalactan, chitin, yeast extract or peptone.</s><s>Growth requires media with enhanced CO<sub>2</sub>/bicarbonate content and salt concentrations of at least 2%(w/v).</s><s>Salt tolerance between 2 and 12%(w/v), optimum at 2-6%.</s><s>Growth possible at 37-55 °C with an optimum at 50 °C; no growth at 30 and 60 °C.</s><s>Ageing cultures exposed to daylight form an orange-red carotenoid pigment similar to flexirubins.</s><s>G+­C content of the DNA 41.8±0.7 mol% (HPLC determination).</s><s>Habitat is anoxic subsurface sites of enhanced temperature and salt content.</s><s>Type strain Fru22<sup>T</sup>, deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig as DSM 12881<sup>T</sup>, and with the Oregon Collection of Methanogens under the deposition number OCM 798<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>