<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1469_nm.3257" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3257" rank="genus">Photorhabdus</organism><reference id="rid.1469"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Boemare</surname><given-names>N.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akhurst</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mourant</surname><given-names>R.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>DNA relatedness between Xenorhabdus spp. (Enterobacteriaceae), symbiotic bacteria of entomopathogenic nematodes, and a proposal to transfer Xenorhabdus luminescens to a new genus, Photorhabdus gen. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>249</fpage><lpage>255</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Photorhabdus</i> Boemare, Akhurst, and Mourant gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Photorhabdus</i> (Pho.to.rhab'dus. Gr. n. <i>photo</i>, light; Gr. fem. n. <i>rhabdus</i>, rod; M.L. n. <i>Photorhabdus</i>, bioluminescent rod-shaped bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, asporogenous rods.</s><s>Cell size is highly variable within and between cultures, ranging from 2 by 0.5 to 10 by 2 μm, with occasional filaments up to 30 μm long; spheroplasts occur in the last stage of exponential growth.</s><s>Motile and peritrichous.</s><s>Most strains produced red-, pink-, or yellow-pigmented colonies, especially on rich media (tryptic soya agar, yolk nutritive agar).</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic; metabolism respiratory and fermentative.</s><s>Bioluminescent, usually detectable by a dark-adapted eye; bioluminescence intensity varies within and between isolates and may be detectable only with a photometer or scintillation counter in some isolates.</s><s>One nonluminescent isolate is known.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-Dgalactopyranoside, Voges-Proskauer, arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests.</s><s>Proteolytic for gelatin.</s><s>Lipolytic activity on Tween 20; many strains are lipolytic for Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80 and/or Tween 85.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose without gas; acid is produced from very few other carbohydrates.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, mannose, and N-acetylglucosamine; acid production from glycerol, ribose, and maltose is variable.</s><s>Succinate, fumarate, L-tyrosine, L-glutamate, and glucosamine are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The optimum temperature is usually ca. 25°C; some strains do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>Pathogenic for insects; the 50% lethal dose is less than 100 cells when the organisms are injected into <i>Galleria mellonella</i> hemocoel.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 to 44 mol%.</s><s>The natural habitat for most strains is the intestinal lumen of entomopathogenic nematodes belonging to the family Heterorhabditidae and insects infected by these nematodes; one DNA relatedness group is associated with human clinical specimens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Within an isolate colony morphology may be highly variable.</s><s>Two extreme types are characterized as phases one and two.</s><s>Phase one is found in the infective stage of the nematode host; phase two is known only from in vitro culture and clinical specimens.</s><s>Phase one cultures produce highly mucoid colonies and absorb dye, forming red colonies from MacConkey agar; they also adsorb other dyes, such as bromothymol blue and Congo red.</s><s>A large proportion of cells contain proteinic inclusion bodies.</s><s>Phase one cultures produce agar-diffusible antimicrobial compounds and lecithinase.</s><s>Phase one is very much more bioluminescent and more lipolytic than phase two.</s><s>In pigmented strains, phase one is differently pigmented than phase two.</s><s>Phase two colonies are not mucoid and do not absorb dye; very weak antimicrobial and lecithinase activities may be detected.</s><s>The change from phase one to phase two usually occurs during the stationary period of in vitro cultures; change from phase two to phase one has not been demonstrated.</s><s>Several intermediate colony forms, possessing at least some phase one properties, have been described.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Photorhabdus luminescens</i> (Poinar and Thomas 1979) Boemare, Akhurst, and Mourant comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>