<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.667_nm.4868" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4868" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4868" rank="species">Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</organism><reference id="rid.667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shute</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berkeley</surname><given-names>R.C.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>69</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i> (am.yl.o.li.que.fac'i.ens. L.n. <i>amylum</i> starch; M.L. part adj. <i>amyloliquefaciens</i> starch digesting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram positive rods, 0.7 to 0.9 by 1.8 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Cells often form chains and are motile, with peritrichous flagella, Oval spores (0.6 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 1.4 μm) are central or paracentral in sporangia which are not swollen.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 30 to 40°C.</s><s>No growth occurs below 15°C or above 50°C.</s><s>Casein, elastin, gelatin, starch, tributyrin, Tween 20, Tween 40, and Tween 60 are degraded, but adenine, cellulose, guanine, hypoxanthine, pectin, testosterone, tyrosine, and xanthine are not. (Only a small proportion of strains is able to degrade DNA.) Acetoin and phosphatase are produced, nitrate is reduced to nitrite, esculin and arbutin are hydrolyzed, citrate is used as a sole carbon source, and growth occurs in the presence of 5% (wt/vol) NaCl, and for most strains 10% NaCl; but neither allantoin nor urea is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, fructose, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, and trehalose when the medium of Gordon et al. (5) is used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 44.35 ± 0.38 mol% (mean ± standard deviation) for eight strains as determined by the thermal denaturation method and 44.2 k 0.7 mol% for the same eight strains as determined by the bouyant density method (17).</s><s>Extensive DNA pairing studies have shown that <i>B. amyloliquefaciens</i> DNA shares less than 25, 13, and 5% homology with DNAs from <i>B. subtilis</i>, <i>B. licheniformis</i>, and <i>B. pumilus</i>, respectively, under optimal conditions (11; Shute, Ph.D. thesis). <i>B. amyloliquefaciens</i> has been isolated from soil and industrial amylase fermentations.</s><s>The type strain, strain ATCC 23350 (=Fukomoto strain F), has a DNA base composition of 44.6 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p></content></protolog>