<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5783_nm.10013" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10013" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10013" rank="species">Pseudidiomarina taiwanensis</organism><reference id="rid.5783"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jean</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shieh</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudidiomarina taiwanensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from shallow coastal water of An-Ping Harbour, Taiwan, and emended description of the family Idiomarinaceae.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>899</fpage><lpage>905</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64048-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585713</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudidiomarina taiwanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudidiomarina taiwanensis</em> (tai.wan.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>taiwanensis</em> pertaining to Taiwan, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is as for the genus with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>During the late exponential to early stationary phase of growth, cells in broth cultures are straight rods that measure approximately 0·8–2·4 μm by 0·6–0·8 μm.</s><s>A small number of the cells produce prosthecae or sac-like processes from the cell wall.</s><s>Colonies produced on agar plates are circular, translucent, non-pigmented and non-luminescent.</s><s>Swarming does not occur.</s><s>Capable of anaerobic growth by reducing nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor, but not by fermenting glucose or other carbohydrates as substrates.</s><s>Grows at 15–42 °C, with optimal growth at 30–35 °C.</s><s>Grows at NaCl levels of 0·5–11 %, with optimal growth at 1–4 % and no growth at 0 and 12 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows optimally at about pH 8, no growth at pH 5–6.</s><s>Gelatinase and lipase tests are positive, but agarase, amylase, caseinase, DNase, arginine dihydrolase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from thiosulphate.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Oxidative or fermentative acid production was not detected from carbohydrates using the API 50CH system.</s><s>According to Biolog GN2 tests, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, uridine, glycogen, succinic acid and glycyl l-glutamic acid are oxidized.</s><s>Resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10–150 μg.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), colistin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (300 U), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to clindamycin (2 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), oxacillin (1 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PIT1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17465<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13360<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shallow coastal water of An-Ping Harbour, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>