<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2620_nm.4635" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4635" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4635" rank="species">Mycoplasma californicum</organism><reference id="rid.2620"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jasper</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ernø</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellinger</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christiansen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma californicum, a new species from cows.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>345</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma californicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma californicum</i> (cal.i.for'ni.cum. M.L. adj. <i>californicus</i> pertaining to California) for this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and staining characteristics: minute coccoid, filamentous, ring, conglomerate, and other pleomorphic forms.</s><s>Staining is dark blue with Wright-Leishman stain plus Giemsa stain.</s><s>The cells are bounded by a single triplelayered cell membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies reach about 0.3 mm in diameter, are somewhat conical in shape, and have a typical fried egg appearance.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Viable cells are readily filtered at 450 nm but are not filterable at 220 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Liquid cultures are slightly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Film and spots are not formed on modified Hayflick medium containing horse serum or 10% egg yolk agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions: glucose is not utilized, and arginine and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Triphenyl tetrazolium chloride is not reduced aerobically, but the phosphatase test is positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs in standard mycoplasma medium without serum.</s><s>Cholesterol is required.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity: causes bovine mastitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: bovine udders with mastitis.</s><s>The normal habitat is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>M. californicum</i> is strain ST-6, which was isolated in 1972 from the first outbreak of mastitis found to be due to this organism.</s><s>Cultures of this strain have been deposited in the Collaborating Center for Animal Mycoplasmas, Institute of Medical Microbiology, University of Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark, under the number AMRC-C 1077 and in the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 33461.</s></p></content></protolog>