<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6895_nm.14062" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14062" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7303" rank="species">Streptomyces thermospinisporus</organism><reference id="rid.6895"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces thermospinisporus sp. nov., a moderately thermophilic carboxydotrophic streptomycete isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1225</fpage><lpage>1228</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02003-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148632</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces thermospinisporus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces thermospinisporus</i> (ther.mo.spi.ni.spo'rus. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i> hot; L. adj. <i>spinosus</i> spiny; M.L. n. <i>spora</i> a spore; N.L. adj. <i>thermospinisporus</i> heat-loving, spiny spores)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data taken from this and earlier studies (Falconer, 1988; O'Donnell et al., 1993).</s><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, moderately thermophilic, facultatively carboxydotrophic actinomycete which forms extensively branched aerial and substrate hyphae.</s><s>Aerial hyphae differentiate into flexuous chains of spores that show spiny ornamentation.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is grey, but the substrate mycelium has no distinctive pigments.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not produced, nor are melanin pigments formed on peptone/ yeast extract/iron agar.</s><s>The organism, which can use carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth, contains major amounts of LL-diaminopimelic acid, octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the predominant isoprenologue, and major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The molar G­C content of the genomic DNA is 73.6 mol%.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, and elastin, starch and L-tyrosine are degraded.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in the presence of phenol (0.1%,w/v), phenyl ethanol (0.3%, v/v) and sodium azide (0.02%, w/v).</s><s><i>meso</i>-Inositol, mannitol, raffinose, sucrose and sodium pyruvate are used as sole carbon sources when the organism is grown heterotrophically.</s><s>The type, and only, strain is AT10<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41779<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 9909<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from garden soil.</s></p></content></protolog>