<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7178_nm.3625" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3625" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3625" rank="species">Desulfuromonas thiophila</organism><reference id="rid.7178"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coates</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfuromonas thiophila sp. nov., a new obligately sulfur-reducing bacterium from anoxic freshwater sediment.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>754</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-754</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226908</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfuromonas thiophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfuromonas thiophila</i> (thi.o.phi'la. Gr. n. <i>thios</i>, sulfur; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. fem. adj. <i>thiophila</i> sulfur loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid, 0.7 to 0.8 μm wide by 1.5 to 2.0 μm long.</s><s>Multiplication is by binary fission.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Chemotrophic growth occurs in mineral medium supplemented with 0.01 to 0.03% Na,S 9H,O as a reductant.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by NaCl concentrations greater than 1.2%.</s><s>Biotin is required as a growth factor.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, succinate, and fumarate are used as electron donors and carbon sources in the presence of 30 mM hydrogen carbonate.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is as the only electron acceptor utilized for growth.</s><s>Fe(III)-NTA is reduced with pyruvate; this reduction does not sustain growth.</s><s>The pH range is 6.5 to 8.2; the optimum pH is 6.9 to 7.9.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 26 to 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Accumulations of cells in colonies or pellets are pink to reddish; under reducing conditions cell suspensions exhibit absorption spectra characteristic of type c cytochromes (absorption maxima at 419, 523, and 553 nm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of strain NZ27<sup>T</sup> is 61.0 ± 1 mol% as determined by the thermal denaturation method and 61.6 ± 0.2 mol% as determined by HPLC.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetically, strain NZ27<sup>T</sup> belongs to the <i>Desulfuromonas</i> cluster of the recently proposed family "<i>Geobacteraceae</i>" in the delta subgroup of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is most closely related to <i>Desulfuromonas acetoxidans</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat is anoxic mud of a freshwater sulfur spring.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain was isolated from anoxic mud from a freshwater sulfur spring at Ngawha Springs near Moerewa, New Zealand.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NZ27, which has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSMZ 8987.</s></p></content></protolog>