<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12338_nm.20367" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20367" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20367" rank="species">Paenibacillus xylanisolvens</organism><reference id="rid.12338"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khianngam</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akaracharanya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus xylanisolvens sp. nov., a xylan-degrading bacterium from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>164</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022269-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20190026</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus xylanisolvens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus xylanisolvens</em> (xy.la.ni.sol′vens. N.L. n. <em>xylanum</em> xylan; L. part. adj. <em>solvens</em> dissolving; N.L. part. adj. <em>xylanisolvens</em> xylan-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, facultatively anaerobic, motile rods (0.4–0.8×1.5–3.0 μm).</s><s>Central or subterminal ellipsoidal endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are 1–5 mm in diameter, circular, flat, white and opaque after 2 days of incubation on C agar medium.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 6–9 (optimally at pH 7–8), at 15–50 °C (optimally at 30–37 °C), in 3 % NaCl (weakly) and under anaerobic conditions, but not at pH 5, at 10, 55 or 60 °C or in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of aesculin (weak), casein, Tween 80, urea and xylan and assimilation of d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol and d-mannose, but negative for methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, fermentation of glucose, hydrolysis of l-arginine, DNA, gelatin, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, starch and l-tyrosine and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, adipic acid, capric acid, phenylacetic acid and potassium gluconate.</s><s>Able to produce acid from aesculin, d-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-glucopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, amygdalin, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, <em>α</em>-mannopyranoside, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, <em>β</em>-xylopyranoside, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is X11-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13042<sup>T</sup> =PCU 311<sup>T</sup> =TISTR 1829<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>