<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6626_nm.6667" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6667" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6667" rank="species">Micropruina glycogenica</organism><reference id="rid.6626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shintani</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamagata</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyaoka</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Micropruina glycogenica gen. nov., sp. nov., a new Gram-positive glycogen-accumulating bacterium isolated from activated sludge</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>207</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826805</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Micropruina glycogenica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Micropruina glycogenica</i> (gly.co.gen.i'ca. Gr. suff. -<i>icus</i> related to, belonging to; N. L. adj. <i>glycogenica</i> referring to the ability to accumulate glycogen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology and chemotaxonomic features of the species are the same as those described above for the genus.</s><s>The species can store substrates as intracellular glycogen.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20-35 °C and at pH 6-8.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature and pH are 30 °C and 7.0, respectively.</s><s>A slow growing organism.</s><s>The species tolerates up to 3.0% NaCl in the medium.</s><s>Cells reduce nitrate to nitrite under anaerobic conditions, but do not reduce nitrite to nitrogen.</s><s>Cells grow on glucose, mannose, galactose, xylose, arabinose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, cellobiose and melibiose, but not trehalose.</s><s>Starch and glycogen are utilized.</s><s>Cells utilize sugar alcohols, including inositol and mannitol, but not dulcitol.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, pyruvate and succinate are utilized, but not malate.</s><s>On the basis of the phylogenetic comparison of 16S rRNA sequences, the bacterium belongs to the high G+C Gram-positive bacteria.</s><s>The closest relative is <i>Microlunatus phosphovorus</i> (93% sequence similarity).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 70.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is Lg2<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (RIKEN) as JCM 10248<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>