<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1628_nm.11370" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11370" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11370" rank="species">Cerasicoccus arenae</organism><reference id="rid.1628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cerasicoccus arenae gen. nov., sp. nov., a carotenoid-producing marine representative of the family Puniceicoccaceae within the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia', isolated from marine sand</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2067</fpage><lpage>2072</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65102-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766873</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cerasicoccus arenae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cerasicoccus arenae</em> (a.ren′ae. L. gen. n. <em>arenae</em> of sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are 0.8–1.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies on 1/5 strength marine agar medium are circular, convex and pale-pink-pigmented.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–30 °C, with optimal growth at 25–30 °C; no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6–9.</s><s>Seawater and NaCl are not required for growth, but up to 8 % (w/v) NaCl can be tolerated.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of ampicillin (1–1000 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and penicillin G (1–1000 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Aesculin and starch are hydrolysed, but agar, DNA, gelatin and urea are not.</s><s><em>o</em>-Nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactosidase (ONPG) and tryptophan deaminase are positive, but acetoin, citrate utilization, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide and indole production are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-lyxose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, aesculin, ferric citrate, lactose, gentiobiose, d-turanose and 5-ketogluconate, but not from trehalose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, erythritol, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are positive, but acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Usual components of bacterial cell walls such as muramic acid and diaminopimelic acid are not detected.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;1.0 %) include iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3.5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (38.7 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH (4.4 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2.3 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.3 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (43.3 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (1.5 %) and C<sub>20 : 0</sub> (1.5 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 54.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM26-026<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08280<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12870<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from acid-treated sediment in Kamaishi, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>