<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3764_nm.10912" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10912" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10912" rank="species">Ochrobactrum cytisi</organism><reference id="rid.3764"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zurdo-Piñeiro</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trujillo</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vizcaíno</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carrasco</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chamber</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palomares</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ochrobactrum cytisi sp. nov., isolated from nodules of Cytisus scoparius in Spain</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>784</fpage><lpage>788</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64613-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392207</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ochrobactrum cytisi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ochrobactrum cytisi</em> (cy.ti′si. N.L. masc. n. <em>Cytisus</em> botanical genus name of the legume <em>Cytisus scoparius</em>; N.L. gen. n. <em>cytisi</em> of <em>Cytisus</em>, referring to the isolation source of the first strains, nodules of <em>C. scoparius</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, non-spore-forming, Gram-negative rods.</s><s>Good growth occurs on YMA and nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on these media are white to beige, mucoid with entire edges and 2–3 mm in diameter within 24 h.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is composed mainly of C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The following fatty acids are detected in small amounts: summed features 2 and 3, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 2-OH and an unknown fatty acid at ECL 11.799.</s><s>The following tests were done by using API 20E and API 20NE systems.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction, indole production and aesculin hydrolysis are positive.</s><s>Production of <em>β</em>-galactosidase is variable.</s><s>Production of urease (after 48 h incubation), arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and gelatinase is negative.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized include d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, citrate, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, adonitol, dulcitol, l-rhamnose, arbutin, maltose, sucrose, turanose, l-lyxose, tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, arabitol, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Assimilation of d-xylose, l-xylose, galactose, d-fructose, lactose, melibiose, cellobiose, trehalose, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside and gluconate is weak.</s><s>Caprate, adipate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, amygdalin, salicin, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose and l-arabitol are not assimilated.</s><s>The following enzymes are detected by using API ZYM strips: alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase C4, lipase C8, lipase C14, leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphoamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Production of <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase is negative.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, penicillin, cefuroxime, cloxacillin, oxytetracycline, polymyxin B, erythromycin, neomycin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>Sensitive to ciprofloxacin and weakly sensitive to gentamicin.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 56.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ESC1<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22713<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7172<sup>T</sup>), and strain ESC5 (=LMG 23703) were isolated from nodules of <em>Cytisus scoparius</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>