<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.449_nm.3326" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3326" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3326" rank="subspecies">Serratia proteamaculans quinovora</organism><reference id="rid.449"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Irino</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Biochemical characterization of Serratia liquefaciens sensu stricto, Serratia proteamaculans and Serratia grimesii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>69</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01568416</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serratia proteamaculans quinovora</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serratia proteamaculans quinovora</i> (<i>quinovora</i> is composed from the chemical name <i>quinate</i> (from Spanish <i>quina</i>, quinine; from Quechua <i>kina</i>, bark) and the Latin verb <i>voro</i>, to devour; hence, the Modern Latin feminine adjective <i>quinovora</i>, quinate-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the use of quinate as sole source of carbon and energy, <i>S. proteamaculans</i> subsp. <i>quinovora</i> can easily be identified by its failure to attack salicin and esculin in two days.</s><s>With API 2OE strips, this subspecies does not produce acid from amygdalin.</s><s>This proposal for a new subspecies within <i>S. proteamaculans</i> designates de facto the type strain of <i>S. proteamaculans</i> (ATCC 19323) as type strain of <i>S. proteamaculans</i> subsp. <i>proteamaculans</i>. <i>Serratia protearnaculans</i> subsp. <i>quinovora</i> has been isolated from plants, wild rodents, insects, and water, but not yet from human clinical specimens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 4364 (=CIP 8195=ATCC 33765) as the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>