<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12541_nm.21400" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21400" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21400" rank="species">Sphingomonas rubra</organism><reference id="rid.12541"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huo</surname><given-names>Y.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>H.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas rubra sp. nov., isolated from bioreactor wastewater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1028</fpage><lpage>1032</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020958-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas rubra</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas rubra</em> (ru′bra. L. fem. adj. <em>rubra</em> red).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, rod-shaped, 0.6–1.1×1.1–3.6 µm and motile.</s><s>Colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, elevated and red when grown on DSMZ 756 medium for 2 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–8 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0 %), at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 7.5) and at 4–37 °C (optimum 28 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20 and 80 and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for indole production and arginine dihydrolase, lysine carboxylase, ornithine carboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease and <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactopyranosidase activities.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>l-Cysteine, d-galactose and l-valine are utilized and glucose and maltose are weakly utilized.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: acetate, l-arginine, l-aspartate, cellobiose, citrate, ethanol, formate, fumarate, gluconate, l-glutamate, glycine, glycerol, l-histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, isoleucine, lactate, malonate, mannitol, l-methionine, l-ornithine, propionate, pyruvate, raffinose, d-ribose, rhamnose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, starch and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose but not from adonitol, ethanol, d-fructose, glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase activities are present, whereas <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase and trypsin activities are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to (<em>μ</em>g unless otherwise stated) amoxicillin (10), cefataxime (30), cefoxitin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), novobiocin (30), rifampicin (5), tetracycline (30) and tobramycin (10) but not to ampicillin (10), bacitracin (0.04 IU), carbenicillin (100), nystatin (100), penicillin (10) or streptomycin (10).</s><s>The predominant quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major polyamine is homospermidine.</s><s>The major polar lipids of strain BH3<sup>T</sup> are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine and diphosphatidylglycerol as well as two sphingoglycolipids and an unidentified lipid.</s><s>Small amounts of two unidentified lipids are also present.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) include C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BH3<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.9113<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16230<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wastewater of a sequential batch reactor treating wastewater taken from a leather plant.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>