<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12520_nm.21372" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21372" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21372" rank="species">Actinophytocola burenkhanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12520"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsetseg</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daram</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ando</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinophytocola burenkhanensis sp. nov., isolated from Mongolian soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1033</fpage><lpage>1038</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021659-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinophytocola burenkhanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinophytocola burenkhanensis</em> (bu.ren.kha.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>burenkhanensis</em> isolated from soil of Burenkhan, Khuvsgul province, Mongolia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive.</s><s>Cells grow well but slowly only on Bennett’s agar medium, forming branched and non-fragmented substrate hyphae.</s><s>Sporulation is very weak and, when sporulation occurs on Bennett’s agar, the surface of the colony changes to a yellow-brown colour.</s><s>Produces irregularly shaped spore-chain-like structures with scanty spherical body formation on scanty aerial mycelium on Bennett’s agar.</s><s>Pale brownish soluble pigment is produced only on Bennett’s agar after 5 weeks of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>No distinct or true aerial hyphae are found on other agar media tested.</s><s>Colour of substrate mycelium is light yellow to moderate yellowish brown on different agar media.</s><s>Good growth occurs only on Bennett’s agar; moderate growth is seen on ISP 2, ISP 3 and ISP 6 agar media; grows weakly on YS, ISP 7 and water agar media; and no growth on ISP 5 agar medium is seen after 5 weeks of incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth is at 25–30 °C; no growth is observed at 37 °C.</s><s>Tolerates up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>The results of biochemical tests are as follows: nitrate is not reduced; urea (weak) and starch are hydrolysed; positive for decomposition of arbutin, hypoxanthine, casein, tyrosine and gelatin; and negative for decomposition of Tweens 20 and 80 and adenine, and assimilation of calcium.</s><s>According to the API ZYM enzyme assay: positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase; weakly positive for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>) and valine arylamidase; and negative for lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>According to the API Coryne enzyme assay: positive for pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, β-galactosidase and hydrolysis of gelatin; weakly positive for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and α-glucosidase; negative for β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucosidase (aesculin) and urease; negative for catalase and nitrate reduction; positive for fermentation of glucose, ribose, mannose, maltose and lactose; and negative for fermentation of xylose, sucrose and glycogen.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid; mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The only menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Characteristic phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxyphosphatidylethanolamine and ninhydrin-positive phosphoglycolipids.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 9-methyl; the whole-cell sugars contain glucose, galactose, ribose, arabinose, mannose, rhamnose and xylose (trace).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MN08-A0203<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 105883<sup>T</sup>  = VTCC D9-23<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil of Burenkhan, Khuvsgul province, Mongolia.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>