<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4629_nm.5801" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5801" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5801" rank="species">Actinomyces radingae</organism><reference id="rid.4629"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wüst</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stubbs</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of Actinomyces pyogenes-like (CDC coryneform group E) bacteria to the genus Actinomyces as Actinomyces radingae sp. nov. and Actinomyces turicensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>76</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="152">Letters in Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Lett Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0266-8254</issn><essn>1472-765X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7534464</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Descrlptlon of <i>Actinomyces radingae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces radingae</i> (pertaining to Radinga, the Latin name for Reading, UK)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on an examination of three strains (Wust et al. 1993).</s><s>The cells consist of straight and slightly curved rods with some branching (approximately 0.5-0.8 μm diameter x 2-3 μm); part of the cells show slight clubbing.</s><s>Most cells stain Gram-positive with some irregularities giving a beaded appearance.</s><s>Growth on sheep blood agar is equal under aerobic conditions with 5% CO<sub>2</sub> and anaerobically.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are whitish to greyish, slightly dull, circular, low convex of about 0.3-0.5 mm diameter after 48-h incubation aerobically with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Haemolysis cannot be detected in two strains and is weak in one strain; haemolysis is absent anaerobically.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, glycogen, maltose, mannose, ribose, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Triple sugar iron agar is acidified in both slant and butt.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, rhamnose and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid production from arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, fructose, galactose, inositol, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, salicin and trehalose was variable.</s><s>C4 and C8 esterases, leucin arylamidase and pyrazinamidase are positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, trypsin, β-glucuronidase, lipase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, phosphohydrolase, α-mannosidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase are negative.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed only slowly by two strains.</s><s>Urea and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The main metabolic fatty acids are succinic and lactic acids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids when grown in PRAS peptone yeast glucose medium with Tween 80 are 10:0 (approximately 4-6%), 14:0 (3-7), 16:1<i>cis</i>9 (8-12), 16:0 (11-13), 18:1<i>cis</i>9 (39-57), feature 10 (18:1C11/T9/T6 or un-17.834 equivalent chain length fatty acid) (8-12).</s><s>DNA base composition is 60 mol% G + C (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Peptidoglycan is of the L-Lys(L-Orn)-L-Lys-D-Glu tvpe (A5α).</s><s>Strains have mainly been isolated from mixed infections associated with anaerobes, <i>Streptococcus 'milleri'</i>, enterococci, and Gram-negative rods.</s><s>The habitat is unknown.</s><s>The type strain (APLI) is DSM 9169<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 32394<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>