<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2561_nm.7996" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7996" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8067" rank="species">Bacteroides zoogleoformans</organism><reference id="rid.2561"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelley</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides zoogleoformans, Weinberg, Nativelle, and Prévot 1937) corrig. comb. nov.: emended description</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>274</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides zoogleoformans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The growth characteristics of strain ATCC 33285 were distinctive and exactly as previously described (10, 12). A viscous, glutinous mass which was very difficult to remove with a capillary pipette formed in broth cultures, especially cultures containing fermentable carbohydrate (Fig. 1). This organism was strictly anaerobic and nonmotile and grew well at 30 and 37°C, slightly at 25°C, and not at all at 45°C. Hemin was required for growth since this strain did not survive a third transfer into hemin-free medium. There was no growth in peptone-yeast extractglucose medium supplemented with 20% bile. No gas was detected in peptone-yeast extractglucose agar deep cultures, and cultures were odorless.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 24 h of incubation at 37°C in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth, the cells of strain ATCC 33285 were gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods with rounded ends (Fig. 2).</s><s>These cells stained unevenly, and they were straight or slightly curved and 0.4 to 0.8 by 0.8 to 8.0 μm; usually they occurred singly, but occasionally they occurred in pairs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on 48-h-old blood agar plates incubated anaerobically were nonhemolytic, 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, circular, entire, pulvinate, opaque, buff colored, shiny, smooth, and butyrous.</s><s>No internal structure was visible.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The amounts of fermentation acids which were detected in a 4-day-old peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth culture were as follows (in milliequivalents per 100 ml): succinic acid, 4.6; acetic acid, 1.8; propionic acid, 0.3; and isovaleric acid, 0.2.</s><s>Hydrogen production was dependent on culture conditions; large amounts were produced when strain ATCC 33285 was inoculated under a gas mixture containing 90% nitrogen and 10% CO<sub>2</sub> into media supplemented with rabbit serum (final concentration, 9%), and little or no hydrogen was detected when the strain was inoculated under 100% CO<sub>2</sub> into media without serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As stated in the original description (12), glucose, maltose, fructose, sucrose, and lactose were fermented strongly (to a pH of 5.5 or lower, compared with a final pH of 6.1 in basal broth medium), galactose was fermented weakly (pH 5.6) and mannitol was not fermented.</s><s>In addition, we found that arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannose, pectin, raffinose, salicin, starch, and xylose were fermented strongly and that melibiose was fermented weakly.</s><s>Adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, esculin, glycerol, inositol, melezitose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, sorbose, trehalose, gum arabic, larch arabinogalactan, and xylan were not fermented, although growth was good with all of these substrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain ATCC 33285 produced ammonia in peptone-yeast extract broth cultures and H<sub>2</sub>S in SIM medium (BBL Microbiology Systems, Cockeysville, Md.).</s><s>Urease, catalase, lecithinase, lipase, and deoxyribonuclease were not detected.</s><s>This strain hydrolyzed esculin and starch.</s><s>A solid acid curd formed in milk.</s><s>After 3 weeks of incubation, a chilled gelatin culture liquefied after 15 min at room temperature, whereas an uninoculated control was still solid after 60 min.</s><s>Neither milk nor meat was digested.</s><s>Indole was not produced.</s><s>Nitrate was not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pyruvate was converted to acetate, but propionate was not formed from either lactate or threonine.</s><s>Strain ATCC 33285 was susceptible to the concentrations of chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin G, and tetracycline tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of strain ATCC 33285 deoxyribonucleic acid was 47 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>