<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1633_nm.11385" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11385" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11385" rank="species">Jannaschia donghaensis</organism><reference id="rid.1633"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jannaschia donghaensis sp. nov., isolated from seawater of the East Sea, Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2132</fpage><lpage>2136</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65026-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766886</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jannaschia donghaensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jannaschia donghaensis</em> (dong.ha.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>donghaensis</em> of Donghae, the Korean name for the East Sea of Korea, from where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and rod-, oval- or coccoid-shaped (0.5–2.5×0.6–5.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, raised, strong orange in colour and 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur on TSA, NA or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 32 °C, but not at 33 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 6.0, but not at pH 5.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 7 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA or on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is not produced.</s><s>Hypoxanthine and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but casein, l-tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) and leucine arylamidase are present, but lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>l-Arabinose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, acetate, benzoate, pyruvate, salicin, formate and l-glutamate are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or <em>myo</em>-inositol.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to lincomycin or oleandomycin.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 65.2 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSW-17<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12862<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14563<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater off Dokdo in the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>