<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8405_nm.13199" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13199" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13199" rank="species">Agrococcus jejuensis</organism><reference id="rid.8405"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrococcus jejuensis sp. nov., isolated from dried seaweed.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2297</fpage><lpage>2300</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65731-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842844</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agrococcus jejuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agrococcus jejuensis</em> (je.ju.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>jejuensis</em> of Jeju, Republic of Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, non-endospore-forming, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, non-motile rods 1.3–1.5 μm in length and 0.3–0.4 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, translucent, yellow-coloured and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, with an optimum at 30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>pH for growth is in the range 6.1–12.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3 % NaCl, but not at 4 %.</s><s>Positive for gelatin hydrolysis, but negative for indole production and glucose fermentation.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, but not adipate, d-arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate or phenyl acetate (API 20NE).</s><s>Hydrolyses casein and elastin, but not starch.</s><s>Does not degrade hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Acid is produced from melibiose and salicin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, d-lactose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, 1,2-propanediol, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from l-ribose is weak.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, esterase (C4) (weak) and esterase lipase (C8) (weak), but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>The diagnostic cell-wall diamino acid is 2,4-diaminobutyric acid; alanine, glycine, glutamic acid, threonine and aspartic acid are also detected.</s><s>The acyl type of the muramic acid is acetyl.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-10 and MK-9.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (56.7 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (13.2 %).</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SSW1-48<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19198<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14256<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a dried seaweed sample collected on Samyang Beach, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>