<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1236_nm.937" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.937" rank="genus">Rhodopila</organism><reference id="rid.1236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rearrangements of the species and genera of the phototrophic "purple nonsulfur bacteria."</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>340</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodopila</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodopila</i> (Rho.do.pi'la. Gr.n. <i>rhodon</i> rose; M. L. fem.n. <i>pila</i> ball or sphere; M. L.fem.n. <i>Rhodopila</i> red-colored spherical bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of <i>Rhodopila</i> is <i>Rhodopila globiformis</i> Pfennig 1974 comb. nov.</s><s>Formerly this species has been included in the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical to ovoid and motile by means of flagella, have vesicular intracytoplasmic membranes, and grow only at low pH values.</s><s>Biotin and p-aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to oxygen, but growth at low oxygen tensions in the dark is possible.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The intracytoplasmic membrane structure is similar to that of <i>Rhodobacter</i> species, but a number of significant differences exist between these two genera. <i>Rhodopila</i> reduces adenosine 5'- phosphosulfate instead of 3'-phosphate adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate, has different quinone, carotenoid, and polar lipid compositions, and has a small cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub>.</s><s>It stands apart from <i>Rhodobacter</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i> species according to DNA-rRNA hybridization studies and 16s rRNA analyses, and it has in common with <i>Rhodomicrobium vannielii</i> reduction of sulfate via adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate, the presence of a small type of cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub> substantial amounts of a high-potential iron-sulfur protein, and the presence of unusual arninolipids as major components of the polar lipids.</s><s>Therefore, <i>Rhodopila</i> is significantly different from all other genera and should be recognized as a separate genus.</s></p></content></protolog>