<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6780_nm.6732" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6732" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6732" rank="species">Crossiella equi</organism><reference id="rid.6780"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Donahue</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sells</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Crossiella equi sp. nov., isolated from equine placentas</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2169</fpage><lpage>2173</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02257-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508885</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Crossiella equi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Crossiella equi</i> (e«qui. L. gen. n. <i>equi</i> of the horse, referring to the source of isolation of this microorganism, equine placentas)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pale orange to light-brown substrate mycelium is produced on most media.</s><s>Copious white aerial mycelium is produced.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics correspond to those typical for the genus Crossiella.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, starch and tyrosine are hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Adenine, allantoin, xanthine and urea are not hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Gelatin, hypoxanthine and hippurate are hydrolysed variably.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, benzoate, citrate, propionate and succinate are viably assimilated; lactate, malate, mucate, oxalate and dltartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose and raffinose; no acid is produced from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, mannitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-xyloside, D-sorbitol or sucrose; acid production is variable from arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, rhamnose, salicin, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5%(w}v) NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10-42°C.</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA is 71.4 mol% (thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Isolated from equine placenta in Lexington, KY, USA.</s><s>Implicated in equine placentitis and spontaneous abortions in mares.</s><s>The type strain is strain LDDC 22291-98<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-24104<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44580<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>