<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1371_nm.10049" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10049" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10049" rank="species">Photobacterium halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.1371"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García-Fraile</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium halotolerans sp. nov., isolated from Lake Martel in Spain</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1067</fpage><lpage>1071</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64099-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627656</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Photobacterium halotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Photobacterium halotolerans</em> (ha.lo.to′le.rans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>halotolerans</em> referring to the ability to tolerate high salt concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, Gram-negative and motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on TSA supplemented with 1.5 % (w/v) NaCl are circular, smooth, white to cream in colour, opaque and usually 2–4 mm in diameter within 2 days at 28 °C.</s><s>The isolate grows on TCBS medium, producing blue colonies.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 49.8 mol%.</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, chemo-organotrophic, mesophilic and halotolerant.</s><s>Able to ferment carbohydrates.</s><s>Negative Voges–Proskauer reaction and negative for indole production and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, caseinase, urease, esterase, esterase lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphohydrolase or glucuronidase.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed and the hydrolysis of aesculin is weak.</s><s>The strain produces amylases, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, acid and alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Positive for reduction of nitrate to nitrite; tryptophan deaminase production is weak.</s><s>Negative for luminescence on marine agar.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl concentrations up to 8 % (w/v) and optimally in the presence of 1.5 % (w/v) NaCl at 28 °C, although salt is not essential for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C (optimal growth occurs at 28 °C), at pH 5–8.5 (optimal growth occurs at pH 7).</s><s>Shows sensitivity to the vibriostatic agent O/129 and is novobiocin-positive.</s><s>The most abundant fatty acids are summed feature 3 (32.6 %; comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (21.2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (19.9 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6.6 %) and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (5.9 %).</s><s>The following fatty acids were detected in small amounts: summed feature 2 (3.0 %; comprising C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I, an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain length of 10.928 and/or C<sub>12 : 0</sub> ALDE), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (2.5 %), an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain length of 12.484 (1 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso (1 %) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1 %).</s><s>Ferments glucose, mannitol, sucrose and l-arabinose.</s><s>Uses <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, citrate, adipate, glucose, malate, maltose, mannitol, phenylacetate, sucrose, fructose and trehalose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilization of l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, gentiobiose, starch and glycogen is weak.</s><s>Does not use amygdalin, caproate, d-arabinose, l-xylose, l-rhamnose, galactose, sorbose, d-mannose, melibiose, cellobiose, lactose, melezitose, raffinose, turanose, lyxose, tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-xyloside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, arbutin, salicin, inulin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, dulcitol, erythritol, xylitol, arabinitol, glycerol and 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate as carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MACL01<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22194<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5860<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Lake Martel, Mallorca, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>