<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12334_nm.20361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20361" rank="species">Haloactinopolyspora alba</organism><reference id="rid.12334"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloactinopolyspora alba gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic filamentous actinomycete isolated from a salt lake, with proposal of Jiangellaceae fam. nov. and Jiangellineae subord. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>200</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021725-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20190023</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloactinopolyspora alba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloactinopolyspora alba</em> (al′ba. L. fem. adj. <em>alba</em> white).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–45 °C, pH 4.0–9.0 and 7–23 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 28–37 °C, pH 7.0–8.0 and 10–15 % (w/v) NaCl, and no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin, Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are degraded, but casein, starch, dextrin, chitin, Tween 20 and urea are not.</s><s>Tests for milk peptonization and coagulation are positive, but gelatin liquefaction, nitrate reduction, starch hydrolysis, and H<sub>2</sub>S and melanin production are negative.</s><s>Cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, rhamnose, sucrose, sorbitol and trehalose are utilized as sole carbon sources, while erythritol, galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycine, mannitol, raffinose, d-ribose, sodium propionate, trisodium citrate, xylitol and d-xylose are not.</s><s>Adenine, l-arginine, l-histidine, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine are utilized as sole nitrogen sources, whereas growth on l-alanine, d-arabinose, l-asparagine, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine and xanthine is not observed.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α-</em> and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α-</em> and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are positive; acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 93246<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45211<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19409<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>