<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5847_nm.4988" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4988" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4988" rank="species">Bacillus subterraneus</organism><reference id="rid.5847"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kanso</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greene</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus subterraneus sp. nov., an iron- and manganese-reducing bacterium from a deep subsurface Australian thermal aquifer.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>869</fpage><lpage>874</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01842-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054251</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus subterraneus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus subterraneus</i> (sub.ter.ra'ne.us. L. adj. <i>subterraneus</i> underground, subterranean, referring to the isolation source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-spore-forming, facultatively anaerobic, slightly curved, rod-shaped bacterium (0.5-0.8x2-25 μm) that stains Gram-negative but has a Gram-positive-type cell wall.</s><s>After 2 days incubation at 40 °C on nutrient agar plates, colonies are 0.5-1.2 mm in diameter, translucent and convex with irregular and undulating edges, whereas, on tryptic soy agar plates, colonies are rhizoidal, dark yellow to orange and mucoid.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Utilizes amorphous iron(III), manganese(IV), nitrate, nitrite and fumarate as electron acceptors in the presence of yeast extract, glucose, sucrose, fructose, maltose, xylose, starch, glycerol, ethanol or lactate.</s><s>Electron acceptors are not obligately required for growth, and growth is better in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>Yeast extract at 0.02%(w/v) is required for growth and is used as a sole carbon and energy source at concentrations higher than 0.1%.</s><s>Tryptophan deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, β-galactosidase, arabinosidase, glucuronidase, glucosaminidase, nitroanilidase, xylosidase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced but glucosidase is present.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed but casein is not.</s><s>Aesculin and catalase, but not oxidase and urease, are produced.</s><s>Acid is not detected from arabinose, mannose, sucrose, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol, mannitol, adonitol, galactose or inositol.</s><s>Cells grow optimally at 37-40 °C at pH 7.0-9.0 with 5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43±1 mol%.</s><s>A member of the family <i>Bacillaceae</i>, <i>B. infernus</i> and <i>B. firmus</i> being the closest phylogenetic neighbours.</s><s>The habitat is the deep subterranean thermal waters of the Great Artesian Basin of Australia.</s><s>The type strain is COOI3B<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA 136<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13966<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>