<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6988_nm.4936" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4936" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4936" rank="species">Bacillus luciferensis</organism><reference id="rid.6988"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhelst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Diaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus luciferensis sp. nov., from volcanic soil on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1985</fpage><lpage>1989</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02282-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508857</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Bacillus luciferensis sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Bacillus luciferensis (lu.cif.er.en'sis. N.L. adj. <i>luciferensis</i> referring to Lucifer Hill, a volcano on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich Islands, the soil of which yielded the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from geothermal soil taken from an active fumarole on Lucifer Hill, a volcano on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago.</s><s>Cells are motile, rounD-ended rods (0.4-0.8¬3-6 lm), occurring singly and in pairs and showing pleomorphism (narrow and broad cells, the latter showing swellings) on TSA MnSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Gram-positive, but becoming Gram-negative within 24 h of culture at 30 °C.</s><s>Endospores are apparent in overnight cultures incubated at 30 °C on TSA MnSO<sub>4</sub> and are formed in large numbers within 2-3 days of incubation; they are ellipsoidal, lie subterminally and occasionally terminally and may swell the sporangia slightly (Fig. 1).</s><s>After 1 day on TSA, colonies are 1-5 mm in diameter, raised, with irregular margins and surfaces, and show some spiking along streak lines; the larger colonies appear to comprise several smaller colonies that have coalesced.</s><s>Colonies are moist and loosely butyrous, creamy-grey and translucent with a glossy appearance; by 10x magnification, they show cream and whitish streaking giving an appearance reminiscent of cut glass.</s><s>Minimum temperature for growth lies between 15 and 20 °C, the optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C and the maximum growth temperature lies between 35 and 45 °C.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 5.5 and 6.0, the optimum pH for growth is 7.0 and the maximum pH for growth lies between 8.0 and 8.5.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and weakly catalase-positive.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed, but growth is poor on skim milk medium.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, Voges-Proskauer reaction is positive and gelatin is hydrolysed; reactions for o-nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and nitrate reduction are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium: amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, β-gentiobiose, D-glucose, maltose, D-melezitose, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, salicin, starch (weak), sucrose, dtrehalose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, D- or larabinose, D- or L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D- or L-fucose, galactose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-dgluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl xyloside, D-raffinose, ribose, rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, xylitol or D- or lxylose.</s><s>Sensitive to disks of the following antibiotics: ampicillin (25 μg), chloramphenicol (50 μg), colistin sulphate (100 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (50 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and tetracycline (100 μg).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso C<sub>15:0</sub> and iso C<sub>15:0</sub> (respectively representing about 25 and 50% of total fatty acid).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts (between about 1.5 and 4.5%): iso C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i></sub> alcohol, iso C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1<i>ω</i>11<i>c</i></sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, anteiso C<sub>17:0</sub> and C<sub>16:1<i>ω</i>9<i>t</i></sub>, while trace but significant amounts of iso C<sub>17:0</sub> and of summed feature 5 (C<sub>17:1</sub> iso I and/or C<sub>17:1</sub> anteiso B) are also present.</s><s>Details of the FAME composition are available as supplementary material in IJSEM Online (http ://ijs.sgmjournals.org/).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 33.0 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG 18422<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107105<sup>T</sup>=Logan collection number B1761<sup>T</sup>=isolate SSI061); the 16S rDNA sequence of this strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJ419629.</s></p></content></protolog>