<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11589_nm.18624" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18624" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18624" rank="species">Thermovenabulum gondwanense</organism><reference id="rid.11589"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ogg</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greene</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermovenabulum gondwanense sp. nov., a thermophilic anaerobic Fe(III)-reducing bacterium isolated from microbial mats thriving in a Great Artesian Basin bore runoff channel</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1079</fpage><lpage>1084</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009886-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666811</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thermovenabulum gondwanense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thermovenabulum gondwanense</em> (gond.wa.nen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>gondwanense</em> pertaining to the large land mass known as Gondwana, which included Australia, Africa, India and South America before they separated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, straight to slightly curved rods.</s><s>Gram-reaction is positive, but the cell-wall ultrastructure is Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells possess peritrichous flagella.</s><s>No spores are detected.</s><s>Growth occurs between 50 and 70 °C (optimum temperature 65 °C), and between pH 6.0 and 9.0 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Ferments pyruvate and Casamino acids, but not yeast extract, peptone, tryptone, starch, galactose, fructose, sucrose, glucose, maltose, lactose, mannitol, arabinose, xylose, ethanol, glycerol, acetate, lactate or propionate.</s><s>Fe(III), Mn(IV), thiosulfate and elemental sulfur are used as electron acceptors, but not sulfate, sulfite, nitrate, nitrite or fumarate.</s><s>Growth is increased in the presence of Fe(III), which is reduced in the presence of yeast extract, peptone, tryptone, starch, pyruvate, Casamino acids, amyl media, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>, but not acetate, lactate, propionate, formate, benzoate, glycerol or ethanol.</s><s>Sensitive to streptomycin, tetracycline, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol and NaCl concentrations of 2 % and above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R270<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 5616<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21133<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a microbial mat sample from the outflow of a Great Artesian bore (the New Lorne Bore) in Queensland, Australia.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content is 41±1 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetically, related to <em>Thermovenabulum ferriorganovorum</em> DSM 14006<sup>T</sup> (96.1 % similarity).</s></p></content></protolog>