<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8670_nm.13592" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13592" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13592" rank="species">Ruminococcus gauvreauii</organism><reference id="rid.8670"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Domingo</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huletsky</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boissinot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berbard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Picard</surname><given-names>F.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bergeron</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ruminococcus gauvreauii sp. nov., a glycopeptide-resistant species isolated from a human faecal specimen.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1393</fpage><lpage>1397</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65259-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523184</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ruminococcus gauvreauii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ruminococcus gauvreauii</em> [gau.vreau′i.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>gauvreauii</em> of Gauvreau, named after Léo Gauvreau (MD, FRCPC), a microbiologist Emeritus Professor, former Director of the Department of Microbiology of Université Laval in Quebec City (Québec, Canada), known as an excellent teacher for his contribution to clinical diagnostic microbiology especially as it relates to botulism, an infection often observed in aboriginal people from northern Canada].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic, Gram-positive cocci (0.5–1.0 μm).</s><s>Cells are not motile.</s><s>Colonies on Brucella blood agar are small, white and convex.</s><s>Growth occurs at 35–37 °C under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Resistant to vancomycin and teicoplanin and harbours the acquired <em>vanD</em> gene cluster.</s><s>Indole, catalase, oxidase, lecithinase, lipase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, inositol and sucrose.</s><s>Does not produce acid from d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, trehalose, d-arabinose, cellobiose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, <em>α</em>-raffinose, l-xylose, d-salicin, adonitol, amygdalin, glycerol, glycogen, erythritol, inulin, <em>α</em>-melezitose, l-rhamnose or starch.</s><s>No peptonization of milk occurs.</s><s>Biochemical tests using Rapid ID 32A and RapID ANA II systems are negative for all substrates tested.</s><s>Based on testing with the API ZYM system, only acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are produced.</s><s>The major end product of glucose metabolism is acetic acid.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatty acids consist primarily of C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (16.94 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (16.91 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 dimethyl acetyl (DMA) (13.53 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>11 DMA (9.94 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 (8.41 %), as well as other minor components of DMA forms including C<sub>14 : 0</sub> DMA (5.96 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> DMA (4.03 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 DMA (3.95 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> DMA (2.64 %).</s><s>Only acetic acid is produced as end product in PY medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCRI-16110<sup>T</sup> (=NML 060141<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 54292<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14987<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a human faecal specimen.</s><s>The extent of habitat is not known, but is probably the mammalian gastrointestinal tract.</s></p></content></protolog>