<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6296_nm.10648" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10648" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3800" rank="species">Campylobacter hyointestinalis</organism><reference id="rid.6296"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>On</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bloch</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter hyointestinalis subsp. lawsonii subsp. nov., isolated from the porcine stomach, and an emended description of Campylobacter hyointestinalis.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>767</fpage><lpage>774</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-767</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547297</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Campylobacter hyointestinalis</i> Gebhart, Edmonds, Ward, Kurtz, and Brenner 1985.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, gram-negative rods (0.2 to 0.5 μm wide and 1.2 to 2.5 μm long) which are curved or loosely helical. Motile by means of a single, unsheathed, polar flagellum. Some cells possess two polar flagella (12; this study). Glucose is not fermented or oxidized. Optimal growth occurs under microaerobic (ca. 5% O<sub>2</sub>) conditions; some strains may grow anaerobically (7, 41; this study). No growth occurs in air. The inclusion of blood in the culture medium enhances but is not essential for growth. After 48 h of growth on 5% blood agar at 37°C, colonies are circular, convex, and pinpoint to 2.0 mm in diameter. A greenish color, accompanied by alpha-hemolytic activity, may be apparent in cultures of some strains. All strains grow at 42°C. Oxidase and catalase are produced. Selenite and nitrate are reduced. Hydrolysis of hippurate, indoxyl acetate, and urea does not occur. Hydrogen sulfide is usually produced in triple sugar iron medium. Strains grow in the presence of 1% bile and 0.032% methyl orange; some strains exhibit tolerance to 1 .5 and 2.0% bile. Not tolerant to NaCl(&#x003E;2.0%). All strains are resistant to nalidixic acid (32 mg/liter); most strains are susceptible to cephalothin (32 mg/liter)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the intestines and stomachs of pigs, hamster intestines, and the feces of cattle, deer, and humans.</s><s>Associated with enteritic disorders, but pathogenicity is not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 80-4577-4 (= LMG 781 7 = NCTC 11608 = CCUG 14169 = ATCC 35217), which was isolated from the intestine of a pig with proliferative enteritis in Minnesota in 1980.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of this strain is 35 mol% (this study) or 36 mol% (10).</s></p></content></protolog>