<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3793_nm.2699" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2699" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2699" rank="species">Pseudomonas thivervalensis</organism><reference id="rid.3793"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutra</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fromin</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Degraeve</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas brassicacearum sp. nov. and Pseudomonas thivervalensis sp. nov., two root-associated bacteria isolated from Brassica napus and Arabidopsis thaliana.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>9</fpage><lpage>18</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826782</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas thivervalensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas thivervalensis</i> (thi.ver.va.len«sis. M.L. adj. <i>thivervalensis</i> pertaining to Thiverval, France, the place where most of the strains have been isolated from the rhizoplane of <i>Arabidopsis thaliana</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative motile rods, 1.0-1.5 μm in length, about 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Forms mucoid colonies with regular margins when grown on TSA and produces brown-orange diffusible pigment at late stationary phase on TSA and in TSB, but not on these media when diluted tenfold.</s><s>They can also produce a fluorescent pigment when grown on CAA medium. <i>P. thivervalensis</i> has the same general characteristics as <i>P. brassicacearum</i>.</s><s>Oxidation of the following substrates is variable : D-galacturonic acid, glucuronamide, D-glucuronic acid, L-ornithine, putrescine and L-threonine.</s><s>Unlike <i>P. brassicacearum</i>, <i>P. thivervalensis</i> strains do not oxidize succinamic acid. <i>P. thivervalensis</i> strains do not assimilate benzoate unlike 80% of <i>P. brassicacearum</i> strains.</s><s>The oxidation and the assimilation of the other organic substrates tested with BIOLOG GN microplates and with Biotype 100 strips are the same for strains of <i>P. thivervalensis</i> as for <i>P. brassicacearum</i> strains (see above).</s><s>DNA G+­C content is 60.8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain SBK26<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Collection Française de Bactéries Phytopathogènes (CFBP) under number CFBP 11261<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>