<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2630_nm.2604" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2604" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2604" rank="species">Pseudomonas flavescens</organism><reference id="rid.2630"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hildebrand</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palleroni</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hendson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toth</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas flavescens sp. nov., isolated from walnut blight cankers.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>410</fpage><lpage>415</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520732</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas flavescens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas flavescens</i> (fla.ves'cens. L.v. <i>flavesco</i>, to become golden yellow; L. part. adj. <i>flavescens</i>, becoming golden yellow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both strains that have been isolated are aerobic, gram negative, and oxidase positive.</s><s>The cells are slightly curved rods (0.6 to 0.7 by 1.6 to 2.3 μm) and are motile by means of a single polar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>They are negative for arginine dihydrolase activity, ice nucleation, and hypersensitivity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They do not denitrify, nor do they accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin, starch, and Tween 80 is negative, and growth does not occur at 37°C.</s><s>Colonies are yellow on YDCP medium and King medium B, and a diffusible fluorescent pigment is produced on King medium B.</s><s>β-Glucosidase, rutin glycosidase, and pectinolytic enzymes are not produced.</s><s>These organisms do not cause soft rot of potatoes and do not produce levan.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized for growth: acetate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, D-alanine, L-alanine, α-aminobutyrate, L-arabinose, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, betaine, 2,3-butanediol, caprate, caproate (slowly), caprylate, choline, citrate, citrulline, creatine, ethanolamine, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconate, glucose, glutamate, glycerate (slowly), glycerol, glycolate, heptanoate, L-histidine, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, β-hydroxybutyrate, β-hydroxymethylglutarate, itaconate, α-ketoglutarate, L-lactate, L-leucine, D-malate, L-malate, malonate, mannitol, mannose, mesaconate, mucate, pelargonate, proline, pyruvate, quinate, saccharate, serine (slowly), succinate, sucrose, <i>m</i>-tartrate, trehalose, trigonelline, and xylose.</s><s>The substances not utilized for growth include acetamide, transaconitate, adipate, adonitol, <i>p</i>-alanine, α-aminobutyrate, α-aminovalerate, δ-aminovalerate, α-amylamine, anthranilate, D-arabinose, L-arabitol, L-arginine, D-aspartate, azelate, benzolate, benzoylformate, benzylamine, butanol, butylamine, butyrate, cellobiose, citraconate, <i>n</i>-dodecane, dulcitol, erythritol, ethanol, ethylene glycol, D-fucose, geraniol, glycine, <i>n</i>-hexadecane, hippurate, histamine, homoserine, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, inositol, insulin, isobutanol, isobutyrate, isoleucine, isovalerate, 2-ketogluconate, kynurenate, kynurenine, lactose, levdinate, L-lysine, maltose, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, melibiose, naphthalene, nicotinate, norleucine, pantothenate, phenol, phenylacetate, phenylalanine, phthalate, pimelate, <i>n</i>-propanol, propionate, propylene glycol, ornithine, L-rhamnose, ribose, rutin, salicin, sebacate, sorbitol, sorbose, spermine, starch, suberate, D-(-)-tartrate, L-(+)-tartrate, testosterone, L-threonine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, L-tyrosine, and L-valine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The base composition of the DNA is 63 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is NCPPB 3063.</s></p></content></protolog>