<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3944_nm.2693" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2693" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2693" rank="subspecies">Pseudomonas syringae savastanoi</organism><reference id="rid.3944"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janse</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas syringae subsp. savastanoi (ex Smith) subsp. nov., nom. rev., the bacterium causing excrescences on Oleaceae and Nerium oleander L.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>166</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-2-166</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> subsp. <i>savastanoi</i> (ex Smith 1908) subsp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> subsp. <i>savastanoi</i> (sa.vas.ta'no.i. M.L. gen. noun <i>savastanoi</i> of Savastano, named for L. Savastano, the first to study olive knot)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods with rounded ends, 0.3 to 0.7 by 1.0 to 1.8 μm, occurring singly or in pairs; motile by means of one to five polar flagella.</s><s>Rather slow-growing, gray-white, smooth, glistening, raised and circular or slightly irregular to undulate colonies are produced on nutrient agar; levan negative or levan positive on nutrient-sucrose (5%) agar; produces a weak, blue-green fluorescent, diffusible pigment on King’s B medium; some strains produce a brown diffusible pigment.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory.</s><s>Oxidase negative, catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-(+)-galactose, glucose, D-(+)-ribose, sucrose (slow), D-(+)-xylose, and mannitol; no acid is produced from maltose, D-(+)-raffinose, erythritol, or salicin; alkali is produced from L-(+)-tartrate; esculin, arginine, gelatin, and starch are not hydrolyzed; generally, arbutin and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from cysteine.</s><s>No growth occurs in nutrient broth at 37°C or with 5% NaCl.</s><s>Hypersensitivity is produced in tobacco leaves.</s><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid contains 60 mol% guanine plus cytosine (3).</s><s>Causes galls and wartlike excrescences on various species of <i>Oleaceae</i> and <i>N. oleander</i> L.</s><s>Gall-forming isolates produce indolyl-acetic acid and cytokinin-like substances in vitro.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this subspecies is ATCC 13522 (= NCPPB 639).</s><s>This strain was isolated by D. Šutić from <i>Olea europea</i> in Yugoslavia.</s><s>Its description is identical to that of the subspecies, but with the following modifications: levan negative on nutrient-sucrose (5%) agar; casein hydrolysis is weak; produces galls on <i>O. europea</i> L. and <i>F. excelsior</i> L.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following pathovars of <i>P. syringae</i> subsp. <i>savastanoi</i> are recognized: pathovar oleae, causing parenchymatic galls on various species of the <i>Oleaceae</i> (15, 16); pathovar nerii, causing parenchymatic galls or wartlike excrescences on <i>N. oleander</i> L. and various species of the <i>Oleaceae</i> (14); and pathovarfruini, causing wartlike excrescences on <i>F. excelsior</i> L. and <i>O. europea</i> L. (2, 5, 13).</s></p></content></protolog>