<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12210_nm.20204" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20204" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20204" rank="species">Amycolatopsis pigmentata</organism><reference id="rid.12210"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otoguro</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.-i.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis helveola sp. nov. and Amycolatopsis pigmentata sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2629</fpage><lpage>2633</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017871-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20023060</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis pigmentata</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis pigmentata</em> (pig.men.ta′ta. L. fem. adj. <em>pigmentata</em> painted, coloured, pigmented, referring to the production of soluble pigment in some media).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative hyphae are finely branched and fragmentation is not observed.</s><s>Sporophores show monopodial or dichotomous branching.</s><s>The spore chain may be straight, hooked or flexuous.</s><s>The spores (0.7–1.5 μm in diameter) are spherical, oval or rod-shaped with a smooth surface and are non-motile.</s><s>Colony colour is yellow.</s><s>Good growth occurs between 25 °C and 37 °C; no growth occurs at NaCl concentrations higher than 3 % (w/v).</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>However, the following compounds are not utilized as carbon sources: d-adonitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, ferric citrate, l-fucose, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, glycogen, d-maltose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-sucrose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside or l-xylose.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction, acid phosphatase, chymotrypsin, esterase lipase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, and trypsin.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, lipase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, however, gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, 2-OH-iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TT99-32<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 103392<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19330<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a pineapple field soil sample from Iriomote Island, Japan.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 67.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>