<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.280_nm.14075" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14075" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3942" rank="species">Clostridium halophilium</organism><reference id="rid.280"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fendrich</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschalk</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium halophilium sp. nov. and Clostridium litorale sp. nov., an obligate halophilic and a marine species degrading betaine in the Stickland reaction.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>154</volume><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>132</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00423321</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium halophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium halophilum</i> (ha.lo'phi.lum, hals, halos Gr. n. salt; philein Gr. v. loving, <i>halophilum</i> M.L. adj. saltloving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, 0.8-1.0 μm x 2.5 x 7.0 μm in size, with straight ends; motile, spherical spores (1.2 μm) formed terminally in aging cultures, preferentially after growth on sugars; gram-reaction positive; gram-positive  cell wall with surface-layer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph: D-cellobiose, dulcitol, D-fructose, D-glucose, inulin, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-ribose, salicin and D-sorbitol are fermented under acidification.</s><s>Betaine is as oxidant in the Stickland reaction reductively cleaved into trimethylamine and acetate with hydrogen, glycine, L-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-valine, L-phenylalanine or L-histidine.</s><s>Produces propionate from threonine and grows on pyruvate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In complex standard media gas, including hydrogen, is produced; acetate and ethanol are the major fermentation products.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide, indole and ammonia are formed.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by Tween 80.</s><s>It is positive for esculin hydrolysis, and there is reduction of neutral red and resazurin.</s><s>It is catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Lipase, lecithinase or urease is not produced.</s><s>Meat and milk are not digested.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed and nitrate, sulfate, thiosulfate or sulfite are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant against chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth requires addition of complex nutrients.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range. 18°C-49°C; optimum growth at 41°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH Range. 6.0-8.0; optimum growth at 7.4; obligately halophilic, 1.5% NaCl required; optimum growth at 6.0% NaCl, growth not inhibited by 10.0% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio. 26.9% G+ C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats.</s><s>Anoxic hypersaline sediments of the Maledive Islands and Solar Lake, Egypt, as well as marine sediments of the North Sea, Germany.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain M1, DSM 5387, deposited in Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, FRG.</s></p></content></protolog>