<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.167_nm.2028" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2028" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2028" rank="species">Azoarcus tolulyticus</organism><reference id="rid.167"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fries</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chee-Sanford</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analyses of a new group of denitrifiers capable of anaerobic growth of toluene and description of Azoarcus tolulyticus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>500</fpage><lpage>506</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-500</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590677</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azoarcus tolulyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azoarcus tolulyticus</i> (to.lu.ly'ti.cus. N. L. n. Fr. Sp. <i>tolu</i>, balsam from Santiago de Tolu, toluene; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; N. L. masc. adj. <i>tolulyticus</i>, toluene dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, short, motile rods (length, 1.4 to 2.1 μm) when the organisms are grown anaerobically on toluene; cells are longer motile rods (length, 2.1 to 2.8 μm) or occur in long chains when the organisms are grown on M-R2A agar.</s><s>Growth on M-R2A medium results in uniform translucent yellowish colonies that are approximately 2 to 3 mm in diameter and have dark centers.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Cells lack tryptophanase, β-galactosidase, urease, and arginine dihydrolase activities.</s><s>Nitrate and oxygen can serve as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Capable of growth on nitrogen-free media under a nitrogen (N<sub>2</sub>) atmosphere.</s><s>Grows well on M-R2A medium, nutrient agar, a few aromatic substrates, including toluene, and organic acids such as malate.</s><s>Grows poorly on TSA.</s><s>Limited substrate range.</s><s>All strains grow at pH 6 to 9, in the presence of up to 1% NaCl, and at 25 to 37°C.</s><s>All strains have <i>cis</i>-7 16:1 and 16:O fatty acids as their predominant cellular fatty acids.</s><s>This organism belongs to the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> as determined by 16s rRNA gene sequence analyses.</s><s>In contrast to the previously described species of the genus <i>Azoarcus</i>, the strains are able to degrade toluene under denitrifying conditions, grow on glucose and maltose, contain a considerable amount of 12:O fatty acid, and lack 3-OH 8:O fatty acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain Tol-4, the type strain, has been deposited in The American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51758.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a petroleum-contaminated core taken from the Bear Lake aquifer in Northern Michigan.</s></p></content></protolog>