<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5251_nm.3653" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3653" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3653" rank="species">Syntrophobacter wolinii</organism><reference id="rid.5251"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Boone</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionate-Degrading Bacterium, Syntrophobacter wolinii sp. nov. gen. nov., from Methanogenic Ecosystems.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>626</fpage><lpage>632</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16345640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophobacter wolinii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophobacter wolinii</i> (wolin .i.i, M.L. gen. n. <i>wolinii</i> of Wolin)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative rods occurring singly and in pairs with some short chains and filaments.</s><s>The cell width is 0.6 to 1 μm, with filaments up to 35 μm long.</s><s>The width of a cell is sometimes irregular, especially in filaments.</s><s>Cells are highly refractile, but no endospores have been observed.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies in roll tubes of <i>S. wolinii</i>-<i>Desulfovibrio</i> sp. cocultures are black-centered, convex, and circular, with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies form in 3 to 5 weeks and may reach 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Subsurface colonies are lenticular.</s><s>Energy-yielding metabolism involves oxidation of propionate, but not other fatty acids, with the production of acetate and, presumably, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth occurs only when H<sub>2</sub> is constantly removed by the action of H2-utilizing bacteria.</s><s>Sulfate does not serve as an electron acceptor in the energy metabolism, and no growth occurs in thioglycolate medium.</s><s>Thus, glucose or materials present in the large amount of yeast extract and tryptic digest of casein added do not support growth.</s></p></content></protolog>