<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7204_nm.6025" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6025" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6025" rank="species">Terracoccus luteus</organism><reference id="rid.7204"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Prauser</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Terracoccus luteus gen. nov., sp. nov., an LL-diaminopimelic acid-containing coccoid actinomycete from soil.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1218</fpage><lpage>1224</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1218</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336932</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Terracoccus luteus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Terracoccus luteus</i> (lu'te.us M. L. adj. <i>luteus</i>, yellow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are spherical to slightly ellipsoidal, 0.7 to 1.3 μm in diameter, gram positive, not acid fast, and nonmotile.</s><s>The colonies, 0.05 to 2.0 mm in diameter, may be rough or smooth.</s><s>Rough colonies are lobed and irregularly raised; smooth colonies are circular and convex.</s><s>The cells of rough colonies are mostly arranged in more or less regular sarcinoid packets, which may form large irregular clusters.</s><s>The cells of smooth colonies occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads, or in small irregular clusters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Urease and H2S are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Formation of acids from sugars and alcohols is not observed.</s><s>Only a few of the tested compounds are utilized for growth, i.e., D-arabitol, gluconate, N-acetybglucosamine, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-proline, succinate, sucrose, and D-turanose.</s><s>Starch, casein, gelatin, esculiii, and DNA are hydrolyzed; Tween 80 is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Sodium acetate, formate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, hippurate, disodium succinate, and potassium tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Xanthine, hypoxanthine, adenine, and DL-tyrosine are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The LL-A<sub>2</sub>pm-containing cell wall peptidoglycan contains three glycine residues as an interpeptide bridge and another glycine residue bound to glutamic acid of the peptide subunit.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acids are 13-methyl tetradecanoic acid and 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid.</s><s>Diagnostic polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 73 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The only known isolation site is soil at the water-soil interface of a duck pond at the island of Hiddensee, Germany.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IMET 7848.</s><s>It has been deposited in the DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures GmbH as strain DSM 44267<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>