<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1375_nm.6539" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6539" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6539" rank="species">Micromonospora rosaria</organism><reference id="rid.1375"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Horan</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brodsky</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Micromonospora rosaria sp. nov., nom. rev., the rosaramicin producer.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>478</fpage><lpage>480</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Micromonospora rosaria</i> sp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Wagman, Waitz, Marquez, Murawski, Oden, Testa, and Weinstein, 1972)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The specific epithet refers to the wine red diffusible pigment formed by strain NRRL 3718<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The vegetative hyphae are branched and approximately 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Spores that are 1.5 to 1.8 μm in diameter occur along the length of the hyphae, are borne singly, and are either sessile or on short sporophores.</s><s>Growth and sporulatioh is of the open web type of Luedemann (13) (Fig. 1).</s><s>Electron microscopic analysis of spores reveals the presence of warts which arise from the outer portion of the spore wall (Fig. 2), as described by Luedemann and Casmer for <i>Micromonospora chalcea</i> spores (16).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains grow well on most of the rich organic media tested (Table 2).</s><s>Poor growth occurs on calcium malate, calcium citrate, and peptone-glucose agar media.</s><s>Strains grow in the presence of gentamicin, sisomicin, erythromycin, rosaramicin, everninomicin, novobiocin, clindamycin, lincomycin, cycloserine, penicillin G, and cephalothin at concentrations of 50 μg/ml but do not grow in the presence of neomycin, kanamycin, streptomycin, tetracycline, or rifamycin at  concentrations of 50 μg/ml.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl and in the presence of Na<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>0<sub>3</sub> at a concentration of 4%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of lysozyme or salicylate.</s><s>Strains are sensitive to acid, as determined by lack of growth on potato slices (12).</s><s>Growth on ATCC medium 172 (1) agar slants is most abundant at 35 and 40°C and is poor at 42°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 10 and 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative mycelial pigments range from orangish brown to purplish black.</s><s>A characteristic wine red diffusible pigment is formed on most media, as is a grayish white bloom of short, sterile aerial mycelia (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzed whole cells contain both hydroxy (20) and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acids as characteristic amino acids.</s><s>Arabinose and xylose are the characteristic sugars.</s><s>Galactose is also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D- and L-arabinose, fructose, methyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, D-ribose , sucrose, D-trehalose, and D-xylose are utilized with the formation of wine red to reddish brown diffusible pigments.</s><s>The pigment interferes in the Gordon acid production test for carbon utilization (6), turning the yellow positive reaction back to a color similar to the color of the original purple indicator, making readings impossible.</s><s>Adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, and D-raffinose are not utilized.</s><s>D-Galactose utilization is weak.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the organic acids tested, acetate, gluconate, glutamate, propionate, and pyruvate are utilized; benzoate, citrate, lactate, malate, oleate, oxalate, succinate, and tartrate are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tyrosine, xylan, chitin, casein, starch, gelatin, esculin, and arbutin are hydrolyzed; hypoxanthine, xanthine, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The breakdown of Dorset egg medium and Loeffer serum medium is weak.</s><s>Urease is formed.</s><s>Nitrate reductase is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of strain NRRL 3718<sup>TM</sup> deoxyribonucleic acid is 75 mol% (T.</s><s>R.</s><s>Monahan, M.S. thesis, Seton Hall University, South Orange, N.J., 1976).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M . rosaria</i> strain NRRL 3718 (= ATCC 29337) is designated the type strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>