<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6822_nm.6224" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6224" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6224" rank="species">Corynebacterium glaucum</organism><reference id="rid.6822"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium glaucum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>705</fpage><lpage>709</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02394-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807190</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium glaucum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium glaucum</em> (glau′cum. L. neut. adj. <em>glaucum</em> bluish, light-grey, pertaining to the appearance of colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive and non acid–alcohol-fast.</s><s>They are non-motile, non-spore-forming and dumbbell-shaped (when examined after 18 h growth), showing typical coryneform morphology (when examined after 1 week of growth).</s><s>On Columbia blood agar supplemented with 5 % sheep blood, BHI agar and trypticase soy agar, colonies are light-grey in colour.</s><s>Grows facultatively anaerobically and is catalase-positive.</s><s>It contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e. cell-wall chemotype IV).</s><s>Contains corynemycolic acids and the fatty acid profile contains saturated and unsaturated fatty acids.</s><s>Tuberculostearic acid is absent.</s><s>Contains MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) as respiratory menaquinones, with MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) as the major component.</s><s>Phospholipid pattern type PI, with no nitrogen-containing compounds.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose and sucrose but not from arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Hydrolyses hippurate but not aesculin, gelatin or starch.</s><s>Displays alkaline phosphatase, pyrazinamidase, ester lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities but is negative for acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, nitrate reductase and urease.</s><s>Acetoin production is positive but indole production is negative.</s><s>Produces lactate as the major product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 64·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain IMMIB R-5091<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44530<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-24142<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a cosmetic dye.</s></p></content></protolog>