<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6800_nm.8222" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8222" rank="family">Sphingobacteriaceae</organism><reference id="rid.6800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steyn</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sandra</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joubert</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of heparinolytic bacteria into a new genus, Pedobacter, comprising four species: Pedobacter heparinus comb. nov., Pedobacter piscium comb. nov., Pedobacter africanus sp. nov. and Pedobacter saltans sp. nov. proposal of the family Sphingobacteriaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>165</fpage><lpage>177</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-165</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542086</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingobacteriaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Descriptive information for the family is taken from the literature (1, 3, 5,9, 12, 17, 28, 32) and the present paper. Organisms belonging to the family are Gramnegative. Cells are short to relatively long rods and are usually 0.3-0.6 μm wide and 0.5-6 μm long (except [<i>Flexibacter</i>] <i>canadensis</i> which is filamentous) and are non-sporulating. Flagella are absent. Non-motile or motile by gliding. Aerobic growth with optimum temperature in a range of 10-30 °C ([<i>Flexibacter</i>] <i>canadensis</i> also grows as a facultative anaerobe). Colonies are usually yellow pigmented. Chemoorganotrophic. All members produce catalase, oxidase and phosphatase, are indole-negative, and can utilize a large number of carbohydrates. Few organic acids and amino acids are utilized. Dominant fatty acids are iso-15:0, iso-15:0(2-OH), iso-15:0(3-OH), 16:0, 16:1ω7c, 16:0(3-OH) and iso-17:0(3-OH). Menaquinone 7 is the major respiratory quinone. Presence of sphingolipids. Homospermidine is the major polyamine. The G + C content is 36-45 mol %. Members of this family are commonly isolated from soil or activated sludge and from clinical specimens. No species are considered as true pathogens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type genus is <i>Sphingobacterium</i>.</s><s>Other members are <i>Pedobacter</i> and [<i>Flexibacter</i>] <i>canadensis</i>.</s><s>All these organisms belong to the same rRNA branch within rRNA superfamily V (the <i>Cytophaga</i>-<i>Flavobacterium</i>-<i>Bacteroides</i> group).</s><s>Differential characteristics between the taxa belonging to the family <i>Sphingobacteriaceae</i> are given in Tables 4,5 and 6 and the literature (3, 12, 24, 28, 32).</s><s>The family <i>Sphingobacteriaceae</i> belongs to the order <i>Cytophagales</i> Leadbetter 1974, 99<sup>AL</sup> (22).</s></p></content></protolog>