<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1414_nm.3911" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3911" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3911" rank="species">Clostridium cellulolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.1414"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Petitdemange</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caillet</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giallo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gaudin</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium cellulolyticum sp. nov., a cellulolytic, mesophilic: Species from decayed grass.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-155</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium cellulolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium cellulolyticum</i> (cel.lu.lo.ly´ti.cum. Gr. n. <i>cellulosum</i> cellulose; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i> dissolving; N .L. adj. <i>cellulolyticum</i> cellulose dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells (Fig. 1) are anaerobic, gram-positive, straight to slightly curved rods that are 3 to 6 μm long by 0.6 to 1 μm wide.</s><s>Spores are present in cultures on cellulose media 3 or more days old; these spores are spherical (diameter, 1.5 μm) and terminal, produce swollen cells (Fig. 1 A and B), and resist a temperature of 100°C for 30 min.</s><s>Spores are rarely formed on other carbohydrate media.</s><s>The cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 2) and have a cell wall that is typical of the cell walls of gram-positive species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On cellulose agar medium colonies appear after 5 to 6 days of incubation at 35°C.</s><s>Surface colonies are smooth, circular, approximately 0.5 mm in diameter, slightly raised, translucent, and unpigmented with undulate margins, and a butyrous texture.</s><s>Clear zones showing complete solubilization of cellulose around the colonies are 1 to 4 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The maximum growth temperature is 45°C, the optimum growth temperature is 32 to 35°C, and the minimum growth temperature is 25°C; growth does not occur at 20 and 50°C even after 2 months.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There is no growth with adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Poor growth is produced with galactose, mannose, or ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate growth is produced with arabinose, cellobiose, cellulose, fructose, glucose, and xylose, and the final pH is 5.5 to 5.2.</s><s>The doubling times with cellobiose, cellulose, and glucose are 7, 15, and 10 h, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed; starch is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, nitrite, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Milk is unchanged, casein is not digested, and no growth occurs in chopped meat broth.</s><s>Pyruvate and lactate are not utilized.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied, and thiosulfate is not reduced.</s><s>Catalase, urease, lipase, and lecithinase are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbon dioxide, hydrogen, acetate, ethanol, lactate, and formate are produced from cellulose.</s><s>Little glucose is detected among the reducing sugars produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated in autumn from decayed grass compost packed for 3 to 4 months.</s><s>The mean G+C content of the DNA is 41 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain H<sub>10</sub> (= ATCC 35319).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In <i>Bergey's Manual of Determinative Bacteriology</i>, 8th ed. (14), the only member of the group III clostridia that is recognized as cellulolytic is <i>Clostridium cellobioparum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The most significant differences between <i>C. cellulolyticum</i> and <i>C . cellobioparum</i> are shown in Table 1. <i>C. cellulolyticum</i> differs from <i>C . cellobioparum</i> in not fermenting dulcitol, lactose, mannose, and sorbitol.</s><s>Furthermore, from cellulose digestion <i>C. cellobioparum</i> forms only cellobiose, the strain isolated by Skinner (13) forms glucose and little or no cellobiose, and our isolate forms cellobiose and little glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. cellulolyticum</i> also differs from <i>Clostridium papyrosolvens</i>, a new species described by Madden et al. (8), in not fermenting glycerol and particularly in being unable to grow at temperatures below 25°C.</s><s>Finally, the G+C content of the DNA of <i>C. papyrosolvens</i> is 30 mol%; thus, this species can be readily distinguished from <i>C. cellulolyticum</i>, which has a G+C content of 41 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>