<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6111_nm.10251" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10251" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10251" rank="species">Burkholderia silvatlantica</organism><reference id="rid.6111"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Perin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Aguilar</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paredes-Valdez</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Estrada-de Los Santos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reis</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caballero-Mellado</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia silvatlantica sp. nov., a diazotrophic bacterium associated with sugar cane and maize</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1931</fpage><lpage>1937</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64362-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902033</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia silvatlantica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia silvatlantica</em> (sil.vat.lan′ti.ca. L. n. <em>silva</em> wood, forest; L. fem. adj. <em>Atlantica</em> pertaining to the Atlas Mountains and by extension to the Atlantic Ocean; N.L. fem. adj. <em>silvatlantica</em> pertaining to the Atlantic forest of Brazil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods (1.6–1.9 μm long and 0.8–0.9 μm wide), each having a polar tuft of flagella.</s><s>Isolates are Gram-negative and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth and nitrogenase activity are observed with different carbon sources in nitrogen-free LGI, JMV and BAz semi-solid media.</s><s>Strains grown on JMV agar plates produce colonies that are round, cream-coloured with yellow in the centre, smooth, convex with entire margins and that are 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows on BSE medium at 29 and 37 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>Does not grow on MacConkey agar or <em>B. cepacia</em> selective agar medium at 29 or 37 °C.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics useful for differentiation from other N<sub>2</sub>-fixing <em>Burkholderia</em> species and the most closely related species, <em>B. sacchari</em>, are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not to N<sub>2</sub>; there is urease activity and aesculin hydrolysis, but not liquefaction of gelatin or indole production.</s><s>Additional phenotypic characteristics are listed in Table 3.</s><s>Can be differentiated phenotypically from all diazotrophic <em>Burkholderia</em> species and from <em>B. sacchari</em> on the basis of SDS-PAGE protein profiles, the electrophoretic mobility patterns of metabolic enzymes and fatty acid profiles.</s><s>Strains SRMrh-20<sup>T</sup>, SRMrh-85, PPCR-2 and AB48 show 100 % similarity among their 16S rRNA gene sequences and show 99.77 % similarity to strain SRCL-318.</s><s>Can also be differentiated genomically from all diazotrophic <em>Burkholderia</em> species, and from <em>B. sacchari</em>, by ARDRA profiles.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SRMrh-20<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23149<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1244<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of maize var. Avantis A2345, cultivated in the Experimental Campus of Embrapa Agrobiology in Seropédica, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</s><s>The phenotypic and genomic characteristics of the type strain are the same as those described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>