<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7254_nm.10344" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10344" rank="genus">Nonomuria</organism><reference id="rid.7254"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Thermomonospora and Microtetraspora</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>411</fpage><lpage>422</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-411</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nonomuria</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nonomuria</i> (No.no.mu.ri.a. M.L. fem. n. <i>Nonomuria</i> after H. Nonomura, a Japanese taxonomist of actinomycetes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>According to chemical criteria and 16s rRNA oligonucleotide sequence data of the Microtetrasporapusilla group, Goodfellow, Stackebrandt &#x0026; Kroppenstedt proposed a new genus, <i>Nonomuria</i>, in 1988 to accommodate species of the <i>Actinomadura pusilla</i> group (10), but it was not formally published.</s><s>Based on earlier investigations (1, 21, 34, 35,41, 42, 43, 57) and our phylogenetic analysis, the <i>Microtetraspora pusilla</i> group (clade IV) was found to be distinct from the three original <i>Microtetraspora</i> species (clade II), which includes the type species <i>Microtetraspora glauca</i>, and should be considered as a new genus.</s><s>The description of <i>Nonomuria</i> presented here is taken from this and previous studies (7, 10, 21, 35).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Aerial mycelia bear chains of spores which are hooked, spiral or straight.</s><s>Spore surface folded, irregular, smooth or warty.</s><s>Growth temperature ranges from 20 to 45 °C, in some cases up to 55 °C.</s><s>Cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-DAP and the whole-cell hydrolysate contains madurose as the diagnostic sugar (cell wall type III/B).</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), -9(H<sub>6</sub>) and -9(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>Phospholipids are type IV (PE, DPG, NPG, OH-PE).</s><s>Major types of fatty acids are 10 methyl-17-and iso-16-branched fatty acids (in some cases the amount of the former is more than the latter).</s><s>G + C content ranges from 64 to 69 mol%.</s><s>Analysis of 16s rRNA gene sequences showed that this genus belongs to the family Streptosporangiaceae.</s><s>Type species is <i>Nonomuria pusilla</i> (Nonomura and Ohara 1971) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>