<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.729_nm.1537" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1537" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1537" rank="species">Azorhizobium caulinodans</organism><reference id="rid.729"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dreyfus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Azorhizobium caulinodans gen. nov. a stem nodulating nitrogen-fixing bacterium isolated from Sesbania rastrata.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>98</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azorhizobium caulinodans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azorhizobium caulinodans</i> (cau.li'no.dans. M. L. n. <i>caulis</i> stem; M. L. v. <i>nodare</i> to nodulate; M. L. part. adj. <i>caulinodans</i> stem nodulating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are as described above for the genus.</s><s>They effectively nodulate roots and stems of <i>S. rostrata</i>, possess arginine dihydrolase and lysine decarboxylase, and grow in the presence of 8% KNO<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>They grow on azelate, maleate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, gluconate, mucate, crotonate, nicotinate, 2-ketogluconate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, valerate, isovalerate, caproate, laurate, 2-ketoglutarate, fumarate, glutarate, sebacate, DL-malate, citrate, pyruvate, aconitate, citraconitate, D-glucuronate, α-D-galacturonate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-aspartate, quinate, L-α-alanine, L-lysine, L-asparagine, betaine, and sarcosine.</s><s>Do not oxidize mannitol.</s><s>Assimilate 1,2-propanediol and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Growth occurs from 12 to 43°C.</s><s>Among the vitamins, nicotinic acid is required for N<sub>2</sub> fixation under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>Equally good growth is observed between pHs 5.5 and 7.8.</s><s>Other physiological characteristics are as described above for the genus.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66.5 mol%.</s><s>Strain ORS 571 (=LMG 6465) is the type strain.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 66 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>