<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1622_nm.10981" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10981" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10981" rank="species">Pseudomonas simiae</organism><reference id="rid.1622"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutiérrez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rollán</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simarro</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas simiae sp. nov., isolated from clinical specimens from monkeys (Callithrix geoffroyi)</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2671</fpage><lpage>2676</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64378-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082409</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas simiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas simiae</em> (si′mi.ae. L. gen. n. <em>simiae</em> of an ape, of a monkey).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, catalase- and oxidase-positive, strictly aerobic and motile rods approximately 1–1.5 μm in size.</s><s>Cells produce a yellow pigment on tryptic soy agar.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia blood agar are circular, non-pigmented and slightly haemolytic.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C; optimal growth occurs at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Fluorescent pigment is produced on King's medium B.</s><s>The isolates reduce nitrate and hydrolyse gelatin.</s><s>None of the isolates produces acid from glucose, acetoin or <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Reaction for arginine dihydrolase is positive.</s><s>Urea and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are assimilated: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>None of the isolates assimilated <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Esterase (C4), ester lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase activities, and a weak reaction for valine arylamidase are detected.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphoamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not produced.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain OLi<sup>T</sup> is 49.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, OLi<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50988<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7078<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the liver of a monkey with acute bronchopneumonia and bacteraemia.</s></p></content></protolog>