<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12575_nm.21829" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21829" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21829" rank="species">Bacillus luteolus</organism><reference id="rid.12575"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus luteolus sp. nov., a halotolerant bacterium isolated from a salt field</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1344</fpage><lpage>1349</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021683-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20584813</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus luteolus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus luteolus</em> (lu.te.o′lus. L. masc. adj. <em>luteolus</em> yellowish, pale tangerine-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, strictly aerobic, thin rods, 0.7–0.9×2.0–5.0 µm, motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Supplementary Fig. S4).</s><s>Spherical endospores are produced in a terminal position.</s><s>Colonies are 0.5–2 mm in diameter, circular, pale tangerine in colour, convex and opaque on GTY medium.</s><s>Grows at 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimal growth at 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–45 °C and at pH 6.0–8.0, with optimal growth at 28–37 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite under anaerobic or aerobic conditions.</s><s>Catalase is detected.</s><s>Oxidase, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Dextrin and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acids are produced from potassium 5-ketogluconate (weakly), d-fructose, sucrose, turanose, d-xylose, glycerol (weakly) and glycogen (weakly), but not from l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, trehalose, melezitose or raffinose (API 50CHB).</s><s>In the API 20E system, positive for arginine dihydrolase and urease, but negative for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl β-d-galactoside hydrolysis, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, tests for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase are positive, but valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon or nitrogen sources: l-arginine, hypoxanthine, sodium citrate, lactose, l-rhamnose, d-xylose, d-ribose and glycerol.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disc unless indicated) amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), clindamycin (2), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), novobiocin (30), streptomycin (10), tobramycin (10), vancomycin (30), amoxicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), netilmicin sulfate (30), norfloxacin (10), penicillin (10 U), rifampicin (5), trimethoprim sulfonamide (1.25) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is of the A1γ type, containing <em>m</em>-Dpm as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside and two unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 36.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 93174<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22388<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 13210<sup>T</sup>  = CCTCC AA 208068<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt field in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>