<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3346_nm.8226" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8226" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8226" rank="species">Sphingobacterium faecium</organism><reference id="rid.3346"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposals of Sphingobacterium faecium sp. nov., Sphingobacterium piscium sp. nov., Sphingobacterium heparinum comb. nov., Sphingobacterium thalpophilum comb. nov. and two genospecies of the genus Sphingobacterium and synonymy of Flavobacterium yabuuchiae and Sphingobacterium spiritivorum.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>465</fpage><lpage>482</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingobacterium faecium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingobacterium faecium</i> (fae'ci.um. L. n. <i>faecis</i>, dregs; L. gen. pl. n, <i>faecium</i>, of the dregs, of feces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporing rods 0.4-0.5 X 0.5-1.0 μm.</s><s>Nonmotile, nongliding (no sliding translocation occurs).</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Circular, entire, low convex, smooth and opaque colonies developing on nutrient agar after 2 days; on nutrient agar, a yellow or creamy white, nonfluorescent pigment is produced.</s><s>Grows at 5°C and 37°C but not at 42°C.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, urease, extracellular deoxyribonuclease and phosphatase (alkaline and acid) are produced, but gelatinase is not produced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>D-Xylose, L-arabinose, D-glucose, D-fructose, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, starch and inulin are utilized.</s><s>Heparin, succinoglucan, pectin, polypectate, cellulose, arginate, chitin and agar are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from salicin, trehalose, raffinose, D- and L-arabinose, L-fucose, inulin, melibiose and melezitose but not from L-xylose, sorbose, rhamnose, xylitol, mannitol, D-ribose or ethanol (3%).</s><s>β-Glucosidase and valine arylamidase are produced but trypsin and β-glucuronidase are not.</s><s>G + C content of DNA is 39.0 to 40.4 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major non-polar fatty acids from whole cells are i-15:0 and 16:1 and 2-hydroxy i-15:0, 3-hydroxy i-15:0 and 3-hydroxy i-17:0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IFO 15299 (KS 0470).</s></p></content></protolog>