<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9562_nm.14736" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14736" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14736" rank="species">Streptomonospora flavalba</organism><reference id="rid.9562"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomonospora amylolytica sp. nov. and Streptomonospora flavalba sp. nov., two novel halophilic actinomycetes isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2471</fpage><lpage>2475</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007682-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622663</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomonospora flavalba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomonospora flavalba</em> (fla.val′ba. L. adj. <em>flavus</em> yellow; L. adj. <em>albus</em> white; N.L. fem. adj. <em>flavalba</em> yellow–white, referring to the colour of aerial mycelium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows well on yeast extract-malt extract agar and nutrient agar media supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl, but grows poorly on Czapek's agar or glycerol/asparagine agar supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced on most media tested, except for potato extract agar (pH 7.0) supplemented with 10 % (w/v) NaCl, on which deep yellow diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Aerial and substrate mycelia are not fragmented.</s><s>Yellow–white aerial mycelia form spore chains at maturity, with non-motile, oval to cylindrical spores (0.5–0.6×0.7–0.9 μm).</s><s>Single, oval spores are borne on sporophores of substrate mycelium.</s><s>Substrate mycelia are pale yellow on inorganic salt-starch agar, oatmeal agar, yeast extract-malt extract agar, glycerol/asparagine agar and nutrient agar and yellow–white on Czapek's agar and ivory–olive–brown on potato extract agar.</s><s>Growth occurs with 5–25 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 10 %), at 20–45 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0).</s><s>Utilizes arabinose, glucose, maltose and rhamnose as sole carbon and energy sources, and alanine, arginine, glycine, histidine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, tryptophan and tyrosine as sole nitrogen, carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of starch, melanin production and milk coagulation and peptonization, but negative for gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of cellulose and urea, H<sub>2</sub>S production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, and galactose is the major diagnostic sugar in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.5 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 91394<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45155<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 208047<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from saline soil collected from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>