<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3455_nm.1783" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1783" rank="genus">Acidovorax</organism><reference id="rid.3455"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goor</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thielemans</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of several phytopathogenic Pseudomonas species to Acidovorax as Acidovorax avenae subsp. avenae subsp. nov., comb. nov., Acidovorax avenae subsp. citrulli, Acidovorax avenae subsp. cattleyae, and Acidovorax konjaci.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>119</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-1-107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1371056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Acidovorax</i> Willems et al. 1990.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The original description of the genus <i>Acidovorax</i> is extended with the characteristics given below. Cells are straight to slightly curved rods that are 0.2 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 5.0 μm; they occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains. Motile by means of one polar flagellum or, rarely, by means of two or three polar flagella. On nutrient agar colonies are round with smooth to slightly scalloped or spreading margins. Sometimes different margin types which cannot be isolated as stable forms occur in one culture. Colonies are convex, smooth to slightly granular, and beige to faintly yellow. A translucent marginal zone may be present. At 30°C diameters of 0.5 to 3 mm in 3 days and 4 mm in 7 days can be attained. <i>Acidovorax</i> species occur in soil, water, clinical samples, and infected plant material. Some of the phytopathogenic strains produce a yellow to slightly brown diffusible pigment. The optimal growth temperature is 30 to 35°C. The DNA base composition as determined by thermal denaturation ranges from 62 to 70 mol% G + C. In DNA-rRNA hybridizations <i>Acidovorax</i> strains have T<sub>m(e)</sub>, values of at least 77°C versus rRNA from either <i>Acidovorax avenae</i> NCPPB 1011<sup>T</sup> or <i>Acidovorax facilis</i> ATCC 11228<sub>T</sub>. The genus <i>Acidovorax</i> belongs to the family <i>Comamonadaceae</i> in the beta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> (rRNA superfamily III) together with the genera <i>Comamonas</i>, <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, <i>Xylophilus</i>, and <i>Variovorax</i>. Characteristics that differentiate the seven <i>Acidovorax</i> taxa are shown in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>