<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1556_nm.10713" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10713" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4281" rank="species">Eubacterium yurii</organism><reference id="rid.1556"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Margaret</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krywolap</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium yurii subsp. yurii sp. nov. and Eubacterium yurii subsp. margaretiae subsp. nov.: test tube brush bacteria from subgingival dental plaque.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>149</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-145</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium yurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium yurii</i> (yur'i i. masc. noun. <i>Yuri</i> [author])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming , straight gram-positive rods with slightly rounded ends.</s><s>Individual cells are motile by means of a single subpolar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>The cells form three-dimensional brushlike aggregates held together by an amorphous, extracellular substance (Fig. 2 and 3).</s><s>Cells from 48-h Schaedler broth culture measure approximately 0.5 by 4 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 48 h of incubation at 37°C on Schaedler blood agar, colonies measure 1 mm in diameter, with delicate, spreading margins.</s><s>A pale yellow pigment may be evident.</s><s>Growth on MM1O blood agar is similar, although the colonies are smaller.</s><s>Colonies do not spread on media without blood.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In Schaedler broth growth is typically as a granular sediment, with colonies adhering to the glass; the supernatant fluid remains clear; gas may be formed.</s><s>Growth is poor in chopped-meat medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vitamin K is not required for growth.</s><s>The cultures grow well at 34 to 37°C but not at 25 or 40°C.</s><s>All strains are H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, and RNase positive and negative for esculin, gelatin, hippurate, and starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Catalase is negative; acetylmethylcarbinol is not produced.</s><s>Most strains are asaccharolytic.</s><s>DNase, glucose, maltose, sucrose, and phosphatase reactions are variable (Table 1).</s><s>In peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth, the major product is butyrate, with lesser amounts of acetate and propionate.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin, erythromycin, tetracycline, clindamycin, and chloramphenicol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: subgingival dental plaque.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The moles percent guanine plus cytosine content is 32 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p></content></protolog>