<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6773_nm.6877" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6877" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6876" rank="species">Streptomyces avermitilis</organism><reference id="rid.6773"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces avermitilis sp. nov., nom. rev., a taxonomic home for the avermectin-producing streptomycetes.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2011</fpage><lpage>2014</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02265-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508861</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces avermitilis</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces avermitilis</i> (a.ver.mi'ti.lis. N.L. adj. <i>avermitilis</i> avermectin producer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and an earlier study (Burg et al., 1979).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic actinomycete which forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium and aerial hyphae that differentiate into long, compact spiral chains which become more open as the culture ages.</s><s>The spore chains consist of 15 or more spherical to oval-shaped spores with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Sporulation occurs on standard media such as egg albumin, glycerol-asparagine, inorganic salts-starch and oatmeal agars.</s><s>A grey aerial spore mass is formed on oatmeal agar; the colony reverse is dark brown to tan.</s><s>Melanin pigments are produced on peptone yeast extract iron agar and brown diffusible pigments on a range of standard media.</s><s>The culture grows well at 28 and 37 °C, but does not grow at 50 °C.</s><s>In addition to the properties shown in Table 1, it metabolizes casein but not tyrosine, liquefies gelatin, and uses glucose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, but not cellulose, as sole carbon sources for energy and growth.</s><s>Avermectins, a family of 16-membered antiparasitic macromolecules, are produced.</s><s>Isolated from a soil sample collected at Kawana, Ito City, Shizuoka Prefecture, Japan.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Streptomyces avermitilis</i> MA-4680<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 31267<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 12804<sup>T</sup>=NRRL 8165<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>