<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9959_nm.14944" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14944" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14944" rank="species">Falsibacillus pallidus</organism><reference id="rid.9959"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Falsibacillus pallidus to replace the homonym
Bacillus pallidus Zhou et al. 2008</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3176</fpage><lpage>3180</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014316-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19767356</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Falsibacillus pallidus</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Falsibacillus pallidus</em> (pal.li′dus. L. masc. adj. <em>pallidus</em> pale or paleish, the light pink colour of colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This name may be linked to the illegitimate name: <em>Bacillus pallidus</em> Zhou <em>et al.</em> 2008.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular morphology, oxygen relationships, colony shape and pigmentation are as given in the genus description above.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–42 °C, with an optimum at 30–37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 6.0–8.5, with an optimum at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Growth in the absence of NaCl, but no growth in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Casein and gelatin are hydrolysed, but Tween 80, chitin, starch, DNA, pectin and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Weak catalase activity is present.</s><s>Oxidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lipase, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced in the triple-sugar iron test.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive, indole is not produced.</s><s>Utilizes aesculin, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and d-xylose, but not <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 5-ketogluconate, d-lactose, amygdalin, d-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbitose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or l-xylose (API CHB tests).</s><s>The polar lipid, fatty acid, respiratory lipoquinone and G+C content of the DNA are as given in the genus description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CW 7<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13200<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB 207188<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24451<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a forest soil in Anhui Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>