<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9944_nm.14921" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14921" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14921" rank="species">Marinobacterium maritimum</organism><reference id="rid.9944"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>D.-N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>B.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>B.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhee</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacterium maritimum sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from Arctic sediment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3030</fpage><lpage>3034</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009134-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643903</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacterium maritimum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacterium maritimum</em> (ma.ri′ti.mum. L. neut. adj. <em>maritimum</em> living near the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, slightly halophilic, oxidase- and catalase-positive, straight rods (0.5–0.6×0.8–0.9 μm), motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Favourable growth occurs aerobically, with circular colonies with regular edges forming within 3 days, approx. 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 7–37 °C (optimum, 25–28 °C), at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.5–8.0) and in 0.5–7 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 1–2 %).</s><s>Requires sodium ions for growth.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrates to nitrites and nitrogen, indole production, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, arginine dihydrolase, urease and hydrolysis of gelatin, aesculin, starch and Tween 80.</s><s>DNA is hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes propionate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, l-proline, acetate, l-alanine, malate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Utilizes d- and l-lactate weakly.</s><s>Does not utilize d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, caprate, valerate, citrate, l-histidine, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, itaconate, suberate, malonate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, l-serine, d-mannose, gluconate or adipate (API 32GN, API 20NE).</s><s>Enzyme activity tests for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase are positive; activity tests for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative (API ZYM).</s><s>Acid is produced from 5-ketogluconate and aesculin and is produced weakly from d- and l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, turanose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose and d- and l-arabitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate (API 50 CH).</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline, but resistant to kanamycin.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is detected as the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and summed feature 7 (one or more of C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, <em>ω</em>9<em>t</em> and <em>ω</em>12<em>t</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.9 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AR11<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22254<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15134<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Arctic marine sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>