<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12774_nm.22556" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22556" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22556" rank="species">Vibrio artabrorum</organism><reference id="rid.12774"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Diéguez</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaz-Hidalgo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balboa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Romalde</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio atlanticus sp. nov. and Vibrio artabrorum sp. nov., isolated from the clams Ruditapes philippinarum and Ruditapes decussatus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2406</fpage><lpage>2411</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025320-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075909</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio artabrorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio artabrorum</em> [ar.ta.bro′rum. L. gen. pl. n. <em>artabrorum</em> intended to mean that this species was isolated from ‘Portus Magnus Artabrorum’ (the largest harbour of the Artabri), the Latin name of the main gulf in the Galician coasts].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic rods (0.8–1.0×1.4–1.8 µm in size).</s><s>On MA plates after 24 h of incubation at 25 °C, non-swarming, beige, round and smooth 2–6 mm diameter colonies are observed.</s><s>Strain Cmf 6.5 produces a brownish diffusible pigment.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>All isolates form yellow colonies on TCBS agar.</s><s>Growth occurs with 3–6 % NaCl (w/v) (one isolate is able to grow in media with 0.5–8 % NaCl).</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 °C, but not at 35 °C (one exception).</s><s>Mostly susceptible to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 µg per disc).</s><s>All isolates are positive for oxidase and catalase and reduce nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive, but lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, indole, gelatinase and lipase tests are negative.</s><s>All strains produce acid from d-ribose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and potassium gluconate.</s><s>None of the strains produce acid from erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, amygdalin, salicin, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, d-fucose, l-arabitol or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The type strain, Vb 11.8<sup>T</sup>, also produced acid from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-xylose and d-rhamnose.</s><s>All isolates can use as sole carbon source d-ribose, d-fructose, trehalose, d-mannose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, gluconic acid, glucuronic acid, d-mannitol, glycerol, succinic acid, l-arginine, l-citrulline and aspartic acid, but not l-rhamnose, salicin, amygdalin, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, butyric acid, l-ornithine, amino-<em>N</em>-butyric acid, l-lysine, putrescine or 3-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>The type strain, Vb 11.8<sup>T</sup>, can also use as sole carbon source d-xylose, d-glucose, d-galactose, galacturonic acid, sodium acetate, threonine and α-ketoglutaric acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Vb 11.8<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7226<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 23865<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from clam, <em>Ruditapes philippinarum</em>, in Galicia, north-west Spain, in January 2005.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain Vb 11.8<sup>T</sup> is 44.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>