<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1185_nm.203" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.203" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.203" rank="species">Methanogenium thermophilicum</organism><reference id="rid.1185"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rivard</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a thermophilic marine methanogenic bacterium: Methanogenium thermophilicum sp.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>430</fpage><lpage>436</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-4-430</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanogenium thermophilicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanogenium thermophilicum</i> sp. nov. (ther.mo.phil'.i.cum; Gr. n. therme, heat; Gr. adj. philicum, loving; M.L. adj. thermophilicum, heat loving.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose that this new thermophilic marine methanogenic bacterium be placed in the family <i>Methanomicrobiaceae</i> in the genus <i>Methanogenium</i>.</s><s>The microbe belongs in this genus because its cells are gram-negative, irregular coccoids which occur singly or in pairs, it is sensitive to 1% sodium dodecyl sulfate, its cell walls become disassociated in older cultures, and it possesses internal membrane components.</s><s>It also resembles the members of the genus in that it has a high G+C base ratio, it utilizes only formate or hydrogen and carbon dioxide as growth substrates and for methane formation, and it has a requirement for sodium chloride.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new isolate is similar to <i>Methanogenium cariaci</i> in its optimum pH for growth and to <i>Methanogenium marisnigri</i> in its G+C base ratio and its Trypticase requirement.</s><s>It differs from <i>M. cariaci</i> and <i>M . marisnigri</i> in its optimum growth temperature (55°C) and by its lack of flagella. (Although <i>M. cariaci</i> and <i>M. marisnigri</i> possess flagella, the flagella appear to be nonfunctional.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Recent immunological fingerprint data (E.</s><s>C . dehlacario, personal communication) obtained by the indirect immunofluorescence technique show the new isolate to react only with <i>M. cariaci</i>, <i>M. marisnigri</i>, and <i>Methanomicrobium</i> mobile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, irregular cocci which occur singly or in pairs, with an average diameter of 1.0 to 1.3 μm; spores are not formed.</s><s>Electron micrographs reveal occasional internal membrane components.</s><s>Colonies in agar tubes are beige and circular with entire edges.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Either formate or hydrogen and carbon dioxide can serve as a growth substrate.</s><s>Neither growth nor methane production was detected within 2 weeks when the H electron donor was replaced by ethanol, methanol, acetate, propionate, or pyruvate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism requires Trypticase and a trace vitamin solution.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature for optimum growth is 55°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH for optimum growth is 7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The sodium ion concentration for optimum growth of 0.25 M.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 59 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sediment underlying the high temperature effluent channel of the Crystal River Nuclear Power Plant, Florida Power Company, Crystal River, Fla.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: CR-1 (= ATCC 33837 = DSM 2373).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>