<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.662_nm.8716" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8716" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8716" rank="species">Mycobacterium cosmeticum</organism><reference id="rid.662"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cooksey</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Waard</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yakrus</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivera</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chopite</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toney</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morlock</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium cosmeticum sp. nov., a novel rapidly growing species isolated from a cosmetic infection and from a nail salon</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2385</fpage><lpage>2391</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63238-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545488</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium cosmeticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium cosmeticum</em> (cos.me′ti.cum. N.L. neut. adj. <em>cosmeticum</em> referring to cosmetics).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid-fast rods (approx. 0·55×1·5 μm) that rarely form cell aggregates in liquid culture.</s><s>Motility-related structures, spores and cell branching are not present.</s><s>Colonies on Middlebrook 7H10 or LJ agar have smooth surfaces and edges, are domed and are scotochromogenic.</s><s>Colonies from a dilute inoculum on LJ agar are visible after 3 days incubation in an aerobic atmosphere at 28 or 35 °C, but no growth is observed at 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar without crystal violet but not on LJ agar containing 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tests for niacin production and 3-day arylsulfatase activity are negative, but tests for 14-day arylsulfatase activity, nitrate reduction and iron uptake are positive.</s><s>Tests for utilization of d-mannitol, d-xylose, iso-<em>myo</em>-inositol, l-arabinose, d-trehalose and citrate are positive, but that for d-sorbitol utilization is negative.</s><s>Isolates are susceptible <em>in vitro</em> to ciprofloxacin, amikacin, tobramycin, cefoxitin, clarithromycin, doxycycline, sulfamethoxazole and imipenem.</s><s>The mycolic acid HPLC pattern consists of two three-peak clusters and is most similar to patterns for <em>M. smegmatis</em>, <em>M. wolinskyi</em> and <em>M. goodii</em>.</s><s>Partial sequences of the <em>rpoB</em> (321 bp), 16S rRNA (1506 bp) and <em>hsp65</em> (441 bp) genes are different from those of all currently recognized <em>Mycobacterium</em> species.</s><s>Characteristics that distinguish this species from other RGM species include the inability to grow at 45 °C or on media containing 5 % (w/v) NaCl, the utilization of trehalose or citrate, but not sorbitol, as a sole carbon source, and a unique banding pattern after restriction of a 441 bp region of the <em>hsp65</em> gene that includes major fragments of 310 and 130 bp (when <em>Bst</em>EII is used) or of 140, 96, 80 and 40 bp (when <em>Hae</em>III is used).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, isolate LTA-388<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-878<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108170<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a granulomatous lesion of a female patient in Venezuela who was undergoing mesotherapy.</s></p></content></protolog>