<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5948_nm.8619" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8619" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8619" rank="species">Hydrocarboniphaga effusa</organism><reference id="rid.5948"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palleroni</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Port</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zylstra</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrocarboniphaga effusa gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the gamma-Proteobacteria active in alkane and aromatic hydrocarbon degradation</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1203</fpage><lpage>1207</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03016-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280292</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hydrocarboniphaga effusa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hydrocarboniphaga effusa</em> (ef.fu′sa. L. adj. <em>effusa</em> spreading, diffuse, making reference to the spreading tendency of colonies growing on minimal agar medium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>General morphology and physiological characteristics are given above under the genus description.</s><s>All strains grow on aliphatic hydrocarbons from C6 to C19, amyl alcohol, l-arginine, 2,3-butylene glycol, erythritol, ethanol, fumarate, l-glutamate, l-isoleucine, dl-lactate, l-leucine, l-malate, mannitol, l-phenylalanine, propylene glycol, pyruvate, l-rhamnose, succinate and l-valine.</s><s>Growth on butyrate, caprate, caproate and caprylate is slow and very poor.</s><s>None of the strains uses the following for growth: acetate, aconitate, adipate, l-alanine, <em>α</em>-aminobutyrate, <em>δ</em>-aminolaevulinate, amygdalin, <em>α</em>-amylamine, anthranilate, arbutin, benzoate, betaine, <em>n</em>-butanol, l-citrulline, creatine, creatinine, dipicolinate, dulcitol, ethylene glycol, d-fucose, galactose, gluconate, glucosamine, glucuronate, histamine, <em>m</em>-, <em>o</em> or <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 2-ketogluconate, 2-ketogulonate, 2-propanol, l-kynurenine, l-lysine, l-lyxose, malonate, maltose, d- or l-mandelate, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-mannoside, mucate, naphthalene, nicotinate, norleucine, norvaline, pantothenate, l-proline, quinate, saccharate, sarcosine, sebacate, l-serine, sorbose, spermine, d-, <em>meso</em>- or l-tartrate, terephthalate, l-threonine, <em>o</em>-, <em>m</em>- or <em>p</em>-toluate, turanose or xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AP103<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-332<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16095<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>