<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10086_nm.15037" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15037" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15037" rank="species">Streptococcus porci</organism><reference id="rid.10086"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Perez</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zamora</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palacios</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus porci sp. nov., isolated from swine sources</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>104</fpage><lpage>108</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011171-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648324</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus porci</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus porci</em> (por′ci. L. gen. n. <em>porci</em> of a pig).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter, occurring in pairs or short chains of three to eight cells.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small, circular and non-pigmented, 0.75–1.0 mm in diameter and <em>α</em>-haemolytic at 37 °C.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, catalase-negative and non-motile.</s><s>Cells react to streptococcal group B antisera and are able to grow at 37 °C and at pH 9.6, but do not grow at 10 or 42 °C or in the presence of 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>With the API 50CH and Rapid ID32 Strep kits (bioMérieux), cells are able to produce acid from d-lactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, salicin, maltose, melibiose, d-galactose, d-xylose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, trehalose, starch, cellobiose, arbutin, raffinose and sucrose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, gentiobiose, d-mannitol, inositol, dulcitol, melezitose, inulin, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, l-sorbose, turanose, d-lyxose, xylitol, d-fucose, l-fucose, amygdalin, sorbitol, aesculin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, cyclodextrin or tagatose.</s><s>Cells are able to produce acid from glycogen and l-arabinose using the API 50CH system.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from l-rhamnose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside (API 50CH) and pullulan (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase (API ZYM), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM and Rapid ID32 Strep), alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep) are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, lipase C14, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (API ZYM), alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (API ZYM and Rapid ID32 Strep), <em>β</em>-mannosidase or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Arginine, hippurate and urea are not hydrolysed (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Acetoin is not produced (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 2923-03<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7374<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55896<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the heart of a pig with pericarditis.</s><s>Full range of habitat is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>