<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2865_nm.4673" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4673" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4673" rank="species">Mycoplasma genitalium</organism><reference id="rid.2865"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taylor-Robinson</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma genitalium, a new species from the human urogenital tract.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>387</fpage><lpage>396</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-387</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma genitalium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma genitalium</i> (ge. ni. ta' lium. L. n. <i>genitalis</i> genitals; <i>genitalium</i> pertaining to the genitals)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and ultrastructure.</s><s>Dark-field microscopy of cultures showed small, discrete, apparently nonmotile, coccoid bodies; no details of these bodies could be resolved.</s><s>Gram staining revealed small coccoid to irregular gram-negative units.</s><s>Electron microscopy of either negatively stained (Fig. 1A) or sectioned (Fig. 1B and C) material showed that the mycoplasma cells were predominantly flask shaped, although stages of rounding, blebbing, vacuolization, and disruption were observed as cultures aged.</s><s>The dimensions of the cells were as follows: length, 0.6 to 0.7 μm; width, 0.3 to 0.4 μm at the broadest part and 0.06 to 0.08 μm at the tip.</s><s>The tip was often slightly broadened or truncate.</s><s>A characteristic feature was a prominent outer layer or nap extending distally from the tip for only approximately 40 to 60% of the cell length.</s><s>In negatively stained preparations, the nap appeared to be discrete 78-nm irregular particles or aggregates (Fig. 1A and D through F), but in sections we observed a continuous finer particulate or fibrillar layer, 8 to 12 nm thick, which extended outward from the characteristic single limiting membrane of the cell (Fig. 1B and C).</s><s>In negatively stained preparations of naturally or sonically disrupted organisms (Fig. 1D through F) or in sections (Fig. 1C) of some organisms (most were uniformly densely stained), we observed a fibrillar rodlike structure or terminal organelle which was approximately 210 to 250 nm long and from 35 to 60 nm wide.</s><s>The proximal end of this structure was surmounted by a slightly wider cap (67 to 80 nm) (Fig. 1B through F).</s><s>The ultrastructure of the mycoplasma, whether unfixed, glutaraldehyde fixed, negatively stained, or fixed and sectioned or whether from broth cultures or from infected cell cultures was the same.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural properties.</s><s>Cloned and culture-adapted strains G-37<sup>T</sup> and M-30 grown in SP-4 broth medium in glass tubes or vials produced a slightly granular turbidity and a lowering of the pH of the medium after about 4 to 5 days at 37°C.</s><s>When the broth was removed from the tube or vial, a ring of material adherent to the glass was apparent, suggesting that the cells could attach to this surface.</s><s>Inoculation of the mycoplasmas into T-25 plastic flasks containing 10 ml of SP-4 broth medium, followed by incubation at 37°C in a horizontal position, resulted in a similar change in the pH of the medium and a sheet of attached mycoplasma cells on the surface of the plastic after 5 days (Fig. 2A).</s><s>Similar but less marked growth occurred at 30°C (30).</s><s>The two mycoplasma strains also grew well, at least after adaptation to the SP-4 medium, in conventional mycoplasma broth medium containing 20% FBS.</s><s>However, attachment to plastic or glass surfaces occurred only with strain G-37<sup>T</sup> when the organisms were grown in FBS medium.</s><s>When conventional mycoplasma medium supplemented with 20% horse serum was used, strain G-37<sup>T</sup> grew only in suspension and did not attach to the surfaces of the T-25 plastic flasks.</s><s>Strain M-30 did not grow or attach to surfaces when it was cultured in the medium containing horse serum.</s><s>Because few colonies of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> or M-30 were apparent when those organisms were grown on SP-4 solid medium supplemented with 0.8% Noble agar, a more highly purified agar preparation (0.6% agarose) was used.</s><s>On this medium, both strains produced colonies, which varied in diameter from 20 to 200 μm.</s><s>Although a few colonies had a “fried-egg” appearance, most colonies appeared to grow into the agarose and exhibited little surface growth (Fig. 2B).</s><s>More successful colony development occurred on SP-4 agarose medium incubated at 37°C in the GasPak system for 14 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The inhibitory effects of different concentrations of thallium acetate are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The concentrations of thallium used in most mycoplasma media to suppress bacterial growth (1:2,000 to 1:3,000) inhibited the growth of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> in SP-4 broth medium.</s><s>A concentration of thallium acetate of 1 :4,000 was partially inhibitory, and only when a dilution of 1:5,000 was used was the growth of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> comparable to the growth in SP-4 medium without thallium.</s><s>The effects of polymyxin B on the growth of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> in SP-4 broth medium indicated that a concentration of 500 U/ml was not inhibitory (Table 2), suggesting that this compound might be a suitable replacement for thallium acetate in suppressing contamination by gram-negative bacteria in clinical specimens cultured in SP-4 broth medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reversion studies.</s><s>Cultures of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> maintained in antibiotic-free SP-4 broth medium for five to eight consecutive passages exhibited growth characteristics similar to those observed when penicillin was present.</s><s>No evidence of a change to bacterial forms was apparent when the antibiotic-free broth cultures were inoculated onto blood agar or when Gram-stained cells were examined microscopically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration studies.</s><s>A cloned broth culture of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> contained 10<sup>8</sup> CCU/ml before filtration through a series of membrane filters having graded pore diameters.</s><s>After passage through membrane filters having average pore diameters of 450, 300, 220, and 100 nm, the filtrates contained 10<sup>5</sup>, 10<sup>4</sup>, 10<sup>2</sup>, and 0 CCU/ml, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and biological properties.</s><s>The results of various biochemical tests performed on the two mycoplasma strains and other biological properties determined in this study were as follows: fermentation of glucose, positive; hydrolysis of arginine, negative; hydrolysis of urea, negative; phosphatase production, negative; tetrazolium reduction (aerobic), weak; tetrazolium reduction (anaerobic), positive; liquefaction of coagulated serum, negative; film and spot reaction, negative; susceptible to 1.5% digitonin (diameter of inhibition zone, 7 mm); hemadsorption (guinea pig or human type 0 erythrocytes), positive; sterol required for growth; culture turbidity, granular; adherent to glass and plastic surfaces; cytopathic to tissue culture cells (Vero monkey); colonies on agarose variable in size, most without a central zone; preferred atmosphere in broth, aerobic; preferred atmosphere on agar, anaerobic; preferred temperature, 37°C.</s><s>The most notable characteristics were fermentation of glucose and the strong adsorption of erythrocytes (guinea pig or human type 0) to colonies of strains G-37<sup>T</sup> and M-30.</s><s>Treatment of erythrocytes (human type 0) with purified neuraminidase completely abolished adsorption of these cells to colonies of strain G-37<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>The growth responses of strain G-37<sup>T</sup> to cholesterol and to FBS added to serum-free base medium are shown in Table 3.</s><s>No significant growth was apparent in the base medium alone or when cholesterol supplements (1 to 20 μg/ml) were added to the base medium.</s><s>However, there was increased multiplication when 15 to 20% FBS was incorproated into the base medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological studies.</s><s>Growth inhibition and epi-immunofluorescence tests with antisera or conjugates prepared to the mycoplasmas listed in Table 1 indicated that strains G-37<sup>T</sup> and M-30 were serologically unrelated to mycoplasmas described previously, including both fermentative and nonfermentative <i>Mycoplasma</i> and <i>Acholeplasma</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Deoxyribonucleic acid.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of deoxyribonucleic acid obtained from strain G-37<sup>T</sup> was 32.4 ± 1.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tissue culture studies.</s><s>Infection of Vero monkey kidney cell monolayers with the mycoplasmas resulted in the appearance of foci of vacuolization and cell lysis after 5 days at 37°C, as observed by optical microscopy.</s><s>An examination of sections by electron microscopy verified the cytopathogenic changes and showed that there were numerous mycoplasmas closely associated with both intact and disrupting cells (Fig. 3).</s><s>Adherence of the mycoplasmas to the host cell membranes appeared to be mediated only by the nap on the tip and anterior (proximal) two-thirds of the cells (Fig. 1B and C).</s><s>A similar role of the nap was observed in sections of the mycoplasmas adhering to erythrocytes (data not shown).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain G-37 is the type strain.</s><s>A cloned line of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 3353O<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>