<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6560_nm.10875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10875" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10875" rank="species">Moraxella bovoculi</organism><reference id="rid.6560"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Angelos</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spinks</surname><given-names>P.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ball</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>L.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moraxella bovoculi sp. nov., isolated from calves with infectious bovine keratoconjunctivitis.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>789</fpage><lpage>795</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64333-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392208</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Moraxella bovoculi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Moraxella bovoculi</em> (bov.oc′ul.i. L. n. <em>bos</em> -<em>ovis</em> an ox, a bull, a cow; L. n. <em>oculus</em> -<em>i</em> an eye; N.L. gen. n. <em>bovoculi</em> of the eye of a cow, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All 18 isolates grow on 5 % sheep blood agar at 25 and 35 °C under aerobic conditions; 13 of 18 isolates grow on 5 % sheep blood agar incubated at 42 °C (type strain 237<sup>T</sup> is negative).</s><s>Seven of 18 isolates grow on nutrient agar with 0 % NaCl (strain 237<sup>T</sup> is positive).</s><s>Bacteria grown on 5 % sheep blood agar form ≤1 mm diameter colonies that are white to off-white, circular and convex with an entire margin and a moist-looking surface.</s><s>Seventeen of 18 isolates have a zone of <em>β</em>-haemolysis around or under (when picked) each colony (strain 237<sup>T</sup> is <em>β</em>-haemolytic); isolate 2470-1 exhibits <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Gram-negative diplococci with occasional cocci; the cell diameters are 0.7–1.3 μm (Fig. 2) and adjacent sides appear flattened.</s><s>Growth does not occur on MacConkey agar, Salmonella–Shigella agar, Simmons' citrate agar, sodium acetate agar or nutrient agar with 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Sixteen of 18 isolates are nitrate-reduction positive (strain 237<sup>T</sup> positive) and 9 of 18 isolates show proteolysis of Löffler medium (strain 237<sup>T</sup> negative).</s><s>Fourteen of 18 isolates are positive for leucine arylamidase activity (strain 237<sup>T</sup> positive); 9 of 18 isolates are positive for DNase activity (methyl green agar; strain 237<sup>T</sup> negative).</s><s>Seventeen of 18 isolates are positive for hydrolysis of Tween 80 (96 h result; strain 237<sup>T</sup> positive).</s><s>Seventeen of 18 isolates were negative for alkaline phosphatase (strain 237<sup>T</sup> negative).</s><s>All 18 isolates have positive test reactions for the following: penicillin sensitivity, oxidase, lipase (hydrolysis of 5-bromo-3-indoxyl-caprate), catalase, phenylalanine deaminase, C4 esterase (hydrolysis of 2-naphthyl butyrate) and C8 esterase lipase (hydrolysis of 2-naphthyl caprylate).</s><s>All 18 isolates have negative reactions for motility, Litmus milk reaction, hydrogen sulfide production, indole production from tryptophan, sugar fermentation (glucose, xylose, mannitol, lactose, fructose, maltose and sucrose), aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, tests for carbon assimilation (glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, caproic acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid), arginine dihydrolase, urease, ornithine decarboxylase, proline arylamidase, <em>γ</em>-glutamyl transferase, C-14 lipase (hydrolysis of 2-naphthyl myristate), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 237<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1259<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52049<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from ocular secretions of a calf with infectious bovine keratoconjunctivitis in Brown's Valley, California, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>