<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8752_nm.13655" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13655" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13655" rank="species">Tenacibaculum aiptasiae</organism><reference id="rid.8752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tenacibaculum aiptasiae sp. nov., isolated from a sea anemone Aiptasia pulchella.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>761</fpage><lpage>766</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65437-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398166</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tenacibaculum aiptasiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tenacibaculum aiptasiae</em> (aip.ta′si.ae. N.L. n. <em>Aiptasia</em> the scientific name of a genus of sea anemone; N.L. gen. n. <em>aiptasiae</em> isolated from a sea anemone belonging to the genus <em>Aiptasia</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-flagellated, non-spore-forming, straight rods (0.4–0.6 μm in width and 2.0–7.0 μm in length) that are motile by gliding.</s><s>Degenerative spherical cells are occasionally observed in ageing cultures in broth.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are stored as reserve material.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow, circular and convex with spreading margins and approximately 10–20 mm in diameter after 5 days incubation at 25 °C on MA.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent (KOH test negative).</s><s>Carotenoid pigments are present with main absorption peaks at 480, 454 and 425 nm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 8–40 °C, in the presence of 1–10 % NaCl and at pH 7–9.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30–35 °C, with 3–4 % NaCl and at pH 8.0.</s><s>Starch, DNA, casein, aesculin, gelatin and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but chitin and Tween 20 are not.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>In the API 20NE strip, the reaction is positive for aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In the API ZYM strip, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present, but <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin and streptomycin; sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, penicillin G, rifampicin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;9 %) are summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The predominant quinone is MK-6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is a4<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17655<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24004<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sea anemone <em>Aiptasia pulchella</em> cultured in a laboratory in Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>