<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9083_nm.14263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14263" rank="species">Saccharibacillus kuerlensis</organism><reference id="rid.9083"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharibacillus kuerlensis sp. nov., isolated from a desert soil.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>953</fpage><lpage>957</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005199-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406774</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharibacillus kuerlensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharibacillus kuerlensis</em> (ku.er.len′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kuerlensis</em> pertaining to Kuerle, a city of Xinjiang Province in the north-west of China where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive-staining, aerobic, rod-shaped cells, 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 0.8–1.4 μm long, motile by a single lateral flagellum.</s><s>Spores are oval and subterminal and occur in unswollen sporangia.</s><s>After 2 days incubation on LB agar, colonies are 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter, convex, almost-circular, opaque, non-glossy and pink-pigmented.</s><s>Grows at 15–42 °C (optimum, 30–37 °C), pH 5.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–8.0) and 0–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs on nutrient agar, but not on Simmons' citrate agar, MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Tween 20 and aesculin are hydrolysed, but starch, casein, gelatin, DNA, Tween 80, tyrosine and CM-cellulose are not.</s><s>Positive for catalase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and the methyl red reaction.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, indole and hydrogen sulphide production, phenylalanine deaminase and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-lactose, trehalose, d-fructose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, maltose, raffinose, melibiose, cellobiose, melezitose, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-galactose, sucrose, turanose, d-mannitol, inositol, amygdalin, salicin and dextrin.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, l-arabitol, adonitol, acetate, inulin, gluconate and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, but not l-sorbose, xylitol, d-sorbitol, i-erythritol, glycerol, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside or tartrate.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin, but sensitive to amoxicillin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefazolin, ceftazidime, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, ofloxacin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, rifampicin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The main phospholipid is diphosphatidylglycerol and MK-7 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.5 mol%.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HR1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13182<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14865<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.6964<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a desert soil sample collected from Xinjiang Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>