<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4490_nm.1746" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1746" rank="genus">Bordetella</organism><reference id="rid.4490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>von Wintzingerode</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schattke</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siddiqui</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rösick</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Göbel</surname><given-names>U.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gross</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bordetella petrii sp. nov., isolated from an anaerobic bioreactor, and emended description of the genus Bordetella.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1257</fpage><lpage>1265</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491321</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of description of the genus Bordetella (Skerman et al. 1980)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Based on the study of phenotypic and chemotaxonomic characteristics and comparative 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis of strain Se-1111R<sup>T</sup>, the type strain of the species <i>Bordetella petrii</i>, the following emended description of the genus <i>Bordetella</i> is proposed. Gram-negative, catalase-positive, asaccharolytic coccobacilli with an DNA G+C content of 60-69 mol%. Growth occurs strictly aerobically, facultatively anaerobically and non-fermentatively. One species is able to grow anaerobically under conditions favouring respiratory nitrate and selenate reduction. Species assimilate citrate under aerobic conditions, one species assimilates D-gluconate. Additional biochemical attributes are given in Results. The major respiratory isoprenoid quinone is Q-8. Strains were isolated from humans and warm-blooded animals, one strain was isolated from the environment. Based on comparative 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis, the species forms a distinct cluster separated from members of the genera <i>Achromobacter</i> and <i>Alcaligenes</i> within the β-<i>Proteobacteria</i>. The type species of the genus is <i>Bordetella pertussis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>