<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8544_nm.13188" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13188" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13188" rank="species">Acidovorax caeni</organism><reference id="rid.8544"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heylen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidovorax caeni sp. nov., a denitrifying species with genetically diverse isolates from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65387-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acidovorax caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acidovorax caeni</em> (cae′ni. L. gen. neut. n. <em>caeni</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 48 h, colonies are round, smooth and yellow–brown.</s><s>Cells are motile, non-spore-forming rods (0.9×1.8 μm).</s><s>Gram-negative and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15–37 °C but not at 4 or 45–52 °C, at pH 5.5–10.5, but not at pH 4.5–5, and at salt concentrations of 0.5–2 % NaCl (w/v), but not at 3–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic respiration and growth are possible through denitrification.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities: hydrolysis of Tweens 40 and 80, esterase lipase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and production of indole.</s><s>Malate, glycogen, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid and glycerol can be used as carbon sources.</s><s>Can be differentiated from the type strains of its closest phylogenetic neighbours, <em>A. defluvii</em>, <em>A. delafieldii</em>, <em>A. facilis</em> and <em>A. temperans</em>, through SDS-PAGE analysis of whole-cell proteins, by the ability to produce indole and by the presence of trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R-24608<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24103<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19327<sup>T</sup>), has a DNA G+C content of 65.7 mol% and was isolated from activated sludge from an aerobic–anaerobic wastewater treatment plant (Bourgoyen-Ossemeersen) in Gent, Belgium.</s><s>Due to the genetic variation within this species, R-24607, R-24613 and R-24614 were also deposited in the BCCM/LMG collection with strain numbers LMG 24104, LMG 24105 and LMG 24106, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>