<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12687_nm.22426" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22426" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22426" rank="species">Cryobacterium arcticum</organism><reference id="rid.12687"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bajerski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ganzert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mangelsdorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cryobacterium arcticum sp. nov., a psychrotolerant bacterium from an Arctic soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1849</fpage><lpage>1853</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027128-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20817836</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cryobacterium arcticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cryobacterium arcticum</em> (arc′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>arcticum</em> northern, arctic, from the Arctic, referring to the place from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are small, round, slightly convex with entire margins and viscous in consistency.</s><s>Colour is matt light yellow and not translucent.</s><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, non-spore-forming, non-flagellated short, irregular rods, approximately 0.4–2.0 µm long and 0.2–0.4 µm wide after culture for 3 days.</s><s>Grows at between −6 and 28 °C (optimum 20 °C), at pH 5.0–9.5 (optimum pH 6.5–7.5) and with 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0 % NaCl).</s><s>Acid is produced from (+)-d-galactose, glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, (−)-d-salicin and (+)-d-xylose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, dulcitol, lactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, (+)-l-rhamnose, (−)-d-sorbitol or trehalose.</s><s>As sole carbon sources, utilizes l-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose (weakly), melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, d-xylose, glycerol, glycogen, acetate and pyruvate, but not adonitol, dulcitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, l-asparagine, glycine, formate, lactate or succinate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, casein or gelatin.</s><s>Positive for H<sub>2</sub>S production, catalase and methyl-red test, but negative for indole production from tryptophan and urease and oxidase.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>2,4-Diaminobutyrate, glycine, alanine and glutamic acid are present in the cell wall.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10 and MK-11.</s><s>The polar lipids were phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Sensitive to neomycin, streptomycin, oxytetracycline, novobiocin and rifampicin.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, ampicillin, kanamycin sulfate and erythromycin.</s><s>Inhibited by lysozyme.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SK1<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22823<sup>T</sup>  = NCCB 100316<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a soil sample from Store Koldewey, north-east Greenland.</s></p></content></protolog>