<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3007_nm.7544" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7544" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7544" rank="species">Nocardiopsis listeri</organism><reference id="rid.3007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grund</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemotaxonomy and numerical taxonomy of the genus Nocardiopsis Meyer 1976.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-5</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis listeri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on the studies carried out by the ISP (33) and on our observations of strain DSM 40297<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No pigmentation of the substrate mycelium is observed on any of the media which have been tested.</s><s>Usually no aerial mycelium is formed, unless the strain is grown on HT agar (8, 9), on which a white aerial mycelium is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin, adenine, tyrosine, and xanthine are hydrolyzed; calcium oxalate and hypoxanthine are not.</s><s>Glucose, arabinose, xylose, fructose, cellobiose, rhamnose, sucrose, and dextrin are used as carbon sources.</s><s>Melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, lactose, adonitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, and sorbitol do not support growth.</s><s>An alkaline reaction is observed with citrate, lactate, and malate, but no alkaline reaction occurs with quinate and malonate.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5% NaCl but not in the presence of 50 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Benzoic acid, salicylic acid, <i>meta</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid, and <i>para</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid are not degraded.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C, and no growth occurs at 45°C.</s><s>This species is differentiated from <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i> by its different menaquinone pattern, the absence of an alkaline reaction in the presence of malonate, and its inability to hydrolyze hypoxanthine and calcium oxalate crystals.</s><s>Tyrosine crystals are hydrolyzed by this species but not by <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i>.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis listeri</i> is strain DSM 40297 (= ATCC 27442 = ISP 5297 = CBS 661.72 = NCTC 434 = RIA 1321 = IFO 13360 = KCC S-0782).</s></p></content></protolog>