<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10783_nm.17885" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17885" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17885" rank="species">Kinneretia asaccharophila</organism><reference id="rid.10783"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomila</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pinhassi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lalucat</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kinneretia asaccharophila  gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a freshwater lake, a member of the Rubrivivax  branch of the family Comamonadaceae</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>809</fpage><lpage>814</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011478-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661516</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kinneretia asaccharophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kinneretia asaccharophila</em> (a.sac.cha.ro′phi.la. Gr. pref. <em>a</em>- not; Gr. n. <em>saccharon</em> sugar; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>asaccharophila</em> not sugar loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are small, approximately 2–3 mm in width, cream in colour, translucent, with irregular and undulate margins.</s><s>Good growth occurs in R2A medium between 20 and 37 °C; no growth at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction.</s><s>Tryptophanase, glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis, PNPG test and arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease activities are negative, but positive for gelatinase.</s><s>Negative for growth with d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, caprate, l-malate and citrate; good growth with d-gluconate and phenylacetate and extremely weak growth with adipate.</s><s>Good growth in the presence of 0.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive reactions for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4) and leucyl arylamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions for lipase (C14), trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphoamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and cystine and valine arylamidases.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated during growth: acetic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-alaninamide, l-asparagine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, i-erythritol, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glycogen, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, inosine, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, l-phenylalanine, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-proline, hydroxy-l-proline, l-serine, succinic acid monomethyl ester, l-threonine, thymidine, Tweens 40 and 80, uridine and urocanic acid.</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, adonitol, l-alanyl glycine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, dl-carnitine, cellobiose, citric acid, formic acid, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, glucuronamide, d-glucuronic acid, l-histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, l-leucine, malonic acid, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, l-ornithine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, phenylethylamine, propionic acid, d-psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, d-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinic acid, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and xylitol.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 69.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KIN192<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53117<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7319<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from fresh water of Lake Kinneret, Israel.</s></p></content></protolog>