<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2214_nm.6262" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6262" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6262" rank="species">Corynebacterium riegelii</organism><reference id="rid.2214"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium riegelii sp. nov., an unusual species isolated from female patients with urinary tract infections</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>624</fpage><lpage>627</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9508284</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium riegelii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium riegelii</i> (rie.gel'ii. N.L. gen. n. <i>riegelii</i>, of Riegel, to honor contemporary French microbiologist Philippe Riegel for his contributions to the taxonomy of the genus <i>Corynebacterium</i> as well as to the clinical microbiology of coryneform bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the characteristics given below is based on the results of studies with the four strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive, non-spore forming, and nonmotile.</s><s>They are typically club-shaped rods which appear as single cells, in pairs, or in small clusters.</s><s>Colonies are whitish, circular with entire edges, convex, glistening, of up to 1.5 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation, and of a creamy or a slightly sticky consistency.</s><s>They have weak anaerobic growth.</s><s>The organism is catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose, ribose, trehalose, D-tagatose, and 5-ketogluconate, but acid is not produced from glucose, sucrose, mannitol, xylose, glycerol, erythritol, arabinose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, galactose, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, fucose, arabitol, gluconate, or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea hydrolysis is strongly positive.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>The activities of esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, and cystine arylamidase are detected, whereas the activities of pyrazinamidase and alkaline, as well as that of acid phosphatase, are variable.</s><s>The activities of pyrrolidonylarylamidase, lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The organism is isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain, strain DMMZ 2415, has been deposited in CCUG as strain CCUG 38180, in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 44326, and in the Collection of the Institute Pasteur, Paris, France, as strain CIP 105310.</s><s>It has the features described above except that the activity of alkaline phosphatase but not that of pyrazinamidase or acid phosphatase is detected.</s></p></content></protolog>