<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6859_nm.1696" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1696" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1681" rank="species">Wautersia paucula</organism><reference id="rid.6859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Baere</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verschraegen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wautersia gen. nov., a novel genus accommodating the phylogenetic lineage including Ralstonia eutropha and related species, and proposal of Ralstonia [Pseudomonas] syzygii (Roberts et al. 1990) comb. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>327</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02754-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023939</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Wautersia paucula</em> (Vandamme <em>et al.</em> 1999) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Wautersia paucula</em> (pau′cu.la. L. fem. adj. <em>paucula</em> rare, very few, to indicate that these strains only cause human infections sporadically).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Ralstonia paucula</em> Vandamme <em>et al.</em> 1999.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data of Vandamme <em>et al.</em> (1999) and De Baere <em>et al.</em> (2001).</s><s>Gram-negative, non-sporulating and rod-shaped.</s><s>Cells are about 0·8×1·2–2·0 μm after 24 h growth on TSA at 30 °C.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Strains produce convex, circular, non-pigmented colonies with an entire edge and a smooth surface.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>No haemolysis occurs on horse blood agar.</s><s>Aerobic growth occurs at 30, 37 and 42 °C.</s><s>No acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, adonitol, d-fructose or d-xylose.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0·5 and 1·5 % NaCl, but not in the presence of cetrimide, 10 % lactose, penicillin (10 μg discs), or 3, 4·5 or 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to colistin.</s><s>Grows on Drigalski agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80.</s><s>No fluorescence occurs on King B medium.</s><s>Negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and arginine dihydrolase activities.</s><s>No amylase activity is detected.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate or nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolysis of urea, but not of gelatin or aesculin, occurs.</s><s>No <em>β</em>-galactosidase or DNase activities are detected.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>No production of hydrogen sulfide or acid occurs in triple-sugar iron agar.</s><s>No tryptophanase activity is detected.</s><s>Assimilates d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate, phenylacetate and dl-lactate, but not d-glucose, trehalose, l-arginine, dl-norleucine, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose or sucrose.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, leucine, cystine and pyrrolidonyl arylamidases and phosphoamidase are present.</s><s>However, alkaline phosphatase is variable when Rosco tablets are used.</s><s>Valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Isolated from a variety of human clinical sources including blood, wounds, sputum, urine, eye, throat and peritoneal fluid, as well as pool water, groundwater and bottled mineral water.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 65–67 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 700817<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 12507<sup>T</sup>=LMG 3244<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a human respiratory tract in the USA.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 67 mol%.</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rRNA gene sequence of strain LMG 3413 is AF085226.</s><s>The sequence of the type strain has apparently not been submitted to GenBank.</s></p></content></protolog>