<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3867_nm.8593" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8593" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8593" rank="species">Glaciecola polaris</organism><reference id="rid.3867"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glaciecola polaris sp. nov., a novel budding and prosthecate bacterium from the Arctic Ocean, and emended description of the genus Glaciecola</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1765</fpage><lpage>1771</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63123-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388742</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glaciecola polaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glaciecola polaris</em> (po.la′ris. N.L. fem. adj. <em>polaris</em> polar, referring to the origin of the strains in the Arctic Ocean).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0·4×2–3 μm) that are motile by means of a polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Buds can be produced on mother cells or on prosthecae.</s><s>Prostheca formation is peritrichous and prosthecae can be branched (Figs 2, 3 and 4).</s><s>They form non-pigmented, circular, low convex, shiny and opaque colonies that are not adherent to agar and which have entire margins and a diameter of 1–4 mm on marine agar 2216 plates after 7 days incubation at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on marine and PYG agar and there is a slight growth on nutrient agar, but there is no growth on trypticase soy agar or R2A agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5–30 °C, whereas no growth occurs at temperatures of 37 °C or above; growth is observed on R2A agar with up to 10 % (w/v) NaCl, indicating that the cells are moderately halophilic and psychrotolerant.</s><s>There is no evidence for growth under anaerobic conditions, and the catalase and cytochrome oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Tests positive for the degradation of starch, aesculin and DNA, and precipitation on egg-yolk agar occurs.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity is detected for both strains.</s><s>They are able to utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-sucrose, furanose, methylpyruvate, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-pyroglutamic acid and salicin.</s><s>Both strains are negative in tests for indole and acetoin production, in the Voges–Proskauer test and in tests for citrate utilization, hydrolysis of urate, nitrate reduction and the production of hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>No growth is observed on arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, valerate, histidine, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, itaconate, suberate, malonate, dl-lactate, 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, l-serine, alaninamide, l-threonine or glycerol.</s><s>No acids are produced from the carbohydrates glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin or arabinose and tests for the degradation of alginate, chitin, casein, gelatin and urea are negative.</s><s>There is no arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or tryptophan deaminase activity.</s><s>There is no activity for the enzymes lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>For both strains, low activity (score 1) is obtained for valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, medium activity (score 2 or 3) is observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase, and high activity (score 4 or 5) is observed for alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Cells contain fatty acids C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) as the main constituents.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 44·0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21857<sup>T</sup> (=ARK 150<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108324<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the Arctic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>