<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6844_nm.1001" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1001" rank="genus">Neorickettsia</organism><reference id="rid.6844"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dumler</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbet</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bekker</surname><given-names>C.P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dasch</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palmer</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ray</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rikihisa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rurangirwa</surname><given-names>F.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of genera in the families Rickettsiaceae and Anaplasmataceae in the order Rickettsiales: unification of some species of Ehrlichia with Anaplasma, Cowdria with Ehrlichia and Ehrlichia with Neorickettsia, descriptions of six new species combinations and designation of Ehrlichia equi and 'HGE agent' as subjective synonyms of Ehrlichia phagocytophila.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2145</fpage><lpage>2165</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Neorickettsia</i> (Philip, Hadlow and Hughes 1953)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>It is proposed that some descriptions of the genus <i>Ehrlichia</i> be united with the genus <i>Neorickettsia</i> (Pretzman et al., 1995). This requires emendation of the description of the genus <i>Neorickettsia</i> by integration with some descriptions of the genus <i>Ehrlichia</i> and new data, as follows. Small, coccoid, often pleomorphic, intracytoplasmic bacteria that occur primarily in vacuoles of monocytes in the blood and macrophages of lymphoid or other tissues of dogs, horses and humans. Certain tissues of mature fluke vectors, all other fluke stages, eggs, rediae, cercariae and metacercariae have been proven infectious by injection into susceptible vertebrate hosts, as have mature stages of aquatic insects, which confirms that the infectious cycle includes transovarial and trans-stadial transmission in the vectors (Reubel et al., 1998a; Barlough et al., 1998). Gram-negative. Non-motile. Not cultivable in cell-free media or in chicken embryos. Sensitive to tetracycline antibiotics. The G+C content of the DNA is not known. The type species is <i>Neorickettsia helminthoeca</i> (Philip et al., 1953).</s></p></content></protolog>