<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6908_nm.6000" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6000" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6000" rank="species">Demetria terragena</organism><reference id="rid.6908"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Demetria terragena gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus of actinomycetes isolated from compost soil.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1129</fpage><lpage>1133</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1129</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336919</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>D. terragena</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>D. terragena</i> (ter.ra.gen.a L. n. <i>terra</i>, soil; L. suffix <i>gena</i>, origin; M.L. n. <i>terragena</i>, coming from soil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive; not acid fast; irregular coccoid to short rod shaped (0.8 to 1.2 by 0.8 to 3.0 μm); and occur singly, in pairs, in short chains, or in small irregular clusters.</s><s>Nonmotile and nonsporulating.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, entire, smooth, 1 to 3 mm in diameter, and white to pale yellow.</s><s>Aerobic to microaerophilic.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-mannose, and D-ribose.</s><s>No acid production from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-glucitol, inulin, lactose, maltose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, potato starch, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, citrate, malate, and succinate are utilized as carbon sources; benzoate, formate and DL-tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, catalase and hydrogen sulfide are produced, and oxidase and indole are not.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Casein, potato starch, tyrosine, xanthine, and Tween 80 are decomposed; adenine, esculin, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, and urea are not.</s><s>NaCl in combination with R medium is well tolerated at concentrations of 2, 4, 6, and 8% (wt/vol).</s><s>Growth is weak at 10 and 12% NaCl, and there is no growth at 14% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (weakly susceptible [2 μg]), neomycin (30 μg), nitrofuran (300 μg), oxacillin (weakly susceptible [5 μg]), oxytetracycline (30 μg), penicillin G (2 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampin (2 μg), and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Cells are resistant to sulfonamide (301) μg).</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the A4α type, with L-Lys←L-Ser←D-Asp in the interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is complex, with saturated and monounsaturated straight-chain acids and smaller amounts of iso and anteiso branched-chain acids.</s><s>According to the API ZYM enzyme assay, HKI 0089<sup>T</sup> is positive for alkaline phosphatase, chymotrypsin, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, phosphatase acid, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, and α-glucosidase; weakly positive for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), valine arylamidase, trypsin, and α-mannosidase; and negative for cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0089, which has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures as strain DSM 11295.</s></p></content></protolog>