<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2198_nm.3068" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3068" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3068" rank="species">Aeromonas schubertii</organism><reference id="rid.2198"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arduino</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas schubertii, a new mannitol-negative species found in human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>1561</fpage><lpage>1564</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3139706</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas schubertii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas schubertii</i> (pronounced shu-bert'-ee-eye) is derived from the surname of Ralph H. W. Schubert, a German microbiologist who has contributed greatly to our knowledge of the genera <i>Aeromonas</i> and <i>Plesiomonas</i>(10-13). The species name is treated as a modern (neo) Latin genitive noun meaning "of Schubert."</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the species is designated CDC 2446-81 (ATCC 43700).</s><s>A complete description of <i>A. schubertii</i> is given to Tables 2 to 4.</s><s>The complete biochemical reactions of <i>A. schubertii</i> are given in Table 2.</s><s>The features of <i>A. schubertii</i> that differentiate it from other <i>Aeromonas</i> strains are its failure to ferment D-mannitol, sucrose, L-arabinose, or salicin, failure to produce indole, and failure to hydrolyze esculin (Table 5).</s><s>None of the strains produced gas from glucose.</s><s>The carbohydrate fermentation pattern we obtained was the same as that of <i>Vibrio damsela</i>, which is also lysine<sup>+</sup>, arginine<sup>+</sup>, and VP<sup>+</sup>. <i>V. damsela</i>, however, requires NaCl for growth (100%), is sensitive to the vibriostatic compound 0/129 (90%), and is string test positive (80%).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>A. schubertii</i> fits the description of the genus <i>Aeromonas</i> because it is fermentative, oxidase<sup>+</sup>, resistant to 0/129, and string test negative; does not require NaCl for growth; does not grow in 6% NaCl; ferments maltose; and reduces nitrate to nitrite. <i>A. schubertii</i> had an antibiogram typical of other <i>Aeromonas</i> strains: resistance to ampicillin, carbenicillin, and penicillin but susceptibility to chloramphenicol, colistin, gentamicin, and tetracycline (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Practical identification of <i>A. schubertii</i>.</s><s>When the reactions ofthe type strain of <i>A. schubertii</i> were put into our computer program for identification of enteric organisms, it was called "<i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> group-indole<sup>-</sup>, D-mannitol<sup>-</sup>, and sucrose<sup>-</sup>." Therefore, if an <i>Aeromonas</i> species is suspected, negative reactions for acid production in D-mannitol and sucrose would point to <i>A. schubertii</i>.</s><s>When the type strain, 2446-81, was compared biochemically with all other strains of <i>Vibrionaceae</i> and <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> in our computer data base, the closest matches other than the remaining <i>A. schubertii</i> strains were three <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> strains, followed by one <i>Vibrio cholerae</i> strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Clinical significance of <i>A. schubertii</i> strains. <i>A. schubertii</i> strains were isolated from abscesses, wounds, skin, pleural fluid, and blood (Table 1).</s><s>They were isolated in southern coastal states and Puerto Rico.</s><s>The three strains that were isolated from blood and pleural fluid appear to have been from patients with underlying disease.</s><s>There have been no stool isolates.</s><s>The two blood isolates suggest clinical significance, and the sources of <i>A. schubertii</i> are quite typical for extraintestinal isolates of other <i>Aeromonas</i> species.</s><s>Perhaps this paper will stimulate others to report their experience with this organism.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 2478-85.</s><s>Seven of the original eight isolates of Enteric Group 501 were highly related by DNA hybridization and phenotype.</s><s>However, strain 2478-85 was less related (70% at 60°C, 61% at 75°C, with a divergence of 5%).</s><s>This isolate was indole<sup>+</sup> and lysine decarboxylase<sup>-</sup>.</s><s>These findings suggest that this strain is close to <i>A. schubertii</i> but has diverged somewhat.</s><s>For the present we have kept it in Enteric Group 501.</s><s>No clinical information is known about this strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The taxonomy of the <i>A. hydrophila</i> group, which has been discussed in previous papers (7, 9), remains unclear.</s><s>The DNA hybridization groups first described by Popoff et al. (9) and then confirmed at the Centers for Disease Control (7) still cannot all be differentiated phenotypically.</s><s>We recently described a distinct group of ornithine+ strains, <i>A. veronii</i> (7), which can be recognized biochemically.</s><s>However, we have also found an arginine+ group of strains (DNA group) that is highly related to <i>A. veronii</i> (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The new species that we describe in this paper, <i>A. schubertii</i>, can be distinguished phenotypically and by DNA relatedness from all other <i>Aeromonas</i> DNA hybridization groups.</s><s>We hope that by describing this new species, we can eliminate at least one group from the taxonomic confusion.</s><s>The problems of the other DNA hybridization groups will be addressed in a future publication.</s></p></content></protolog>