<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12283_nm.20298" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20298" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20298" rank="species">Euzebyella saccharophila</organism><reference id="rid.12283"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lucena</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giordano</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gambacorta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Euzebyella saccharophila gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2871</fpage><lpage>2876</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020875-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20081010</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Euzebyella saccharophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Euzebyella saccharophila</em> [sac.cha.ro′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>saccharon</em> sugar; N.L. adj. <em>philus</em> <em>-a</em> <em>-um</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> <em>-ê</em> <em>-on</em>) friend, loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>saccharophila</em> sugar-loving].</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics given for the genus, the species displays the following traits: cells are approximately 0.4 μm in width and 1.4–5 μm in length.</s><s>Growth occurs on MA as regular colonies with a non-diffusible yellow–orange pigmentation.</s><s>Growth is mucous on sugar-containing media.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C, no growth at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>Good growth is obtained in media with 3.5–100 g l<sup>−1</sup> marine salts, no growth occurs at 150 g l<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Requires sodium and magnesium ions for growth.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine or ornithine decarboxylases, urease or indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and DNA (weakly), but does not hydrolyse gelatin, casein, alginate, agar, starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Does not produce acid in O/F medium (with MCS) from d-glucose, d-galactose, sucrose, l-arabinose, amygdalin or melibiose, either in aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Carbon sources that sustain abundant growth in basal medium are preferentially carbohydrates: l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, trehalose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose (weak), maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, salicin, d-gluconate and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine.</s><s>The following organic acids, amino acids and carbohydrates are not used: acetate, pyruvate, propionate, butyrate, citrate, t-aconitate, 2-oxoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, malate, lactate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, glycine, l-leucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-glutamate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-tyrosine, l-ornithine, l-citrulline, 4-aminobutyrate, l-aspartate, l-lysine, l-histidine, l-sarcosine, putrescine, d-ribose, amygdalin, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, d-glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-glycerate and d-saccharate.</s><s>The following activities with API ZYM tests are positive: alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Esterase (C4), trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are weak.</s><s>Lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>API 20NE strips give positive responses for aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose.</s><s>Gluconate and pyruvate give a weak response.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of d-mannitol, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate are negative.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are acidified in API 50 CHE tests (48 h): d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose and sucrose.</s><s>A slight acidification is noted on d-ribose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, starch and d-lyxose.</s><s>A negative response is obtained with glycerol, erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Substrates oxidized in Biolog GN microplates after 48 h incubation are: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucosamine, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-gluconic acid and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Weak responses are obtained with the following substrates: adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-rhamnose, xylitol, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, succinamic acid, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, inosine, uridine, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Negative responses are obtained with: Tween 80, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-mannitol, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenyl acetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol and glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 7SM30<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7477<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22655<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater from the western Mediterranean Sea.</s><s>The DNA G+C % content of type strain is 39.5 mol% (HPLC) or 41.2 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s></p></content></protolog>