<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9474_nm.14615" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14615" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14615" rank="species">Oceanobacillus kapialis</organism><reference id="rid.9474"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Namwong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oceanobacillus kapialis sp. nov., from fermented shrimp paste in Thailand</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2254</fpage><lpage>2259</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007161-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620352</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Oceanobacillus kapialis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Oceanobacillus kapialis</em> (ka.pi.a′lis. Korean n. <em>ka-pi</em> shrimp paste; N.L. n. <em>kapium</em> shrimp paste; L. suff. <em>-alis</em> adjectival suffix meaning pertaining to; N.L. masc. adj. <em>kapialis</em> pertaining to shrimp paste, the source of isolation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic rods, approximately 0.4–0.5×0.8–3.0 μm.</s><s>Oval endospores are formed terminally in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are low convex, smooth, circular and white to cream (0.3–2.7 mm in diameter).</s><s>Growth occurs at 8–43 °C (optimum, 37 °C), between pH 6 and 9 (optimum, pH 8.0), and in 0.5–24.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 6–14 % NaCl).</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed in the presence of 1 % (w/v) nitrate.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase activities and hydrolysis of gelatin and casein, but negative for nitrate reduction, urease, DNase, and hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween 80, tyrosine, starch, xanthine and hypoxanthine.</s><s>Produces acid from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and maltose, but not from amygdalin, cellobiose, aesculin, d-gluconic acid, glycerol, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>MK-7 is the major menaquinone.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Contains phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, an unidentified phospholipid and two unidentified glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SSK2-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13177<sup>T</sup>=PCU 300<sup>T</sup>=TISTR 1858<sup>T</sup>), isolated from fermented shrimp paste (ka-pi) produced in Thailand.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>