<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8486_nm.14699" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14699" rank="species">Flaviluna lacus</organism><reference id="rid.8486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of seven candidate species affiliated with the phylum Actinobacteria, representing planktonic freshwater bacteria</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126733</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Flaviluna lacus’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Flaviluna lacus’ [Fla.vi.lu′na. L. adj. <em>flavus</em> yellow; L. fem. n. <em>luna</em> the moon; N.L. fem. n. <em>Flaviluna</em> yellow moon, referring to the yellow pigmentation and selenoid morphology of the first strain. la′cus. L. gen. n. <em>lacus</em> of a lake]. Represented by the aerobic, yellow-pigmented strain MWH-Creno3D3, which was isolated from Lake Creno (Corsica, France). The strain is contained in a mixed culture with only a small fraction of a non-actinobacterial strain. This mixed culture grows in liquid NSY medium and on NSY agar. Plating on agar plates did not provide hints of the presence of a non-actinobacterial strain; however, FISH revealed the presence of small numbers of betaproteobacteria. Basis of assignment is the nucleic acid sequence of the 16S rRNA gene of strain MWH-Creno3D3 (GenBank accession no. AM939567) and the unique oligonucleotide sequence 5′-CCCTAGGGGCATCCCTGGGGATGGA-3′ within the 16S rRNA gene (<em>Escherichia coli</em> positions 183–195). ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Flaviluna lacus’ differs in pigmentation from the other six taxa described here.</s></p></content></protolog>