<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2250_nm.9570" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9570" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9570" rank="species">Thalassobacillus devorans</organism><reference id="rid.2250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mellado</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassobacillus devorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, phenol-degrading, Gram-positive bacterium</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1789</fpage><lpage>1795</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63560-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166667</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassobacillus devorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassobacillus devorans</em> [de.vo′rans. L. v. <em>devorare</em> to devour; L. part. adj. <em>devorans</em> devouring (organic compounds)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 2·0–4·0×1·0–1·2 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of flagella.</s><s>Colonies are uniformly round, circular, regular, convex and cream-coloured on SW-10 medium.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing in a wide range (0·5–20 %, w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimum growth at 7·5–10 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>No other salt requirements determined.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–45 °C (optimal temperature 37 °C) and at pH 6·0–10·0 (optimal pH is 7·0).</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-trehalose, d-mannose and d-fructose.</s><s>As determined by the Biolog GP panel, the following compounds are utilized: dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, 3-methyl glucose, palatinose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, pyruvic acid, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Other characteristics as for the genus.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, G-19.1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16966<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7046<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7282<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil in southern Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>