<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3841_nm.7885" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7885" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7885" rank="species">Serpulina pilosicoli</organism><reference id="rid.3841"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Trott</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duhamel</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hampson</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serpulina pilosicoli sp. nov., the agent of porcine intestinal spirochetosis</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>206</fpage><lpage>215</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-206</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573497</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serpulina pilosicoli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serpulina pilosicoli</i>(pi.lo.si'co.li.) L. adj. <i>pilosum</i>, hairy, napped, shaggy; G neu<sup>+</sup>. n. <i>colon</i>, colon; N. L. gen. n. <i>pilosicoli</i>, of a hairy colon (referring to the fact that infection and attachment by this intestinal spirochete [intestinal spirochetosis] result in a microscopic appearance that resembles a hairy covering on the surface of the colon)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Typical morphology and motility of members of the genus <i>Serpulina</i>.</s><s>Cells are 4 to 12 μm long and 0.2 to 0.3 μm in diameter.</s><s>There are 8, 10, or occasionally 12 periplasmic flagella per cell; 4 to 6 periplasmic flagella are inserted at each end of each cell, and free ends of these flagella overlap in the middle of the cell.</s><s>At least one end of each cell tapers abruptly to a distinct point.</s><s>Weakly beta-hemolytic on Trypticase soy blood agar.</s><s>Isolated from swine with diarrhea (40).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enteropathogenic when pure cultures are inoculated orally into swine (40).</s><s>Each cell attaches by one end to the colonic epithelium.</s><s>Causes watery, mucoid diarrhea (40).</s><s>Similar strains may cause diarrhea in humans (26), dogs (3), and poultry(28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows at 37 to 42°C in Trypticase soy broth or brain heart infusion broth supplemented with serum (minimum concentration, 7%) in the presence of an O<sub>2</sub>-N<sub>2</sub> (1:99) atmosphere and reaches a maximum culture density of 2 X 10<sup>9</sup> cells per ml.</s><s>Tolerates low O<sub>2</sub> tensions (&#x003C;7%) in sealed culture tubes and consumes substrate amounts of O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>NADH oxidase positive (37).</s><s>The population doubling time is 1 to 2 h in BHIS broth at 38°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The growth substrates utilized include D-glucose, D-fructose, sucrose, D-trehalose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-glucosamine, D-mannose, maltose, pyruvate, L-fucose, D-cellobiose, and D-ribose.</s><s>The substrates that do not support growth include L-arabinose, D-fucose, D-raffinose, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-xylose, galactosamine, N-acetylgalactosamine, cellulose, esculin, soluble starch, pectin, mucin, glycogen, glucuronic acid, polygalacturonic acid, glutathione, glycerol, mannitol, acetate, lactate, succinate, and amino acids.</s><s>Limited growth occurs in HS broth supplemented with the minimum concentration of serum required and no additional substrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes hippurate.</s><s>Negative for indole.</s><s>α-Glucosidase negative, α-galactosidase positive, and β-glucosidase negative.</s><s>Growing cells produce acetate (23.3 μmol/ml of medium), small amounts of butyrate and ethanol (1.5 and 2.4 μmol/ml of medium, respectively), CO<sub>2</sub> (11.3 μmol/ml of medium), and H<sub>2</sub> (22.4 μmol/ml of medium) in HS broth supplemented with 0.4% glucose in the presence of an O<sub>2</sub>-N<sub>2</sub> (1:99) atmosphere.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbadox, chloramphenicol, lincomycin, metronidazole, tetracycline, tiamulin, and tylosin.</s><s>Moderately susceptible to erythromycin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, rifampin, spiramycin, and streptomycin.</s><s>Resistant to colistin, nalidixic acid, polymixin B, spectinomycin, and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits 24 to 25% DNA homology with <i>S. hyodysenteviae</i> B7g<sup>T</sup> and 26 to 32% DNA homology with <i>S. innocens</i> B256<sup>T</sup> as determined by the S1 nuclease method.</s><s>The G+C content of strain P43/6/7g<sup>T</sup> DNA is 25 ± 1 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Exhibits 98.5% 16s rRNA sequence homology with <i>S. hyodysenteriae</i> B7g<sup>T</sup> and 99.2% 16s rRNA sequence homology with <i>S. innocens</i> B256<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Has a unique 16s rRNA signature sequence (5'-AGUUUUUUCGCUUCA-3') (29).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain P43/6/78, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51139.</s></p></content></protolog>