<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1703_nm.8631" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8631" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8631" rank="species">Jeotgalicoccus pinnipedialis</organism><reference id="rid.1703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jeotgalicoccus pinnipedialis sp. nov., from a southern elephant seal (Mirounga leonina).</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>745</fpage><lpage>748</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02833-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143018</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jeotgalicoccus pinnipedialis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jeotgalicoccus pinnipedialis</em> (pin.ni.ped.i.a′lis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>pinnipedialis</em> pertaining to pinnipeds).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are coccus-shaped, appearing in ‘bunches of grapes’, in pairs or in tetrads.</s><s>Cells are non-acid fast and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are non-haemolytic, buff or fawn, round, convex and approximately 2 mm in diameter after 24 h aerobic incubation.</s><s>Colonies have a similar appearance on nutrient agar.</s><s>Growth is not enhanced by increased concentrations of CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Grows at 25 and 42 °C, but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 2 and 6 % NaCl but not in 0 or 14 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is not produced from arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, glycogen, fructose, lactose, mannose, mannitol, maltose, melibiose, <em>α</em>-methyl d-glucoside (methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside), raffinose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed, but aesculin and hippurate are not.</s><s>Activity for acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, pyrazinaminidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase is detected.</s><s>Activity for ester lipase C8 is either weak or absent.</s><s>No activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, arginine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase C4, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase C14, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatty acids are primarily of the anteiso- and iso-methyl branched types, with anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> predominating.</s><s>Unsaturated menaquinones with 7 isoprene units (MK-7) are the predominant respiratory lipoquinones.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and an unidentified phospholipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A/G14/99/10<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 42722<sup>T</sup>=CIP107946<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 38·6 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a mouth swab taken from a southern elephant seal.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>