<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9144_nm.14337" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14337" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14337" rank="species">Streptomyces axinellae</organism><reference id="rid.9144"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pimentel-Elardo</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheuermayer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kozytska</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hentschel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces axinellae sp. nov., isolated from the Mediterranean sponge Axinella polypoides (Porifera).</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1433</fpage><lpage>1437</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007856-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502329</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces axinellae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces axinellae</em> (a.xi.nel′lae. N.L. gen. n. <em>axinellae</em> of <em>Axinella</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the marine sponge <em>Axinella polypoides</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive actinomycete that forms extensively branched non-fragmenting substrate and aerial mycelia.</s><s>Spores have a smooth surface and occur in spiral chains.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced except on ISP7 medium.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–37 °C (optimum 30 °C) and in ISP2 medium containing 0–7.5 % NaCl (optimum 0–2.5 %) or 0–100 % ASW.</s><s>Utilizes a variety of organic compounds as carbon sources including <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, d-arabitol, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, l-malic acid, d-mannitol, d-mannose, propionic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-serine, Tweens 40 and 80 and d-xylose, but not acetic acid, adenosine, AMP, d-alanine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, l-asparagine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>- or <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, 2′-deoxyadenosine, d-fructose 6-phosphate, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, glycogen, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, l-lactic acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, lactulose, d-malic acid, maltose, maltotriose, mannan, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, pyruvic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, raffinose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, l-serine, d-sorbitol, stachyose, succinamic acid, succinic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, sucrose, d-tagatose, thymidine, TMP, trehalose, turanose, uridine, UMP or xylitol.</s><s>Positive for gelatin liquefaction, but negative for melanin production, starch hydrolysis, nitrate reduction and hydrogen sulfide production.</s><s>Able to degrade casein, but not adenine, chitin or hypoxanthine.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-A<sub>2</sub>pm.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain glucose, ribose and traces of mannose.</s><s>Major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Phospholipid pattern consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, some unidentified phospholipids, phosphoglycolipids, glycolipids and an aminolipid.</s><s>Fatty acid pattern consists of iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Pol001<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41948<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109838<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the Mediterranean sponge <em>Axinella polypoides</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>