<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7426_nm.1133" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1133" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1133" rank="species">Roseivivax halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.7426"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muroga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahama</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseivivax halodurans gen. nov., sp. nov. and Roseivivax halotolerans sp. nov., aerobic bacteriochlorophyll-containing bacteria isolated from a saline lake.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>629</fpage><lpage>634</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-629</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Roseivivax halotolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Roseivivax halotolerans</i> (ha.lo.to'le.rans. Gr. n. <i>hals</i> salt; L. pres. part. <i>tolerans</i> tolerating; M. L. part. adj. <i>halotolerans</i> salt-tolerating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, slightly convex, entire, glistening, opaque and pink.</s><s>Cells are 0.5-1.0 x 1.0-5.0 μm.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at pH 7.5-8.0 and at 27-30°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.5-20.0% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Cells have urease, but do not have nitrate reductase or phosphatase.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>ONPG reaction is positive.</s><s>Cells produce indole, but do not generate H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin is positive, but hydrolysis of alginate, starch and Tween 80 is negative.</s><s>Cells utilize D-glucose, acetate, butyrate, citrate, DL-lactate, DL-malate, pyruvate, succinate, L-aspartate and L-glutamate, but do not utilize fumarate, glycolate, ethanol or methanol.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-fructose, D-glucose and D-xylose, but are not produced from L-arabinose, D-galactose, lactose, maltose, D-ribose or sucrose.</s><s>Cells are resistant to penicillin and tetracycline, but are sensitive to chloramphenicol and streptomycin.</s><s>The absorption spectrum of the membrane fraction in the near-IR region has maxima at 805 and 871 nm (Nishimura et al., 1994).</s><s>The source of the strain is the epiphytes on the stromatolites of the saline lake.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59.7 mol% (Nishimura et al., 1994).</s><s>The type strain is strain OCh 210<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10271<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>