<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.240_nm.8071" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8071" rank="genus">Flavobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.240"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bernardet</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berthe</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cutting a Gordian knot: emended classification and description of the genus Flavobacterium, emended description of the family Flavobacteriaceae, and proposal of Flavobacterium hydatis nom. nov.  (Basonym, Cytophaga aquatilis Strohl and Tait 1978).</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>128</fpage><lpage>148</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-128</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Flavobacterium</i> Bergey, Harrison, Breed, Hammer, and Huntoon 1923</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are rods with parallel or slightly irregular sides and rounded or slightly tapered ends and usually are 2 to 5 μm long and 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide. Under certain growth conditions, some species may also produce shorter (1-μm) or longer (10- to 40-μm) filamentous cells. The longer rods are flexible. Motile by gliding (this characteristic has not been observed in <i>Flavobacterium branchiophilum</i>). Flagella are absent. Gram negative. Resting stages are not known. Intracellular granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are absent. Colonies are circular, convex or low convex, and shiny with entire or wavy edges (sometimes sunken into the agar) on solid media containing high nutrient contents. On solid media containing low levels of nutrients most species also produce flat or very thin, spreading, sometimes very adherent swarms with uneven, rhizoid, or filamentous margins. Colonies are typically yellow (they vary from cream to bright orange) because of nondiffusible carotenoid or flexirubin types of pigments or both, but nonpigmented strains do occur. Most species do not grow on seawater-containing media; an exception to this is Flavobacteriumfievense. Most species are able to grow on nutrient agar and on Trypticase soy agar. Chemoorganotrophic. Aerobic with a respiratory type of metabolism. When certain growth factors are provided, <i>Flavobacterium hydatis</i> and <i>Flavobacterium succinicans</i> also grow anaerobically (4, 14, 68, 82). Peptones are used as nitrogen sources, and NH<sub>3</sub> is released from peptones; growth occurs on peptone alone. Acid is produced from carbohydrates by all species except <i>Flavobacterium columnare</i> and <i>lavobacterium psychrophilum</i>. All species except <i>Flavobacterium flevense</i> decompose gelatin and casein, and several species also hydrolyze various polysaccharides, including starch, chitin, pectin, and carboxymethyl cellulose. <i>Flavobacterium flevense</i> and <i>Flavobacterium saccharophilum</i> are also agarolytic. Cellulose is never decomposed. Tributyrin and Tween compounds are decomposed. Indole is not produced. Catalase is produced. Cytochrome oxidase is produced by all species except <i>Flavobacterium saccharophilum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Menaquinone 6 is the only respiratory quinone.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 15:0, 15:O iso, 15:l is0 G, 15:0 iso 3OH, summed feature 4 (15:O iso 2OH, 161 ω7c, or 16:1 ω7t or any combination of these fatty acids), 16:0 iso 3OH, 17:1 iso ω9c, and 17:O iso 3OH.</s><s>Sphingophospholipids are absent.</s><s>Homospermidine is the major polyamine in all 10 <i>Flavobacterium</i> species; all species except <i>Flavobacterium branchiophilum</i> and <i>Flavobacterium saccharophilum</i> also contain putrescine as a minor component (33, 34).</s><s>Spermidine and spermine are also minor components in <i>Flavobacterium branchiophilum</i>, while <i>Flavobacterium johnsoniae</i> is the only member of the genus that contains minor amounts of agmatine and 2-hydroxyputrescine (34).</s><s>The optimum temperature range for most species is 20 to 30°C; the optimum temperature range for <i>Flavobacterium psychrophilum</i> is 15 to 18°C.</s><s>These organisms are widely distributed in soil and freshwater habitats, where they decompose organic matter.</s><s>Several species are pathogenic for freshwater fish (<i>Flavobacterium branchiophilum</i>, <i>Flavobacterium columnare</i>, <i>Flavobacterium psychrophilum</i>) or occasionally are isolated from diseased freshwater fish (<i>Flavobacterium hydatis</i>, <i>Flavobacterium johnsoniae</i>, <i>Flavobacterium succinicans</i>).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs are 32 to 37 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Flavobacterium aquatile</i> (Frankland and Frankland 1889) Bergey, Harrison, Breed, Hammer, and Huntoon 1923.</s></p></content></protolog>