<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2470_nm.11387" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11387" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11387" rank="species">Nocardioides panacihumi</organism><reference id="rid.2470"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides panacihumi sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2143</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64806-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766888</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides panacihumi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides panacihumi</em> (pa.na.ci.hu′mi. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> scientific name of ginseng; N.L. gen. n. <em>panacis</em> of ginseng; L. n. <em>humus</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panacihumi</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic and non-motile, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 0.7–1.2 μm long after 3 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Cells show rod-to-coccus morphogenesis from the early exponential phase to the stationary phase.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar (Difco) for 3 days are smooth, circular, convex, opaque and white.</s><s>Neither substrate mycelium nor aerial mycelium is formed.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 °C and at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15–30 °C, pH 5.0–8.0 and in 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced weakly under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur.</s><s>DNA and casein are degraded but xylan, cellulose, starch and chitin are not.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>In addition to the properties listed in Table 1, acetate, l-alanine, gluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, maltose, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, l-rhamnose, salicin and valerate are utilized as sole carbon sources. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamine, adipate, l-arabinose, caprate, citrate, l-fucose, l-histidine, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, l-lactate, malate, malonate, mannitol, d-melibiose, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol and suberate are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>In API 50 CH tests, acid is produced from amygdalin, l-arabinose, aesculin ferric citrate, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-lyxose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose and d-turanose, but acid is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, dl-arabitol, arbutin, adonitol, starch, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, dl-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, methyl <em>α</em>-glucopyranoside, gluconate, inositol, inulin, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, trehalose, xylitol, l-xylose or methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, the type strain is positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, esterase lipase (C8) and <em>α</em>-fucosidase and negative for <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>According to the API 20NE gallery, the type strain is positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase but negative for arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, tryptophan degradation and glucose fermentation.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan is ll-2,6-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acid (&#x003E;45 % of total fatty acids) is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 73 mol%.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 616<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19187<sup>T</sup> =DSM 18660<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field of Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>