<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6579_nm.6022" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6022" rank="genus">Terrabacter</organism><reference id="rid.6579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pimelobacter tumescens to Terrabacter gen. nov. as Terrabacter tumescens comb. nov. and of Pimelobacter jensenii to Nocardioides as Nocardioides jensenii comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Terrabacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Terrabacter</i> (Ter.ra.bac'ter. L. n. <i>terra</i>, earth; M . L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, masc. equivalent of Gr. neut. n. <i>bacterum</i>, a rod; <i>Terrabacter</i>, earth [soil] rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from references 3, 8, 10, and 17.</s><s>A rod-coccus growth cycle occurs during growth in complex media.</s><s>Irregular rods are observed in exponential-phase cultures; stationary-phase cultures are composed of mainly coccoid cells.</s><s>Both rods and coccoid forms are gram positive.</s><s>Cells are non-acid fast and do not form endospores.</s><s>Rods are nonmotile or occasionally motile.</s><s>Growth at 10 and 35°C.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth, ca. 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Does not survive heating at 63°C for 30 min.</s><s>Growth in 5% NaCl.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose and other sugars in peptone-based media.</s><s>Cellulose is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains LL-2,6-diaminopimelaici d (variation A3γ) as the diamino acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatty acids are primarily of the iso-methyl branched types; straight-chain saturated, anteiso-methyl branched, and monounsaturated iso-methyl branched acids are also present.</s><s>The polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and some unknown amino-containing phosphoglycolipids.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinones are tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with eight isoprene units [MK-8 (II,III-H<sub>4</sub>].</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 69.8 to 73.4 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Phylogenetically, <i>Terrabacter</i> belongs to the actinomycetes subdivision, forming together with <i>Nocardioides</i> a separate line of descent.</s><s>The type species is <i>Terrabacter tumescens</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>