<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7181_nm.5910" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5910" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5910" rank="species">Bogoriella caseilytica</organism><reference id="rid.7181"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bogoriella caseilytica gen. nov., sp. nov., a new alkaliphilic actinomycete from a soda lake in Africa</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>788</fpage><lpage>794</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-788</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226911</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bogoriella caseilytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bogoriella caseilytica</i> (ca. sei.ly'ti.ca. L. n. <i>caseus</i>, cheese; Gr. v. <i>lyein</i>, to loosen, dissolve; M. L. fem. adj. <i>caseilytica</i>, loosening or dissolving casein)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular and rod shaped or coccoid and occur singly, in pairs, or in small clusters.</s><s>The cells are 0.5 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 2.5 μm, gram positive, not acid fast, and nonmotile, and no endospores are formed.</s><s>A few cells may be filamentous and up to 10 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are round, smooth, slightly convex, glistening, and 1 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>The colony color varies from pale yellow to intense yellow.</s><s>Alkaliphilic.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at pH 9 to 10 and at 28 to 37°C.</s><s>NaCl tolerant.</s><s>Aerobic or microaerophilic.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-glucitol, glycerol, inulin, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, potato starch, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, succinate, and tartrate are not utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Starch, esculin, casein, and gelatin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urea, hippurate, adenine, hypoxanthine, xanthine, tyrosine, and Tween 80 are not decomposed or hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced; indole is not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, oxacillin, oxytetracycline, penicillin G, polymyxin B, rifampin, and streptomycin.</s><s>Cells are resistant to nitrofuran and sulfonamid.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The G+C content is 70 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain HKI 0088 (= DSM 11294).</s></p></content></protolog>