<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9499_nm.14652" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14652" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14652" rank="species">Winogradskyella rapida</organism><reference id="rid.9499"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pinhassi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hagström</surname><given-names>Å.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Winogradskyella rapida sp. nov., isolated from protein-enriched seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2180</fpage><lpage>2184</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008334-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605730</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Winogradskyella rapida</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Winogradskyella rapida</em> (ra.pi′da. L. fem. adj. <em>rapida</em> fast, referring to the capacity for rapid growth in protein-enriched seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter and 0.8–1.8 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on MA are round, 2–3 mm in diameter and light-yellow-pigmented with a shiny surface.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> ions are required for growth.</s><s>Grows with 1–8 % NaCl (optimum 2–3 %) and at 4–36 °C (optimum 23–25 °C). <em>β</em>-Galactosidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced but indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not detected.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed but agar, DNA, urea, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) and chitin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, d-fructose, glycerol and mannitol, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, l-sorbose, trehalose, dl-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol or citrate.</s><s>d-Mannose is utilized, but l-arabinose, lactose, inositol and sorbitol are not.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine, valine and cystine arylamidases, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present, but <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, doxycycline, erythromycin, lincomycin, oleandomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Resistant to benzylpenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymyxin B and streptomycin.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are antesio-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SCB36<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7392<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 56098<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a protein-enriched surface seawater sample from Scripps Pier (La Jolla, CA, USA), in the Eastern Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>