<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3593_nm.2441" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2441" rank="genus">Oceanospirillum</organism><reference id="rid.3593"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Satomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kimura</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic study of the genus Oceanospirillum based on 16S rRNA and gyrB genes: emended description of the genus Oceanospirillum, description of Pseudospirillum gen. nov., Oceanobacter gen. nov. and Terasakiella gen. nov. and transfer of Oceanospirillum jannaschii and Pseudomonas stanieri to Marinobacterium as Marinobacterium jannaschii comb. nov. and Marinobacterium stanieri comb. no.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>739</fpage><lpage>747</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01427-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054233</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Oceanospirillum</i> Hylemon et al. 1973AL</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Oceanospirillum</i> (O.ce.an.o.spi.ril'lum. Gr. n. <i>okeanos</i> the ocean; N.L. dim. neut. n. <i>spirillum</i> a small spiral from Gr. n. <i>spira</i> spiral ; N.L. <i>Oceanospirillum</i>a small spiral organism from the ocean (sea water))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rigid, helical cells with clockwise helix.</s><s>Cells 0.4-1.2 μm in diameter; length of the helix, 2.0-40 μm.</s><s>A polar membrane underlies the cytoplasmic membrane at the cell poles in all species examined so far by electron microscopy.</s><s>Intracellular poly-β-hydroxybutyrate (PHB) is formed.</s><s>All species form thin-walled coccoid bodies, which predominate in old cultures.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Motile by bipolar tufts of flagella.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, having a strictly respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Nitrate respiration does not occur; nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or beyond the nitrite stage.</s><s>Optimum temperature, 25-32 °C.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Indole-negative.</s><s>Casein, starch, hippurate and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Sea water required for growth.</s><s>Carbohydrates are neither fermented nor oxidized.</s><s>Amino acids or the salts of organic acids serve as carbon sources.</s><s>Growth factors are not usually required.</s><s>Isolated from coastal sea water, from decaying seaweed and from putrid infusions of marine mussels.</s><s>The G+­C content of the genomic DNA ranges from 45 to 50 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type species is <i>Oceanospirillum linum</i> (Williams and Rittenberg 1957) Hylemon et al. 1973<sup>AL</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>