<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12784_nm.22569" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22569" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22569" rank="species">Chitinophaga eiseniae</organism><reference id="rid.12784"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yasir</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>G.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinophaga eiseniae sp. nov., isolated from vermicompost</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2373</fpage><lpage>2378</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023028-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21057055</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinophaga eiseniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinophaga eiseniae</em> (ei.se′ni.ae. N.L. n. <em>Eisenia</em> a genus of earthworm used for vermicomposting, which is the source of isolation of the type strain; N.L. gen. n. <em>eiseniae</em> of <em>Eisenia</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile rods (0.4–0.5×1.2–1.6 µm).</s><s>Colonies are smooth, convex, circular, transparent and yellowish after 2 days of incubation at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 30 °C and growth occurs at 15–42 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–10.0, with an optimum of pH6.5–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and no growth occurs in the presence of &#x003E;2.5 % (w/v) NaCl in R2A broth.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin, penicillin and gentamicin (all at 10 µg), and 30 µg kanamycin, but susceptible to 10 µg tetracycline and rifampicin, and 30 µg vancomycin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, aesculin, gelatin, carboxymethylcellulose, tyrosine and Tween 20, but not xylan, starch, Tween 80 or urea.</s><s>Utilizes dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, methyl β-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-serine and l-threonine (Biolog GN2 micro plate), and d-glucose, l-arabinose, maltose, d-mannose and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine (API 20NE) as single carbon source.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or nitrogen gas.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM): alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase.</s><s>Negative for lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7 and the major polyamine is homospermidine.</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains phosphatidylethanolamine, unknown aminolipids and unknown lipids.</s><s>The fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω5<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and/or C<sub>18 : 2</sub>ω6,9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω5<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> I and/or C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and unknown fatty acid ECL 13.565.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YC6729<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 13774<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22224<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from VC at Masan, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>