<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1897_nm.10570" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10570" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10570" rank="species">Agromyces allii</organism><reference id="rid.1897"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces allii sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of Allium victorialis var. platyphyllum</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>588</fpage><lpage>593</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64733-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329790</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces allii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces allii</em> (al.li′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>allii</em> of <em>Allium</em>, referring to the source of isolation of the micro-organisms, the rhizosphere of <em>Allium victorialis</em> var. <em>platyphyllum</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, slightly curved, rod-shaped and 0.2–0.4×0.5–1.5 μm.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, smooth and yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 33 °C, with an optimum temperature of 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 6.5 and 7.5; growth occurs at pH 5.5, but not at 5.0.</s><s>Growth occurs at &#x003C;3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are not.</s><s>Arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-galactose, d-cellobiose, d-mannose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, sucrose, maltose and salicin are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but d-fructose, pyruvate, formate and l-glutamate are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from melibiose, but not from d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol and d-melezitose.</s><s>Acid production from d-fructose is variable (positive for type strain).</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, esterase(C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to streptomycin, chloramphenicol, cephalothin, gentamicin, tetracycline, lincomycin, oleandomycin, neomycin and carbenicillin.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-11 and MK-12.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>Cell-wall sugars are rhamnose, ribose and galactose; xylose is detected only in the type strain as the major component.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 71.1–71.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain UMS-62<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19181<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13584<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of <em>Allium victorialis</em> var. <em>platyphyllum</em>, a type of wild edible greens grown on Ulleung island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>