<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1978_nm.10833" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10833" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10833" rank="species">Luteimonas composti</organism><reference id="rid.1978"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yen</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Luteimonas composti sp. nov., a moderately thermophilic bacterium isolated from food waste</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>741</fpage><lpage>744</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64701-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392198</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Luteimonas composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Luteimonas composti</em> (com.pos′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile short rods, 0.5 μm in length and about 1.0–1.5 μm in width.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h incubation on TS agar and nutrient agar at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard media at 37 °C are yellow, circular, smooth, shiny and convex with an entire edge, 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter and non-fluorescent.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20 and 45 °C, but not at 50 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 7.0; growth occurs at pH 7 and 10, but not at pH 6.0 or 11.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0–0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No anaerobic growth on plain NA or TSA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granule accumulation is observed via microscopy.</s><s>Shows aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, gelatinase and aesculin.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the predominant quinone.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of strain CC-YY255<sup>T</sup> is detailed in Table 1.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (positive with the Biolog GN2 system): gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-melibiose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid and inosine.</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized (see Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20E and 20NE systems) are seen for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, oxidation of glucose, melibiose and arabinose, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, aesculin hydrolysis, glucose assimilation, arabinose assimilation, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose assimilation, but negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, acetoin, oxidation of mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose and amygdalin, reduction of nitrates to nitrogen, glucose fermentation, urease and assimilation of mannose, mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Positive in API ZYM enzyme reactions for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase (C4), caprylate esterase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-B-1-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for myristate lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Sensitive to gentamicin, tetracyclines, minocycline, nor/quinolones 2G and levofloxacin, but resistant to penicillin, cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, clindamycin, teicoplanin, nitrofurantonin, quinupristine-dalfo, coag-oxacillin and oxacillin.</s><s>Intermediate resistance is observed for vancomycin, rifampicin and fusidic acid.</s><s>Further physiological characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.1 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-YY255<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53595<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109311<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17598<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from compost generated from food waste.</s></p></content></protolog>