<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12736_nm.22512" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22512" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22512" rank="species">Lysobacter bugurensis</organism><reference id="rid.12736"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>G.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.-X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter korlensis sp. nov. and Lysobacter bugurensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2259</fpage><lpage>2265</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024448-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952549</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter bugurensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter bugurensis</em> (bu.gur.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>bugurensis</em> pertaining to Bugur, a county of Xinjiang Province in north-west China, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-reaction-negative, gliding and rod-shaped (0.6–0.7×1.1–1.5 µm).</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, convex and 1–2 mm in diameter with clear margins after incubation at 28 °C for 2 days on half-strength MB agar (Difco).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimum 28 °C), at pH 6–11 (optimum pH 7–8) and in the presence of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth requires the presence of 1–2 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Weakly positive for catalase; oxidase-positive.</s><s>Exhibits α-haemolysis.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin, casein and starch but not tyrosine, ONPG, PNPG, adenine, guanine, hypoxanthine, xanthine, elastin, keratin, testosterone, hippurate, CM-cellulose or chitin.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is weakly positive.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide production, acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer reaction), citrate utilization, indole production and arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease and tryptophan deaminase activities are negative (API 20 E).</s><s>Negative for assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, suberic acid, lactic acid, alanine, glycogen, melibiose, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, proline, inositol, itaconic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate and 4-hydroxybenzoic acid (API 20 NE and API ID 32GN).</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose and maltose but not from d-mannitol, glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, lactose, sucrose or trehalose.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, an unknown aminolipid and four unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH; detailed fatty acid compositions are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ZLD-29<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AB 207175<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 23077<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an arid soil sample collected from Bugur, Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>