<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3362_nm.5017" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5017" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5017" rank="species">Exiguobacterium aurantiacum</organism><reference id="rid.3362"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lund</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemotaxonomic study of an alkalophilic bacterium, Exiguobacterium aurantiacum gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>129</volume><fpage>2037</fpage><lpage>2042</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Exiguobacterium aurantiacum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Exiguobacterium aurantiacum</i> (au.ran.ti'ac.um. L. neut. n. <i>aurum</i> gold; M.L. neut. n. <i>Aurantium</i> generic name of the orange; M.L. neut. adj. <i>aurantiacum</i> orange-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on PPYG agar (Gee et al., 1980) are 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 3 d at 25°C, low convex, orange, opaque, butyrous and easily emulsified.</s><s>Colonies on heart infusion agar are normally flat and fainter orange.</s><s>Orange pigment does not diffuse into medium; pigment production does not occur anaerobically.</s><s>Cells vary in shape from short, almost coccoid forms 1.4 x 1-1 μm in the stationary phase to rods 3.2 x 1-2 μm in the exponential phase (Gee et al., 1980).</s><s>Longer, distorted rods may be formed during exponential growth at pH &#x003E; 10.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-acid fast, non-sporing.</s><s>Motile (peritrichous flagella).</s><s>Growth occurs in aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth (at pH 9.5) about 37°C; temperature range of growth is from 7 to 43°C; at 25 °C the pH range for growth is about 6.5 to 11.5, with two maxima, at pH 8.5 and pH 9-5 (Gee et al. 1980).</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative, glucose metabolized fermentatively.</s><s>Acid produced from glucose, galactose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol and sucrose but not from L-arabinose, dulcitol, lactose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol or xylose.</s><s>Acid sometimes produced from fructose and salicin.</s><s>In anaerobic conditions with glucose as substrate, lactate, acetate and formate are the major end products, the proportions depending on cultural conditions.</s><s>Starch, casein and gelatin are hydrolysed but carboxymethylcellulose, dextran, pectin, tributyrin and Tween 80 are not attacked.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol (10 μg per disc), erythromycin (10 μg), novobiocin (5 μg), oleandomycin (5 μg), penicillin G (1.0 μg) and tetracycline (10 μg) but not sulphafurazole (100 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is based on lysine (type Lysine-glycine,).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA, determined by estimation of the melting point, is 53.2 to 55.8 mol% (Gee et al., 1980; present work).</s><s>The type strain is NCIB 11798.</s></p></content></protolog>