<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.175_nm.2209" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2209" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2209" rank="species">Xanthomonas campestris</organism><reference id="rid.175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Xanthomonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>472</fpage><lpage>489</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Xanthomonas campestris</i> (Pammel 1895) Dowson 1939</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>X. campestris</i> is the same as that of the genus. Strains of this species cause disease in various crucifers (members of the Brassicaceae). This species can be subdivided into the following pathovars on the basis of isolation from certain hosts: <i>X. campestris</i> pv. aberrans, <i>X. campestris</i> pv. armoraciae, <i>X. campestris</i> pv. barbareae, <i>X. campestris</i> pv. campestris, <i>X. campestris</i> pv. incanae, <i>X. campestris</i> pv. raphani and (based on work by Palleroni et al. [37]) <i>X. campestris</i> pv. plantaginis. Strains of <i>X. campestris</i> pv. aberrans and <i>X. campestris</i> pv. raphani have been found to induce disease symptoms in cabbage and radish similar to the disease symptoms induced by <i>X. campestris</i> pv. campestris (50a), and hence the relevance of these two pathovars can be questioned.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. campestris</i> can be distinguished from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species by the presence of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates dextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, cellobiose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, lactulose, maltose, D-melibiose, D-psicose, D-trehalose, monomethylsuccinate, malonic acid, D-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, and L-glutamic acid and by a lack of metabolic activity on the carbon substrates N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, L-arabinose, α-Dlactose, D-mannitol, β-methyl-D-glucoside, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, glucuronamide, L-asparagine, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-phenylalanine, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine,</s></p><p class="description"><s>and DL-α-glycerolphosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. campestris</i> is the type species of the genus, and its G+C content is 65.8 to 66.6 mol% (68.0 to 68.3 mol% for <i>X. campestris</i> pv. incanae).</s><s>The type strain is LMG 568 (= NCPPB 528 = ICMP 13 = ATCC 33913 = DSM 3586).</s></p></content></protolog>