<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1494_nm.2520" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2520" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2520" rank="species">Halomonas subglaciescola</organism><reference id="rid.1494"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burton</surname><given-names>H.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McMeekin</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas subglaciescola, a new species of halotolerant bacteria isolated from Antarctica.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>27</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-1-27</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas subglaciescola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas subglaciescola</i> (sub. gla' ci. es. co. la. L. prefix <i>sub</i> below; L. n. <i>glacies</i> ice; L. suffix <i>cola</i> to dwell; <i>subglaciescola</i> a species which dwells below ice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and occur as single cells, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>Some strains produce long and flexuous cells up to 50 μm long.</s><s>Cell widths range from 0.5 to 1.1 μm.</s><s>Strains have peritrichous flagellation when motile.</s><s>Cells are gram negative.</s><s>Colonies are white to cream on solid media, although yellow colonies can form on media enriched with alanine and, in some cases, hydroxy-L-proline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the species are aerobic, although some strains can utilize nitrate as a terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite by most strains, and a few strains produce gas from nitrate.</s><s>The species is catalase positive, Kovac oxidase positive and cytochrome oxidase positive.</s><s>Sugars do not stimulate growth on complex media, although a number of amino acids and organic acids do so, including alanine, arginine, lysine, threonine, proline, succinate, and lactate.</s><s>Some strains possess ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, urease, beta-galactosidase, phenylalanine deaminase, and phosphatase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin, esculin, and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced.</s><s>The species is methyl red and Voges-Proskauer negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains grow on media containing 0.5 to 20.0% NaCl but not on 25.0% NaCl at 10°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25 and 0°C but not at 37°C.</s><s>Many strains grow at -5°C.</s><s>Growth occurs from pH 5 to 9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to HgCl<sub>2</sub>, and most are susceptible to polymyxin B.</s><s>All strains are resistant to streptomycin, tetracycline, neomycin, gentamicin, and kanamycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain ACAM 12, has been deposited with the Culture Collection of the Department of Microbiology, University of Queensland, St, Lucia, Queensland, Australia, as strain UQM 2926.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species has two biovars.</s><s>Biovar I contains cells which are motile, can be filamentous, and are more than 10 μm long.</s><s>Biovar II contains cells which are nonmotile and less than 10 μm long.</s><s>Strain ACAM 12<sup>T</sup> is a biovar I strain.</s><s>A representative of biovar II, strain ACAM 21, has been deposited with the Department of Microbiology, University of Queensland, as strain UQM 2927.</s><s>Strain ACAM 25 has also been deposited with the Department of Microbiology, University of Queensland, as strain UQM 2925.</s><s>As some attributes are variable within the species, the results for these tests, as determined for type strain ACAM 12 and biovar II reference strain ACAM 21, are shown in Table 4.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 60.9% &#x0026; 1.0 to 62.9% 5 0.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>