<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12312_nm.20325" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20325" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20325" rank="species">Dietzia lutea</organism><reference id="rid.12312"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Dietzia lutea sp. nov., isolated from a desert soil in Egypt</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>32</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>118</fpage><lpage>123</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2008.11.007</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dietzia lutea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dietzia lutea</em> (lu.te’a. L. fem. adj. <em>lutea</em>, orange-yellow coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, short rod- and coccoid-like (1.0–1.2 by 1.1–2.4 μm), non-motile, non-spore-forming and not acid-fast.</s><s>Cells show snapping division and V-forms.</s><s>Forms circular, smooth, opaque, convex, orange-yellow colonies on TSA plates.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Negative for the oxidase reaction, Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole, nitrate reduction, milk coagulation and peptonization, and hydrolysis of gelatin, urea, cellulose and starch.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40 and 80, as well as alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase and α-glucosidase.</s><s>N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, β-fucosidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase are present, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are absent (data from API ZYM test strips).</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-arabinose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, inositol, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, l-xylose and d-xylose, but not d-adonitol, amidon, amygdalin, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, l-fucose, d-fucose, gentiobiose, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, N-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-keto-gluconate, potassium 5-keto-gluconate, d-raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, d-turanose or xylitol (data from API 50CH test strips).</s><s>Tolerates up to 15% NaCl and grows at temperatures between 10 and 45 °C, with an optimum growth temperature of 28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, and arabinose and galactose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub> (1.03%), C<sub>15:0</sub> (3.71%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (15.42%), C<sub>16:1</sub><em>cis</em>-9 (3.86%), C<sub>17:0</sub> (22.42%), C<sub>17:1</sub><em>cis</em>-9 (12.29%), 10-methyl C<sub>17:0</sub> (2.95%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (8.09%), C<sub>18:1</sub><em>cis</em>-9 (10.24%), 10-methyl C<sub>18:0</sub> (tuberculostearic acid) (7.86%), C<sub>19:0</sub> (2.56%), C<sub>16:1</sub><em>trans</em> 9/15i2OH (6.70%) and C<sub>18:1</sub><em>trans</em> 9/t6/c11 (1.77%).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 70.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, YIM 80766<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19232<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45074<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 207008<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil collected from the eastern desert of Egypt.</s></p></content></protolog>