<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3348_nm.7094" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7094" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7094" rank="species">Streptomyces kifunensis</organism><reference id="rid.3348"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakagaito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimazu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Streptomyces atroaurantiacus sp. nov. and Streptomyces kifunensis sp. nov. and transferring Kitasatosporia cystarginea Kusukabe and Isono to the genus Streptomyces as Streptomyces cystargineus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>627</fpage><lpage>633</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces kifunensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces kifunensis</i> (kifune.nsis. M. L. adj. <i>kifune</i>, Mt. Kifune, Kyoto Prefecture, Japan, source of the soil from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data given by Iwami et al. (1), which was emended according to the results of the present study.</s><s>The color of vegetative mycelia is yellowish brown.</s><s>The color of aerial mycelia is gray.</s><s>Mature spore chains on aerial mycelia are long, straight, hooked to spiral and simply branched.</s><s>The spores are cylindrical with a smooth surface.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is produced.</s><s>Light brown soluble pigment is produced on glycerol-asparagine agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 9 to 31°C.</s><s>The concentration of NaCl at which growth occurs is less than 4%.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, starch is not hydrolyzed, and gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Milk is barely peptonized but not coagulated.</s><s>D-Glucose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, sucrose and D-mannitol are utilized, but D-fructose, L-rhamnose, raffinose and inositol are not utilized or are poorly utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains LL- and <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>pm and glycine.</s><s>Galactose is detected as a whole-cell sugar.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is type II.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) are detected.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 71.3 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 15206.</s></p></content></protolog>