<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.835_nm.12248" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12248" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.321" rank="species">Halobacterium distributus</organism><reference id="rid.835"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zvyagintseva</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tarasov</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Extreme halophilic bacteria from saline soils.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>839</fpage><lpage>844</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halobacterium distributus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Pleomorphic, motile rods 0.8-1 x 2.5-7μ, aerobes. Catalyase and oxidase tests, positive; do not hydrolyze gelatin or starch, do not form indole, coagulate milk with slight alkalinization of the medium. All strains of this group, except for strain 13, reduce nitrate to nitrite without producing gas. Hydrogen sulfide is produced by all strains except strain 32. Optimal temperature for growth is 37-45°; growth occurs in the 26-50° range. Sugar (glucose, sucrose, galactose) did not stimulate growth. Sugars were metabolized with the formation of acids. Acidification of the medium was also observed in the presence of glycerin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>These date indicate that cultures belonging to this group have similar morphological and physiological-biochemical properties.</s><s>But, as distinct from a similar species, <i>Halobacterium vallismortis</i>, these strains do not hydrolyze starch, reduce nitrate without forming gas, do not form indole, and are not facultative anaerobes.</s><s>They differ from another similar species, <i>H. saccharovorum</i>, by their extreme pleomorphism and significantly longer cells.</s><s>These differences are a basis for classifying strains 1m, 4p, 13, and 32 as a new species in the genus <i>Halobacterium</i>, designated as <i>H. distributes</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>