<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8585_nm.13576" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13576" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13576" rank="species">Rhodovulum kholense</organism><reference id="rid.8585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aparna</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>Ch.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>Ch.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum kholense sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1723</fpage><lpage>1726</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65620-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599724</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodovulum kholense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodovulum kholense</em> (kho.len′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>kholense</em> pertaining to Khola, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid, 0.5–1.0 μm wide and 1.5–1.8 μm long, motile and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photolithoautotrophy and photo-organoheterotrophy) and under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>Phototrophic cultures are yellow to brown, while aerobic cultures are pink.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells grown in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 468, 520, 590, 803 and 857 nm.</s><s>The absorption spectrum of pigments extracted with acetone has absorption maxima at 455 and 485 nm.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids of the spheroidene series are present as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>The organism is mesophilic, with growth observed at 20–35 °C (optimum at 30 °C).</s><s>Growth occurs at a pH optimum of 6.0–7.0 (range 6.0–8.0).</s><s>NaCl concentrations of 1.0–4.0 % (w/v) (range 0.05–6 %, w/v) are required for optimal growth.</s><s>Photo-organoheterotrophy with various organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Carbon sources for good growth include acetate, pyruvate and intermediates of the citric acid cycle, except citrate.</s><s>Growth also occurs on glutamate, caproate, caprylate, valerate, glucose, lactate, butyrate, gluconate, ascorbate, peptone and Casamino acids.</s><s>Citrate, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, formate, sodium potassium tartarate, benzoate, crotonate, glycolate, glycerol, propionate, methanol, thioglycolate, propanol and cysteine are not utilized for growth.</s><s>Chemolithoautotrophy [aerobically in the dark with thiosulfate (0.5 mM) as the electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> (0.1 % w/v)] and fermentative growth [anaerobically in the dark with pyruvate (0.3 %, w/v)] could not be demonstrated.</s><s>Thiosulfate, sulfate, thioglycolate, cysteine and sodium sulfide are utilized as sulfur sources under photo-organoheterotrophic conditions, but not sulfite, elemental sulfur or methionine.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, molecular nitrogen, glutamate, glutamine and aspartate are utilized as nitrogen sources, but not nitrate, nitrite or urea.</s><s>Biotin, niacin and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63 mol% G+C (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA297<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1544<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14888<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55397<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a mud sample from Bhitarkanika mangrove forest, Khola, Orissa State, India.</s></p></content></protolog>