<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12754_nm.22538" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22538" rank="genus">Rhabdothermus</organism><reference id="rid.12754"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steinsbu</surname><given-names>B.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torsvik</surname><given-names>V.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thorseth</surname><given-names>I.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daae</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pedersen</surname><given-names>R.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhabdothermus arcticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Thermaceae isolated from a hydrothermal vent chimney in the Soria Moria vent field on the Arctic Mid-Ocean Ridge</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2197</fpage><lpage>2204</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027839-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20935086</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhabdothermus</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhabdothermus</em> (Rhab.do.ther′mus. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhabdos</em> rod; Gr. adj. <em>thermos</em> hot; N.L. masc. n. <em>Rhabdothermus</em> a hot rod).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, Gram-negative rods, 0.5–0.7 µm wide and of various lengths.</s><s>They are thermophilic, neutrophilic, aerobic and adapted to the salinity of seawater.</s><s>Flagella and endospores are not present, but cells tend to turn into electron-dense spheres, especially under suboptimal growth conditions.</s><s>Growth accompanied by production of nitrite or sulfide occurs under anaerobic conditions in the presence of nitrate or elemental sulfur, respectively.</s><s>Complex organic substrates like yeast extract, Casamino acids, tryptone and peptone are the preferred substrates for growth.</s><s>MK-8 is the sole respiratory lipoquinone present.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-branched, anteiso-branched and unsaturated iso-branched.</s><s>The cell membrane contains both phospholipids and glycolipids; the major phospholipid has an <em>R</em><sub>f</sub> value corresponding to that of a major phospholipid found in members of the genera <em>Vulcanithermus</em>, <em>Oceanithermus</em>, <em>Thermus</em> and <em>Meiothermus</em>.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence analyses place <em>Rhabdothermus</em> as a separate branch in the family <em>Thermaceae</em> in the phylum ‘<em>Deinococcus–Thermus</em>’.</s><s>The type species is <em>Rhabdothermus arcticus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>