<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3895_nm.75" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.75" rank="genus">Acidianus</organism><reference id="rid.3895"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Plumb</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haddad</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidianus sulfidivorans sp. nov., an extremely acidophilic, thermophilic archaeon isolated from a solfatara on Lihir Island, Papua New Guinea, and emendation of the genus description.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1418</fpage><lpage>1423</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64846-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625168</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Acidianus</em> Segerer <em>et al.</em> 1986</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and occur singly or occasionally in pairs during exponential growth; the cells have an irregular coccoid morphology (sometimes lobed or showing sharp bends, and resembling tetrahedrons, pyramids, discs or dishes).</s><s>Cells are non-motile.</s><s>Cell width is between 0.5 and 2 μm, depending on culture conditions.</s><s>A surrounding envelope about 25 nm wide covering the cell membrane is evident in thin section.</s><s>The envelope is composed of subunits in a hexagonal array.</s><s>The cells are facultative aerobes.</s><s>Lithotrophic growth occurs aerobically by means of S<sup>0</sup> oxidation, mineral sulfide oxidation or Fe<sup>2+</sup> oxidation.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs by means of S<sup>0</sup> or ferric iron reduction with H<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The cells are autotrophic and mixotrophic and may grow organotrophically on yeast extract without S<sup>0</sup> in the presence of O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The organisms are thermoacidophiles, thriving between pH 0.35 and 6 and between 45 and 96 °C.</s><s>They grow in the presence of 0.1 % NaCl and may grow in media containing up to 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Neither muramic acid nor <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid is present, indicating the absence of murein.</s><s>Elongation factor 2 is sensitive to adenosine diphosphate ribosylation by diphtheria toxin.</s><s>Cells contain isopranyl ether lipids, which consist of GDGTs and calditols, including lipids with mid-chain cyclopentyl rings, and also caldariellaquinone.</s><s>Members of the genus are resistant to vancomycin, ampicillin and kanamycin (150 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> each).</s><s>DNA-dependent RNA polymerase shows incomplete immunological cross-reactions with antibody against DNA-dependent RNA polymerase from <em>Sulfolobus acidocaldarius</em> DSM 639<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The purified DNA has a G+C content of 31–33 mol%.</s><s>Members of the genus occur in acidic solfataras and in marine hydrothermal systems.</s><s>The type species is <em>Acidianus infernus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>