<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8967_nm.13048" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13048" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13048" rank="species">Planktothrix agardhii</organism><reference id="rid.8967"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otsuka</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahakahant</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yongmanitchai</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nopartnaraporn</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Day</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic revision of water-bloom-forming species of oscillatorioid cyanobacteria</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1577</fpage><lpage>1595</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01834-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361260</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Planktothrix agardhii</i> (Gomont) Anagnostidis &#x0026; Komárek 1988</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Trichomes are pale blue-green or yellow-green. Trichomes are solitary and float, although in the early stages of cultivation they sometimes become entangled and sink to the bottom of the culture tube; however, they never attach there. They are straight or slightly curved, usually attenuated towards the ends and not surrounded by a sheath under conditions favourable for growth. Under unfavourable conditions (e.g. nutrient depletion, heavy contamination by heterotrophic bacteria), trichomes may be surrounded by a gelatinous sheath and may attach to the walls of the culture tube. Cross-walls are slightly constricted or unconstricted and not granulated. Gas vacuoles are relatively large and scattered at the periphery of the cells. Apical cells show variable shapes: rounded, tapered, bluntly conical, occasionally capitate, with or without calyptra. Cell width is 2.3–9.8 μm, cell length is 1.3–5.1 μm and the ratio of cell length to width is about 1:3–1:1. PE is absent. Not capable of complementary chromatic adaptation. Fatty acid composition is type 2B. DNA G+C content is about 40 mol %. Growth temperature range is 10–30 °C. Salinity tolerance for growth is up to 0.78%. The type strain is strain NIES 204<sup>T</sup> (=CCAP 1460\5<sup>T</sup>) (Table 5).</s></p></content></protolog>