<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3418_nm.7550" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7550" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7550" rank="species">Nocardiopsis synnemataformans</organism><reference id="rid.3418"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gierth</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ungerechts</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lux</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seifert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bal</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Nocardiopsis synnemataformans sp. nov., elevation of Nocardiopsis alba subsp. prasina to Nocardiopsis prasina comb. nov., and designation of Nocardiopsis antarctica and Nocardiopsis alborubida as later subjective synonyms of Nocardiopsis dassonvillei.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>983</fpage><lpage>988</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-983</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336896</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis synnemataformans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis synnemataformans</i> (syn. ne. ma. ta. for'mans. Gr. adv. <i>syn</i>, together; Gr. n. <i>nema</i>, thread; Gr. n. <i>synnema</i>, threads wrapping together; L.v. <i>formare</i>, to form; L. pres. part. <i>formans</i>, forming; M. L. part. adj. <i>synnemataformans</i>, synnema forming, referring to the ability of the organism to form synnemata)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The substrate mycelium is deep pimento colored, penetrates the agar, and bears aerial mycelia; the aerial mycelium is well-developed (diameter, approximately 0.35 to 0.45 μm) with zigzag or spiral forms and is white with a slight pimento touch, which may be reflected color from the substrate mycelium.</s><s>Different spirals are wrapped together to form synnemata.</s><s>The mycelia of a synnema fragment in a later stage to form rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Catalase positive and aerobic.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not produced on either ISP medium 6 or ISP medium 7.</s><s>Adenine, esculin, elastin, gelatin, casein, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine, and urea are hydrolyzed; guanine, keratin, and testosterone are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Assimilates xylose, glucose, galactose, rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, mannitol, citrate, and gluconate, but not arabinose, lactose, raffinose, trehalose, sucrose, melezitose, adonitol, erythritol, inositol, sorbitol, acetate, benzoate, lactate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, adipate, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butandiol, 1,2-propandiol, or paraffin.</s><s>Alanine, gelatin, and proline are used as sole carbon and nitrogen sources, but acetamide and serine are not used.</s><s>Nitrate reductase, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, and phosphatase are produced.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20,30, and 37°C.</s><s>No growth takes place at 42°C.</s><s>Cell wall chemotype III(rnesodiaminopimelic acid and no characteristic sugars).</s><s>Phospholipid type PIII with significant amounts of phosphatidylcholine as the characteristic phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10 and MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>); in addition, there are substantial amounts of MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), and MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>) and trace amounts of MK-9.</s><s>The fatty acid profile includes straight-chain saturated and unsaturated fatty acids, branchedchain fatty acids  of the iso and anteiso types, and 10-methyl branched-chain fatty acids with 16, 17, and 18 carbon atoms.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 74.1 mol%.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the sputum of a 35-year-old male who had received a renal transplant.</s><s>It was isolated only once, so it is difficult to determine the risk group to which the species belongs.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis synnemataformans</i> is strain IMMIB D-1215 (=DSM 44143).</s></p></content></protolog>