<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4330_nm.2195" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2195" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2195" rank="species">Halothiobacillus kellyi</organism><reference id="rid.4330"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sievert</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heidorn</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halothiobacillus kellyi sp. nov., a mesophilic, obligately chemolithoautotrophic, sulfur-oxidizing bacterium isolated from a shallow-water hydrothermal vent in the Aegean Sea, and emended description of the genus Halothiobacillus.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1229</fpage><lpage>1237</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843067</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halothiobacillus kellyi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halothiobacillus kellyi</i> (kel'ly.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>kellyi</i> of Kelly; named after Donovan P. Kelly, a British microbiologist who has made important contributions to research on sulfur.oxidizing bacteria and their physiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile and rod-shaped (0.4-0.6x1.2-2.5 μm).</s><s>They are strictly aerobic and grow autotrophically on thiosulfate, tetrathionate, sulfur and sulfide, but not on thiocyanate.</s><s>Sulfite is oxidized to sulfate if the concentration does not exceed 3 mM.</s><s>The organism does not grow heterotrophically.</s><s>When thiosulfate is used as the primary energy source a transient formation of sulfur occurs.</s><s>During growth on reduced sulfur compounds, the pH decreases from neutrality to around 2.8.</s><s>Thiosulfate is completely oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth on thiosulfate occurs between pH 3.5 and 8.5 and at temperatures of 3.5-49 °C; optimum growth occurs at pH 6.5 and at 37-42 °C.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 0.4-0.5 mM; growth is possible between NaCl concentrations of 0 and 2 M.</s><s>Nitrate is not used as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>The mean maximum specific growth rate on thiosulfate is 0.45 h<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>On thiosulfate agar, cells produce white-yellowish, smooth, entire colonies (diameter on 1.2% agar is 1.4 mm) in which sulfur is deposited and acid is produced.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 62 mol%.</s><s>As determined by 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis, the organism belongs to the γ-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is closely related to other members of this genus.</s><s>The type strain is Milos-BIII<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from a marine shallow-water hydrothermal vent system and is deposited at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, under accession number DSM 13162.</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the nearly complete 16S rRNA gene sequence of <i>H. kellyi</i> is AF170419.</s></p></content></protolog>