<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12685_nm.22424" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22424" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22424" rank="species">Terriglobus saanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12685"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Männistö</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Starovoytov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Häggblom</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Terriglobus saanensis sp. nov., an acidobacterium isolated from tundra soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1823</fpage><lpage>1828</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026005-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21186292</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Terriglobus saanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Terriglobus saanensis</em> (sa.a.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>saanensis</em> pertaining to Mount Saana, Finland).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, aerobic rods, ~0.5–0.7×1.5–3.0 µm.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are light beige to light pink, circular, convex and smooth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–30 °C and pH 4.5–7.5, with optimum growth at 25 °C and pH 6.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, pectin, laminarin and aesculin but not gelatin, cellulose, xylan, lichenan, sodium alginate, pullulan, chitosan or chitin.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates when tested in API 50 CH and API 20 NE systems and/or as 10 mM suspensions in VL55 buffer supplemented with yeast extract (100 mg l<sup>−1</sup>): <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Does not utilize acetate, adipate, adonitol, amygdalin, arbutin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-alanine, caprate, citrate, dulcitol, erythritol, formate, d-fucose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, sodium glucuronate, sodium glutamate, glycerol, glycogen, d-glycine, inositol, inulin, l-leucine, d-lyxose, malate, mannitol, methyl d-mannoside, methyl d-glucoside, methyl xyloside, l-ornithine, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, trehalose or xylitol.</s><s>Produces acid and alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase and α-mannosidase but not esterase, lipase, trypsin, valine or cystine arylamidase.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0.</sub></s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SP1PR4<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23119<sup>T</sup>  = ATCC BAA-1853<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil samples collected from a wind-exposed ridge of Mt. Saana, Finland.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>