<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4733_nm.9133" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9133" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9133" rank="species">Koserella trabulsii</organism><reference id="rid.4733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huntley-Carter</surname><given-names>G.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Koserella trabulsii, a new genus and species of Enterobacteriaceae formerly known as Enteric Group 45.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>39</fpage><lpage>42</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3968202</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Koserella trabulsii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Koserella trabulsii</i> (pronunciation trah-bool-see'-eye = trä-bōōl-sē'ī, derived from the surname of L. R. Trabulsi, a Brazilian bacteriologist. It honors him for his contributions to enteric bacteriology, particularly his studies on the genera <i>Salmonella</i> and <i>Shigella</i> and on diarrhea-causing <i>Escherichia coli</i> in Brazil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because of the low relatedness by DNA hybridization of Enteric Group 45 to other <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and because it does not readily fit into any of the described genera, we propose <i>oserella</i> as a new genus for this group of strains.</s><s>The generic name   Thus, the new genus name, <i>Koserella</i> was coined so that an organism in the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> could again honor Stuart Koser.</s><s>The species name <i>koseri</i> in <i>Citrobacter koseri</i> also was coined to honor Stuart Koser; however, this name is a synonym (subjective, based on DNA hybridization) of <i>Citrobacter diversus</i>.</s><s>Since <i>C. koseri</i> was proposed after <i>C. diversus</i> (1970 Wvrsus 1928), <i>C. diversus</i> is the correct name for the organism.</s><s>Acetate utilization, which is particularly useful for differentiating strains of Shigella from <i>E. coli</i>, is routinely done on the acetate medium of Trabulsi and Ewing (14).</s><s>Strain 3349-72 (ATCC 35313) is designated as the type strain (holotype).</s><s>There presently is only one species in the genus, so the description for the genus and the species is the same. <i>K. trabulsii</i> is the type species for this genus.</s><s>A complete description of <i>K. trabulsii</i> is given in Tables 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6. <i>K. trabulsii</i> has the general characteristics of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (Table 2).</s><s>Biochemically, <i>K. trabulsii</i> is closest to <i>H. alvei</i>.</s><s>These two organisms can be differentiated because <i>K. trabulsii</i> is Voges-Proskauer and glycerol negative; citrate (Simmons), cellobiose, and melibiose positive; and resistant to colistin and to the <i>Hafnia</i>-specific phage of Guinée and Valkenburg; (7); it also gives a very weak, delayed catalase reaction (Table 6).</s><s>All <i>K. trabulsii</i> strains were resistant to colistin (one intermediate) and penicillin.</s><s>All were susceptible to nalidixic acid, sulfadiazine, gentamicin, kanamycin, and chloramphenicol, but there was variable susceptibility to tetracycline, cephalothin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, and streptomycin (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The sources of the strains and accompanying clinical information are given in Table 1.</s><s>Five of the strains were from arm and leg wounds, three were from respiratory sources, and one each was from stool, knee fluid, water, and an unknown source.</s><s>The clinical significance of this organism is unknown.</s><s>Further studies should focus on the isolation of <i>K. trabulsii</i> and its relationship to human disease.</s></p></content></protolog>