<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8631_nm.13632" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13632" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13632" rank="species">Streptomonospora halophila</organism><reference id="rid.8631"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomonospora halophila sp. nov., a halophilic actinomycete isolated from a hypersaline soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1556</fpage><lpage>1560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65513-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599694</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomonospora halophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomonospora halophila</em> (ha.lo.phi′la. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>halophila</em> salt-loving, referring to the ability to grow at high NaCl concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive and aerobic.</s><s>Grows well on most test media, but no diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>Aerial mycelium and substrate mycelium are well developed but not fragmented on most media.</s><s>The yellow–white aerial mycelium (white only on inorganic salts/starch agar) forms straight to flexuous spore chains at maturity; spores are oval to cylindrical (0.4–0.5×0.8–1.0 μm) and non-motile.</s><s>Single, oval to round spores (0.8–1.0 μm diameter) are borne on sporophores of substrate mycelium.</s><s>Colours of the substrate mycelium are pale yellow on Czapek's agar, nutrient agar, potato agar, modified ISP 5 medium and oatmeal agar, pale yellow–white on inorganic salts/starch agar and yellowish brown on yeast extract/malt extract medium.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration, growth pH and temperature are 10 % (w/v), pH 7.0 and 37 °C.</s><s>Ranges of NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 5–20 %, pH 6.0–9.0 and 20–45 °C.</s><s>Inositol, maltose and rhamnose can be utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Positive for milk peptonization, catalase and cellulose, but negative for oxidase, melanin production, amylase, nitrate reduction and production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid is <em>meso</em>-DAP; galactose is the main cell wall sugar.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-11(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides, phosphatidylinositol and an unidentified phospholipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 91355<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45075<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19236<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a hypersaline soil in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA of the type strain is 72.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>