<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9937_nm.14912" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14912" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14912" rank="species">Arenimonas oryziterrae</organism><reference id="rid.9937"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aslam</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenimonas oryziterrae sp. nov., isolated from a field of rice (Oryza sativa L.) managed under a no-tillage regime, and reclassification of Aspromonas composti as Arenimonas composti comb. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2967</fpage><lpage>2972</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006031-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628604</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenimonas oryziterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenimonas oryziterrae</em> (o.ry.zi.ter′rae. L. n. <em>oryza</em> rice; L. n. <em>terra</em> earth, soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>oryziterrae</em> of the rice soil or field, referring to the source of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, short rods, 0.5–0.6 μm wide by 2.3–2.6 μm long.</s><s>Occur singly, in pairs and/or in clusters.</s><s>Colonies grown on half-strength R2A at 28 °C for 3 days are 1–2 mm in diameter, yellowish to creamy-white in colour, smooth and circular in shape.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is between 5.0 and 10.0, with an optimum of pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and no growth occurs in 1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Sensitive to 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> each of rifampicin and tetracycline and resistant to 10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> each of kanamycin and streptomycin and 100 μg ampicillin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Can hydrolyse casein, gelatin, elastin and cellulose but not guanine, hippurate, adenine, aesculin (in API 20 NE), starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Can use l-aspartic acid 4-nitroanilide, Tween 40 and capric acid (in API 20 NE) as a single carbon source.</s><s>In the Biolog GN2 kit, cannot use the following as single carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid, methyl ester, succinic acid, monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, sodium malonate, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, citrate, palatinose, and l-tryptophan, while l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid and <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid are weakly positive.</s><s>In ID 32 E tests, acid is not produced from glucose, inositol, trehalose, d-arabitol, mannitol, maltose, adonitol, sorbitol, rhamnose, palatinose, malonate, galacturonate, 5-ketogluconate, phenol red, l-arabitol, cellobiose, sucrose or l-arabinose, and no enzymic activity against 5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, 5-bromo-3-indoxyl-nonanoate, 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-maltopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide and 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside.</s><s>Also, urea is not hydrolysed, indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or nitrogen gas.</s><s>In the API 20E kit, no acid production from any substrate or enzymic activity except gelatinase.</s><s>Acetoin and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced from sodium pyruvate and sodium thiosulfate, respectively.</s><s>In the API ZYM kit, enzymic activities for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C-4), esterase lipase (C-8), lipase (C-14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsinase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphohydrolase, but not for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Q-8 is the major quinone.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol are the major polar lipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YC6267<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22247<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21050<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a field of rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L.) managed under a no-tillage regime in Jinju, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>