<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.613_nm.1891" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1891" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1891" rank="species">Thiobacillus tepidarius</organism><reference id="rid.613"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Physiological characteristics of a new thermophilic obligately chemolithotrophic Thiobacillus species, Thiobacillus tepidarius.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>434</fpage><lpage>437</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-434</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiobacillus tepidarius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiobacillus tepidarius</i> (tep.i.dar'i.us. L.n. <i>tepidarium</i> a warm bath fed by natural thermal water; M.L. adj. <i>tepidarius</i> warm-bathing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, motile, rod shaped, and 0.2 to 0.4 by 0.6 to 1.0 μm, with polar flagella that are three to five times the length of the cell.</s><s>Cells contain storage polyphosphate inclusions.</s><s>This organism is obligately chemolithotrophic and autotrophic, using the oxidation of thiosulfate, trithionate, tetrathionate, hexathionate, heptathionate, sulfur, and sulfide for growth.</s><s>Thiosulfate is initially quantitatively converted to tetrathionate before growth proceeds.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed by means of ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>On agar medium containing thiosulfate, colonies are creamy white, opaque, and up to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>The temperature for optimum growth is 43 to 45°C.</s><s>The pH for optimum growth is pH 6.0 to 7.5.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but growth does not occur with either nitrate or nitrous oxide.</s><s>The DNA contains 66.6 mol% G+C.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present in the respiratory chain.</s><s>The organism was isolated from water at the Roman baths, Bath, Avon, United Kingdom.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, Federal Republic of Germany, as strain DSM 3134.</s></p></content></protolog>