<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4416_nm.1170" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1170" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1170" rank="species">Sphingomonas alaskensis</organism><reference id="rid.4416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schut</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschal</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas alaskensis sp. nov., a dominant bacterium from a marine oligotrophic environment.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>79</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211276</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas alaskensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingomonas alaskensis</i> (a.las.ken'sis. M.L. adj. <i>alaskensis</i> referring to Alaska, the source of the type strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating and motile small rods.</s><s>When cultivated on low-carbon liquid media as well as highly enriched media such as Marine agar 2216 and Luria broth, very little variation in the remarkably small cell volume has been observed.</s><s>Volumes vary from 0.05 to 0.09 μm<sup>3</sup> (the diameter ranges from 0.2 to 0.5 μm and the length from 0.5 to 3 μm).</s><s>On TSA, somewhat larger and elongated cells (diameter, 0.8 μm; length, 2.3 μm) have been observed.</s><s>Although the strains are isolated at low temperatures (4.8 °C), they all grow aerobically at 28 °C on most common bacteriological media.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature for the type strain is approximately 37 °C but growth is possible between 44 and 48 °C.</s><s>Strains grow at NaCl concentrations ranging from 0.5% (TSA) to at least 3% (isolation conditions).</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, yellow- to beige-pigmented and convex with entire margins.</s><s>No acidification of D-glucose occurs.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are present: oxidase, catalase, hydrolysis of aesculin, and β-galactosidase.</s><s>The urease activity is variable.</s><s>Gelatinase and arginine dihydrolase activities are absent.</s><s>In the API 20NE and API 50CH system, all strains assimilate D-glucose, L-malate, maltose, starch and trehalose.</s><s>Assimilation of the following carbohydrates is strain-dependent: adipate, D-cellobiose and D-galactose.</s><s>None of the strains assimilate phenylacetate, adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, arbutin, caprate, citrate, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fructose, D-fucose, L-fucose, bgentiobiose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, methyl α-D-glucoside, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, D-lyxose, mannitol, D-mannose, methyl α-D-mannoside, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, xylitol, D-xylose, L-xylose and methyL-bxyloside.</s><s>The dominant fatty acid content consists of the fatty acids 14:0 2-OH, 15:0, 15:0 2-OH, 16:0, 16:0 2-OH, 16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 17: 0, 17:1<i>ω</i>6<i>c</i>, 17:1<i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>, 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>c, 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> 11 methyl and `Summed feature 4'.</s><s>The G+­C content is 65 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from seawater from Alaska.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 18877<sup>T</sup> (=RB2256<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13593<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>All strains have been deposited in the BCCM}LMG Bacteria Collection (Laboratorium voor Microbiologie Gent, Gent, Belgium) and only the type strain has been deposited in the DSMZ Culture Collection (Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>