<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6747_nm.2622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2622" rank="species">Pseudomonas indica</organism><reference id="rid.6747"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pandey</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas indica sp. nov., a novel butane-utilizing species.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1559</fpage><lpage>1567</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361258</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas indica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas indica</i> (in'di.ca. L. fem. adj. <i>indica</i> pertaining to India, where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, motile with a single polar flagellum, non-fluorescent and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Cells are straight rods, 2-5 μm long and 1 μm wide, and can grow at between 25 and 42 °C over a pH range of 5.7-10.0 on tryptic soy agar and in NaCl concentrations up to 2.5%.</s><s>Freshly grown colonies are translucent and round with convex surfaces and smooth edges.</s><s>Gives a positive lysine decarboxylase reaction and is able to degrade tyrosine.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, sucrose, mannitol, maltose and glucose under oxidative conditions.</s><s>It cannot hydrolyse casein.</s><s>It can utilize a number of organic compounds such as betaine, pimelic acid, sodium gluconate, sodium pyruvate, 2-ketogluconate, sebacic acid, adipic acid and L-malic acid.</s><s>Nitrogenous compounds such as L-arginine, L-serine, L-valine, L-histidine and L-phenylalanine are utilized.</s><s>One of the most distinguishing properties of this strain is its ability to utilize butane and higher alkanes as well as other hydrocarbons such as p-hydroxybenzoate and protocatechuate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from oilfields in Gujarat, India.</s><s>Strain IMT37<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 3713<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14015<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain.</s><s>Strain IMT40 (=MTCC 3714) is a reference strain.</s></p></content></protolog>