<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9182_nm.14386" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14386" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14386" rank="species">Maribacter antarcticus</organism><reference id="rid.9182"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Maribacter antarcticus sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from a culture of the Antarctic green alga Pyramimonas gelidicola.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1455</fpage><lpage>1459</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006056-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502334</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maribacter antarcticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maribacter antarcticus</em> (ant.arc′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>antarcticus</em> of the Antarctic, the environment from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are psychrophilic, Gram-negative, strictly aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells are rods, approximately 0.3–0.5 μm in width and 1.5–3.0 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, dark orange in colour and about 1 mm in diameter after incubation for 10 days on MA at 10 °C.</s><s>Grows at 4–15 °C (optimum of 10 °C) and pH 7–9 (optimum of pH 8).</s><s>Growth occurs in sea salts concentrations of 2–6 % (w/v) (optimum 3–4 %), but no growth occurs in media containing only NaCl as a salt.</s><s>Cells do not contain poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Starch and Tweens 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but gelatin is not.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are positive, whereas naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase is weakly positive.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are negative.</s><s>In assays with the API 20NE system, aesculin hydrolysis is positive, whereas indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase and urease are negative.</s><s>In assays with the API 50CH system, acid is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, fructose, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, or d- and l-xylose.</s><s>l-Arabinose, citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, mannitol, d-mannose and sucrose are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The predominant quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CL-AP4<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 90069<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15445<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a culture of the Antarctic green alga <em>Pyramimonas gelidicola</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>