<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2815_nm.1904" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1904" rank="genus">Methylovorus</organism><reference id="rid.2815"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>E.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic position and emended description of the genus Methylovorus.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>903</fpage><lpage>906</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63111-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774683</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Methylovorus</em> Govorukhina and Trotsenko 1991</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylovorus</em> [Me.thy.lo.vo′rus. N.L. n. <em>methyl</em> the methyl radical; N.L. masc. adj. <em>vorus</em> (sic) consuming; N.L. masc. n. <em>Methylovorus</em> (sic) the methyl-consumer].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 0·4–0·6×1·0–1·4 μm.</s><s>Motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Do not form endospores or complex intracellular membranes, either sheath or prosthecae.</s><s>Some strains produce slime.</s><s>Multiply by binary fission.</s><s>No aggregation or pigmentation in liquid medium.</s><s>Colonies on methanol/mineral salt agar incubated for 2 days at 30 °C are circular, 1–2 mm in diameter, with entire edges, convex and translucent to opaque, creamy or milky in colour.</s><s>No growth or very poor growth on nutrient agar and in nutrient broth at 30–40 °C.</s><s>No growth under an atmosphere of CH<sub>4</sub>+O<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub>+O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No growth in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth, 7·0–7·5, and temperature, 35–40 °C.</s><s>Strictly aerobic with respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Obligate or restricted facultative methylotrophs.</s><s>Utilize methanol as the carbon and energy source.</s><s>Some strains can grow poorly on methylated amines and glucose.</s><s>Nitrates, ammonium salts, methylated amines and glutamate serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Acetoin, H<sub>2</sub>S and NH<sub>3</sub> are not produced in test medium.</s><s>Urease-, catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Peroxidase is variable.</s><s>Do not degrade cellulose, gelatin or Tween 80.</s><s>Indole is formed from l-tryptophan in mineral medium with methanol as the sole carbon and energy source and with KNO<sub>3</sub> as a nitrogen source.</s><s>Ammonium ions inhibit tryptophan deamination.</s><s>Assimilate C<sub>1</sub> compounds through the RuMP pathway (Entner–Doudoroff variant) and ammonia via the glutamate cycle (glutamate synthase and glutamine synthetase).</s><s>Neither <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase nor the glyoxylate shunt enzymes are present.</s><s>6-Phosphogluconate dehydrogenase is specific for NAD<sup>+</sup> (not NADP).</s><s>The prevailing cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q<sub>8</sub>.</s><s>The dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol (cardiolipin).</s><s>Belong to the <em>β</em>-subclass of the <em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s><s>Habitat: activated sludge, mud, soil, pond water and plants.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 56–58 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The type species is <em>Methylovorus glucosotrophus</em> Govorukhina and Trotsenko 1991.</s></p></content></protolog>