<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2591_nm.11533" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11533" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11533" rank="subspecies">Leucobacter chromiireducens solipictus</organism><reference id="rid.2591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Muir</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leucobacter chromiireducens subsp. solipictus subsp. nov., a pigmented bacterium isolated from the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans, and emended description of L. chromiireducens.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2770</fpage><lpage>2776</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64822-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048723</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leucobacter chromiireducens</em> subsp. <em>solipictus</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leucobacter chromiireducens</em> subsp. <em>solipictus</em> (so.li.pic′tus. L. masc. n. <em>sol</em> the sun; L. masc. part. adj. <em>pictus</em> painted; L. masc. part adj. <em>solipictus</em> painted by the sun).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming irregular rods that are 0.4–0.6 μm wide and 0.8–1.4 μm long when grown at 25 °C in liquid LB medium and 0.5–0.7 μm wide and 0.8–4.3 μm long when grown at 25 °C on solid LB agar for 1–2 days.</s><s>Cells produce an extracellular material.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, convex, small (0.5–1 mm in diameter), smooth, glistening, yellow-pigmented when grown in the light or cream-coloured when grown in the dark, and opaque on LB agar after 2–5 days growth at 25 °C.</s><s>The light-induced pigment is soluble in methanol and displays characteristic peaks in absorption at 413, 436 and 466 nm.</s><s>Pigment production is dependent on light quality and temperature.</s><s>Depigmentation of cells occurs in the combined presence of 0.5 mM fosmidomycin and 0.5 mM mevinolin.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, pH 5.5–9, in LB containing 0–8 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 4 or 40 °C, pH 5 or in the presence of ≥9 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs between 25 and 32 °C at pH 7.5–8.5 in aerated LB lacking salt.</s><s>After 2–5 days incubation at 25 °C, growth can be seen on solid LB agar containing each of the following individually: 1 mM arsenite, 80 μM cadmium and 5 mM hexavalent chromium; however, cells are unable to reduce hexavalent chromium to trivalent chromium.</s><s>Cells are resistant to 50 μg kanamycin ml<sup>−1</sup>, 12.5 μg tetracycline ml<sup>−1</sup>, 10 μg gentamicin ml<sup>−1</sup>, 300 μg streptomycin ml<sup>−1</sup> and 20 μg chloramphenicol ml<sup>−1</sup> and sensitive to 100 μg ampicillin ml<sup>−1</sup> and 100 μg rifampicin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Positive for catalase and alkaline phosphatase activities, but not for cytochrome <em>c</em> oxidase, nitrate reductase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease, gelatinase, amylase, cysteine desulfurase, tryptophanase, phenylalanine deaminase, haemolytic or lipase activities.</s><s>Carbon source utilization profile is given in Table 1.</s><s>No endogenous plasmids are present.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains DAB, alanine, glutamic acid, glycine and threonine.</s><s>The peptidoglycan structure is a B2<em>δ</em>-type variant.</s><s>Galactose is the only cell-wall sugar detected.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinones are MK-11 and MK-10.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and linear C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 69.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TAN 31504<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18340<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1336<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from <em>Caenorhabditis elegans</em> and appeared as a contaminant.</s><s>The location of isolation is designated Stanford, CA, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>