<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4369_nm.11031" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11031" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11031" rank="species">Simplicispira limi</organism><reference id="rid.4369"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Simplicispira limi sp. nov., isolated from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64566-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17220436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Simplicispira limi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Simplicispira limi</em> (li′mi. L. gen. n. <em>limi</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells form white, glistening, translucent, slightly sticky, raised circular colonies with lobate margins on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C (optimum at 30 °C).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.7–0.8 μm wide and 1.5–1.7 μm long (at 25 °C on R2A agar).</s><s>Motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urea, Tween 80, tyrosine and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, Tween 20, hypoxanthine, starch and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-raffinose, d-lactose, d-fructose and d-mannitol, but not from <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-arabinose, d-glucose, sorbitol, sucrose, rhamnose, amygdalin, melibiose, d-galactose, d-mannose, arbutin or salicin.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but not <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes Tweens 40 and 80, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinamic acid, l-proline and 2,3-butanediol (Biolog GN2).</s><s>Other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>Contains a large amount of phosphatidylethanolamine and a small amount of diphosphatidylglycerol as polar lipids.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is ubiquinone-8 (Q-8).</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11-methyl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 63.3 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EMB325<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12608<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17964<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge performing EBPR in a laboratory-scale SBR.</s></p></content></protolog>