<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4669_nm.12210" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12210" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1900" rank="species">Methylophilus leisingerii</organism><reference id="rid.4669"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylophilus leisingerii sp. nov., a new species of restricted facultatively methylotrophic bacteria.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>63</volume><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>536</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylophilus leisingerii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylophilus leisingerii</i> (coming from the names of Swiss microbiologist Thomas Leisinger who isolated this strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonmotile, colorless, asporogenous rods (0.4-0.6 x 1.1-1.7 μm) possessing a small polysaccharide capsule.</s><s>Colonies on methanol salt agar are circular, 1-4 mm in diameter white or pinkish in color, with even edges, smooth surface, convex, translucent.</s><s>Growth is possible at 10-37°C and pH 6.5-7.8, with optima at 30-35°C and pH 6.8-7.2.</s><s>Generation times when grown on methanol or dichloromethane are2 h, and on glucose - 10h, respectively.</s><s>No vitamins or any additional growth factors are required.</s><s>Do not change cellulose and gelatine, starch is slightly hydrolyzed.</s><s>Do not form acetoin, indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and NH<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, and urease positive.</s><s>Strict aerobes, although able to reduce nitrates into nitrites.</s><s>Produce acid (but not gases) from glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Methanol, dicholo- and dibromomethane, glucose, and galactose are used as the carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Utilizable nitrogen sources are ammonium salts and nitrates.</s><s>No growth occurs on methylated amines or in the presence of 3% NaCl.</s><s>Methanol is oxidized by PQQ-dependent methanol dehydrogenase.</s><s>Dicholormethane is dechlorinated by the inducible dehalogenase.</s><s>Formaldehyde is assimilated via the RuMP pathway (KDPG-varient).</s><s>Glucose is phosphorylated by ATP-dependent glucokinase.</s><s>The tricarboxylic acid cycle is impaired in α-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase cycle, whereas glutmate dehydrogenase is absent.</s><s>Palmitic (C<sub>16:0</sub>) and palmitoleic (C<sub>16:1</sub>) acids are prevailing in cellular fatty acid composition, the elongation coefficient (A<sub>16:0</sub>) is 0.01.</s><s>Cardiolipin is absent in cellular phospholipids.</s><s>A major ubiquinone is ubiquinone Q-8.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 50.2 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The type strain <i>M. leisingerii</i> VCM B-2013 is deposited at the Institute of Biochemistry and Physiology of Microorganisms (Russian Academy of Sciences).</s></p></content></protolog>