<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5786_nm.10011" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10011" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10011" rank="species">Deinococcus ficus</organism><reference id="rid.5786"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deinococcus ficus sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of Ficus religiosa L.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>787</fpage><lpage>791</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64007-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585695</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Deinococcus ficus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Deinococcus ficus</em> (fi′cus. L. n. <em>ficus</em> a fig tree and the name of a botanical genus; L. gen. n. <em>ficus</em> of <em>Ficus</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the rhizosphere of <em>Ficus religiosa</em> L.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-positive and show good growth after 48 h on nutrient agar and tryptic soy agar at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, pale pinkish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges; colonies become mucoid.</s><s>Pink pigmentation is non-diffusible, non-fluorescent and does not change upon the addition of 20 % KOH.</s><s>Unable to grow at 5 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5·5–10.</s><s>Resistant to UV irradiation (254 nm, 8–10 cm for 10 min).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, 17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> iso, 16 : 0, 17 : 0 iso and 15 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>.</s><s>MK-8 is the predominant lipoquinone.</s><s>An unknown phosphoglycolipid is the predominant polar lipid.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources (i.e. produce positive results in the Biolog system): dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine (weakly), l-arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-d-glucose, α-d-lactose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl α-d-galactoside, methyl β-d-galactoside, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, acetic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, l-alanine, alanyl l-glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine (weakly), glycerol, adenosine, 2-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, dl-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, acetoin production, gelatinase, mannitol oxidation and cytochrome oxidase activity, alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, leucine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-FR2-10<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53391<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108832<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of <em>Ficus religiosa</em> L.</s></p></content></protolog>