<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6687_nm.4909" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4909" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4909" rank="species">Bacillus galactosidilyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6687"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus galactosidilyticus sp. nov., an alkali-tolerant beta-galactosidase producer.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>617</fpage><lpage>621</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02816-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023985</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus galactosidilyticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus galactosidilyticus</em> (ga.lac.to.si.di.ly′ti.cus. N.L. neut. n. <em>galactosidum</em> galactoside; N.L. masc. adj. <em>lyticus</em> lysing, dissolving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>galactosidilyticus</em> referring to a positive ONPG test, revealing <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0·7–0·9 μm in diameter and 2–5 μm in length, motile in a tumbling motion, Gram-positive or -variable, small, plump, round-ended rods that occur singly or in pairs, and occasionally in short chains.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal endospores that lie in central, paracentral and subterminal positions within slightly swollen sporangia (Fig. 2).</s><s>After 2 days on TSA, colonies are approximately 1 mm in diameter, smooth, flat and butyrous; their edges are usually irregular with pointed projections that may spread and become rhizoid in old cultures; they are creamy or off-white in colour, with opaque centres.</s><s>Organisms are facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30 and 40 °C, but not at 50 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 6 and 10·5, but not at pH 5 or below.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is very weak.</s><s>In API 20E tests, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside reaction is positive; arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are negative; citrate is not utilized; hydrogen sulphide is not produced; urease production is variable; Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative; indole is not produced; and gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>In the API 50 CHB gallery, acid is produced without gas, often weakly, from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-fructose and d-glucose.</s><s>Acid production from the following carbohydrates is variable and, when positive, is usually very weak: amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, galactose, gentiobiose, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, d-raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, glycerol, gluconate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, glycogen, d-lyxose, methyl d-mannoside, <em>meso</em>-inositol, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose, methyl xyloside and xylitol.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids (mean percentage±sd of total fatty acids) are: C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8·32±2·51 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (12·71±1·72 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (32·60±1·94 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (27·42±3·04 %).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts (mean percentage±sd of total fatty acids): iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3·96±0·73 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (5·31±1·08 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2·45±0·44 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (4·49±0·72 %).</s><s>Trace amounts (&#x003C;1 % of total fatty acids) of the fatty acids iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> are also present.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 37·7 mol% for the type strain and 35·7–38·2 mol% for other strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photomicrograph of sporangia and vegetative cells of <em>B. galactosidilyticus</em> LMG 17892<sup>T</sup>, viewed by phase-contrast microscopy; ellipsoidal spores lie centrally, paracentrally and subterminally in slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Bar, 2 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 17892<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15595<sup>T</sup>=Logan B2188<sup>T</sup>=MB 800<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is deposited at GenBank/EMBL under accession no. AJ535638.</s><s>In the variable characters listed above, the type strain is negative for urease hydrolysis and acid is produced without gas from arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s></p></content></protolog>