<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2803_nm.5493" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5493" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5493" rank="species">Carnobacterium inhibens</organism><reference id="rid.2803"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jöborn</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsson</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Westerdahl</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kjelleberg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Carnobacterium inhibens sp. nov., isolated from the intestine of Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar).10.1099/00207713-49-4-1891</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1891</fpage><lpage>1898</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1891</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555373</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Carnobacterium inhibens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Carnobacterium inhibens</i> (in.hi'bens. M.L. adj. <i>inhibens</i> from L. v. <i>inhibeo</i> to inhibit, referring to the growth-inhibitory activity that the bacterium shows)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Carnobacterium inhibens</i> is a Gram-positive, motile (monotrichous), non-spore-forming rod which occurs singly or two, or as chains of four cells.</s><s>Many standard laboratory media support growth but not MRS or TCBS.</s><s>Colonies (TSA, 20°C) are 1-2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, and semi-translucent.</s><s>The colour of the colonies is whitish at aerobic growth conditions and buff at anaerobic growth conditions.</s><s>The temperature range that supports growth is 0-30°C and the pH range that supports growth is 5.5-9.0.</s><s>Does not produce catalase or oxidase but pseudo-catalase is produced on HBA.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Produces acid from sucrose, maltose, galactose, glucose, fructose, rnannose, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, trehalose, lactose (weak). mannitol. ribose, inulin (weak), gentibiose and methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, whereas it does not produce acid from cyclo-dextrin, glycerol, erythritol, xylose, adonitol, methylxyloside, sorbose, rhaninose, dulcitole, inositol, tagatose, D-arabitol, L-arabinose, melezitose, melibiose, pullulan, glycogen, raffinose, methyl D-mannoside, methyl D-glucoside, starch, xylitol, turanose. lyxose, fucose, gluconate and sorbitol.</s><s>Does not produce acetoin or H<sub>2</sub>S and is not able to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses hippurate. pglucosidase activity is demonstrated whereas no activity of the following enzymes have been detected: urease, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, acid pyroglutamine arylamidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>The most abundant cellular fatty acids are 16:O (31.1 %), 16:1 (24.2%) and 18:1<i>cis</i>9 (23.4%).</s><s>Other fatty acids are 18:2<i>cis</i>9,12 or 18:O (10.8%), 14:O (5.4%) and 18:0 (3.5%).</s><s>Atlantic salmon (<i>Salmo salar</i>) is a host for <i>C. inhibens</i>. <i>C. inhibens</i> is not known to be related to disease. <i>C. inhibens</i> has a unique 16s rDNA signature and the significance of the branching points in the unrooted phylogenetic tree (Fig. 1) is 73% (<i>C. funditum</i> S86170/<i>C. mobile</i> X54271), 98.1% (<i>C. alterfunditum</i> L08623/<i>C. inhibens</i> strain K1<sup>T</sup>), 100% (<i>C. gallinarum</i> X54269/<i>C. piscicola</i> X54268) and 100% (<i>Vagococcus salmoninarum</i> X54272/<i>Vagococcus fluvialis</i> X54258).</s><s>The <i>C. inhibens</i> type strain (K1<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at CCUG as 31728<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The EMBL accession number for the 16s rDNA sequence is Z73313.</s></p></content></protolog>