<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3182_nm.5491" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5491" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5491" rank="species">Carnobacterium funditum</organism><reference id="rid.3182"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Höpfl</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrotrophic, lactic acid-producing bacteria from anoxic waters in Ace Lake, Antarctica; Carnobacterium funditum sp. nov. and Carnobacterium alterfunditum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>156</volume><fpage>255</fpage><lpage>262</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1793333</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Carnobacterium funditum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Carnobacterium funditum</i> (fun.di'tum L.adj <i>funditus</i>-from the bottom)</s></p><p class="description"><s>= Phenon 1 : gram-positive, asporogenus rods, 0.8-1.3 x 1.7-0.8 μm, which occur singly, in pairs, or short chains (typically of four cells), motile by a single subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Old cells usually stain gram-negatively and are non-motile.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase negative, aerobic or anaerobic with better growth at 20°C anaerobically.</s><s>Resazurin is decolorized in media which support good growth, L(+)-lactic acid is the major end product from D(+)-glucose with traces of ethanol, acetic acid, and formic acid.</s><s>D(-)-ribose is fermented to lactic acid and moderate amounts of ethanol, acetic acid and formic acid.</s><s>Glycerol is fermented to mainly acetic acid and formic acid and traces of ethanol are produced.</s><s>Gas is not produced.</s><s>No growth in MRS, arginine-MRS or SL broths.</s><s>A component in yeast extract is required for good growth, and at least 0.1% yeast extract is required for good growth.</s><s>Pyruvate, lactate, formate, acetate, methanol, betaine⋄H<sub>2</sub>O, trimethylammonium chloride, glycine or an atmosphere of H<sub>2</sub>:CO<sub>2</sub> (2 bar, 80:20) do not stimulate growth.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, ribose, maltose, mannose, fructose, salicin, sucrose, cellobiose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from galactose, mannitol and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, raffinose, inulin, melibiose, hippurate, starch, dulcitol, esculin, xylose, rhamnose, sotbose, adonitol, melezitose, amygdalin, glycogen, erythritol or lactose.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Chopped meat medium and litmus milk remain unchanged.</s><s>Gelatinase negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0°C but not at 30°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 22-23°C.</s><s>The optimum initial pH for growth is between 7.0 and 7.4.</s><s>Sodium is required for growth and optimal growth occurs at a sodium chloride concentration of 1.7%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain meso-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>C 18:1<i>cis</i>9 is a major component of its fatty acids.</s><s>Respiratory lipoquinones are not produced.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA ranges from 31.6±1.2 to 34±0.6.</s><s>The type strain pf3 (G+C=33.8±1.4) has been deposited in the DSM and ACAM (DSM 5970 = ACAM 312).</s><s>Isolated from the anaerobic monimolimnion of an antarctic lake of about seawater salinity.</s></p></content></protolog>