<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3435_nm.7658" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7658" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7658" rank="species">Kineosporia rhamnosa</organism><reference id="rid.3435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsushima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of four new species of the genus Kineosporia: Kineosporia succinea sp. nov., Kineosporia rhizophila sp. nov., Kineosporia mikuniensis sp. nov. and Kineosporia rhamnosa sp. nov., isolated from plant samples, and amended description of the genus Kineosporia.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1245</fpage><lpage>1255</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1245</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828426</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kineosporia rhamnosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kineosporia rhamnosa</i> (rham.no'sa. M.L. fem. adj. <i>rhamnosa</i> pertaining to rhamnose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelia are orange to light brown (especially on yeast extract-starch agar).</s><s>Does not produce any diffusible pigments in yeast extract-starch and oatmeal agar media.</s><s>Decomposes casein, DNA and urea, but not aesculin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>Utilizes D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, starch and D-xylose as a sole carbon source, but not adonitol, D-arabitol, i-erythritol, D-lactose, D-melezitose, melibiose, methyl α-D-glucoside, D-ribose, salicin, L-sorbose, D-trehalose and xylitol.</s><s>Utilizes fumaric acid, L-malic acid and succinic acid, but not benzoic acid, citric acid, mucic acid, oxalic acid and L-tartaric acid.</s><s>Produces acids from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose and D-xylose, but not adonitol, i-erythritol and D-melezitose.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 2% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 68-69 mol%.</s><s>Contains a major amount of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall.</s><s>Contains rhamnose and 3-O-methylrhamnose in the whole-cell hydrolysate.</s><s>The type strain is strain I-132<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 9954<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>