<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7472_nm.6352" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6352" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6352" rank="species">Mycobacterium genavense</organism><reference id="rid.7472"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Böttger</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirschel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coyle</surname><given-names>M.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium genavense sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>841</fpage><lpage>843</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-841</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240965</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium genavense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium genavense</i> (ge.na.ven'.se. L. gen. n. <i>geneva</i>, referring to Geneva, the source of the first isolate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in tissues and in broth are small, clumped, acid-fast coccobacilli (1.0 by 2.0 μm).</s><s>Does not form spores, capsules, or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Grows fastidiously; produces variable growth in liquid media.</s><s>Primary cultures for isolation require broth media (for example, BACTEC 13A medium, Middlebrook 7H12 medium, Middlebrook 7H9 medium, BACTEC pyrazinamidase test medium [Becton Dickinson] or Septi-Check AFB medium [Roche Diagnostic Systems]) and incubation for 3 to 12 weeks; acid broth media facilitate primary isolation (8). <i>M. genavense</i> does not grow on standard solid media used for isolation of mycobacteria (e-g., Löwenstein-Jensen, unsupplemented Middlebrook 7H11, or Middlebrook 7H10 medium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Visible growth on solid Middlebrook 7H11 medium supplemented with MJ after inoculation with a broth culture requires 3 to 9 weeks, and the growth consists of tiny, transparent, nonphotochromogenic, dysgonic colonies.</s><s>As agar cultures age, they may produce variant eugonic colonies, which are either dense and creamy or flat and dry.</s><s>The acid-fast bacilli in creamy colonies are pleomorphic cells that range in length from 1 to 6 μm; the majority are about 2 μm long.</s><s>Variable amounts of cells occur in clumps.</s><s>Cells in dry colonies are similar to cells in creamy colonies, but they are more variable in length and are somewhat curved and more clumped than cells in creamy colonies.</s><s>After incubation for more than 3 months the predominant cells are coccoid, short rods about 1 to 2 μm long that frequently occur in clumps.</s><s>All strains grow at 31, 37, and 42°C, with slightly better growth at 42°C.</s><s>No strains grow at 45°C, and most strains produced barely visible growth at 24°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown on Middlebrook 7H11 agar supplemented with MJ consistently yield positive results in tests for catalase (semiquantitative and 68°C), pyrazinamidase, and urease.</s><s>The organisms do not produce nicotinic acid or hydrolyze Tween nor have nitrate reductase or arylsulfatase activity.</s><s>All isolates tested are susceptible in vitro to streptomycin and rifampin and resistant to isoniazid and ethambutol.</s><s>Whole-cell fatty acid analysis by gas-liquid chromatography reveals a distribution of fatty acids similar to that of <i>Mycobacterium fortuitum</i> (3).</s><s>Mycolic acid analysis demonstrates the presence of α-, α'-, and keto-mycolates (3,7). <i>M. genavense</i> is not pathogenic for immunocompetent mice, but can be propagated in nude mice (7).</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis based on an evaluation of 16s rRNA sequences places <i>M. genavense</i> on the same branch as <i>Mycobacterium simiae</i>, rooted deeply from the basis of slowly growing mycobacteria (2,15).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. genavense</i>, an opportunistic pathogen, has been isolated from specimens (blood, bone marrow, livers, spleens, intestines, lymph nodes) obtained from patients with AIDS, most of whom had fever and diarrhea and experienced weight loss.</s><s>In addition, strains have been isolated from pet birds.</s><s>Strain 2289 is the type strain; a culture of this strain (dry colony type) has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51234.</s><s>A creamy variant of strain 4096 has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51233.</s></p></content></protolog>