<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1723_nm.4703" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4703" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4703" rank="species">Mycoplasma muris</organism><reference id="rid.1723"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McGarrity</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dion</surname><given-names>A.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma muris, a new species from laboratory mice.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>350</fpage><lpage>355</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-350</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma muris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma muris</i> (mur' is. L. n. <i>mus</i> mouse; L. gen. n. <i>muris</i> of a mouse)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolation of mycoplasmas.</s><s>Vaginal samples were obtained from 42 female strain RIII mice (21 were pregnant) and 32 female strain C57BL/6 mice (20 were pregnant).</s><s>Three isolates were obtained, all from pregnant strain RIII mice.</s><s>These three isolates, which were designated RIII-1, RIII-4<sup>T</sup>, and RIII-8, grew only on SP-4 medium at 37°C and only under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The recovery of these mycoplasmas from strain RIII mice did not appear to be chance isolations. since a repeat sampling of the individual mouse that yielded strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> 6 weeks after the primary culture was obtained also yielded a mycoplasma with the same characteristics.</s><s>This female was also pregnant at the time of the second isolation.</s><s>Colonies of the organisms were first detected after incubation of broth cultures for 14 days at 37°C.</s><s>Each isolate was purified by standard filtration and cloning techniques, and strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> was selected for further characterization.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and cultural properties.</s><s>Broth cultures of strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> examined by dark-field microscopy contained numerous pleomorphic, round or coccobacillary forms.</s><s>Preparations stained by the Gram technique revealed gramnegative pleomorphic structures similar to those observed in dark-field microscopy preparations.</s><s>An examination of thin sections of cell pellets by electron microscopy confirmed the frequent occurrence of oval cells, which generally were about 300 nm in diameter (Fig. 1).</s><s>No cell wall material was apparent outside the unit membrane of the organism.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth cultures of strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> in SP-4 medium were slightly turbid after 5 days of incubation under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Approximately the same amount of growth occurred when this organism was cultivated in the broth containing 20% fetal bovine serum.</s><s>Although a few classical "fried-egg" colonies were observed, most growth on SP-4 agar plates after 7 days of incubation in the GasPak system consisted of granular colonies.</s><s>The colonies were generally small, averaging 50 to 100 μm in diameter.</s><s>No growth occurred in broth or on agar plates when cultures were incubated aerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reversion studies.</s><s>Cultures of mycoplasmas maintained in antibiotic-free SP-4 broth for at least five passages exhibited growth characteristics similar to those observed when penicillin was present.</s><s>There was no evidence of reversion to bacterial forms when the organisms were plated onto bacteriological agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration studies.</s><s>A cloned broth culture of strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> contained 1.9 X 10<sup>6</sup> colony-forming units per ml before filtration through a series of membrane filters.</s><s>After filtration through membrane filters with average pore diameters of 450, 300, 220, and 100 nm, preparations contained 2.0 x 10<sup>3</sup>, 1.3 x 10<sup>3</sup>, 5.8 x 10<sup>2</sup>, and 0 colony-forming units per ml, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical and biological properties.</s><s>Various biochemical tests were performed on strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup>, and other biological properties were also determined.</s><s>The characteristics of this strain are as follows: does not ferment glucose; hydrolyzes arginine but not urea; phosphatase negative; produces film and spot reactions; reduces tetrazolium anaerobically; exhibits uridine phosphorylase activity (91.5% conversion in 180 min); shows strong hemadsorption of guinea pig erythrocytes; does not liquefy coagulated serum: susceptible to 1.5% digitonin (zone of inhibition, 9 mm); requires sterol; light culture turbidity; colonies on agar are small and granular, with a few fried-egg types; anaerobic atmosphere preferred (H<sub>2</sub> containing 5% CO<sub>2</sub>); preferred growth temperature is 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>The growth responses of strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> to cholesterol and fetal bovine serum are shown in Table 1 .</s><s>Little growth was apparent in the base broth medium without additives, in broth containing various levels of cholesterol, or when small concentrations (0.5 to 5%) of fetal bovine serum were added.</s><s>Significant growth occurred only when 10 to 20% fetal bovine serum was added to the base medium, thus confirming the requirement for serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological tests.</s><s>Growth inhibition and plate immunofluorescence tests, which were performed with antisera or conjugates prepared to the mycoplasmas listed above, indicated that the strain RIII isolates are not serologically related to previously described <i>Mycoplasma</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The results of a thin-layer chromatographic analysis of DNA extracted from strain RIII-4<sup>T</sup> indicated that this strain has a G+C content of 24.9 ± 1.0 mol% (Table 2).</s><s>Control preparations of strains of <i>A. laidlawii</i> and <i>E . coli</i> showed G+C contents of 35.8 and 49.6 mol%, respectively.</s><s>These values are consistent with previously published data ( 5 . 10)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain RIII-4 is the type strain.</s><s>A cloned line of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 33757.</s></p></content></protolog>