<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3437_nm.6270" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6270" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6270" rank="species">Corynebacterium sundsvallense</organism><reference id="rid.3437"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nyberg</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium sundsvallense sp. nov., from human clinical specimens</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>361</fpage><lpage>366</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-361</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319456</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium sundsvallense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium sundsvallense</i> (sunds.vall.en'se. N. L. gen. n. <i>sundsvallense</i> from Sundsvall, Sweden, named after the city from where the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming pleomorphic coryneform rods ; some branching and bulges/knobs at the ends of some cells may be observed.</s><s>Colonies are buff or yellowish, opaque, shiny, heaped and adherent to medium.</s><s>Nonhaemolytic.</s><s>Non-lipophilic and C AMP-negative.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth possible in 6% NaCl but not in 10% NaCl.</s><s>Acid produced from fructose, glucose, maltose and sucrose but not from amygdalin, N-acetylglucosamine, galactose, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, ribose, raffinose, salicin, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Lactate and succinate are the major products of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed but not aesculin, gelatin or starch.</s><s>Nitrate not reduced. α-Glucosidase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Weak phosphoamidase activity detected.</s><s>Some strains are positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, ester lipase C8 and esterase C-4.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin (10 U) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The cell wall contains meso-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main cellular long-chain fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid and octadecenoic acid.</s><s>Tuberculostearic acid is not present.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>Type strain is CCUG 36622<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>G + C content of the type strain is 64 mol%.</s><s>Type strain has the features described above except weak reactions for pyrazinamidase and alkaline phosphatase are observed but leucine arylamidase, ester lipase C8 and esterase C-4 activities are not detected.</s></p></content></protolog>