<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4923_nm.7546" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7546" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7546" rank="species">Nocardiopsis lucentensis</organism><reference id="rid.4923"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Galinski</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wohlfarth</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jahnke</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new Actinomycete species, Nocardiopsis lucentensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>266</fpage><lpage>271</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis lucentensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis lucentensis</i> (lu. cen. ten'sis. M. L. adj, <i>lucentensis</i>, referring to Lucentum, the ancient Latin name of Alicante, a city in Spain, where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile, filamentous actinomycete.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Cultures of strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> grow well on both complex and defined media.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are initiated when NaCl at a concentration of up to 10% is added to the growth medium.</s><s>The aerial spore mass color is predominantly white.</s><s>The reverse side of culture growth is yellow to yellowish brown.</s><s>No distinctive pigmentation is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological characteristics. (i) Aerial mycelium.</s><s>On ISP medium 2, ISP medium 3, and ISP medium 4, all supplemented with 5 to 10% NaCl, well-developed branched aerial hyphae are present.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are white, long, and at the beginning of sporulation more or less zig-zag shaped (Fig. 1).</s><s>The zig-zag-shaped hyphae subdivide into smaller spores (Fig. 1).</s><s>Spores are elongated and have smooth surfaces (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Substrate mycelium.</s><s>Strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> produces an extensive substrate mycelium that fragments.</s><s>It first appears to be yellowish and then becomes yellowish brown on ISP medium 2, ISP medium 3, and ISP medium 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics.</s><s>Strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> produces acid from the following carbohydrates: glucose, inositol, mannitol, raffinose, and rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, lactose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glucitol, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth does not occur in ISP medium 9 supplemented with different carbon sources.</s><s>However, growth occurs in ISP medium 9 which is supplemented with 5 to 10% NaCl and contains mannose, glucose, rhamnose, maltose, mannitol, D-fructose, sucrose, raffinose, glycerol, trehalose, and <i>myo</i>-inositol as sole sources of carbon but not in medium containing L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-galactose, and lactose.</s><s>Citrate, malate, succinate, acetate, pyruvate, and propionate are decarboqdated, but lactate and oxalate are not.</s><s>Strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> decomposes adenine, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, and xanthine and hydrolyzes casein, starch, gelatin, and esculin but not urea, allantoin, and arbutin.</s><s>It produces catalase and phosphatase but neither β-galactosidase nor β-glucosidase.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on either ISP medium 6 or ISP medium 7.</s><s>The organism reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> is resistant to lincomycin (128 μg/ml), penicillin G (128 μg/ml), gentamicin (64 μg/ml), streptomycin (64 μg/ml), and neomycin (4 μg/ml) but not rifampin (128 μg/ml).</s><s>The organism is susceptible to lysozyme and tolerates NaCl at levels up to and including 10%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemotaxonomy.</s><s>Hydrolyzed whole cells contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Glucose and arabinose are detected in whole-cell extracts.</s><s>Thus, strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> has a type III cell wall and a variant of the type C sugar pattern.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>Phospholipid determinations performed with whole cells indicate that phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, and diphosphatidylglycerol are present.</s><s>Therefore, strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> has a type PIII phospholipid pattern.</s><s>The menaquinones detected in strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> are octahydrogenated menaquinones with 10 isoprene units [MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>)].</s><s>Minor amounts of tetra-, hexa-, and decahydrogenated menaquinones with 10 isoprene units [MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>10</sub>)], as well as tetra-, hexa-, octa-, and decahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units [MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), MK- 9(H<sub>10</sub>)], are also present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of strain consists of major amounts of saturated branched-chain fatty acids of the iso and anteiso types (iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>, 32%; anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>, 14.5%; iso-C<sub>18:0</sub>, 9.4%), straight-chain saturated fatty acids (<i>n</i>-C<sub>16:0</sub>, 3.9%; <i>n</i>-C<sub>17:0</sub>, 1.5%;  <i>n</i>-C<sub>18:0</sub> 9.9~%:), and 10-methyl branched-chain fatty acids represented by tuberculostearic acid (10-methyl C<sub>18:0</sub>, 15.4%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization.</s><s>The renaturation rates as determined by the optical method reveal binding values that range from 40 to 46% between strain A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> and the other <i>Nocardiopsis</i> species (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain A5-1 (= DSM 44048).</s><s>It was isolated from soil collected in Alicante, Spain.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and thus serves as the type strain description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Another variant, strain A4-2, which was found to be phenotypically identical to A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup>, exhibited a DNA relatedness level of 39% to A<sub>5-1</sub><sup>T</sup> (Table 3).</s><s>However, we hesitate to suggest a new species for this strain because it is recommended that “a distinct genospecies that cannot be differentiated from another genospecies on the basis of any known phenotypic property shall not be named until they can be differentiated by some phenotypic property” (49).</s></p></content></protolog>