<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1765_nm.1462" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1462" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1462" rank="species">Bradyrhizobium liaoningense</organism><reference id="rid.1765"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ge</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bradyrhizobium liaoningense sp. nov., isolated from the root nodules of soybeans.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>706</fpage><lpage>711</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-706</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547289</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bradyrhizobium liaoningense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bradyrhizobium liaoningense</i> (li.a.o.ning.en'se. M. L. adj., <i>liaoningense</i>, referring to Liaoning, a province in the People’s Republic of China from which rhizobia were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods are about 0.5 by 1.5 to 4.5 μm.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>The colonies are circular, entire, semitranslucent, raised, non-mucoid, and usually 0.2 to 1 mm in diameter within 7 to 14 days on YMA.</s><s>The strains utilize a narrow range of carbohydrates, organic acids, and amino acids as sole carbon sources.</s><s>All of the ESG strains tested utilize arabinose, glutamic acid, and sodium glutamate.</s><s>Most strains assimilate rhamnose, xylose, mannose, xylose, ribose, glutamine, sodium lactate, sodium gluconate, sodium pyruvate, and sodium succinate.</s><s>The ESG strains use cystine, isoleucine, histidine, valine, aspartic acid, arginine monohydrochloride, glutamine, glutamic acid, cytosine, and asparagine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Most strains also utilize methionine, serine, tryptophan, lysine, proline, arginine, tyrosine, leucine, and proline.</s><s>The ESG strains have an extralong generation time.</s><s>Alkali production occurs on YMA (pH up to 7.45 to 8.08) (Table 3).</s><s>The optimum growth temperature range is 25 to 30°C, and the optimum pH is 6.5 to 6.8.</s><s>The tolerance of the ESG strains to antibiotics is lower than that of other <i>Bradyrhizobium</i> spp.</s><s>The ESG strains are susceptible to bleomycin (25 μg/ml), erythromycin (100 μg/ml), and penicillin (25 μg/ml), but are resistant to lincomycin (25 U/ml), neomycin (30 U/ml), bacitracin (25 μg/ml), gentamicin (25 U/ml), chlortetracycline (25 U/ml), doxycycline (25 U/ml), oxacillin (25 U/ml), and oxytetracycline (25 μg/ml).</s><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The type strain of <i>B. liaoningense</i> is 2281, which is the center strain of this species group.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>