<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4780_nm.3058" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3058" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3058" rank="species">Aeromonas jandaei</organism><reference id="rid.4780"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carnahan</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joseph</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas jandaei (formerly genospecies DNA group 9 A. sobria), a new sucrose-negative species isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>560</fpage><lpage>564</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2037673</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Designation of <i>Aeromonas jandaei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas jandaei</i> (pronounced jan.dae'i, is derived from the surname of J. Michael Janda, an American microbiologist who has contributed greatly to our knowledge of <i>Aeromonas</i> species, in particular, their biotypes and clinical significance and the relative pathogenicities of mesophilic members (11-16). The species name is treated as a modern (neo) Latin genitive noun and was derived after consultation with T. O. Mac-Adoo, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg. The ending "ei" is appropriate for a male name ending in the vowel "a" and has been proposed and accepted as such in the latest revision of Appendix 9, Orthography, of the International Code of Nomenclature ofBacteria (21, 22))</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose the name <i>A. jandaei</i> for the nine strains listed in Table 1.</s><s>The species name</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of the species is designated ATCC 49568 (CDC 0787-80), with a complete description of the species given in Tables 2 and 5.</s><s>The unique profile of <i>A. jandaei</i> is as follows: negative esculin hydrolysis, negative fermentation of sucrose and cellobiose, and resistance to a specific dilution of colistin (4 μg/ml).</s><s>In previous taxonomic work in 1984, Turnbull et al. (28) noted the presence of a small asaccharolytic group of aeromonads that were sucrose and esculin negative, and even earlier work in 1981 on antimicrobial susceptibility by Richardson et al. (27) established the nearly universal susceptibility of most <i>Aeromonas</i> species to colistin. <i>A. jandaei</i> resides in the genus <i>Aeromonas</i> because it is an oxidase-positive, glucose-fermenting, motile gram-negative rod that is resistant to 0/129, is string test negative, reduces nitrate to nitrite, and does not require NaCl for growth.</s><s>It is nearly uniformly resistant to ampicillin, cefazolin, cephalothin, imipenem, piperacillin, and ticarcillin (Table 4).</s></p></content></protolog>