<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4061_nm.8366" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8366" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8366" rank="species">Fusobacterium pseudonecrophorum</organism><reference id="rid.4061"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shinjo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraiwa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyazato</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Recognition of biovar C of Fusobacterium necrophorum (Flügge) Moore and Holdeman as Fusobacterium pseudonecrophorum sp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Prévot 1940)</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>71</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-71</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223600</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium pseudonecrophorum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium pseudonecrophorum</i> (pseu.do.ne.cro'pho.rum. Gr. adj. <i>pseudes</i>, false; Gr. adj. <i>necros</i>, dead; Gr. adj. <i>phorum</i>, bearing; M.L. neut. adj. <i>pseudonecrophorum</i>, false necrosis producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Fusobacterium pseudonecrophorum</i> is an obligatory anaerobic, gram-negative, nonsporulating , rod-shaped organism; the cells are thick, semilong rods and are filamentous.</s><s>After 3 day of incubation, colonies on GAM agar supplemented with 5% defibrinated horse blood are about 2.5 mm in diameter, umbonate, grayish, and translucent.</s><s>The margins are undulate, and the surfaces are granular.</s><s>This species exhibits no hemolysis with the blood of rabbits and horses.</s><s>All of the strains produce butyric acid from glucose and propionic acid from threonine and lactic acid.</s><s>They are negative for esculin hydrolysis and positive for indole production.</s><s>The results of tests for starch hydrolysis, motility, nitrate reduction, gas formation, catalase production, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and growth in 20% bile are consistent with the description of <i>F. necrophorum</i> in Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology (15).</s><s>They are negative in the lipase reaction.</s><s>Each strain produces acid from glucose and fructose (weak).</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, galactose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>None of the strains agglutinates chicken erythrocytes.</s><s>No liver abscesses are formed in mice.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 28.0 to 30.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. pseudonecrophorum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev. (ex PrCvot 1940) is strain Fn521 (= JCM 3722).</s></p></content></protolog>