<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7429_nm.1123" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1123" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1123" rank="species">Rhodovulum iodosum</organism><reference id="rid.7429"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Straub</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Widdel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum iodosum sp. nov. and Rhodovulum robiginosum sp. nov., two new marine phototrophic ferrous-iron-oxidizing purple bacteria.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>729</fpage><lpage>735</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-729</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319496</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodovulum iodosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodovulum iodosum</i> (i.o.do'sum. M.L. adj. from Gr. adj. <i>iodaes</i> violet, and also rusty, indicating the formation of rusty, ferric iron deposits during photoautotrophic growth on ferrous iron)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ovoid to rod-shaped, non-motile cells, 0.5-0.8 μm wide and 2-4-34 μm long.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Colour of strictly anaerobically grown cells is yellow-brown.</s><s>Cells contain bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>Electron donors for photoautotrophic growth are hydrogen, sulfide, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur and ferrous iron; the main product of ferrous iron oxidation is ferrihydrite.</s><s>Photoheterotrophic growth occurs with acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, pyruvate, lactate, succinate, fumarate, malate, cysteine, glutamate and mannitol.</s><s>Grows chemoheterotrophically in the dark with oxygen.</s><s>Optimal growth on ferrous iron occurs at 20-25°C, pH 6.5, and with 25-50 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Growth is not possible with sulfate as sole sulfur source; thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, sulfide or cysteine is necessary as a source of reduced sulfur for cell synthesis.</s><s>Biotin and nicotinate are required as growth factors.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 66 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, N1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12328<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of the mud flat of the Jadebusen, North Sea coast, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>