<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7289_nm.994" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.994" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.994" rank="species">Ehrlichia equi</organism><reference id="rid.7289"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lewis</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huxsoll</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ristic</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Experimentally induced infection of dogs, cats, and nonhuman primates with Ehrlichia equi, etiologic agent of equine ehrlichiosis</article-title><year>1975</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>85</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><source id="224">American Journal of Veterinary Research</source><abbrev>Am J Vet Res</abbrev><issn>0002-9645</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1115421</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ehrlichia equi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The susceptibility of goats, sheep, and dogs to experimentally induced infection with the agent of equine ehrlichiosis had been reported. In the predsent study, 3 additional species, <i>F. catus</i>, <i>M, mulatta</i>, and <i>P. anubis</i>, shown to be susceptible to experimentally induced infection with <i>E. equi</i>, the etiologic agent of equine ehrlicbiosis. Experimental transmission of <i>E. equi</i> from horse to dog (Beagle), horse to cat (<i>P. catus</i>), horse to human primates (<i>M. mulatta</i> and <i>P. anubis</i>, as well nonhuman primate (<i>M. mulatta</i>) to horse, dog (Beagle) to dog (Beagle and Gennan Shepherd Dog), and dog (Beagle) to cat (<i>F. catus</i>) was demonstrated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morulae were observed in 11 of 17 Beagles and 3 of 6 Gennan Shepherd Dogs inoculated with <i>E. equi</i> infected blood, but the disease produced was mild to inapparent.</s><s>None of the dogs inoculated with <i>E. equi</i> developed any of the usual clinical signs occurring in dogs infected with <i>E. canis</i> such as anorexia, conjunctivitis, and pancytopenia.</s><s>Moreover, the serverity of disease caused by <i>E. equi</i> was not breed related as recently was reported for <i>E. canis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Previous infection with <i>E equi</i> did not provide protection against subsequent infection with <i>E. equi</i>.</s><s>Each of the 8 challenge-inocutated dogs (5 Beagles and 3 German Shepherd Dog) developed signs of TCP consisting of pyrexia, central nervous system depression, increase of erythrocyte sedimentation rate, and pancytopenia within 7 to 10 day after inoculation with <i>E. canis</i>.</s><s>Morulae of <i>E canis</i> were observed in monocytes of both breeds of dogs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The isolation of a neutrophilic strain of <i>E. canis</i> from a dog in Arkansas was recently (1971) reported.</s><s>Morulae were found both in neutrophils and in eosinophils of dogs experimentally infected with this strain.</s><s>This organism produced relatively mild disease in the naturally infected do from which the isolate was recovered, as well as in the experimentally infected dogs.</s><s>The mild disease produced by this strain in dogs resembles the mild to inapparent disease induced in dogs in the present study.</s><s>Both agents are characterized by the presence of morulae of similar appearance in granulocytea.</s><s>The neutrophilic strain of <i>E. canis</i> and <i>E. equi</i> may be similar, if not the same, agent.</s><s>The 2 agents also have marked morphologic resemblance to the agents of tick-borne lever and bovine petechial fever.</s><s>A recent (1912) report on the ultrastructure of the agent of bovine petechial fever suggested that the etiologic agent of equine ehrliciosis, the agents of tickborne fever, and the agent of bovine petechial fever be combined into a single genus.</s><s>All of these agents appear as morulae ID granulocytes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The suseptibility of nonhuman primates to infection with <i>E. equi</i> provides a basis for consideration of the potential transmission of ehrlichial agents to man.</s><s>The transmission of <i>Rickettsia canis</i> presently classified as <i>E. canis</i>, to the monkey <i>Macacus inuus</i> has been reported.</s></p><p class="description"><s>One human case in which an ehrlichial agent was incriminated as the etiologic agent of fever, epistaxis, and progressive pancytopenia has been recently (1973) reported.</s><s>Due to the unavailability of diagnostic tests for ehrlichiosis in human disease and the general unawareness of their existence, it is conceivable that ehrlichial agents for which man is the primary host have not yet been recognized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Further studies are needed to evaluate the disease role of ehrlichial agents in man and animals.</s><s>Elucidation and comparison of the ultrastructure of all of these agents, the development of serologic procedures for detection of antibody to the various ehrlichial agents, and an awareness of the presence of these agents will facilitate such studies.</s></p></content></protolog>