<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1405_nm.246" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.246" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.246" rank="species">Methanohalophilus mahii</organism><reference id="rid.1405"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Paterek</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanohalophilus mahii gen. nov., sp. nov., a methylotrophic halophilic methanogen.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>123</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-122</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanohalophilus mahii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanohalophilus mahii</i> (mah’i. i. N. L. n. <i>mahii</i> of Mah, in honor of R. A. Mah for his noteworthy research history in the areas of anaerobic microbiology and methanogenic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and colony characteristics are the same as those described above for the genus.</s><s>Sodium chloride optimum, 2.0 M.</s><s>Temperature optimum, 35°C, no growth at temperatures above 45°C.</s><s>pH optimum, approximately 7.5.</s><s>Source, anaerobic sediment from Great Salt Lake, Utah.</s><s>Physiology, fastidious anaerobe.</s><s>Trimethylamine, dimethylamine, methylamine, and methanol serve as substrates for growth and methanogenesis; hydrogen-carbon dioxide, formate, and acetate do not serve as substrates.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 48.5 mol%, as determined by buoyant density.</s><s>No definite antigenic relationship occurs between type strain SLP and members of the families <i>Methanobacteriaceae</i>, <i>Methanomicrobiaceae</i>, and <i>Methanosarcinaceae</i> as revealed by indirect immunofluorescence serotyping (Conway de Macario, personal communication).</s><s>The type strain is strain SLP (Salt Lake Paterek).</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 35705.</s></p></content></protolog>