<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12472_nm.21303" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21303" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21303" rank="species">Altererythrobacter aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.12472"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choe</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ka</surname><given-names>J.-O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Altererythrobacter namhicola sp. nov. and Altererythrobacter aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>709</fpage><lpage>715</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021196-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20418413</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Altererythrobacter aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Altererythrobacter aestuarii</em> (aes.tu.a′ri.i. L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of a tidal flat, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile rods, 1 µm wide and 3.5–5.7 µm long (Supplementary Fig. S2b).</s><s>Colonies on MA are yellow-pigmented, circular, smooth and convex with entire margins, approximately 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 7 days at 30 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and at pH 5–11 (optimum, pH 6–8).</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–6 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 1–2 %).</s><s>Does not contain BChl <em>a</em> as a photosynthetic pigment.</s><s>Methanol-soluble pigment is characterized by absorption maxima at 447 and 475 nm.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for acid production from d-glucose and maltose, production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glucose, malate, maltose, mannitol, mannose and phenylacetate.</s><s>Aesculin and Tweens 20 and 80 are degraded, but casein, CM-cellulose, DNA, egg yolk, gelatin, starch, l-tyrosine, urea and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, alkaline phosphatase, β-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase and trypsin activities are present, but <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the GN2 microplate (Biolog), dextrin, formic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, β-hydroxybutyric acid (weak), α-d-glucose (weak), dl-lactic acid (weak) and succinic acid monomethyl ester (weak) are utilized.</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized (Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (µg per disc, unless indicated) amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10) and vancomycin (30), but resistant to nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300 IU) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>DPG, PE, PG, SGL and PC are the major polar lipids (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>The predominant whole-cell fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KYW147<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22735<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16339<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample collected from the South Sea, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>