<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2325_nm.12236" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12236" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7259" rank="species">Streptomyces scabies</organism><reference id="rid.2325"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Loria</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces scabies sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>387</fpage><lpage>392</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-387</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces scabies</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces scabies</i> (sca'bies. L. n. <i>scabies</i>, mange, the name originally given by Thaxter [29] in reference to the ability of this organism to cause potato scab)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are 0.5 by 0.9 to 1.0 μm, smooth, and grey and are borne in mature spiral chains containing 20 or more spores.</s><s>Melanin is produced on tyrosine agar and peptone iron agar, and growth does generally not occur below an agar medium pH of 5.</s><s>All ISP sugars are used (i.e., L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, rhamnose, sucrose, D-xylose, and raffinose).</s><s>Most strains which have been studied do not degrade xanthine and are susceptible to 20 μg of streptomycin per ml and 0.5 μg of crystal violet per ml.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of this species is 71 mol%.</s><s>S. scabies differs from other virulent potato pathogens in having spiral spore chains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species is placed in the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> as it possesses morphology typical of this genus and cell walls with the LL-diaminopimelic acid isomer, The type strain of <i>S. scabies</i> is strain RL-34 (= ATCC 49173).</s><s>This strain was isolated in central New York in 1984.</s></p></content></protolog>