<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7477_nm.1181" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1181" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1181" rank="species">Sphingomonas herbicidovorans</organism><reference id="rid.7477"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zipper</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nickel</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Angst</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kohler</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Complete microbial degradation of both enantiomers of the chiral herbicide mecoprop [(RS)-2-(4-chloro-2-methylphenoxy)propionic acid] in an enantioselective manner by Sphingomonas herbicidovorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>62</volume><fpage>4318</fpage><lpage>4322</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8953704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas herbicidovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Taxonomical characteristics of strain MH. Strain MH is a yellow-pigmented, gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive rod with a length of 1.5 to 4.0 μm and a width of 0.6 to 0.8 μm. It is aminopeptidase positive and ADH and urease negative, lyses only esculin but not gelatin or DNA, cannot reduce nitrate, is not able to grow anaerobically, and does not form acids from sugars. Analysis of the cellular fatty acids showed that the strain belongs to the <i>Sphingomonas</i> group within the a subgroup of the proteobacteria. Partial sequencing of the gene for the 16S rRNA allowed an unequivocal classification of strain MH as a member of this group. The highest degree of similarity (99%) was obtained with the gene for the 16S rRNA of <i>Rhizomonas suberifaciens</i> and <i>S. yanoikuyae</i>. DNA-DNA hybridization experiments between strain MH and the type strains of these two species (37.4% identity to <i>R. suberifaciens</i> DSM 7465 and 33.8% identity to <i>S. yanoikuyae</i> DSM 7462) showed that strain MH belongs to a new species within the group. Although it has been suggested that <i>S. yanoikuyae</i> should be placed into the genus <i>Rhizomonas</i> (18, 21), we decided to name strain MH <i>S. herbicidovorans</i>, because—according to opinion 14 of the <i>International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria</i> (8)—the genus name <i>Rhizomonas</i> is a nomen rejiciendum and therefore usage of this name is in violation of rule 28a of the code. <i>S. herbicidovorans</i> MH has been deposited as the type strain with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig (DSM 11019).</s></p><p class="description"><s>It took at least 3 days at 308C before circular, brightly yellow colonies with a smooth surface could be observed on nutrient agar plates.</s><s>The shape of the colonies changed to a flower-like appearance when plates were incubated over longer time periods (up to 7 days).</s><s>Cells secreted a brownish pigment into the medium when grown on solid or liquid nutrient broth.</s><s>Cells taken from the exponential growth phase were rod shaped and often sticked together forming a chain, whereas cells taken from the stationary phase were almost of a coccoid shape.</s><s>In mineral salts medium with racemic mecoprop as the sole source of carbon and energy, strain MH needed supplements of vitamins and peptone (20 mg/liter) for growth.</s><s>Minimal agar plates had to be incubated up to 7 days until colonies appeared.</s><s>These colonies were smaller than the colonies grown on nutrient agar and not as intensely colored, but upon examination with a stereoscopic microscope, both colony types looked identical.</s></p></content></protolog>