<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7380_nm.3413" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3413" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3413" rank="species">Actinobacillus succinogenes</organism><reference id="rid.7380"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guettler</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rumler</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus succinogenes sp. nov., a novel succinic-acid-producing strain from the bovine rumen.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>216</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-207</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028265</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinobacillus succinogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinobacillus succinogenes</i> (suc.ci.no'ge.nes. M. L. n. <i>acidum succinicum</i> succinic acid; Gr. v. <i>gennaio</i> to produce; M .L. adj. <i>succinogenes</i> succinic-acid-producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, pleomorphic, Gram-negative rods (0.8 x 1 μm).</s><s>Occasional filamentous cells are seen in most cultures. 'Morse code' forms and chains are common in actively growing broth cultures.</s><s>Cells within an extracellular matrix are common in aerobically grown cultures.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Yeast extract and CO<sub>2</sub> stimulate growth.</s><s>Colonies produced on TSB agar are circular, entire, grey, translucent and 1-1.5 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation at 37°C with CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37-39°C, but not at 20 or 45°C.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase- positive.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced within 24 h from D-glucose and D-fructose.</s><s>Acid is also produced with L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, galactose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, raffinose, β-gentiobiose, D-arabitol, gluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from dulcitol, inositol, inulin, glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, Lsorbose, L-rhamnose, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl-α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, D-melibiose, trehalose, melezitose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>β-Galactosidase, arginine-β-arylamidase and leucine arylamidase were produced in large amounts.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Indole and urease are not produced.</s><s>Rapid and extensive growth observed utilizing arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, sucrose, xylose or salicin in media made with yeast extract and CSL.</s><s>Marked production of succinic acid in the presence of CO<sub>2</sub> and high substrate concentration.</s><s>DNA G+C content is approximately 45 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, strain 130Z<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from the bovine rumen, preserved by freezing in glycerol vials and by lyophilization, and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 55618<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>