<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3271_nm.1647" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1647" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1647" rank="species">Burkholderia stabilis</organism><reference id="rid.3271"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahenthiralingam</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henry</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Speert</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification and population structure of Burkholderia stabilis sp. nov. (formerly Burkholderia cepacia genomovar IV).</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>1042</fpage><lpage>1047</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10698993</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia stabilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia stabilis</i> (sta'bi.lis. L. adj. <i>stabilis</i>, stable, permanent, referring to the relative genomic stability of this <i>B. cepacia</i> genomovar)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile rods that are 1.0 to 2.0 μm long and 0.6 to 0.9 μm wide (the description is based on data obtained in the present study for all 21 strains and on data reported previously [23] for strains LMG 6997, LMG 7000, LMG 14086, LMG 14291, LMG 14294, LMG 14295, LMG 14940, and LMG 15949).</s><s>Growth is observed at room temperature and at 37°C but not at 42 or 5°C.</s><s>So far, no pigmented strains have been detected and no melanin-like pigment is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>There is growth on MacConkey agar and Simmons citrate agar.</s><s>There is oxidation in OF medium, an alkaline reaction on Christensen’s citrate agar, and growth in the presence of cetrimide.</s><s>There is no reduction of 0.4% selenite.</s><s>Tolerance to KCN is strain dependent (two of eight strains tested showed weak growth; all others were negative).</s><s>There is no fluorescence on King’s B medium.</s><s>Tyrosine, Tween 20, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, and lecithinase activities are present; urease and beta-galactosidase (ONPG test) activities are absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is strain dependent when it is determined as described by Holmes et al. (9) (three of eight strains tested reduced nitrate; all others did not) but is uniformly negative with the API strip; nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>There is no indole, hydrogen sulfide, or 3-ketolactose production, no hydrolysis of esculin or starch, and no DNase activity.</s><s>Liquefaction of gelatin and hydrolysis of casein are strain dependent (16 of 21 strains tested liquefied gelatin by the API assay; all but 1 of the strains liquefied gelatin when liquefaction was determined by a tube test [8]; 2 of 8 strains tested liquefied gelatin when liquefaction was determined by a plate test [9]; 7 of 8 strains tested hydrolyzed casein).</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and arginine desimidase activities are absent.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylase activities are absent when the activities were tested for as described by Barrow and Feltham (1) but were present when the activities were tested for as described in the present study.</s><s>There is no oxidation of gluconate and no production of phenylpyruvic acid, and all strains utilize malonate.</s><s>Poly-beta-hydroxybutyrate is utilized and is present as inclusion granules.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucosepeptone-water sugar.</s><s>Acid is produced from 10% (wt/vol) glucose, from 10% (wt/vol) lactose, and from the following sugars in ammonium salt medium: glucose, adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, sorbitol, trehalose, xylose, and fructose.</s><s>Acid is not produced\ (or is only weakly produced) from raffinose, rhamnose, ethanol, or sucrose.</s><s>Acid production from salicin is strain dependent (three of eight strains tested produced acid from salicin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base ratio is 68 to 69 mol%.</s><s>Major fatty acid components are 14:0 (about 4.4%), 14:0 3OH (about 5.4%), 16:1 ω7c (about 3.3%), 16:0 (about 25.6%), 17:0 cyclo (about 7.8%), 16:0 3OH (about 5.7%), 18:1 (about 10.6%), and 19:0 cyclo ω8c (about 15.3%).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>B. stabilis</i> strains have been isolated from the sputum of cystic fibrosis patients, from blood, ear, and respiratory tract infections in non-cystic fibrosis patients, and from the hospital environment.</s><s>The full range of pathogenicity is incompletely understood.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 14294, which was isolated in 1993 in Leuven, Belgium, from the sputum of a cystic fibrosis patient.</s><s>Its DNA base ratio is 68 mol%, and its phenotypic characteristics are as described above for the species.</s><s>The database accession number of its 16S rRNA gene sequence is AF148554.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and several additional strains are available from the Belgian Co-ordinated Collections of micro-organisms/Laboratorium Microbiologie Gent Culture Collection  and National Collection of Type Cultures culture collections.</s></p></content></protolog>