<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8819_nm.13777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13777" rank="species">Simiduia agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.8819"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shieh</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jean</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Simiduia agarivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine, agarolytic bacterium isolated from shallow coastal water from Keelung, Taiwan</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>895</fpage><lpage>900</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65371-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398190</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Simiduia agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Simiduia agarivorans</em> (a.ga.ri.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>agarum</em> agar; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, destroying; N.L. part. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells are predominantly straight to slightly curved rods, approximately 2–5 μm long and 0.4–0.6 μm wide, during the exponential phase of growth in broth cultures.</s><s>Nearly all cells are non-motile and non-flagellated; a few cells (&#x003C;1 %) exhibit motility and monotrichous flagella.</s><s>Most of the cells form sticky, amorphous aggregations during the stationary phase of growth.</s><s>Cells in the stationary growth phase are pleomorphic, often irregular, long rods 5–50 μm in length.</s><s>Blebs and prosthecae are produced; prosthecae are peritrichous and can be branched or network-shaped (Fig. 2a, c).</s><s>Capable of anaerobic growth by reducing nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor, but not by fermenting glucose or other carbohydrates as substrates.</s><s>Colonies produced on marine agar and PY plate medium are circular, off-white to cream-coloured, convex, non-luminescent and agarolytic; marine agar is hydrolysed more readily than PY plate medium.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 40 °C, with optimum growth at 30–35 °C; no growth occurs at 4–10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–7 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 2–3 % (w/v); no growth occurs without NaCl or in the presence of 8–10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Able to grow over a pH range of 7–10, but not at pH 6.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated as an intracellular product.</s><s>Not haemolytic.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Aesculin, alginate, casein, cellulose, chitin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but DNA, lecithin, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are absent.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase and trypsin.</s><s>Able to grow on the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: cellobiose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, acetate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-lysine and tyrosine.</s><s>Unable to grow on the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellulose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, trehalose, d-xylose, salicin, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, citrate, fumarate, lactate, malic acid, malonate, l-aspartic acid, citruline, l-glutamine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>Isoprenoid quinones comprise Q-10 (87.5 %), MK-9 (6.6 %) and MK-7 (5.9 %).</s><s>Polar lipids comprise phosphatidylethanolamine (71.8 %), diphosphatidylglycerol (12.7 %), phosphatidylglycerol (12.2 %) and phosphatidylserine (3.3 %).</s><s>Cellular fatty acids present at levels ≥1 % are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH; 28.6 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (22.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14.5 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (11.0 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (6.4 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3.6 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.4 %), C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH (1.2 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (1.0 %) and C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (1.0 %).</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U) and tetracycline (30 μg); intermediately susceptible to kanamycin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to cephalothin (30 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), colistin (10 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), neomycin (30 μg), oxacillin (1 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), streptomycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 55.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SA1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17597<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13881<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shallow coastal water from Keelung, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>