<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4536_nm.5479" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5479" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5479" rank="species">Facklamia miroungae</organism><reference id="rid.4536"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomson</surname><given-names>L.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Facklamia miroungae sp. nov., from a juvenile southern elephant seal (Mirounga leonina).</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1401</fpage><lpage>1403</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491339</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Facklamia miroungae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Facklamia miroungae</i> (mi.roung'ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>miroungae</i> of Mirounga, named because the organism was isolated from the southern elephant seal, <i>Mirounga leonina</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, ovoid in shape (approx. 0.8-0.9 μm in diameter) and occur in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Cells are asporogenous and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are γ-haemolytic, small (&#x003C;0.5 mm in diameter after 24 h), circular, entire, shiny, convex and grey in colour.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows in 5% NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 25 and 42 °C.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose and trehalose, but not from mannitol, maltose, sorbitol, lactose, raffinose, glycogen, pullulan, melibiose, melezitose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, tagatose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, cyclodextrin or sucrose.</s><s>Activity is detected for arginine dihydrolase, alaninephenylalanine-proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and urease.</s><s>Weak activity is observed for valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, phosphoaminidase, acid phosphatase and glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are weak or absent.</s><s>No activity is observed for esterase [C-4], ester lipase [C-8], lipase [C-14], trypsin, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, bgalactosidase and β-glucuronidase.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Isolated from a juvenile elephant seal.</s><s>The type strain, A/G13/99/2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 42728<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106764<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a nasal swab.</s></p></content></protolog>