<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5535_nm.8435" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8435" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8435" rank="species">Actinomyces dentalis</organism><reference id="rid.5535"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces dentalis sp. nov., from a human dental abscess</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>427</fpage><lpage>431</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63376-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653913</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces dentalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces dentalis</em> (den.ta′lis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>dentalis</em> pertaining to teeth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, filamentous, beaded, rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Cells are non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>After 48 h of anaerobic incubation on Fastidious Anaerobe Agar with 5 % horse blood, colonies are tiny, white and breadcrumb-like and pit the agar.</s><s>Catalase-negative and anaerobic; does not grow in air or in air plus 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The end products of glucose metabolism are acetic and lactic acids.</s><s>Using conventional tests, acid is formed from cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose (weak), mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose and trehalose but not from arabinose, mannitol or xylose.</s><s>Gelatin, urea and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, acid is produced from glucose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose and trehalose but not from d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, ribose, sorbitol, tagatose or d-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but hippurate is not.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Activity is detected for alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase and histidine arylamidase (weak); activity for <em>β</em>-galactosidase may or may not be detected.</s><s>Activity is not observed for alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, glycine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, tyrosine arylamidase, serine arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer negative.</s><s>Isolated from human dental abscess.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R18165<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 48064<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108337<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>