<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5574_nm.6097" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6097" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6097" rank="species">Aureobacterium resistens</organism><reference id="rid.5574"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nolte</surname><given-names>F.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aureobacterium resistens sp. nov., exhibiting vancomycin resistance and teicoplanin susceptibility</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>158</volume><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9453161</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aureobacterium resistens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aureobacterium resistens</i> (re'sis.tens. L. pres. part. <i>resistens</i>, being resistant, referring to the vancomycin resistance which is very unusual for coryneform bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, asporogenous, small (1 to 2 μm in length) and slim rods which are nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies are up to 1.5 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation, glistening, convex, of creamy consistency, and exhibit a yellow pigment.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from glucose, maltose, and sucrose but not from mannitol and xylose.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are utilized: glycerol, ribose, galactose, D-fructose, D-mannose, rhamnose, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdaline, salicine, cellobiose, lactose, trehalose, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are not utilized: erythritol, L-arabinose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, D-ra¤nose, amidon, glycogen, D-fucose, D-arabitol, and L-arabitol.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Esculin, tyrosine, and casein are hydrolyzed but not urea or starch.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>DNase activity is present.</s><s>Activities of pyrazinamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase are present whereas activities of pyrrolidonyl arylmidase, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, and β-glucuronidase are not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains ornithine as diamino acid, the peptidoglycan type is B2α ([L-ornithine]D-glutamic acid-D-ornithine), and of the glycolyl type.</s><s>C15:0<i>ai</i>, C16:0<i>i</i>, and C17:0<i>ai</i> are the predominant cellular fatty acids.</s><s>Strains are resistant to vancomycin but susceptible to teicoplanin.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain DMMZ 1710 has been deposited in the culture collection of the University of Göteborg, Sweden, as strain CCUG 38312.</s></p></content></protolog>