<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6294_nm.7852" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7852" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7852" rank="species">Diplocalyx calotermitidis</organism><reference id="rid.6294"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bermudes</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margulis</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Morphology as a basis for taxonomy of large spirochetes symbiotic in wood-eating cockroaches and termites: Pillotina gen. nov., nom. rev.; Pillotina calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx gen. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Hollandina gen. nov., nom.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>302</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Diplocalyx calotermitidis</i> (ex Gharagozlou 1968) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Diplocalyx calotermitidis</i> (cal.o.ter.mi.ti.dis. M.L. gen. <i>calotermitidis</i>, named for the host termite <i>Calotermes</i> [synonyms <i>Kalotermes</i>, <i>Incisitermes</i>] <i>flavicollis</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells, lobate in cross section, are 0.8 μm in diameter, with approximately 40 flagella (diameter, 20 nm) in a tight bundle.</s><s>The angle subtended by the flagella ranges from 50 to 70°.</s><s>The angle of concavity ranges from 150 to 160°.</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane varies from 3.8 to 13.5 nm (average, 12 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness is between 0.6 and 2.0 (average, 1.7).</s><s>The thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane ranges from 6 to 14 nm (average, 10 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane to the inner membrane thickness varies from 0.9 to 2.1 (average, 1.5).</s><s>The thickness of the outer coat of the inner membrane (the calyx) ranges from 42 to 51 nm (average, 48 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the outer coat of the inner membrane to the inner membrane thickness is between 6.4 and 7.7 (average, 7.3).</s><s>The protoplasmic cylinder is slightly oblong and 0.38 μm (narrowest point) to 0.43 μm (widest point) in diameter.</s><s>The ratio of the protoplasmic cylinder diameter to the cell diameter is between 0.48 and 0.53 (average, 0.51).</s><s>The outer coat of the inner membrane is bisected by the sillon.</s><s>The position of the sillon is opposite the flagellar bundle.</s><s>The type specimen (8) is from <i>Calotermes flavicollis</i> found in southern France.</s></p></content></protolog>