<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2212_nm.5883" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5883" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5883" rank="species">Arthrobacter woluwensis</organism><reference id="rid.2212"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfyffer</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wauters</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation of Arthrobacter spp. from clinical specimens and description of Arthrobacter cumminsii sp. nov. and Arthrobacter woluwensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>2356</fpage><lpage>2363</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8880479</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter woluwensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter woluwensis</i> (wo.lu'wen.sis N.L. fem. adj. <i>woluwensis</i>, from Woluwe, a town near Brussels, Belgium, where the type strain was isolated from a patient)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are coryneform bacteria which develop into cocci when the cultures become older (72 h).</s><s>Jointed rods are observed after 1 to 2 days of incubation.</s><s>No spores formed.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile.</s><s>The organism is obligately aerobic.</s><s>The colonies are whitish-grayish, smooth, convex, and larger than 2 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation at 37°C in 5% CO<sub>2</sub> on SBA.</s><s>The organism is catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea (72 h) and esculin (24 h) are hydrolyzed.</s><s>DNase and gelatinase activities are detected within 24 h.</s><s>Glycerol, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdaline, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, D-raffinose, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-arabitol, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, and 5-keto-gluconate are utilized.</s><s>Erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, inositol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, inulin, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, and L-arabitol are not utilized.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are detected: alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, and α-mannosidase.</s><s>Chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, and α-fucosidase are not present.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is L-lysine–D-aspartic acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 69 mol% G+C.</s><s>The organism was isolated from cultures of human blood.</s><s>The type strain (CUL 1808) has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures as strain DSM 10495.</s></p></content></protolog>