<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2600_nm.11567" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11567" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11567" rank="species">Chitinilyticum aquatile</organism><reference id="rid.2600"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinilyticum aquatile gen. nov., sp. nov., a chitinolytic bacterium isolated from a freshwater pond used for Pacific white shrimp culture.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2854</fpage><lpage>2860</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65168-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048738</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinilyticum aquatile</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinilyticum aquatile</em> (L. neut. adj. <em>aquatile</em> living in water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 2.5–4.0 μm long and 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter, occurring singly.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C, pH 7–11 and 0–0.75 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for glucose fermentation.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production (triple-sugar iron agar and sulfide indole motility medium), acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer test) and fermentation of mannitol, sucrose, arabinose and rhamnose.</s><s>API 20NE tests show positive reactions for nitrate reduction, glucose fermentation, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of glucose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and gluconate and negative reactions for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of arabinose, mannitol, maltose, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, shows positive results for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and negative reactions for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, trypsin and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (Biolog GN2): dextrin, glucose, d-fructose, sucrose, cellobiose, mannose, trehalose, turanose, gluconate, d-glucuronic acid, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, glucose 6-phosphate and l-alanine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized (Biolog GN2): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, arabinose, maltose, lactulose, psicose, d-melibiose, itaconic acid, l-fucose, inosine, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-galactose, d-raffinose, gentiobiose, l-rhamnose, mannitol, xylitol, glycerol, arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-galacturonic acid, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, 2-aminoethanol, monomethyl succinate, citrate, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, methyl pyruvate, malonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, urocanic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-glucosaminic acid, phenyl ethylamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-aspartic acid, l-leucine, l-threonine, l-phenylalanine, l-asparagine, l-serine, d-alanine, d-serine, l-proline, hydroxy-l-proline, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, dl-carnitine, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-alanyl glycine, putrescine, alaninamide, glucuronamide, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>Sensitive to amikacin (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), penicillin G (10 U) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, c14<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17533<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23346<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water of an aquaculture pond containing Pacific white shrimp (<em>Litopenaeus vannamei</em>) at Pingtung in southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>