<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.311_nm.2112" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2112" rank="genus">Rhabdochromatium</organism><reference id="rid.311"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dilling</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhabdochromatium marinum gen. nom. rev., sp. nov., a purple sulfur bacterium from a salt marsh microbial mat</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>164</volume><fpage>125</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02525318</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhabdochromatium</i> gen. nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhabdochromatium</i> (Rhab.do.chro.ma'tium. Gr. n. rhabdos a rod; Gr. n. chromatium, color, paint; ML. neut.n. <i>Rhabdochromatium</i> colored rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <i>Rhabdochromatium</i> was established by Winogradsky (1888) for long, rod- or spindle-shaped red sulfur bacteria observed in samples from natural habitats.</s><s>Since none of the described species has so far been observed again in samples from nature and enrichment cultures, the genus has not been included in the 'Approved Lists of Bacterial Names'.</s><s>The name <i>Rhabdochromatium</i> is revived according to Rule 33c of the International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria (1992) for a long, rod-shaped, red sulfur bacterium, the morphology of which has proven to be stable in pure culture for more than 8 years now.</s><s>As only one species can be described at present, the genus and species description are given together.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most cells long, straight, rod-shaped, 1.5-1.7 μm wide and 16-32 μm long after and before division.</s><s>Slightly bent cells may occur.</s><s>Cells have slightly conical ends.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Cells possess a flagellar tuft of about 10-20 fibrils in polar position; cells may be flagellated at both ends.</s><s>Cells stain gram-negative.</s><s>Color of cell suspensions is beige to orange-brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photosynthetic membranes of vesicular-type; contain bacteriochlorophyll a and lycopene as main photosynthetic</s></p><p class="description"><s>pigments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic, obligately phototrophic.</s><s>Hydrogen, hydrogen sulfide, elemental sulfur, and thiosulfate are used as electron donors for photoautotrophic growth.</s><s>Globules of sulfur are stored inside the cells as intermediary product.</s><s>In sulfide-reduced, bicarbonate-containing media, acetate, propionate, and pyruvate are photoassimilated.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sodium chloride (1.5-5%) is required for growth; no growth below 1% and above 6.5%.</s><s>Optimum pH 7.2-7.3.</s><s>Optimum temperature 30°C no growth below 8 and above 35°C Optimum light intensity about 500 1x (tungsten lamp).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 60.4 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: The bacterium was isolated from a laminated microbial mat at Great Sippewissett Salt Marsh, Cape Cod, Mass., USA.</s><s>Type strain: strain 8315, DSM 5261.</s></p></content></protolog>