<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12569_nm.21814" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21814" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21814" rank="species">Bifidobacterium actinocoloniiforme</organism><reference id="rid.12569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Killer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kopečný</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mrázek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koppová</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Havlík</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benada</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kott. T.</surname><given-names /></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium actinocoloniiforme sp. nov. and Bifidobacterium bohemicum sp. nov., from the bumblebee digestive tract</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1315</fpage><lpage>1321</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022525-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656822</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium actinocoloniiforme</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bifidobacterium actinocoloniiforme</em> (ac.ti′no.co.lo′ni.i.for′me. Gr. fem. n. <em>actis</em>, -<em>inos</em> a ray; L. n. <em>colonia</em> a dwelling group, a colony; L. neut. adj. <em>forme</em> formed, shaped. N.L. neut. part. adj. <em>actinocoloniiforme</em> shaped like a ray-shaped colony).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-type-positive, F6PPK-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, irregularly shaped rods (0.3–0.6 µm wide and 0.4–1.2 µm long) with enlarged or tapered ends (Fig. 3a, b).</s><s>They grow singly or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies on TPY agar under anaerobic conditions are cream in colour, sometimes irregularly circular with entire edges and rigid cores, and reach 2.05–3.97 mm in diameter after 2 days of incubation.</s><s>Some colonies have filamentous parts growing around the solid core (Supplementary Fig. S3) when they are incubated for 72 h under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Colonies are also formed under microaerophilic conditions, when they reach 1.79–2.62 mm in diameter after 2 days of incubation.</s><s>Growth in TPY broth occurs at 25 and 37 °C, but not at 47 °C (after 24–48 h).</s><s>In TPY broth, the lowest pH attained is 4.5; minimum initial pH for growth is pH 5.</s><s>Cells contain relatively large amounts of palmitic, oleic and stearic acids.</s><s>DNA G+C content and biochemical parameters are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Scanning electron photomicrographs of cells of <em>Bifidobacterium actinocoloniiforme</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LISLUCIII-P2<sup>T</sup> (a, b) and <em>Bifidobacterium bohemicum</em> sp. nov.</s><s>JEMLUCVIII-4<sup>T</sup> (c, d). (a, b) Chains of curved irregular cells and clubbed cells; (c, d) chains of very irregular cells and cells with occasional constrictions.</s><s>Bars, 1 µm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LISLUCIII-P2<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22766<sup>T</sup>  = CCM 7728<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the digestive tract contents of a bumblebee (<em>Bombus lucorum</em>) sampled from Central Bohemia, Czech Republic, in 2006.</s></p></content></protolog>