<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6957_nm.1464" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1464" rank="genus">Afipia</organism><reference id="rid.6957"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>La Scola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Afipia birgiae sp. nov. and Afipia massiliensis sp. nov. and recognition of Afipia felis genospecies A.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1773</fpage><lpage>1782</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361286</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Afipia</i> (Brenner et al. 1992)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Afipia</i> (A.fip'i.a. N.L. fem. n. <i>Afipia</i> derived from the acronym AFIP, for Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, where the type species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus are Gram-negative, but well stained by Gimenez staining, oxidase-positive, weakly catalase-positive rods in the α-2 subgroup of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Most are motile by means of single polar or subpolar flagella.</s><s>They grow on BCYE agar and nutrient broth, but not on nutrient broth containing 6% NaCl.</s><s>All grow well at 25 and 30°C, but none grows at 42°C.</s><s>Colonies are grey-white, glistening, convex and opaque.</s><s>All are urease-positive.</s><s>Negative for haemolysis, arginine dihydrolase activity, aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis, β-galactosidase activity, H<sub>2</sub>S production and acid production by fermentation or oxidation of most carbon substrates, including glucose, fructose, mannose, sucrose, mannitol and maltose.</s><s>The G+C content is 59.3-64.0 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Afipia felis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>