<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1847_nm.3379" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3379" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3379" rank="species">Pasteurella caballi</organism><reference id="rid.1847"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schlater</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Packer</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pasteurella caballi, a new species from equine clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>2169</fpage><lpage>2174</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2584369</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella caballi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella caballi</i> (ca.bal'li. L.n. <i>caballus</i>, a horse; L.gen.n. <i>caballi</i>, of a horse; <i>Pasteurella caballi</i>, the <i>Pasteurella</i> of a horse)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.8 to 1.0 by 1.3 to 1.9 μm), bipolar stained, and arranged singly or in pairs with occasional swollen, curved, or filamentous forms observed.</s><s>The bacterium is gram negative, not acid fast, nonmotile, and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are 1.0 to 1.5 mm in diameter, smooth, slightly raised, and grayish yellow on blood agar after 24 h of incubation.</s><s>Colonies grow at room temperature and at 37°C but not at 4°C.</s><s>Colonies are not hemolytic on bovine, sheep, or rabbit blood agar but do impart a brownish discoloration to these media under areas of confluent growth.</s><s>Growth scraped up from the surface of the blood agar is cream (less frequently) to bright yellow (usual).</s><s>Growth on MacConkey agar is scant or absent.</s><s>The bacterium is X factor and V factor independent and positive for oxidase, phosphatase, and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Methylene blue milk is reduced.</s><s>Porphyrins are produced from δ-aminolevulinic acid.</s><s>Catalase, indole, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, α-fucosidase, and β-glucuronidase are not produced.</s><s>Esculin, gelatin, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests are negative.</s><s>D-Glucose is fermented, with the production of acid and gas.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose, D-galactose, lactose, D-mannose, and sucrose.</s><s>Fermentation of lactose is delayed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, inulin, salicin, starch, or trehalose.</s><s>The bacterium contains 3-OH C<sub>14:0</sub> and approximately 25% each of C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, ω7c, and C<sub>16:0</sub> acids, which is the characteristic fatty acid profile of all members of the family <i>Pastuerellaceae</i>.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 41 to 42 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>). <i>P. caballi</i> strains have been isolated from equine clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain of <i>P. caballi</i> is 83851 (=ATCC 49197), and it exhibits all of the characteristics described above.</s><s>Additional variable characteristics are given in Table 4.</s><s>The type strain was isolated in 1983 from the uterus of a mare.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA was 42 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>