<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5967_nm.9265" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9265" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2687" rank="species">Malikia spinosa</organism><reference id="rid.5967"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Malikia granosa gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel polyhydroxyalkanoate- and polyphosphate-accumulating bacterium isolated from activated sludge, and reclassification of Pseudomonas spinosa as Malikia spinosa comb. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>621</fpage><lpage>629</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63356-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774634</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Malikia spinosa</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Malikia spinosa</em> (spi.no′sa. L. adj. <em>spinosa</em> thorny, spiny).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Pseudomonas spinosa</em> Leifson 1962 (Approved Lists 1980).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results of this study confirm to a large extent the data provided by Leifson (1962) in the original description.</s><s>However, additional data obtained in this study make an emendation of the species description necessary.</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods with rounded ends, 1·1 μm wide and 3–6 μm long, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Occasionally filaments up to 50 μm long are formed.</s><s>Motile by one to three polar flagella.</s><s>Under conditions of nitrogen limitation cells accumulate large amounts of PHAs that are visible as highly refractile granules by phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>Poly-Ps are accumulated under conditions of carbon starvation.</s><s>Colonies appear after 24 h on R2A agar and reach approximately 1 mm in diameter after 2 days incubation.</s><s>They are smooth, circular, raised, cream–white and translucent.</s><s>After several days colonies appear mucoid owing to the formation of extracellular slime.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are formed.</s><s>Growth in liquid medium is homogeneous without formation of visible aggregates.</s><s>Temperature and pH optima for growth are 32 °C and 7·5–8·0, respectively.</s><s>The upper temperature limit for growth is about 36 °C.</s><s>Growth in media containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl is weak; no growth occurs above 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Substrates utilized for growth: adipate, gluconate, fumarate, l-malate, d-mannitol, d-glucose, d-maltose and sucrose.</s><s>Substrates not utilized for growth: acetate, benzoate, citrate, glycolate, glyoxylate, dl-lactate, malonate, propionate, pyruvate, oxaloacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, succinate, adonitol, glycerol, arabinose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, lactose, l-glutamate, l-histidine and l-proline.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrogen cannot be utilized for chemolithoautotrophic growth.</s><s>Thiosulfate is not oxidized.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 66 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from river water (DuPage River, IL, USA).</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 14606<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15801<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>