<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2540_nm.11465" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11465" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11465" rank="species">Roseospira goensis</organism><reference id="rid.2540"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kalyan Chakravarthy</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>Ch.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseospira visakhapatnamensis sp. nov. and Roseospira goensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2453</fpage><lpage>2457</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65105-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978198</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseospira goensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseospira goensis</em> (go′en.sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>goensis</em> pertaining to Goa, a state in India known for its beautiful beaches, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are vibrioid to crescent-shaped, 0.8–1.0 μm wide and 3.0–8.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a pair of monopolar flagella and divide by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photoorganoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemoorganoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>Phototrophic cultures are red–brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 473, 503, 540, 590, 803 and 857 nm confirming the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and most probably rhodovibrine.</s><s>The type strain is mesophilic (30 °C), with a pH optimum at 7.5 and requires 1–3 % NaCl (w/v) for optimal growth.</s><s>The preferred mode of growth is photoorganoheterotrophy with a few organic compounds.</s><s>Butyrate, valerate, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, glutarate, glycerol, 2-oxoglutarate and peptone are good carbon sources.</s><s>Growth also occurs on formate, acetate, malate and glucose.</s><s>Photoautotrophic and chemoautotrophic growth does not take place in the presence of sulfide/thiosulfate/hydrogen as the electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as the carbon source.</s><s>Fermentative growth does not take place in the presence of pyruvate as the fermentable carbon source.</s><s>Sulphate assimilation is absent.</s><s>Sulfide, thiosulphate, thioglycolate and elemental sulfur are used as sulfur sources.</s><s>Niacin, thiamine and <em>p-</em>aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 71 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>Natural habitats are marine salterns.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA135<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1364<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14191<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from sediment samples from a marine saltern, Goa, facing the Arabian sea on the West coast of India.</s></p></content></protolog>