<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.714_nm.9409" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9409" rank="species">Aneurinibacillus terranovensis</organism><reference id="rid.714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Allan</surname><given-names>R.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buchanan</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacillus levickii sp. nov. and Aneurinibacillus terranovensis sp. nov., two novel thermoacidophiles isolated from geothermal soils of northern Victoria Land, Antarctica</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1039</fpage><lpage>1050</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63397-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879231</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aneurinibacillus terranovensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aneurinibacillus terranovensis</em> [terr.a.no.ven′sis. N.L. adj. <em>terranovensis</em> referring to Terra Nova Bay Station (Italy), northern Victoria Land, Antarctica, where the strains were first isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, becoming Gram-negative after 48 h, motile, round-ended rods (0·8–1·0×2·0–8·0 μm), occurring singly, in pairs and in chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, occurring paracentrally and subterminally in very swollen sporangia (Fig. 4b).</s><s>After 48 h incubation on 1/2 BFA (pH 5·5) at 40 °C, colonies are circular, flat, up to 1·5 mm in diameter and cream-coloured with a slightly glossy appearance and butyrous consistency.</s><s>Minimum growth temperature is 20–25 °C, with optimum growth at 37–45 °C and maximum growth temperature of 50–55 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 3·5 and 6·0 and the optimum pH for growth is pH 5·0–5·5.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 2–3 % NaCl.</s><s>Microaerophilic and weakly catalase-positive.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed after 48 h.</s><s>Starch is weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>No growth occurs on casein agar.</s><s>In the API 20E strip reactions, arginine dihydrolase, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and nitrate reduction are positive.</s><s>Citrate utilization is variable.</s><s>Reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and gelatin hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in the Biotype 100 system: aesculin, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, d-gluconate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-glutamate, glycerol, dl-lactate, d-mannose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and <em>myo</em>-inositol.</s><s>Utilization of the following substrates is variable: adonitol, 2-oxoglutarate, <em>α</em>-lactose, l-alanine, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, l-aspartate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, d-galactose, d-galacturonate, d-glucosamine, dl-glycerate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-malate, l-malate, d-mannitol, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-proline, putrescine, quinate, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, succinate, sucrose, <em>trans</em>-aconitate and d-trehalose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: 3-phenylpropionate, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyrate, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-valerate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, d-alanine, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, benzoate, betaine, <em>β</em>-gentobiose, caprate, caprylate, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, ethanolamine, gentisate, d-glucuronate, glutarate, histamine, l-histidine, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, i-erythritol, itaconate, lactulose, d-lyxose, malonate, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, <em>m</em>-coumarate, d-melezitose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl-<em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl-d-glucopyranose, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, mucate, phenylacetate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, palatinose, propionate, protocatechuate, d-raffinose, d-saccharate, l-serine, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d-tartrate, l-tartrate, tricarballyate, trigonelline, tryptamine, l-tryptophan, d-turanose, l-tyrosine, xylitol and d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates in API Biotype 100 produce alkaline reactions when inoculated with a suspension in 1/2 BFB prepared without yeast extract or (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, but containing 0·006 % phenol red: 2-oxoglutarate, l-aspartate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, d-galacturonate, d-gluconate, l-glutamate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, malonate, mucate, quinate, d-saccharate, succinate, l-tartrate and d-tartrate.</s><s>Alkaline reactions for the following substrates are variable: d-alanine, l-alanine, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, caprylate, d-glucuronate, l-histidine, dl-lactate, d-malate, l-malate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, l-proline, propionate, l-serine, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, tricarballyate and l-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, accounting for approximately 41 and 46 % total fatty acid content, respectively.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts (at least 1·0 %): C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (detailed fatty acid are given in Supplementary Table A).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 43·2–44·6 mol% and the G+C content of the type strain (Logan B-1599<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22483<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108308<sup>T</sup>) is 43·2 mol%.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain utilizes citrate, fumarate, d-galactose, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-lactose, l-malate, quinate and <em>trans</em>-aconitate; alkaline reactions are observed in dl-lactate, d-malate, l-malate and <em>trans</em>-aconitate.</s></p></content></protolog>