<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11707_nm.19319" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19319" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19319" rank="species">Rhizobium soli</organism><reference id="rid.11707"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>H.-S.</surname><given-names /></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>C.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium soli sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1387</fpage><lpage>1393</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013094-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19671727</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, aerobic rods, 0.4–0.7×1.0–4.5 μm.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, convex, smooth, glistening, pale yellow and 1.2–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 31 °C, with optimum growth at 25 °C, but not at 32 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.5 and 8.5, but not at pH 5.0 or 9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.5–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth in the presence of 0.5–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nodulation is not observed on three different legumes and the <em>nodD</em> and <em>nifH</em> genes are not detected by PCR.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but casein, starch, tyrosine, hypoxanthine, xanthine and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are not.</s><s>Glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, cellobiose, melibiose, xylitol, l-fucose, d-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate are utilized and maltose, trehalose, gentiobiose and d-lyxose are utilized weakly, but l-xylose, adonitol, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside, amygdalin, salicin, lactose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-arabitol and 5-ketogluconate are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, l-rhamnose, melibiose and l-arabinose, but not from d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, sucrose or amygdalin.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present and esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and acid phosphatase activities are weak, but arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, tetracycline and neomycin, but not to ampicillin, lincomycin or penicillin G.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DS-42<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12873<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14591<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil from Dokdo, an island of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>