<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6735_nm.8174" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8174" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8174" rank="species">Myroides odoratimimus</organism><reference id="rid.6735"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torck</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernadet</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Flavobacterium odoratum (Stutzer 1929) strains to a new genus, Myroides, as Myroides odoratus, comb. nov. and Myroides odoratimimus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>926</fpage><lpage>932</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Myroides odoratimimus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Myroides odoratimimus</i> (o.do.ra.ti’mi.mus. Gr. nom. n. mimos, imitator; N. L. n. odoratimimus, imitator of <i>M. odoratus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Myroides odoratimimus</i> is the same as that given above for the genus, with the following additions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As determined by Biotype 100 galleries, <i>M. odoratimimus</i> strains grow on L-aspartate, L-glutamate, and L-proline and exhibit variable reactions for growth on L-malate, succinate, and fumarate.</s><s>When the Biolog GN MicroPlate assay is used, all strains oxidize Tween 40, Tween 80, methylpyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, inosine, uridine, and thymidine.</s><s>Variable reactions are detected for oxidation of L-fucose, formic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, L-histidine, L-phenylalanine, D-serine, urocanic acid, phenyl ethylamine, 2,3-butanediol, and glycerol.</s><s>None of the strains oxidizes α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cellobiose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, <i>p</i>-methybglucoside, D-psicose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucuronic acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, D-alanine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-pyroglutamic acid, DL-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, DL-α-glycerolphosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The levels of DNA relatedness range from 80 to 100%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 13:O iso, 15:0, 15:0 iso, 15:0 iso 3OH, 16:0 30H, 17:0 iso 30H, 17:1 iso <i>ω</i>9<i>c</i>, and summed feature 4.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 4029 (= NCTC 11180).</s><s>The G+C content is 30 to 35 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>