<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6350_nm.1992" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1992" rank="genus">Nitrosomonas</organism><reference id="rid.6350"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Koops</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Böttcher</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Möller</surname><given-names>U.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pommerening-Röser</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stehr</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of eight new species of ammonia-oxidizing bacteria: Nitrosomonas communis sp. nov., Nitrosomonas ureae sp. nov., Nitrosomonas aestuarii sp. nov., Nitrosomonas marina sp. nov., Nitrosomonas nitrosa sp. nov., Nitrosomonas eutropha sp. nov., Nitrosomonas oligotropha sp. nov. and Nitrosomonas halophila sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>137</volume><fpage>1689</fpage><lpage>1699</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Nitrosomonas</i> Winogradsky 1892</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nitrosomonas</i> (Ni. tro. so. mo'nas. ML adj. <i>nitrosus</i> nitrous; Gr. fem. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; ML fem. n. <i>Nitrosomonas</i> nitrite monad, i.e. the monad producing nitrite)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The emended description summarizes results of the present investigation and earlier publications (Watson, 1971a; Watson et al., 1981, 1989).</s><s>Gram-negative organisms ; marine forms can possess an additional outer protein cell wall layer.</s><s>Shape and size of cells are variable between species; generally rod-shaped to coccoid, with rounded or pointed ends.</s><s>Proclivity to grow in aggregates in mixed but not in pure cultures.</s><s>Motility rarely established, and seems to depend on the stage of culture development; motile cells bear polar flagella.</s><s>Extensive intracytoplasmic membranes arranged as flattened vesicles in the peripheral protoplasm ; sometimes intrusions into the inner protoplasm.</s><s>Carboxysomes present in some but not all species.</s><s>Cells reddish coloured due to cytochromes.</s><s>Aerobic organisms ; can grow at reduced oxygen concentration with denitrifying activities.</s><s>Obligately lithotrophic with ammonia as energy source ; urea used as ammonia source by some not all species.</s><s>Organisms generally grow autotrophically, carbon dioxide being assimilated via the Calvin cycle; can grow mixotrophically but not heterotrophically.</s><s>Terrestrial and marine forms occur; marine species are obligately halophilic.</s><s>Optimum growth at pH values between 7.5 and 8.0.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth around 30 °C, minimum temperature in general about 5 °C; one species grows at below 0 °C.</s><s>Optimum ammonia concentration for growth 10-50 mM, variable between species.</s><s>G + C content of the DNA 45.8-53.3 mol%; variable between species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species : <i>Nitrosomonas europaea</i> Winogradsky 1892, Watson 1971a.</s></p></content></protolog>