<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12305_nm.20334" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20334" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20334" rank="species">Pseudomonas arsenicoxydans</organism><reference id="rid.12305"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Campos</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valenzuela</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yarza</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidal</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zaror</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mondaca</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopez-Lopez</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Móra</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas arsenicoxydans sp nov., an arsenite-oxidizing strain isolated from the Atacama desert</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>193</fpage><lpage>197</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.02.007</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas arsenicoxydans</em> sp nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(ar.se.nic.ox’y.dans. N.L. n. arsenicum arsenic; N.L. v. oxydare to oxidize; N.L. part. adj. arsenicoxydans arsenic-oxidizing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, oxidase and catalase positive, rod shaped, of about 5.5 μm in length and 0.5–1.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Motile by means of multiple polar flagella.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C; but growth occurs between 4 and 37 °C, but not at 41 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth ranges between 7.5 and 8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.5 and 10.0, but not at pH 6.0 or 10.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–2% (w/v) NaCl; but optimal growth occurs without adding NaCl to the media.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Fluorescent pigments are not produced on King B medium.</s><s>Hydrolysis of arginine, triglyceride and urea are positive.</s><s>Enzymatic hydrolysis of p-nitrophenyl-n-acetyl-β-d-glucosaminide, and proline-β-naphthylamide are positive; and hydrolysis of aliphatic thiol, p-nitrophenyl-phosphoester, p-nitrophenyl-alpha-d-glucoside, p-nitrophenyl-β-d-glucoside, p-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactoside, pyrrolidine-β-naphthylamide, gamma-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide, tryptophan-β-naphthylamide, N-benzyl-arginine-β-naphthylamide are negative.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>Utilization of tryptophan, nitrate, and glucose is negative.</s><s>In assays with the API 20NE, l-arginine, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, potassium gluconatecapric acid are positive, but l-tryptophan, urea, aesculin, ferric citrate, p-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactopyranoside, and d-maltose are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>VC-1 could be differentiated from its closest relatives by its multiple polar flagella, its ability to grow with acetate, arabinose and sorbitol as sole carbon sources, the enzymatic activity of arginine dihydrolase (ADH), and the absence of fluorescent pigments on King B media.</s><s>In addition, none of the closest relative reference strains used could oxidize arsenite, a character that additionally differentiated VC-1.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in <a href="#tbl1">Table 1</a> and <a href="#app1">supplementary Table S1</a>.</s><s>This strain is able to tolerate 5 mM As[III] and to oxidize 100% of the arsenite present in the medium with lactate as a carbon source.</s><s>The type strain is VC-1 (CCUG 58201<sup>T</sup>; CECT 7543<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>