<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2870_nm.10296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10296" rank="species">Xylanibacter oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.2870"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akasaka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hattori</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Xylanibacter oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel strictly anaerobic, Gram-negative, xylanolytic bacterium isolated from rice-plant residue in flooded rice-field soil in Japan.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2215</fpage><lpage>2221</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64364-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957124</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Xylanibacter oryzae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Xylanibacter oryzae</em> (o′ry.zae. L. fem. n. <em>oryza</em> rice and the genus name of rice; L. gen. n. <em>oryzae</em> from/of rice or rice plants, referring to rice-plant residue from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Haemin significantly stimulates growth.</s><s>In the presence of B-vitamin mixture as well as haemin, acetate, propionate and succinate are produced as major fermentation products.</s><s>Slightly acidophilic and grows with an optimum pH of 5.7–6.2 (pH range, 4.7–7.3).</s><s>Growth temperature range is 15–35 °C with the optimum at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth at 37 °C is significantly delayed.</s><s>NaCl concentration range for growth is 0–0.5 % (w/v) in PYG medium containing haemin and B-vitamin mixture.</s><s>Utilizes arabinose, ribose, xylose, fructose, galactose, glucose, mannose, rhamnose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, CMC, soluble starch, xylan, pectin, salicin and pyruvate as growth substrates.</s><s>Acids are produced from these substrates, but gas is not.</s><s>Does not use sorbose, melezitose, cellulose powder, filter paper, inulin, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, fumarate, lactate, malate or succinate.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin is not.</s><s>Urease is negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of bile salts.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content is 43.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KB3<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13648<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17970<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from stubble and roots of rice-plant residue in anoxic rice-field soil in Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>