<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4817_nm.2984" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2984" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2984" rank="species">Vibrio mimicus</organism><reference id="rid.4817"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Madden</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bradford</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of biochemically atypical Vibrio cholerae strains and designation of a new pathogenic species, Vibrio mimicus.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>631</fpage><lpage>639</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7037833</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio mimicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio mimicus</i> (min. ic' us, M.L. noun <i>mimicus</i> to mimic, because of its similarity to <i>V. cholerae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Vibrio mimicus</i> is proposed for the sucrose-negative, cholera-like strains.</s><s>The type strain of <i>V. cholerae</i> is 1721-77 (ATCC 33653). <i>V. cholerae</i> is a gram-negative, oxidase-positive, vibrio-shaped bacterium that is motile by means of a single polar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>It is positive in the string test, is sensitive to polymyxin and to the vibriocidal agent 0/129, and grows in the absence in NaCl and in 1% NaCl; approximately 50% of the strains grow in 6% NaCl.</s><s>Negative reactions for sucrose fermentation, Voges-Proskauer, and lipase (10% positive) are the most useful diagnostic tests in separating <i>V. mimicus</i> from <i>V. cholerae</i>.</s><s>The overall biochemical reactions for <i>V. mimicus</i> are shown in Table 2, and its antibiotic susceptibility profile is shown in Table 4.</s><s>Most strains are typable in antisera produced against <i>V. cholerae</i> (Table 1). <i>V. mimicus</i> has been isolated frequently from water and shellfish, from human diarrheal stools, and ear infections (Table 1).</s><s>Some strains produce either heat-labile or heat-stable enterotoxin (Table 3).</s></p></content></protolog>