<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12481_nm.21315" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21315" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21315" rank="species">Shimia isoporae</organism><reference id="rid.12481"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shimia isoporae sp. nov., isolated from the reef-building coral Isopora palifera</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>823</fpage><lpage>827</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022848-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20453104</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shimia isoporae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shimia isoporae</em> (i.so.por′ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>isoporae</em> of <em>Isopora</em>, isolated from a coral belonging to the genus <em>Isopora</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped (0.9–1.0 µm in diameter and 2.1–2.3 µm in length) and motile by monopolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on MA are beige coloured, circular and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.7–1.0 mm in diameter on MA after 72 h incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C, 1–5 % NaCl and pH 7–11.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 25–30 °C, 3–4 % NaCl and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>No poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granule accumulation is found.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase and DNase activities and hydrolysis of Tweens 20 and 60.</s><s>Negative for lipase (corn oil) activity and hydrolysis of casein, starch, alginate, chitin, lecithin, Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for aesculin hydrolysis, β-galactosidase activity and assimilation of mannose, maltose and gluconate, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, gelatin hydrolysis, d-glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities, and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN2 MicroPlate: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to gentamicin, kanamycin, sulphamethoxazole plus trimethoprim, rifampicin, novobiocin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, penicillin G and ampicillin; resistant to tetracycline.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid (&#x003E;10 %) is summed feature 8 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>; 64.1 %).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is ubiquinone Q-10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SW6<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25377<sup>T</sup> = BCRC 80085<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the reef-building coral <em>Isopora palifera</em>, collected off the coast of southern Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 54.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>