<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1538_nm.10294" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10294" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10294" rank="species">Sphingobacterium daejeonense</organism><reference id="rid.1538"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium daejeonense sp. nov., isolated from a compost sample</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2031</fpage><lpage>2036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64406-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957095</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobacterium daejeonense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobacterium daejeonense</em> (dae.jeon.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>daejeonense</em> pertaining to Daejeon, a city in Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped (0.5–1.0 μm wide and 1.2–1.8 μm long).</s><s>After 3 days incubation at 30 °C on R2A, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, convex, round and slightly yellowish.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 42 °C; the optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.0–9.0, with an optimum between pH 6.5 and 7.0.</s><s>Tolerates 5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 7 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of chitin, starch, cellulose, DNA, xylan, casein and aesculin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-xylose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, d-adonitol and amygdalin.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, pyruvate, formate, acetate, propionate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, caprate, maleate, fumarate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, gluconate, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, glycerol, methanol, glycogen, inulin, dextran, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and the Voges–Proskauer test are positive; tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, gelatinase, hydrogen sulphide and indole production are all negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-melibiose and amygdalin, but not from l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone, and major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 38.7 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TR6-04<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12579<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23402<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52468<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from compost that was collected near Daejeon city in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>