<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2405_nm.11269" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11269" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11269" rank="species">Marinobacterium litorale</organism><reference id="rid.2405"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choo</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacterium litorale sp. nov. in the order Oceanospirillales</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1659</fpage><lpage>1662</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64892-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625212</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacterium litorale</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacterium litorale</em> (li.to.ra′le. L. neut. adj. <em>litorale</em> of the seashore, a shallow-seawater dweller).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, facultatively anaerobic, straight rods (1.2–2.0 μm long and 0.5–0.8 μm wide).</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, opaque, beige–milky in colour and 0.1 mm in diameter when observed after 2–3 days of incubation.</s><s>Growth occurs at 8–42 °C, optimally at 30 °C, but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–12 and 1.0–7.5 % NaCl, optimally at pH 9.0 and 3.0–3.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are positive.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are negative.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin and acid phosphatase activities are present.</s><s>Based on the tests contained in the Biolog GN2 microplate, the following carbon substrates are utilized: pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em> -ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine, <em>γ</em> -aminobutyric acid and phenyl ethylamine.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon sources weakly: glycogen, Tween 80, i-erythritol, d-galacturonic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-ornithine, putrescine and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are not utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but resistant to vancomycin.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (36.6 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH (26.7 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (24.3 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5.2 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (3.5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.2 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0.8 %) and C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0.7 %).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone type is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 60.6±0.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1877<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12756<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23872<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface seawater of the coast of Deokjeok island, Yellow Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>