<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4255_nm.1858" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1858" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1858" rank="species">Tepidimonas ignava</organism><reference id="rid.4255"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moreira</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Silva</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tepidimonas ignava gen. nov., sp. nov., a new chemolithoheterotrophic and slightly thermophilic member of the beta-Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>742</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tepidimonas ignava</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tepidimonas ignava</i> (ig.na'va. L. adj. <i>ignavus</i> lazy, pertaining to the organism's trait not to use sugars for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms short rod-shaped cells 1.0-2.0 μm in length and 0.5-1.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Gram stain is negative.</s><s>The cells are motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Degryse 162 medium are not pigmented and are 1-2 mm in diameter after 60 h growth.</s><s>Growth occurs above 35 °C and below 65 °C; the optimum growth temperature for strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> is 50-55 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH is between pH 7.5 and 8.5; growth does not occur at pH 6.0 or pH 10.0.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C16:0 and C17:0; unsaturated fatty acids are also present in large amounts.</s><s>Ubiquinone 8 is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>Strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> is strictly aerobic, and positive for cytochrome oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Yeast extract or growth factors are required for growth.</s><s>Strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Thiosulfate is oxidized to sulfate and serves as an energy source coupled to the assimilation of organic substrates.</s><s>Strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> is not chemoautotrophic on reduced sulfur compounds.</s><s>Urease is positive; methyl red, Voges-Proskauer and indole are negative.</s><s>Hide powder is degraded, but xylan, starch, casein, elastin and fibrin are not.</s><s>Several amino acids and organic acids are utilized for growth but strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> does not utilize hexoses, disaccharides, pentoses or polyols.</s><s>The DNA of strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> has a G+­C content of 69±7 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from the hot spring at São Pedro do Sul in central Portugal.</s><s>Strain SPS-1037<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 12034<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>