<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5520_nm.9829" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9829" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9829" rank="species">Lactobacillus sobrius</organism><reference id="rid.5520"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Konstantinov</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poznanski</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuentes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akkermans</surname><given-names>A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smidt</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Vos</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus sobrius sp. nov., abundant in the intestine of weaning piglets.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>29</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63508-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403862</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus sobrius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus sobrius</em> (so′bri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>sobrius</em> sober, moderate; in Calvinism, referring to a hard working, invisible person).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods that are 0·6–1·0 μm in width and 2·0–20·0 μm in length and occur singly, in pairs or often in long chains.</s><s>Colonies are 1·4–2 mm in diameter, circular to slightly irregular to rough in form and white when the organism is grown on MRS agar at 37 °C for 2 days.</s><s>There is no growth at 15 °C, but the bacterium grows at 45 °C.</s><s>The organism is facultatively anaerobic and produces d- and l-lactic acid homofermentatively.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced without gas formation from d-glucose, d-mannose, maltose, galactose, d-fructose, lactose, aesculin, sucrose, starch, mannitol (two of six strains), cellobiose (three of six strains), salicin (two of six strains), trehalose (two of six strains), amygdalin (two of six strains, weak reaction), <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine (two of six strains), ribose (two of six strains, weak reaction), glycogen (three of six strains) and 5-ketogluconate (two of six strains, weak reaction).</s><s>FOS and unidentified compounds of SBP are also fermented by all strains.</s><s>There is no acid formation from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, melezitose, rhamnose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, sorbitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, arbutin, inulin, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 35–36 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, OTU171-001<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16698<sup>T</sup>=NCCB 100067<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from pig intestine.</s></p></content></protolog>