<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1611_nm.10638" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10638" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10638" rank="species">Brevibacillus ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.1611"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacillus ginsengisoli sp. nov., a denitrifying bacterium isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2665</fpage><lpage>2669</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64382-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082408</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacillus ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacillus ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of the soil of a ginseng field, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, motile, slightly curved rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 3.5–5.0 μm in length after 2 days culture on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 2 days are smooth, circular, glossy, white and convex.</s><s>Central and subterminal oval spores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Grows well at 20–42 °C and pH 5.0–8.5, but does not grow at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 2.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Able to grow anaerobically in denitrifying conditions.</s><s>Xylan, chitin, starch, cellulose and DNA are not degraded.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production, acid production and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (see Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>Urease, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, protease and malic acid assimilation are positive in tests using API 20E and API 20NE strips.</s><s>Reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, tryptophan deaminase, idole production, acetoin production and adipic acid assimilation are negative.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in the API 50 CH and ID 32GN tests: glycerol, d-glucose, salicin, d-celiobiose, sodium acetate, l-serine, valeric acid, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline.</s><s>Tests are negative for the utilization of the following substrates: erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, propionic acid, capric acid, trisodium citrate and 4-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 52.1 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 3088<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13938<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23403<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>