<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8784_nm.13226" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13226" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13226" rank="species">Aurantimonas frigidaquae</organism><reference id="rid.8784"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoa</surname><given-names>K.T.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aurantimonas frigidaquae sp. nov., isolated from a water-cooling system.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1142</fpage><lpage>1146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65421-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450703</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aurantimonas frigidaquae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aurantimonas frigidaquae</em> (fri.gi.da′quae. L. adj. <em>frigidus</em> cold; L. fem. n. <em>aqua</em> water; N.L. gen. n. <em>frigidaquae</em> from/of cold water, because the type strain was isolated from a water-cooling system).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short rods (0.6–0.8×0.8–1.2 μm).</s><s>Gram-negative, motile, facultatively anaerobic and yellow-pigmented bacterium.</s><s>Grows best on media such as TSA, NA and R2A.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey medium.</s><s>Colonies on TSA agar are convex, circular, smooth, opaque with entire margins, approximately 3 mm in diameter after 5 days at 25 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–7 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum growth in the absence of NaCl).</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–11 (optimum pH 7) and at 15–37 °C (optimum 25 °C).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present, but lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, l-phenylalanine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities are absent.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but casein, DNA, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from 0.5 % (w/v) glucose, but not from maltose.</s><s>Negative for methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions.</s><s>No precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>In API 50CH tests, acid is produced from cellobiose, d-fucose, fructose, raffinose, sucrose, adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, inositol, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin and salicin, but not from lactose, melezitose, d-tagatose, dulcitol, glycerol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, inulin, glycogen, starch, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase activities are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β-</em>glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300 U), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30), but resistant to bacitracin (10), penicillin (10 U) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (64.7 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14.1 %); the complete fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CW5<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12893<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14755<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a water-cooling system at Gwangyang, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>