<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5980_nm.8478" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8478" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8478" rank="species">Arthrobacter gangotriensis</organism><reference id="rid.5980"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Delille</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter gangotriensis sp. nov. and Arthrobacter kerguelensis sp. nov. from Antarctica</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2375</fpage><lpage>2378</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63110-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545486</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter gangotriensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter gangotriensis</em> (gan.go.tri.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>gangotriensis</em> pertaining to the Indian Antarctic station Dakshin Gangotri).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, psychrotolerant, Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, yellow-pigmented and exhibit a rod–coccus cycle.</s><s>Grows between 4 and 30 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature and pH for growth are 22 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, phosphatase, urease and gelatinase and negative for methyl red, indole and Voges–Proskauer tests, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and arginine decarboxylase.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin, Tween 80 or starch and does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-galactose and d-mannose but not from d-arabinose, d-glucose, lactose, d-mannitol, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Can utilize adonitol, d-arabinose, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, d-galactose, inulin, d-fructose, d-glucose, pyruvate, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, d-xylose, xylitol, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glycine and l-phenylalanine but not glycerol, d-mannitol, d-rhamnose, trehalose, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine or tryptophan as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Resistant to nalidixic acid and nitrofurantoin but sensitive to amikacin, ampicillin, cefoperazone, cefuroxime, ciprofloxacin, co-trimoxazole, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, lincomycin, lomefloxacin, norfloxacin, penicillin, roxithromycin, streptomycin, tetracycline, tobramycin and vancomycin.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinones MK-8, MK-9 and MK-10 are present in the ratio 1 : 4·5 : 2.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids at 25 °C are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (61·6 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5·8 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (9·0 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5·5 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (4·0 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (3·0 %) and C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (4·2 %) (details available as supplementary material in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The yellow pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits three absorption maxima, at 494, 528 and 571·5 nm.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan type is Lys–Glu (variation A4<em>α</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Lz1y<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15796<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12166<sup>T</sup>), isolated from penguin rookery soil.</s></p></content></protolog>