<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3007_nm.11734" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11734" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7534" rank="species">Nocardiopsis alborubidus</organism><reference id="rid.3007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grund</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemotaxonomy and numerical taxonomy of the genus Nocardiopsis Meyer 1976.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-5</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis alborubidus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on the studies carried out by the ISP (33) and on our observations of strain DSM 40465<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Usually there is no pigmentation of the substrate mycelium; however, on some substrates, such as melezitose, a brownish-red pigmentation of the substrate mycelium appears.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is in the white color series, and the spore chains are recti-flexibilis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Calcium oxalate, esculin, and adenine are hydrolyzed; hypoxanthine, tyrosine, and xanthine are not.</s><s>Glucose, arabinose, xylose, fructose, melezitose, rhamnose, sucrose, dextrin, adonitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, and sorbitol are used as sole sources of carbon, and no growth is observed with melibiose, cellobiose, raffinose, or lactose as the carbon source.</s><s>An alkaline reaction is observed with quinate, citrate, lactate, malate, and malonate.</s><s>The organism can grow in the presence of 5% NaCl but not in the presence of 50 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Benzoic acid, salicylic acid, and parahydroxybenzoic acid are degraded, but <i>meta</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid is not.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C, and no growth occurs at 45°C.</s><s>The organism is alkali tolerant and grows at pH 11.5.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis alborubidus</i> is strain DSM 40465 (= ATTC 23612 = ISP 5465 =INA 6476/62 = CBS 693 = RIA 1953 = IFO 13392 = KCCS-0717).</s></p></content></protolog>