<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4354_nm.10930" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10930" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10930" rank="species">Paracoccus homiensis</organism><reference id="rid.4354"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus homiensis sp. nov., isolated from a sea-sand sample.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2387</fpage><lpage>2390</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64275-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012567</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus homiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus homiensis</em> (ho.mi.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>homiensis</em> pertaining to Homi Cape, South Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming and rod- to ovoid-shaped (0.7–2.5×0.5–0.7 μm).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, convex and colourless to creamy white.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 40 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum pH 6.0–8.0).</s><s>Grows optimally at 3–5 % NaCl and weakly at 15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase and hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin, Tween 80 and tyrosine.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, hydrolysis of alginic acid, casein, carboxymethylcellulose, pectin, starch and urea.</s><s>Enzymic activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but no activity is observed for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes Tween 80, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, iso-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, phenylethylamine and glycerol.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, lactulose, maltose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content is 63.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DD-R11<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11518<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17862<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sea-sand sample collected from Homi Cape, Pohang city, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>