<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5069_nm.1568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1568" rank="species">Rhodoplanes elegans</organism><reference id="rid.5069"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoplanes gen. nov., a new genus of phototrophic bacteria including Rhodopseudomonas rosea as Rhodoplanes roseus comb. nov. and Rhodoplanes elegans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>665</fpage><lpage>673</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodoplanes elegans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodoplanes elegans</i> (e'le.gans. L. adj. <i>elegans</i>, choice, elegant)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are the same as the characteristics described above for the genus.</s><s>Additional properties are as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.8 to 1.0 μm wide and 2.0 to 3.5 μm long.</s><s>Reproduce by budding with a division tube occurring between the mother and daughter cells.</s><s>Rosettes and clusters are formed in older cultures.</s><s>Absorption maxima of cell extracts are at 373, 466, 491, 527, 592, 799, and 855 nm.</s><s>The pH range for phototrophic growth is 6.0 to 8.5.</s><s>Thiamine and <i>p</i>-aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors.</s><s>The following organic compounds are photoassimilated: acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, malate, citrate, tartrate, Casamino Acids, and yeast extract.</s><s>The following organic compounds are not utilized: formate, long-chain fatty acids with more than six carbon atoms, glycolate, malonate, benzoate, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, fructose, glucose, mannose, galactose, dulcitol, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, propanol, alanine, aspartate, asparagine, glutamate, and leucine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69.6 to 69.7 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from activated sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AS130, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, RIKEN, Wako, Japan, as R. elegans JCM 9224.</s></p></content></protolog>