<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1753_nm.8764" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8764" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8764" rank="species">Paenibacillus timonensis</organism><reference id="rid.1753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus massiliensis sp. nov., Paenibacillus sanguinis sp. nov. and Paenibacillus timonensis sp. nov., isolated from blood cultures.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1049</fpage><lpage>1054</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02954-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus timonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus timonensis</em> (ti.mo.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>timonensis</em> from the name Hôpital de la Timone, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic rods (0·5 μm wide, 2·0 μm long).</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are greyish, translucent, shiny, 1·5 mm in diameter, regularly shaped and low convex after incubation for 24 h at 30 °C.</s><s>Bacteria are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Catalase-positive, but oxidase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30–37 °C, but growth is not inhibited at 50 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the presence of 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced weakly, but gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from blood culture, is strain 2301032<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108005<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 48216<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>