<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6686_nm.8304" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8304" rank="genus">Hymenobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6686"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Buczolits</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Hymenobacter norwichensis sp. nov., classification of 'Taxeobacter ocellatus', 'Taxeobacter gelupurpurascens' and 'Taxeobacter chitinovorans' as Hymenobacter ocellatus sp. nov., Hymenobacter gelipurpurascens sp. nov. and Hymenobacter chitinivorans sp. nov., respectively, and emended description of the genus Hymenobacter Hirsch et al. 1999.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2071</fpage><lpage>2078</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64371-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957101</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Hymenobacter</em> Hirsch <em>et al.</em> 1999</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics summarized by Hirsch <em>et al.</em> (1998), several other genus-specific characteristics can be identified.</s><s>Temperature maximum is up to 42 °C but most strains do not grow at this temperature.</s><s>All members have a polar lipid profile containing phosphatidylethanolamine, an unknown aminophospholipid (APL3) and two unknown polar lipids (L3, L5) and a mixture of several other unknown aminophospholipids, aminolipids, phospholipids, glycolipids and polar lipids.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of predominantly branched fatty acids of the iso- and anteiso-type with iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I/anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B) always present in moderate to major amounts.</s><s><em>sym</em>-Homospermidine is the major compound in the polyamine pattern and the quinone system is MK-7.</s><s>Highly sensitive to the action of numerous antibiotics.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of species within the genus ranges from 55 to 65 mol%.</s><s>Currently comprises seven species, <em>Hymenobacter actinosclerus</em>, <em>Hymenobacter aerophilus</em>, <em>Hymenobacter norwichensis</em>, <em>Hymenobacter chitinivorans</em>, <em>Hymenobacter gelipurpurascens</em>, <em>Hymenobacter ocellatus</em> and <em>Hymenobacter roseosalivarius</em> (type species of the genus).</s></p></content></protolog>