<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4442_nm.11764" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11764" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5463" rank="species">Aerococcus sanguicola</organism><reference id="rid.4442"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Truberg-Jensen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aerococcus sanguicola sp. nov., isolated from a human clinical source.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>475</fpage><lpage>479</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321093</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aerococcus sanguicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aerococcus sanguicola</i> (san.gui'co.la. L. n. <i>sanguis</i> blood; L. subst. <i>cola</i> dweller; M.L. n. <i>sanguicola</i> blood-dweller, pertaining to the initial isolation source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci that occur singly, in pairs, in tetrads or in small groups.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows in 6±5% NaCl.</s><s>Colonies are small (&#x003C;1 mm in diameter), entire and non-pigmented when grown on Columbia horse-blood agar.</s><s>α-Haemolytic and produces a positive reaction in the bile-aesculin test.</s><s>When commercial API systems are used, acid is produced from maltose, sucrose and trehalose but not from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, pullulan, sorbitol, tagatose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-dglucopyranoside, D-raffinose, D-ribose or D-xylose.</s><s>Positive reactions for acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, cysteine arylamidase, esterase C-4 (weak reaction), β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, chymotrypsin, ester lipase C8, α-fructosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, glycine-tryptophan arylamidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, phosphoamidase, trypsin and urease.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Isolated from human blood.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 43001<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106533<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>