<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1226_nm.3667" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3667" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3667" rank="species">Syntrophus buswellii</organism><reference id="rid.1226"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mountfort</surname><given-names>D.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brulla</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophus buswellii gen. nov., sp. nov.: a benzoate catabolizer from methanogenic ecosystems.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>216</fpage><lpage>217</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-216</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophus buswellii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophus buswellii</i> (bus. wel'li.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <i>buswellii</i> in honor of A. M. Buswell, who first demonstrated degradation of benzoate in enrichments from methanogenic ecosystems)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description is the same as the description given above for the genus,with the following additions. <i>S. buswellii</i> does not use acetate, adipate, aspartate, 4-amino-benzoate, butyrate, cellobiose, ethanol, fructose, glucose, <i>n</i>-heptanoate, <i>n</i>-hexanoate, succinate, methanol, phenylacetate, pimelate, propionate, or <i>n</i>-valerate and probably does not use cyclohexanone, ferulate, phenol, or vanillate, but does use benzoate as an energy source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DM-2 (= DSM 2612A and DSM 2612B).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid has not been determined yet because of the necessity for coculture with other species, but this might be done if the deoxyribonucleic acid is sufficiently different from that of the hydrogenotroph or if the deoxyribonucleic acid can be obtained free of the deoxyribonucleic acid of the hydrogenotroph.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In cocultures <i>S. buswellii</i> has extremely long generation times of 166 h (strain DSM 2612B), 132 h (strain DSM 2612A), and 96 h (with fumarate and no sulfate added; (strain DSM 2612B).</s><s>We hypothesize that a shorter generation time of 50 to 70 h could be obtained by coculture of <i>S. buswellii</i> with Wolinella succinogenes and fumarate as the electron acceptor for H<sub>2</sub> and formate oxidation.</s><s>Experiments with two different species have indicated these shorter generation times (S.</s><s>Barik and M.</s><s>P.</s><s>Bryant, unpublished data).</s></p></content></protolog>