<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.53_nm.7913" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7913" rank="genus">Fibrobacter</organism><reference id="rid.53"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Montgomery</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flesher</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stahl</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Bacteroides succinogenes (Hungate) to Fibrobacter gen. nov. as Fibrobacter succinogenes comb. nov. and description of Fibrobacter intestinalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>430</fpage><lpage>435</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fibrobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fibrobacter</i> (Fi. bro. bac'ter. L. fem. n. <i>fibra</i>, fiber or filament in plants or animals; M. L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, equivalent of bacterium, a small rod; M. L. masc. n. <i>Fibrobacter</i>, small rod specialized to subsist on fiber)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, gram-negative, nonsporing rods or pleomorphic ovoid cells that are not detectably motile, notwithstanding their apparent migration through agar medium.</s><s>Ferment a narrow range of carbohydrates, including cellulose and cellobiose.</s><s>The major fermentation products are succinic and acetic acids, sometimes with a small amount of formic acid.</s><s>The cells require carbon dioxide, straight-chain and branched-chain saturated fatty acids, and one or more vitamins; ammonia is essential as the nitrogen source.</s><s>In the strains tested, sphingophospholipids are absent (26), and isoacids are a minor part of the fatty acids (19); ethanolamine plasmologen constitutes a majority of the phospholipid (41).</s><s>Distinct from other organisms tested based on 16s rRNA sequence homology data.</s><s>The G+C content is 45 to 51 mol% (27) (Table 3).</s><s>Habitats include mammalian gastrointestinal tracts.</s><s>The only species known at this time are <i>Fibrobacter succinogenes</i> and <i>Fibrobacter intestinalis</i>.</s><s>Other members of <i>Fibrobacter</i> may be isolated with characteristics which differ from currently known strains, thus requiring emendation of the present description.</s><s>The members of the genus <i>Fibrobacter</i> can be distinguished from members of other genera of anaerobic, immotile, gram-negative rods (and coccoid organisms) by their ability to digest cellulose with succinic and acetic acids as the primary fermentation products (Table 4).</s><s>The type species is <i>Fibrobacter succinogenes</i> (Hungate 1950) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>