<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2241_nm.2506" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2506" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2506" rank="species">Halomonas halodurans</organism><reference id="rid.2241"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hebert</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vreeland</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic comparison of halotolerant bacteria: Halomonas halodurans sp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>347</fpage><lpage>350</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-347</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas halodurans</i> sp. nov., nom. rev., comb nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas halodurans</i> (ha. lo. dur'ans. Gr. n. <i>hals</i>, salt, the sea; L. v. <i>durare</i>, to last out, to endure; <i>halodurans</i>, to endure salt)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism was first described as “<i>Pseudomonas halodurans</i>” by Rosenberg (11).</s><s>Gram-negative rods, growing singly, in pairs, and in chains.</s><s>Produces smooth, glistening, translucent white, convex colonies with entire edges that are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 24 h at either 20 or 30°C on either Bacto-Marine agar without added NaCl or Casamino Acids medium supplemented with 8% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 20°C in media without NaCl and 30°C in media containing 8% NaCl.</s><s>When tested in media containing either 1.7 or 8% NaCl, the species gives positive results for catalase, lysine decarboxylase, acid production from galactose, glucose, fructose, and ribose, and use of L-lysine as a sole carbon source.</s><s>The species is also consistently negative for acetylmethyl carbinol production, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and indole production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When tested in media containing 8% NaCl, the species is positive for urease, production of acid from arabinose and xylose, and utilization of inulin, mannitol, and creatine.</s><s>If the tests are conducted in 1.7% NaCl, these same tests can be expected to yield negative results.</s><s>In 1.7% NaCl the species reduces NO<sub>3</sub> to NO<sub>2</sub> but is negative for this test in 8% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When grown in media containing 8% NaCl, the species is positive for esculin hydrolysis, ornithine decarboxylase, and malonate utilization.</s><s>The species also uses L-glutamine, proline, pyruvic acid, glycine, glycerol, DL-glycerophosphate, L-alanine, DL-threonine, DL-tryptophan, mannitol, and leucine.</s><s>The species is negative for phenylalanine deaminase, utilization of arabinose, inositol, adonitol, and sorbitol, beta-galactosidase, and acid production from mannose and lactose.</s><s>This organism cannot use phenylalanine or methionine as a sole carbon source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In media without salt, strains are susceptible to tetracycline (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), chloromycin (30 μg), polymixin B (30 μg), erythromycin (30 μg), and nalidixic acid (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 63.2 ± 1.1 mol% (thermal denaturation and</s></p><p class="description"><s>bouyant density methods).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species is strain ATCC 29686<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from Great Bay Estuary, New Hampshire.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiation of <i>H. elongata</i> and <i>H . halodurans</i>. <i>H. elongata</i> produces beta-galactosidase, utilizes DL-serine, L-cysteine, dihydrocholesterol, heptadecanoic acid, and L-tyrosine as sole carbon sources, whereas <i>H. halodurans</i> is negative for these characteristics. <i>H. halodurans</i> utilizes inulin, whereas <i>H. elongata</i> does not.</s><s>These differential characteristics should be determined by using media containing 8% NaCl at 30°C.</s></p></content></protolog>