<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4730_nm.3337" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3337" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3337" rank="species">Tatumella ptyseos</organism><reference id="rid.4730"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hickman</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tatumella ptyseos gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Enterobacteriaceae found in clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>79</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7263854</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tatumella ptyseos</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tatumella ptyseos</i> (pronunciation, tie' see us, this epithet is treated as a modern Latin genitive noun derived from the Greek noun ptyseos, meaning "a spitting.")</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain H36 (=ATCC 33301, =CDC D6168, =CDC 9591-78) is the type strain for this species. <i>T. ptyseos</i> is the type species for the genus <i>Tatumella</i>.</s><s>We propose the following citations of the genus and species, which recognize the greater contributions of three of the authors: <i>Tatumella</i> Hollis, Hickman and Fanning; <i>Tatumella ptyseos</i> Hollis, Hickman and Fanning.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The proposed genus has only one species; therefore, the description is a combined generic and specific description.</s><s>The cells are gram-negative rods which are 0.6 to 0.8 by 0.9 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Some filaments may be formed.</s><s>Endospores have not been observed.</s><s>One strain, strain H25, is motile at 36°C (3 to 5 days), and 66% are weakly motile (3 to 7 days) at 25°C.</s><s>Flagella are difficult to demonstrate, but they appear to be single polar, subpolar, and lateral and, rarely, bipolar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On blood agar at 24 h, colonies are 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter, low convex with entire edges, semitranslucent, smooth, and glossy.</s><s>The colonies are not as large as those of most species of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>, but <i>T. ptyseos</i> strains do grow on MacConkey, eosin methylene blue, Tergitol 7, and brilliant green agars.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25 and 36°C, but not at 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. ptyseos</i> strains ferment D-glucose, produce catalase, reduce nitrate to nitrite, and are positive for phenylalanine and VP (Coblentz method).</s><s>Oxidase, urease, indole, L-lysine decarboxylase, L-ornithine decarboxylase, and gelatin tests are negative.</s><s>The L-arginine dihydrolase reaction is variable.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, sucrose, trehalose, salicin, D-mannose and (usually) D-xylose, melibiose, and glycerol without gas formation.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-mannitol, lactose, or maltose.</s><s>Simmons citrate tests are usually positive at 25 but not 36°C.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of the <i>T. ptyseos</i> type strain is 54 mol%. <i>T. ptyseos</i> is susceptible as deternined by the broth dilution method to amikacin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, tetracycline, and tobramycin.</s><s>Because <i>T. ptyseos</i> grows poorly on Mueller-Hinton agar, categorizing it as sensitive, intermediate, or resistant by the disk diffusion method in the same way that rapidly growing <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> are categorized may not be appropriate.</s><s>The most frequent source of isolates has been sputum.</s><s>Strains have also been isolated from the throat and pharynx, from blood, from a tracheal aspirate, from a stool, from urine, and from a feeding tube.</s><s>One strain which was isolated from sputum and was referred to our laboratory was reported to have been in nearly pure culture, and three strains from sputum and one strain from a throat were isolated with other flora present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 8 shows some characteristics useful for presumptive identification of <i>T. ptyseos</i>.</s><s>For a detailed description of the genus, see Tables 2 through 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Our description of <i>T. ptyseos</i> is largely compatible with the definition of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>The main difference is flagellation.</s><s>Other motile members of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> have peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Peritrichous flagella have been defined as flagella which are arranged haphazardly around the whole cell (15).</s><s>The motility of <i>T. ptyseos</i> is weak, and flagella are difficult to demonstrate.</s><s>Usually, only one flagellum, (either polar, subpolar, or lateral) is observed per cell.</s><s>Only rarely are cells with two or three flagella observed.</s><s>This organism can be identified without performing a flagellum stain.</s><s>Another distinct characteristic of <i>T. ptyseos</i> is that it grows more lightly and does not survive on laboratory media as well as other members of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>At the beginning of this study, we found that two of nine strains received in the Enteric Section had become nonviable in our stock media (10, 13).</s><s>These two strains were 3 and 5 years old.</s><s>All of the 37 Special Bacteriology Section strains had been frozen at -400C in defibrinated rabbit blood for up to 14 years and were viable.</s><s>Although a controlled study was not done, we found that <i>T. ptyseos</i> did not survive on blood plates for more than 1 week.</s><s>We recommend that this organism be maintained frozen at -70 to -40°C.</s><s>The large zone of inhibition around penicillin (average size diameter, 24 mm) is also an unusual characteristic and may result because <i>T. ptyseos</i> grows poorly on Mueller-Hinton medium.</s><s>Most of the members of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> that have been tested in the Enteric Section are either resistant to penicillin or have smaller zones of inhibition (unpublished data); however, <i>S. typhi</i> is known to have a fairly large zone of inhibition with penicillin (12).</s><s>The biochemical reactions of <i>T. ptyseos</i> are most similar to those of <i>E. agglomerans</i> and <i>C. violaceum</i>.</s><s>This organism can be differentiated from <i>E. agglomerans</i> on the basis of its mannitol- negative reaction.</s><s>The type strain of <i>T. ptyseos</i> was 38% related to one DNA hybridization group of <i>E. agglomerans</i>. <i>T. ptyseos</i> can be distinguished from <i>C. violaceum</i> because <i>T. ptyseos</i> is VP positive, gelatin negative, and often xylose positive. <i>T. ptyseos</i> DNA was essentially unrelated to DNA from the type strain of <i>C. violaceum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We have a limited amount of clinical information on 14 of the patients from whom <i>T. ptyseos</i> was isolated.</s><s>One of the three blood isolates was from an 8-year-old male with leukemia, and one was from a male (age unknown) with an abdominal tumor; however, there was no information on the third blood isolate.</s><s>The tracheal aspirate was from a 15-year-old male who developed pneumonitis after heart surgery.</s><s>Other clinical diagnoses and associated illnesses included asthmatic bronchitis, pharyngitis (source, pharynx), ataxia telangiectasis, neuromuscular disease (source, feeding tube), Wegener granulomatosis, pneumonia, pulmonary edema, chronic lung disease, seizures (etiology unknown), respiratory failure, and gastroenteritis (source, stool).</s><s>Of the 30 patients whose sex is known, 19 were male, and 11 were female.</s><s>Of the 20 patients whose age is known, 14 were adults and 6 were children (15 years old or younger).</s><s>The clinical importance of this organism is not known.</s><s>However, the small amount of clinical information available suggests that it may be an opportunistic pathogen, since the immune systems of several of the patients were compromised.</s><s>The incidence of <i>T. ptyseos</i> is unknown.</s><s>Perhaps this report will stimulate others to search for this organism.</s></p></content></protolog>