<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.591_nm.2493" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2493" rank="genus">Halomonas</organism><reference id="rid.591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vreeland</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Litchfield</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>E.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elliot</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas elongata, a new genus and species of extremely salt-tolerant bacteria.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>485</fpage><lpage>495</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halomonas</i> (Gr. n. <i>hals</i>, <i>halos</i> salt, the sea; Gr. <i>monas</i> small rod; M . L. fem. n. <i>Halomonas</i> the salt short rods)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and occur singly or in pairs in the logarithmic phase of growth.</s><s>Elongated, flexuous rods are produced during the stationary growth phase in complex medium.</s><s>In chemically defined media, shorter flexuous rods are observed in approximately 25% of the cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Flagellar arrangement depends on the strain, but it is either lateral or polar.</s><s>On solid, complex media containing 8% salt, colonies are white to cream, opaque, and less than 2 mm in diameter; spreading may occur after extended incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>NO<sub>3</sub> is reduced to NO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Catalase positive; generally Kovac oxidase positive, but all strains are cytochrome oxidase negative.</s><s>Ornithine and lysine are decarboxylated, but phenylalanine is not deaminated; H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from cysteine; and casein and starch are not usually hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose is fermented without gas production.</s><s>Glycerol, sucrose, mannose, and cellobiose are oxidized.</s><s>These carbohydrates can also serve as sole carbon sources with (N<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> as the nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All cultures are susceptible to HgCl<sub>2</sub> (1:5,000), and most are suscpetible to chloromycetin (30 U).</s><s>Generally resistant to penicillin (10 U), ampicillin (30 U), tetracycline (30 U), 2,4-diamino- 6,7-diisopropyl pteridine (Vibriostat O/129), no vobiocin (30 U), streptomycin (10 μg), bacitracin (10 U), nalidixic acid (30 U), and neomycin (30 U).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs from pH 5 to 9 in Casamino Acid medium containing 8% solar salt.</s><s>The strains grow in Casamino Acid medium or nutrient broth without added salt or in similar media containing up to 32% solar salt when incubated at temperatures of 23 to 37°C.</s><s>Growth can also occur in media with 3.5 to 20% solar salt at 15 and 45°C.</s><s>Optimum conditions for growth on complex media are 3.5 to 8% solar salt (wt/vol) at 30 or 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 60.5 ± 0.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>H. elongata</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>