<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8810_nm.13356" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13356" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13356" rank="species">Halomonas nitroreducens</organism><reference id="rid.8810"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González-Domenech</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas nitroreducens sp. nov., a novel nitrate- and nitrite-reducing species.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>872</fpage><lpage>876</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65415-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398185</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas nitroreducens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas nitroreducens</em> (ni.tro.re.du′cens. Gr. n. <em>nitron</em> potassium nitrate, saltpetre; L. adj. from pres. part. of verb <em>reduco</em> reduce, convert to a different condition; N.L. adj. <em>nitroreducens</em> reducing nitrate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 1.5–2.2×0.4–0.5 μm, appearing either singly or in pairs.</s><s>The cells are non-motile.</s><s>It produces exopolysaccharide, accumulates polyhydroxyalkanoate and does not form endospores.</s><s>Cell colonies are circular, convex, creamy white in colour and quite mucoid.</s><s>Its growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>It is a moderate halophile, capable of growing in NaCl concentrations of 3–20 % w/v, with optimum growth at 5–7.5 % w/v.</s><s>It is not able to grow without NaCl or in NaCl concentrations lower than 3 % w/v or higher than 20 % w/v.</s><s>Growth was tested within the temperature range of 4–45 °C (4, 15, 20, 25, 32, 37 and 45 °C), with positive results within the whole range and with optimum growth between 20 and 32 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth was tested from pH 5 to 10 at intervals of 1 pH unit, growing between these limits (optimum growth between pH 7.0 and 9.0).</s><s>It resists heating to 80 °C for 10 min.</s><s>It is chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Its metabolism is of the respiratory type with oxygen, nitrate and nitrite as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>It produces gas from nitrate and nitrite in anaerobiosis.</s><s>It is catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Gluconate is not oxidized.</s><s>It does not produce acids from adonitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose or trehalose.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>It reduces selenite, nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>It hydrolyses urea, gelatin and tyrosine but not aesculin, starch, Tween 20, Tween 80, lecithin, casein or blood.</s><s>DNase is produced but not phosphatase.</s><s>It does not produce phenylalanine deaminase or pigment from tyrosine.</s><s>It grows on MacConkey agar and cetrimide agar.</s><s>ONPG is negative.</s><s>The following compounds are acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, ethanol, d-fructose, lactose, fumarate, d-galactose, dl-glycerol, gluconate, d-glucose, lactate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, propionate, sorbitol, starch, succinate and trehalose.</s><s>The following compounds are not acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, aesculin, l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, malonate and d-salicin.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-lysine, l-histidine and l-serine are used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>l-Cysteine, dl-isoleucine, l-methionine and l-valine are not used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>It is susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), aztreonam (30 μg), cefalotin (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), penicillin (10 μg), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (30 μg), sulfamide (250 μg) and trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1.25/23.75 μg).</s><s>It is resistant to tobramycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Principal fatty acids are (%): 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (29.92), 16 : 0 (27.80), 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-15 : 0 2-OH (22.30), 12 : 0 3-OH (5.56), 12 : 0 (2.10), 10 : 0 (2.08) and 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (7.02).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.37 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 11S<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7281<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24185<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>It was isolated from a solar saltern in Cahuil, a region close to Pichilemu in Chile.</s></p></content></protolog>