<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2191_nm.973" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.973" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.973" rank="species">Rickettsia slovaca</organism><reference id="rid.2191"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sekeyová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rehácek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia slovaca sp. nov., a member of the spotted fever group rickettsiae.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1455</fpage><lpage>1462</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1455</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828449</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia slovaca</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia slovaca</i> (slo.va.ca'. L. gen. n. <i>slovaca</i> from Slovakia, the country where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately intracellular Gram-negative bacteria.</s><s>Most of the strains were isolated from <i>Dermacentor marginatus</i> ticks (Řeháček et al., 1972).</s><s>However, rickettsial strains closely related to <i>R. slovaca</i> were detected and isolated from <i>Ixodes ricinus</i> (Urvolgyi &#x0026; Brezina, 1978; Řeháček, 1984), <i>Haemaphisali punctata</i> (Řeháček et al., 1972,, <i>Haemaphisalis inermis</i> (Řeháček, 1984), <i>Ixodes hexagonus</i> (Sixl et al., 1973) and <i>Argus persicus</i> (Řeháček et al., 1977b).</s><s>Distribution of <i>R. slovaca</i> widely exceeds the borders of the Slovak and Czech Republics.</s><s>It has since been isolated in Armenia (Balayeva tit al., 1994; Makarova et al., 1978; Řeháček et al., 1977b; Tarasevich et al., 1976), Crimea (Balayeya et al.. 1993), The Ukraine (Balayeva et al., 1993; Urvolgyi &#x0026; Brezina, 1978), France (Beati et al., 1993; Raoult (it al., 1997), Switzerland (Beati et al., 1994), Yugoslavia (Manor et al., 1992; Sixl et al., 1976) and Portugal (Bacellar et al., 1995).</s><s>Positive serology was reported from the Lithucnian Republic (Tarasevich et al., 1981 1, Germany (Řeháček et al., 1977a) and Austria (Sixl et al., 1973).</s><s>It therefore seems to closely follow the distribution of its main host tick, <i>D. marginatus</i>, which can be found throughout Europe and as far as the western border of the People's Republic of China (Eremeeva et al., 1993) (Fig. 2). <i>R. slovaca</i> eshibits features characteristic of those of the SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>It is a typical rod-shaped rickettsia, with di%ensions of approximately 0.37-0.45 x 0.8- 1.2 μm (Řeháček, 1984). <i>R. slovaca</i> can be propagated on chicken embryo, HEL, Vero, L929 and tick cells, although no cytopathologic changes in any of the cell cultures inoculated (despite the high multiplicity of infected) have been noted (Beati et al., 1993; Řeháček, 1984; Řeháček et al., 1977a).</s><s>Infected cells stained by the Gimenez method revealed rickettsiae either scattered in host cytoplasm, in clusters or occasionally within the nuclei of cells.</s><s>Electron microscopical studies showed that the bacteria were free in the cytoplasm and were surrounded by a slime layer (Řeháček, 1984) (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The quantitative distribution of <i>R. slovaca</i> in organs and haemolymph of infected adult <i>D. marginatus</i> collected in a natural focus of this rickettsia in central Slovakia has been demonstrated (Župančičová &#x0026; Kováčová, 1972).</s><s>The majority of rickettsiae were seen in the haemolymph, gut, Malpigian tubes and nerve ganglia; rickettsiae were less frequent ig the connective tissues, salivary glands and testes (Župančičová &#x0026; Kováčová, 1972).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intraperitoneal injection of rickettsiae does not kill white mice.</s><s>Pathological changes in mice are limited to a slightly enlarged spleen.</s><s>Guinea pigs react only occasionally to intraperitoneal injection of rickettsiae, by demonstrating a brief and mild fever. <i>Lepus europaeus</i> infected subcutaneously with <i>R. slovaca</i> suffer a asymptomatic infection accompanied by irregular rickettsiaemia and distribution9f rickettsiae to different organs (Brezina et al., 1969; Řeháček, 1984).</s><s>The course of infection with rickettsiae in hamsters after intraperitoneal inoculation is asymptomatic (Jablonskaja, 1976).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Human illness caused by <i>R. slovaca</i> was not described until recently.</s><s>This agent has been suspected to be responsible for meningoencephalitis, accompanied by a prolonged persistance of neurasthenic disorders (Mittemayer et al., 1980; Řeháček, 1984; Řeháček &#x0026; Tarasevich, 1988).</s><s>The most recent reported case in France confirmed its pathologic role (Raoult et al., 1997).</s><s>The symptoms of the patient's illness were severe headache, a necrotic eschar on the occiput surrounded by a reddish halo and four enlarged occipital lymph nodes, and a general weakness and tiredness that persisted for 2 months.</s><s>A patient with meningoradiculitis following a tick bite was observed in south-west France (D.</s><s>Raoult, unpublished data).</s><s>Cases of patients bitten by <i>D. marginatus</i> ticks who developed the same clinical symptoms as those presented by this French patient were described in France as early as 1955.</s><s>A rickettsial origin of these tick-transmitted diseases was suspected, but the aetiological agent was not identified (Giroud et al., 1965).</s><s>In 1981, again in France, the pathogenicity of <i>R. slovaca</i> was hypothesized by Edlinger in the aetiology of erythema chronicum migrans (Edlinger, 198 1).</s><s>Raoult et al. ( 1997) suggested that <i>Borrelia</i>-seronegative patients with manifestations resembling those of Lyme disease (a local erythema accompanied by meningoencephalitis) should perhaps be tested for <i>R. slovaca</i>.</s><s>This might also apply in the case of patients from Hungary whose clinical symptoms - a benign infection with positive serology to Lyme borreliosis - detected in only some of the patients raised questions about the aetiology of the ongoing disease (Lakos, 1997).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>In vitro</i> susceptibility of <i>R. slovaca</i> to various antibiotics has been previously tested; the MIC for doxycycline was found to be 0.125 μg ml<sup>-1</sup> and the MIC for rifampicin was 0.5 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Doxycycline is the recommended treatment, and fluoroquinolones can be used as alternatives (MICs of 1 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>MICs for thiamphenicol, amoxicillin, cotrimoxazole are relatively high (1-128 μg mi<sup>-1</sup>), whereas macrolide compounds are also effective, and can therefore be considered as alternative treatments during childhood and pregnancy (Rolain et al., 1998).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>R. slovaca</i> is strain B, an isolate obtained from <i>D. marginatus</i> ticks; this strain has been deposited in the Collection of the World Health Organization Collaborative Center for Rickettsial Reference, Marseille, France and in the American Type Culture Collection.</s></p></content></protolog>