<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9241_nm.14505" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14505" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14505" rank="species">Adhaeribacter terreus</organism><reference id="rid.9241"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Adhaeribacter terreus sp. nov., isolated from forest soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1595</fpage><lpage>1598</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004796-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542137</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Adhaeribacter terreus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Adhaeribacter terreus</em> (ter′re.us. L. masc. adj. <em>terreus</em> earthly).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, heterotrophic, oxidase-positive and catalase-negative.</s><s>Cells are rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 1.0–2.0 μm in length, devoid of flagella and gliding motility, producing copious amounts of extracellular fibrillar material and intracellular granules of a PHB-like substance.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, entire and pink.</s><s>Their mucous consistency makes the cells difficult to suspend in liquids or to pellet by centrifugation.</s><s>No growth occurs in TSB broth (30 g l<sup>−l</sup>) at strengths 1 and 0.5 or in LB at strengths 1 and 0.1, but growth occurs in TSB at strengths 0.2, 0.1 and 0.05.</s><s>Growth is significantly increased by addition of 0.1 % gellan to the diluted TSB.</s><s>Growth occurs at 16–33 °C (optimum, 28 °C), pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0–7.5) and in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl (w/v) (optimum, 0 %).</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Casein, aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, but starch and Tweens 20 and 80 are not.</s><s>Urease activity is present, but arginine dihydrolase activity is absent.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose.</s><s>l-Arabinose, trehalose, l-glutamic acid, l-methionine and l-phenylalanine are assimilated.</s><s>l-Arginine, l-proline and glycine are weakly assimilated.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>Ν</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, adonitol, fructose, fumarate, galactose, inositol, d-lactate, lactose, pyruvate, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-xylose, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine and ornithine are not assimilated.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present.</s><s>Weak esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present.</s><s>Esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>Ν</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc unless otherwise stated) amikacin (30), carbenicillin (100), cefoperazone (75), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), penicillin G (10 U), tobramycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and summed feature 4 (comprising iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DNG6<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6961<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104235<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from forest soil.</s></p></content></protolog>