<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7141_nm.2750" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2750" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2750" rank="species">Moraxella boevrei</organism><reference id="rid.7141"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kodjo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tønjum</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moraxella boevrei sp. nov., a new Moraxella species found in goats.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>115</fpage><lpage>121</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-115</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995812</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Moraxella boevrei sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Moraxella boevrei (boev’re.i, L. gen. n. boevrei, of BQvre, in honor of Kjell Bovre, a Norwegian microbiologist, in recognition of his many contributions to the field of Moraxella and Neisseria identification and taxonomy [4, 7, 23, 29, 32])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative thin rods to coccus-like structures and have a tendency to occur as diplobacilli or in short chains.</s><s>They are nonmotile, aerobic, and mesophilic.</s><s>Colonies are grey-white, rough, and small (diameter after 48 h, 0.5 mm) and are surrounded by a wide area of hemolysis.</s><s>Growth occurs in an aerobic atmosphere (preferably containing 5% CO<sub>2</sub>) on 5% sheep or human blood agar plates or chocolate agar plates.</s><s>Growth does not occur or occurs weakly on nutrient agar.</s><s>The oxidase and catalase reactions are strongly positive.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze Tween 80 and reduce nitrate.</s><s>No acid is produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>All strains are proteolytic (Loeffler slants and gelatin positive).</s><s>Indole and urease reactions are negative.</s><s>The only conventional characteristic that distinguishes <i>M. boevrei</i> from <i>M. bovis</i> is the reduction of nitrate.</s><s>Otherwise all other conventional and hydrolytic enzymes of <i>M. boevrei</i> and <i>M. bovis</i> are exactly the same.</s><s>The G+C content ranges from 41 to 41.5 mol% (Table 4).</s><s>The clinical significance is uncertain.</s><s>Strain 88365 (=ATCC 700022=CCUG 35435=NCTC 12925=CIP 104716), which was isolated in 1988 from the nasal cavity of a healthy goat, is the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>