<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6561_nm.11119" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11119" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11119" rank="species">Trabulsiella odontotermitis</organism><reference id="rid.6561"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Trabulsiella odontotermitis sp. nov., isolated from the gut of the termite Odontotermes formosanus Shiraki</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>696</fpage><lpage>700</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64632-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392189</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Trabulsiella odontotermitis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Trabulsiella odontotermitis</em> (o.don.to.ter′mi.tis. N.L. n. <em>Odontotermes</em> the scientific name of a genus of termite; N.L. gen. n. <em>odontotermitis</em> of a termite of the genus <em>Odontotermes</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, motile, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped.</s><s>After 24 h growth on nutrient agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is about 0.5–0.7×1.0–1.5 μm.</s><s>Growth is observed at 28, 30, 37 and 42 °C.</s><s>Positive (API 20E) for catalase, ONPG test, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, acetoin production and acid production from glucose, mannitol, sorbitol, rhamnose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, gelatinase, inositol, sucrose and melibiose.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase, but negative for C8 lipase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>The following compounds (Biolog GN2) are oxidized: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, dl-lactate, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not oxidized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, adonitol, d-arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Utilization of l-fucose, formic acid and quinic acid is strain-specific and differs between the two strains isolated.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 16 : 0, 17 : 0 cyclo, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, summed feature 2 (14 : 0 3-OH and/or 16 : 1 iso I) and summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 iso 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Eant 3-9<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17577<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23580<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain Eant 3-9<sup>T</sup> and reference strain Eant 3-3 were isolated from the gut of the termite <em>Odontotermes formosanus</em> Shiraki from southern Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C contents of strains Eant 3-3 and Eant 3-9<sup>T</sup> are 55.5 and 55.7 mol%, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>