<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1918_nm.10869" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10869" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10869" rank="species">Microlunatus ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.1918"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microlunatus ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>713</fpage><lpage>716</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64395-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392192</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microlunatus ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microlunatus ginsengisoli</em> (gin.seng.i.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-motile, coccus-shaped and 0.5–0.8 μm in diameter after 24 h culture on MR2A agar plates.</s><s>Colonies grown on MR2A agar for 3 days are very small, smooth, circular, non-glossy, yellowish and convex.</s><s>Grows well at 20–30 °C and at pH 5.5–8.5, but does not grow at, or below, 15 °C or above 37 °C.</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar but not MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth on MR2A agar occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 4.0 % (w/v) NaCl, weakly with 5.0 % NaCl (w/v), but not with 6.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate, as a nitrogen source, is reduced under aerobic conditions, but nitrite is not.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur; nitrate is not reduced under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In API 20E tests, urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase results are negative; results for <em>β</em>-galactosidase and gelatinase activities and for the Voges–Proskauer reaction are positive.</s><s>No acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-melibiose or amygdalin.</s><s>d-Glucose is utilized as a sole carbon source, but neither acid nor gas is produced.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: l-rhamnose, d-fructose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, l-xylose, propionate, valerate, fumarate, salicin, lactate, malate, tartrate, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, gluconate, d-adonitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, amygdalin, inulin, dextran, alanine, asparagine, aspartate, histidine, phenylalanine, proline and tyrosine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: d-fucose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, formate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, caprate, maleic acid, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalic acid, arginine, cysteine, glutamate, glycine, glutamine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, serine, threonine, tryptophan and valine.</s><s>Xylan, chitin, cellulose, casein, olive oil, starch and DNA are not degraded.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are the major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA is 69.8 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-DAP.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 633<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13940<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17942<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>