<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.554_nm.7641" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7641" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7641" rank="species">Blastococcus aggregatus</organism><reference id="rid.554"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urzì</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salamone</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Blastococcus saxobsidens sp. nov., and emended descriptions of the genus Blastococcus Ahrens and Moll 1970 and Blastococcus aggregatus Ahrens and Moll 1970.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>259</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02745-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742489</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Blastococcus aggregatus</em> Ahrens and Moll 1970</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The emendation is based on the description of Ahrens &#x0026; Moll (1970), supplemented with data reported in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, highly irregular vibrioid or rod-shaped cells occurring singly or in three-dimensional coccoid aggregates.</s><s>The manifestation of one of these stages is influenced by environmental conditions.</s><s>Low salt concentrations, temperatures of 5–10 °C and microaerophilic conditions favour the motile rod stage.</s><s>Single cells are either motile vibrioid (0·3–1·5×0·4–3·0 μm) or rods or ellipsoid (1·2–1·5×1·5–3·0 μm).</s><s>Rods are often separated by disc-like septa.</s><s>These motile or non-motile rods carry one to six vibrioform buds, attached to the mother cell by a tapered pole.</s><s>Increased temperatures and salt concentrations induce the formation of non-motile coccoid aggregates (1·2–2·5 μm in diameter), appearing as linear, band-like or column-like three-dimensional forms.</s><s>Larger aggregates (1 mm diameter) are separated by rectangular and/or radial partitions.</s><s>Cell types of different size occur mostly side by side.</s><s>After 5 days on peptone/yeast extract agar at 20 °C, colonies are pink, turbid, round and convex with a shiny surface.</s><s>In liquid media, thin turbidity and formation of pink sediment is observed.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>No growth in mineral medium; weak growth in the presence of ethanol, but not with glucose, acetate, citrate, methanol, ethylamine or paraffin.</s><s>Good growth in mineral medium plus peptone (0·5 %) and yeast extract (0·1 %); in these media, addition of 1 % of either glucose, acetate, citrate, ethylamine or paraffin reduces growth.</s><s>Growth is enhanced in peptone/yeast extract medium by the addition of 1 % NaCl.</s><s>No acid or gas from glucose, galactose, fructose, xylose, sucrose, maltose, lactose or glycerin.</s><s>Methyl-red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>No hydrolysis of starch, chitin, alginate or cellulose.</s><s>Reactions towards substrates provided by the API ZYM, API 20 NE and Biolog GP2 panels are indicated in Table 2.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 14-methyl pentadecanoic acid (iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>) and 14-methyl pentadecenoic acid (iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub>).</s><s>Diamino acid of peptidoglycan, menaquinone and polar lipids are as described for the genus.</s><s>Two unknown phospholipids may occur.</s><s>Extinction maxima of carotenoids at 470 and 500 nm.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 73·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSM 4725<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 25902<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the Baltic Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>