<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6314_nm.9256" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9256" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4736" rank="species">Mycoplasma coccoides</organism><reference id="rid.6314"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Neimark</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stewart</surname><given-names>L.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis and description of Eperythrozoon coccoides, proposal to transfer to the genus Mycoplasma as Mycoplasma coccoides comb. nov. and Request for an Opinion.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1385</fpage><lpage>1391</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63437-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879286</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycoplasma coccoides</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycoplasma coccoides</em> (coc.coi′des. Gr. n. <em>coccus</em> a berry; N.L. n. <em>coccus</em> a coccus; Gr. n. <em>eidus</em> shape; N.L. adj. <em>coccoides</em> coccus-shaped).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Eperythrozoon coccoides</em> Schilling 1928 (Approved Lists 1980).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Organisms in peripheral blood are coccoid and about 350 nm in diameter.</s><s>Their association with the erythrocyte does not produce a noticeable indentation in the erythrocyte surface (Tanaka <em>et al.</em>, 1965).</s><s>Many organisms also are free in the plasma, especially early in the infection.</s><s>Ring-shaped cells commonly observed in stained smears are an artefact of the staining process which suggests these organisms are easily deformed from their coccoid form.</s><s>The cells are filterable through at least a 360 nm mean pore size colloidon filter (Niven <em>et al.</em>, 1952).</s><s>An epierythrocytic parasite of laboratory and wild mice, albino rats, hamsters and rabbits.</s><s>Organic arsenicals (Neoarsphenamine; Oxophenarsine) are effective therapeutic agents that can eradicate a latent infection (Thurston, 1953; Thompson &#x0026; Bayles, 1966; Powers <em>et al.</em>, 1969); tetracyclines only suppress infection.</s><s>The organism can influence the course of viral or protozoan infection in experimentally co-infected mice.</s><s>Reported from Europe, North and South America and Africa.</s><s>The louse <em>Polypax spinulosa</em> is a vector.</s><s>The organism has not been cultured on artificial media.</s><s>Organisms in citrated blood remain infective for several hours at 16 °C and approximately 11 days at 3 °C (Thurston, 1955) and are maintained by animal passage, and storage at −70 °C.</s><s>DNA G+C content (mol%) not determined.</s><s>Genome size not determined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because this bacterium is uncultivated, no type strain is established.</s><s>However, it is suggested that, where possible, chromosomal DNA from this and other uncultivated bacteria be deposited in a type culture collection to provide a type strain reference.</s></p></content></protolog>