<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3398_nm.4701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4701" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4701" rank="species">Mycoplasma mobile</organism><reference id="rid.3398"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kirchhoff</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beyene</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flossdorf</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heitmann</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Khattab</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopatta</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosengarten</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yousef</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma mobile sp. nov., a new species from fish.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>192</fpage><lpage>197</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-192</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma mobile</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma mobile</i> (L. adj. <i>mobilis</i>, motile; referring to the most striking property of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and ultrastructure.</s><s>Strain 163K produced typical fried-egg colonies on modified Hayflick medium containing horse or bovine serum and on modified Friis medium after incubation times of 2 to 6 days (17).</s><s>The diameter of the colonies varied from 10 to 500 μm depending on their density.</s><s>Colony-like aggregates with a diameter of up to 500 μm were observed in broth medium, as flocks in the fluid producing a granular turbidity or attached to the bottom of the culture vessel.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of strain 163K distinguish themselves from most other mycoplasmas by their morphology: they are conical or flask shaped and have a distinct terminal structure.</s><s>This could even be recognized in the dark-field microscope.</s><s>Scanning and transmission electron microscopy confirmed this observation and revealed details.</s><s>The flask shape exists in many variations ranging from coccoid to strong elongated forms (Fig. 1) with dimensions from 0.3 to 1.6 μm in length and 0.1 to 0.5 μm in width.</s><s>In spite of this pleomorphism all the cells are divided in a coccoid “body part” and a “head part.” The head part is hemispherical or triangular and somewhat thickened (Fig. 1 and 2).</s><s>On many cells, between the head part and body part there is a “neck part” showing a different length.</s><s>Electron microscopy of ultrathin sections revealed that the organisms lack a cell wall and are bounded by a single membrane (Fig. 2a and b).</s><s>An electron-dense membrane-associated inner layer can be seen in the area of the headlike structure (Fig. 2c) representing probably a cytoskeletal element.</s><s>The organisms stained pink in Giemsa stain and were gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adherence.</s><s>Organisms of strain 163K showed a remarkable ability to adhere to glass and plastic surfaces as well as to erythrocytes and tissue cells.</s><s>When broth cultures were cultivated in plastic and glass petri dishes, the organisms attached to the bottom of the vessels, where they produced colonies which could not be removed by repeated extensive washing with PBS (pH 7.2).</s><s>The ability to adhere to glass appeared within a few minutes (to the slide as well as to the cover slip).</s><s>The adherence to erythrocytes and tissue cells was confirmed in dark-field preparations and in the adsorption of erythrocytes and tissue cells to colonies of strain 163K.</s><s>Two types of hemadsorption depending on the age and the density of the colonies were observed (Fig. 3): the erythrocytes adhered to the whole colony or they adhered only to the peripheral part of the colony.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gliding motility.</s><s>The most exciting property of strain 163K is its ability to glide on glass and plastic surfaces.</s><s>The gliding motion of strain 163K is unique among mycoplasmas because of its speed, which is 2 to 4 μm/s on average and 7.5 μm/s maximum under adequate culture conditions.</s><s>Gliding motion can be observed in a simple dark-field preparation, in which the organisms are gliding on the slide as well as on the lower side of the coverslip.</s><s>The organisms move in straight lines, in arcs, or in circles, with their headlike structure always orientated in the direction of the movement, and show a tendency to aggregate.</s><s>They form gliding chains and also lay together with their sides in close contact during gliding.</s><s>The gliding is not interrupted by resting periods.</s><s>Subcultivation of the organisms for more than 50 passages on artificial medium did not have any effect on the ability to glide or velocity of movement.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Strain 163K grows under aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The growth characteristics under aerobic conditions were recorded by growth curves during growth at different temperatures (4, 17, 25, 30, and 37°C).</s><s>Figure 4 shows good growth of the organisms from 17 to 30°C with an optimum at 25°C.</s><s>Weak growth occurred even at 4°C, but organisms died within 10 h at 37°C.</s><s>At all temperatures enabling growth, the maximum cell number was reached between 40 and 50 h of incubation.</s><s>The media used in the experiments did not have any decisive influence on the growth of strain 163K.</s><s>Thus, there were no significant differences in growth curves obtained by cultivation in Hayflick medium (with either bovine or horse serum) or in modified Friis medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fiterability and reversion.</s><s>Organisms of strain 163K passed through membrane filters of 450-nm pore size with a slight reduction in the number of cells (from 10<sup>9</sup> down to 10<sup>6</sup> to 10<sup>7</sup> CFU/ml) and through filters of 220-nm pore size with a strong reduction in the number of organisms (from 10<sup>9</sup> down to 10<sup>2</sup> to 10<sup>3</sup> CFU/ml).</s><s>No evidence of a change to bacterial forms was apparent during 12 consecutive passages on medium devoid of inhibiting substances, whether agar colonies or broth preparations, examined microscopically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sterol requirement.</s><s>Strain 163K was strongly sensitive to 1% (wt/vol) digitonin (inhibiting zone, 12 to 15 mm) and showed a partial sensitivity to sodium polyanethol-sulfonate.</s><s>Around the saturated disks was a zone of 2 to 10 mm (depending on the concentration of the polyanetholsulfonate) where colonies were much smaller and less dense than on the remaining areas of the plate.</s><s>The growth response of strain 163K to the cholesterol content of the medium is shown in Table 2.</s><s>No growth was apparent in medium without serum and in serum-free medium enriched with 0.05% bovine serum albumin (fraction V) and 10 μg of palmitic acid per ml (base medium).</s><s>However, there was increasing multiplication when 1 to 20 μg of cholesterol per ml was added to the base medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics.</s><s>The results of the biochemical investigations of strain 163K are given in Table 3.</s><s>Variable results were obtained with some tests.</s><s>Potassium tellurite reduction was positive in about half of the experiments only and depended on the size of the colonies, the duration of incubation and the concentration of the potassium tellurite.</s><s>The color reaction demonstrating phosphatase activity was weak in comparison to the reference species <i>M. arthritidis</i> and present in only 25% of the experiments.</s><s>Gas production after addition of hydrogen peroxide, demonstrating catalase activity, was weak and could be observed only with young colonies.</s><s>The reactions for oxidase activity were positive in about 50% of the experiments.</s><s>A strong film and spot production were observed on the modified Hay flick medium containing horse serum within 3 to 5 days of incubation, whereas no film and spots were produced on media containing bovine or swine serum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serology.</s><s>Strain 163K was compared with all of the established <i>Mycoplasma</i> and <i>Acholeplasma</i> species (Table I) by the IFT, GIT, and MIT.</s><s>The tests showed that strain 1163K is serologically unrelated to all previously described <i>Mycoplasma</i> and <i>Acholeplasma</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA.</s><s>The G+C contents were 32.7 mol% for the DNA of <i>A. laidlawii</i>, 27.2 mol% for the DNA of <i>M. pulmonis</i>, and 23.5 mol% (range, 22.4 to 24.6) for the DNA of strain 163K.</s></p></content></protolog>