<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8258_nm.5826" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5826" rank="suborder">Micrococcineae</organism><reference id="rid.8258"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tóth</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>International Committee on Systematics of Prokaryotes; Subcommittee on the taxonomy of the suborder Micrococcineae Minutes of the meetings, 7 August 2008, Istanbul, Turkey</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>643</fpage><lpage>644</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011320-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Minute 7. Minimal standards for the description of new taxa of the suborder <em>Micrococcineae</em>.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The Chairman outlined some points of the draft that required the special attention of the subcommittee members. After an intense discussion, all members agreed that the 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity threshold for the necessity of DNA–DNA hybridization is hard to define within the suborder. It was decided to keep the threshold value of 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity that suggests the affiliation of strains to a separate genomic species at 97 % with the exception of members of the genus <em>Microbacterium</em> where it has been shown that 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity of &#x003C;98 % may justify a separate species status. In these cases DNA–DNA hybridizations may not be necessary, provided that there is clear evidence that the strain(s) under study is (are) phenotypically clearly different from the most closely related species on the basis of at least five traits which must have been studied concurrently. Clear evidence may be provided by examination of several strains for which non-clonal relatedness is demonstrated. Species identity and non-clonal relatedness may be demonstrated by genomic fingerprinting (high degree of similarity but still differences present in the banding patterns). The construction of phylogenetic trees should be calculated by more than one algorithm. It should be included in the minimal standards that cellular fatty acid profiles and other phenotypic data should be analysed in one and the same laboratory rather than making comparisons of new data with those available from the literature. The discussion was continued as to which characteristics should be considered as ‘minimal requirements’ and which ‘additional data’, e.g. sequences of housekeeping genes as well as polyamine and total protein profiles, should get the status of additional characteristics. The draft will be updated with respect to the decisions of the meeting and recent descriptions of new taxa and will be circulated among the authors to prepare the manuscript for submission.</s></p></content></protolog>