<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2985_nm.5234" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5234" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5234" rank="species">Staphylococcus auricularis</organism><reference id="rid.2985"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus auricularis sp. nov.: an inhabitant of the human external ear.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>9</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-9</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus auricularis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus auricularis</i> (au. ri. cu. la' ris. NL. adj. <i>auricularis</i> pertaining to the ear)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of <i>S. auricularis</i> is based on a total of 20 strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells were gram-positive cocci, 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter, nonmotile, and nonsporeforming and occurred predominantly in tetrads and pairs.</s><s>Colonies on P agar were convex, opaque, circular, slightly glistening, white, and very small, ranging from 1.4 to 2.8 mm in diameter (after incubation for 3 days at 34°C and for 2 days at 25°C).</s><s>Small colony size was also observed on several commercially prepared agar media (e.g., nutrient, tryptic soy, and brain heart infusion agars).</s><s>The colony texture of 90% of the strains was smooth; 10% of strains had colonies with a granular texture and ornate, wrinkled, or rough surface.</s><s>The colony edges were entire to slightly undulate and usually became crimpled after 4 to 5 days of incubation.</s><s>Young colonies (1 to 3 days old) exhibited an unusually high profile for staphylococci, which was rather similar to the profiles of certain micrococci (e.g., <i>M. kristinae</i> and <i>Micrococcus sedentarius</i> [12]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth was weak to moderate in the aerobic portion of a semisolid thioglycolate medium and very weak to weak in the anaerobic portion, suggesting a slight facultative anaerobic capability.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produced only L-lactic acid from glucose under anaeroibic conditions.</s><s>All strains grew well at NaCl concentrations up to 10%.</s><s>A total of 70% of the strains grew poorly at an NaCl concentration of 15%; 30% of the strains grew moderately at this high salt concentration.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature range was 30 to 40°C.</s><s>No strain grew at 15°C, and 90% of the strains grew weakly to moderately at 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains had a moderate to strong catalase activity, were positive for the benzidine test, and were oxidase negative.</s><s>Like most staphylococci, all strains contained class I fructose-1,6-biophosphate aldolase.</s><s>All failed to produce coagulases or to exhibit clear hemolysin activity, although upon prolonged incubation (more than 3 days) some partial hemolysis or dark “greening” of the surrounding bovine blood agar medium became evident.</s><s>A total of 50% of the strains failed to produce acetylmethylcarbinol, whereas the remaining 50% produced only low levels of this compound.</s><s>No strain produced reduced nitrates to nitrites slowly, and 70% demonstrated weak deoxyribonuclease activity.</s><s>Growth was not stimulated by the addition of Tween 80 to P agar at concentrations ranging from 0.2 to 3%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produced acid aerobically from D-(+)-glucose and glycerol; 90% of the strains produced acid from β-D-(-)-fructose and D-(+)-trehalose, 70% produced acid from maltose, and 40% produced acid from sucrose.</s><s>A total of 10% of the strains produced acid from D-(+)-mannose, α-lactose, and D-(+)-galactose, and 5% produced weak acid from D-(-)-ribose; 35% of the strains produced very weak acid from D-(+)-turanose.</s><s>All failed to produce acid from β-gentiobiose, D-sorbitol, L-(-)-sorbose, salicin, D-(+)-raffinose, L-(+)-rhamnose, xylitol, D-(+)-xylose, L-(+)-arabinose, D-(+)-fucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-(+)-melezitose, and D-(+)-cellobiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When we used the API STAPH-IDENT system (Analytab Products, Plainview, N.Y .) with 10 miniaturized biochemical tests (14), all <i>S. auricularis</i> strains were negative for alkaline phosphatase, urease, β-glucosidase, and β-glucuronidase activities and failed to produce acid aerobically from D-mannitol and salicin.</s><s>A total of 80% of the strains produced acid from D-(+)-trehalose, and 10% produced acid from D-(+)-mannose; 60% utilized arginine, and 25% exhibited weak to moderate β-galactosidase activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains were resistant to 50 μg of lysozyme per ml and were susceptible to 100 μg of lysostaphin per ml and 1.6 μg of novobiocin per ml.</s><s>The minimum inhibitory concentration for novobiocin was from 0.1 to 0.8 μg/ml.</s><s>Agar disk diffusion tests indicated that all strains were susceptible to penicillin G, methicillin, erythromycin, tetracycline, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, kanamycin, gentamicin, lincomycin, neomycin, vancomycin, and bacitracin (9, 11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains contained cell wall peptidoglycan of the basic type Lys-Gly<sub>5</sub>; however, 15% of the strains had peptidoglycans that had significant amounts of glycine (0.5 to 0.6 mol/mol of glutamic acid) replaced by serine.</s><s>All strains possessed an atypical cell wall teichoic acid, namely, poly(N-acetylglucosamine 1-phosphate) (15,19).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the DNAs of the two strains tested (ATCC 33753<sup>T</sup> [type strain] and ATCC 33754) were 38 and 39 mol%, respectively.</s><s>The variable characteristics of the strains are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA reassociation reactions performed under optimal and stringent conditions indicated that the 10 strains of <i>S. auricularis</i> examined were very closely related (≥90% relative DNA binding or homology) to one another at the species level (Table 2).</s><s>When <i>S. auricularis</i> and other <i>Staphylococcus</i> species were compared, the DNA homology values were much lower (5 to 15% under stringent reassociation conditions and, with the one exception of <i>Staphylococcus</i> caseolyticus strain ATCC 29750, 24 to 41% under optimal reassociation conditions) and were as expected for separate species.</s><s>These values were significantly higher than those between <i>S. auricularis</i> and a member of another gram-positive genus, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>. <i>S. auricularis</i> can be distinguished from all other staphylococci primarily on the basis of its slow growth and resulting colonial morphology, carbohydrate reaction pattern, cell wall composition, and DNA sequence relationships.</s><s>There are also some significant differences between this species and some other species in the parameters of cell arrangement, anaerobic growth pattern in thioglycolate, various enzyme activities, and susceptibility to novobiocin (2, 5, 6, 9, 11, 17, 20, 21).</s><s>Simple characters useful in separating <i>S. auricularis</i> from other <i>Staphylococcus</i> species are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain ATCC 33753 (originally designated WK 811M) is the type strain of <i>S. auricularis</i>.</s><s>A description of this strain follows.</s><s>Cells: spheres 1.0 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring predominantly in tetrads and pairs.</s><s>Nonmotile and nonsporeforming.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies: circular, entire, convex, smooth with slight glossy surface, opaque, white, and 1.8 to 2.2 mm in diameter (after 5 days).</s><s>Older colonies develop a crimpled edge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and benzidine tests are positive.</s><s>Oxidase is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotroph; metabolism is respiratory.</s><s>Slightly facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature relationships: no growth at 15°C and poor growth at 45°C; optimum growth temperature, 34 to 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on agar containing NaCl: good growth with 10% NaCl, poor growth with 15%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coagulases are not produced.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced slowly and weakly; phosphatase and acetylmethylcarbinol are not produced.</s><s>Deoxyribonuclease activity is very weak.</s><s>Hemolysins are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced aerobically from glucose, glycerol, fructose, maltose, and trehalose and weakly from sucrose and turanose.</s><s>No acid is produced from gentiobiose, sorbitol, sorbose, salicin, raffinose, rhamnose, xylose, xylitol, arabinose, fucose, inositol, mannitol, mannose, lactose, melezitose, cellobiose, galactose, or ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities: susceptible to lysostaphin (100 μg/ml) and novobiocin (20.1 μg/ml); susceptible to penicillin G, methicillin, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, kanamycin, tetracycline, gentamicin, neomycin, lincomycin, vancomycin, and bacitracin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fructose-1,6-biphosphate aldolase: class I.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type: L-Lys-Gly<sub>4.4</sub>, Ser<sub>0.5</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall teichoic acid composition: poly(N-acetylglucosamine 1-phosphate).</s><s>Atypical.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA: 38.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>