<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3491_nm.2171" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2171" rank="genus">Halorhodospira</organism><reference id="rid.3491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The phylogenetic relationship among Ectothiorhodospiraceae: a reevaluation of their taxonomy on the basis of 16S rDNA analyses.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>165</volume><fpage>106</fpage><lpage>113</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050304</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8593098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halorhodospira</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halorhodospira</i> (Ha.lo.rho.do.spi'ra. Gr.n. <i>halos</i> salt; Gr.n. <i>rhodos</i> the rose; Gr.n. <i>spira</i> the spiral; M.L.fem.n. <i>Halorhodospira</i>, the red spiral requiring salt)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spiral-shaped, may under some conditions appear as rods, 0.5–1.2 μm in diameter, motile by bipolar flagella, and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are present as lamellar stacks that are continuous with the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll a or b and carotenoids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs photoautotrophically under anoxic conditions with reduced sulfur compounds as electron donors, or photoheterotrophically with a limited number of simple organic compounds.</s><s>Sulfide is oxidized to elemental sulfur, which is deposited outside the cells and may be further oxidized to sulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is dependent on saline and alkaline conditions.</s><s>A minimum of more than 10% total salts are required by all known species, some of which grow in saturated salt solutions.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Storage products are polysaccharides, poly-β-hydroxy-butyrate, and polyphosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Halorhodospira</i> species are found in hypersaline and extremely saline environments with slightly to extremely alkaline pH that contain sulfide and that are exposed to light, such as salt flats, salt lakes, soda lakes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G+C of the DNA is 50.5–69.7 (Td).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species: <i>Halorhodospira halophila</i> (<i>Ectothiorhodospira halophila</i>, Raymond and Sistrom 1969, 125)</s></p></content></protolog>