<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6919_nm.6148" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6148" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6148" rank="species">Plantibacter flavus</organism><reference id="rid.6919"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Naumann</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Diversity of grass-associated Microbacteriaceae isolated from the phyllosphere and litter layer after mulching the sward; polyphasic characterization of Subtercola pratensis sp. nov., Curtobacterium herbarum sp. nov. and Plantibacter flavus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1441</fpage><lpage>1454</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02138-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361245</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Plantibacter flavus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Plantibacter flavus</i> (fla'vus. L. adj. <i>flavus</i> yellow, referring to the colony colour)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological and physiological description of the species is based on five strains.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, irregularly shaped rods that sometimes form V-shapes.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, shiny, slightly convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Oxidase and Voges-Proskauer reaction are negative, whereas catalase is positive.</s><s>Aesculin, DNA, Tween 60 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilization of starch is strain dependent; the type strain is positive for hydrolysis of starch.</s><s>None of the strains hydrolyses casein, gelatin or cellulose.</s><s>Formation of levan from sucrose is negative.</s><s>Strains produce acid oxidatively from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, D-trehalose, ribose and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid formation from inulin, melibiose, D-sorbitol and L-sorbose is strain dependent, whereas the type strain is negative for these carbohydrates.</s><s>All strains are negative for adonitol and inositol.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is about 25°C.</s><s>At 4°C, grows slowly; at -2°C, growth also occurs, but is even slower.</s><s>Major menaquinones and structure of peptidoglycan are the same as described for the genus.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid (a-15:0), 14-methyl pentadecanoic acid (i-16:0), 14-methyl hexadecanoic acid (a-17:0) and 13-methyl tetradecanoic acid (i-15:0).</s><s>DNA G+C composition for the type strain is 70 mol%.</s><s>Strains were isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses and from the litter layer after mulching the sward.</s><s>The type strain, isolated from the phyllosphere, is DSM 14012<sup>T</sup> (=P 297/02<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19919<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>