<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6503_nm.10245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10245" rank="species">Pseudomonas borbori</organism><reference id="rid.6503"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vanparys</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heylen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas peli sp. nov. and Pseudomonas borbori sp. nov., isolated from a nitrifying inoculum</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1875</fpage><lpage>1881</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64224-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902024</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas borbori</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas borbori</em> (bor′bo.ri. Gr. n. <em>borboros</em> sludge; N.L. gen. n. <em>borbori</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 24 h incubation at 28 °C on TSA, colonies are 1–2 mm, smooth, round with irregular edges and beige.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (1 μm wide and 2–3 μm long) with rounded ends, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Cells are motile and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>After 24 h, good growth is observed at 22–28 °C, but not at 4 °C or above 37 °C.</s><s>No anaerobic growth is observed.</s><s>Enzyme activities and carbon source utilization are given in Table 3.</s><s>Can be differentiated from all <em>P. straminea</em> strains characterized by Uchino <em>et al.</em> (2000) by the ability to assimilate d-maltose and the inability to assimilate l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannose and d-mannitol.</s><s>Can be differentiated from all <em>P. flavescens</em> strains characterized by Uchino <em>et al.</em> (2000) and Hildebrand <em>et al.</em> (1994) by the ability to assimilate d-maltose and the inability to assimilate d-galactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and d-trehalose.</s><s>Can be differentiated from all <em>P. argentinensis</em> strains characterized by Peix <em>et al.</em> (2005) by the ability to assimilate d-maltose and the inability to assimilate l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and d-trehalose.</s><s>Can be differentiated from <em>P. anguilliseptica</em> LMG 21629<sup>T</sup> by the ability to assimilate d-glucose, d-maltose and gluconate, the inability to assimilate d-galactose and the absence of acid phosphatase.</s><s>Can be differentiated from <em>P. peli</em> by the ability to reduce nitrate and to assimilate d-glucose, d-maltose and gluconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 23199<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17834<sup>T</sup>=R-20821<sup>T</sup>), which has a DNA G+C content of 60.7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain and eight other strains were isolated from a nitrifying inoculum in Gent, Belgium (Table 1).</s></p></content></protolog>