<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12899_nm.22718" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22718" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22718" rank="species">Spongiibacter borealis</organism><reference id="rid.12899"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>H.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Spongiibacter borealis sp. nov., isolated from Arctic seawater, and reclassification of Melitea salexigens Urios et al. 2008 as a later heterotypic synonym of Spongiibacter marinus Graeber et al. 2008 with emended descriptions of the genus Spongiibacter and Spongiibacter marinus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2895</fpage><lpage>2900</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028795-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257692</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Spongiibacter borealis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Spongiibacter borealis</em> (bo.re.a′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>borealis</em> related to the north, boreal).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, motile (by single polar flagellum), rods approximately 0.6–0.7 µm wide and 1.3–2.5 µm long.</s><s>After 5 days on marine agar plates at 25 °C, colonies are creamy, circular and convex, and approximately 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C (optimum 20–25 °C) and pH 5.8–9.3 (optimum pH 6.6–8.0).</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of NaCl as sole salt.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–8 % (w/v) sea salts (optimum 3–4 %).</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but DNA, gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Negative for ornithine and lysine deaminase activities, Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>According to the API ZYM test, positive for acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidases, α- and β-glucosidases, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>According to the API 20NE test, positive for aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase (PNPG) and gelatinase, glucose fermentation, indole production, nitrate reductase and urease.</s><s>Pyruvate and d-mannose (weakly positive) are utilized as sole carbon source, but acetate, arabinose, l-arginine, cellobiose, citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, mannitol, l-ornithine, l-rhamnose, d-salicin, sorbitol, succinate and xylose are not utilized.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified aminophospholipid.</s><s>The minor polar lipids are two unidentified aminophospholipids.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone 8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-AS9<sup>T</sup> ( = KCCM 90094<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 17304<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Arctic seawater.</s></p></content></protolog>