<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1_nm.8176" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8176" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8176" rank="species">Ornithobacterium rhinotracheale</organism><reference id="rid.1"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Hove</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mannheim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ornithobacterium rhinotracheale gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the avian respiratory tract</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>24</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-24</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123560</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ornithobacterium rhinotracheale</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ornithobacterium rhinotracheale</i> (rhi.no.tra.che.a'le. Gr. n. <i>ris</i> nose, nostril; medical term <i>trachea</i>, windpipe; L. neut. adj. suff. <i>-ale</i>, pertaining to; N. L. neut. adj. <i>rhinotracheale</i>, relating to nostrils and windpipes, because the organism was first isolated from specimens obtained from windpipes and nostrils)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>O. rhinotracheale</i> cells are 0.2 to 0.9 μm wide and 1 to 3 μm long.</s><s>Most strains grow aerobically, microaerobically, anaerobically, and in a C0<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30, 35, and 42°C.</s><s>Weak or no growth occurs at 24°C.</s><s>After storage for 6 weeks at 6 to 8°C, blood agar cultures can be subcultured on blood agar.</s><s>Colonial adherence, spreading, and corrosion do not occur.</s><s>No hemolysis occurs on horse blood agar.</s><s>Smooth, nonpigmented colonies develop after 2 days of incubation on rich peptone, peptone-blood, or chocolate agar at 36°C.</s><s>Oxidase activity is present in most strains; catalase activity is absent.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar, Endo agar, Drigalski agar, or Simmons citrate medium.</s><s>No growth factors are required.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and P-galactosidase (o-nitrophenyl-P-D-galactopyranosidete st) are present.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced; some strains reduce nitrites, but no denitrification occurs.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is present in most strains if the strains are grown in Möller medium (Difco) after 3 days of incubation at 36°C.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboqlase, phenylalanine deaminase, lecithinase, DNase, and gelatinase activities are absent.</s><s>Urease activity as determined by Lautrop's nonproliferative test (30) is present.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not detected in Kligler's agar, triple sugar iron agar, or SIM agar.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is produced in the Voges-Proskauer test.</s><s>Methyl red test negative.</s><s>Hyaluronidase and chondroitin sulfatase activities are present.</s><s>Ethanol is not oxidized.</s><s>D-Glucose in oxidation-fermentation medium is weakly and slowly oxidized or not detected.</s><s>Wheat starch is acidified by most strains.</s><s>Most strains use D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, lactose, and sucrose as carbon sources.</s><s>D-Xylose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, and malonate are not used by most strains as carbon sources.</s><s>In general, carbohydrates are catabolized better in media supplemented with 2% chicken serum.</s><s>Wheat starch is acidified by most strains within 1 to 5 days if cultures are incubated at 36°C.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are always present: alkaline and acid phosphatase, ester lipase C8, leucine arylamidase, phosphoamidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosaminidase, phosphodiesterase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, lysine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, α-glutamyl-α-glutamic acid arylamidase, glycyl-phenylalanine arylamidase, phenylalanyl-arginine arylamidase, prolyl-arginine arylamidase, seryl-methionine arylamidase, 2-glycyl-glycylarginine arylamidase, and alanyl-phenylalanyl-prolyl-alanine arylamidase.</s><s>All strains exhibit strong or weak α- and β-galactosidase, esterase C4, valine and cysteine arylamidase, and trypsin activities.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are always absent: β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, lipase C14, phenylalanine deaminase, hippurate hydrolysis, gamma-glutamyl arylamidase, and phospholipase.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-glucosaminic acid, D-saccharic acid, L-fucose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>The additional fatty acids present in small quantities in all strains include two unidentified fatty acids with equivalent chain lengths of 13.566 and 16.580, 16:0, 17:O iso, and 16:O 30H.</s><s>Lyxose, ribose, glucose, galactose, and mannose are the principal carbohydrate components, while altrose, sorbose, and heptose do not occur.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from respiratory tracts of turkeys, chickens, rooks, and a partridge, and most strains have been associated with infections such as tracheitis, pericarditis, sinusitis, airsacculitis, and pneumonia.</s><s>At present, our knowledge with regard to pathogenicity in birds is incomplete.</s><s>Our clinical observations and the results of diagnostic work (unpublished data) indicate with a high level of probability that <i>O. rhinotracheale</i> is able to produce a contagious disease.</s><s>However, it is not yet clear whether cofactors are involved in pathogenesis.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 37 to 39 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 9086 (= MCCM 01774 = CCUG 23171), which was isolated from a turkey in the United Kingdom.</s><s>Its G+C content is 38 mol%.</s><s>All <i>O. rhinotracheale</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie and the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg Department of Clinical Bacteriology.</s></p></content></protolog>