<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3147_nm.4163" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4163" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4163" rank="species">Ruminococcus pasteurii</organism><reference id="rid.3147"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentation of tartrate enantiomers by anaerobic bacteria, and description of two new species of strict anaerobes, Ruminococcus pasteurii and Ilyobacter tartaricus</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>139</volume><fpage>409</fpage><lpage>414</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00408388</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ruminococcus pasteurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ruminococcus pasteurii</i> (pa. steu'ri.i.M.L. gen. attr. referring to <i>Louis Pasteur</i> who probably first enriched and observed this bacterium during studies on tartrate fermentation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cocci, 1.0-1.5 μm in diameter, single, in pairs or small packages, surrounded by thick slime capsules.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporeforming.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>L-Tartrate, citrate, oxaloacetate, pyruvate utilized for growth as well as a variety of sugars including glucose, fructose, lactose, sucrose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, raffinose, sorbose, rhamnose, trehalose.</s><s>No growth on D-tartrate, m-tartrate, glycerol, glycerate, formate, acetate, lactate, glyoxylate, glycolate, fumarate, malate, ethanol, ethylene glycol, 2,3-butanediol, 3-hydroxybutyrate, xylose, arabinose, cellulose, xylane, peptone, yeast extract.</s><s>Fermentation products include acetate, formate, ethanol, and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Growth in freshwater medium with less than 1% sodium chloride.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate, sulfite, or nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Indole not formed, gelatin or urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No catalase activity, no cytochromes.</s><s>Biotin required for growth in mineral medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selective enrichment from freshwater sediments with L-tartrate as sole carbon and energy source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 5.5 - 8.8; optimum pH 7.0 - 7.5.</s><s>Temperature range: 0-42°C; optimum temperature 35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 45.2±1.0% G + C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats: anoxic muds in freshwater lakes and creeks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: KoTa2, DSM 2381, deposited in Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen, Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>