<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3491_nm.2161" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2161" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2161" rank="species">Ectothiorhodospira marina</organism><reference id="rid.3491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>The phylogenetic relationship among Ectothiorhodospiraceae: a reevaluation of their taxonomy on the basis of 16S rDNA analyses.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>165</volume><fpage>106</fpage><lpage>113</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050304</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8593098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ectothiorhodospira marina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ectothiorhodospira marina</i> (ma.ri'na. L.fem.adj. <i>marinus</i> marine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved, sometimes slightly bent rods, 0.8–1.2 μm wide, and 1.5–4.0 μm long.</s><s>They are motile by means of polar tufts of flagella and are gram-negative.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are present as lamellar stacks.</s><s>Color of cell suspensions that are free of polysulfides and elemental sulfur is red.</s><s>Absorption spectra of living cells show characteristic absorption bands at 379, 483, 513, 552, 593, 798, 826, 853, and 893 nm.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll a (esterified with phytol) and carotenoids of the spirilloxanthin series with spirilloxanthin as the major component.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grow preferably anaerobically in the light under photoautotrophic and photoheterotrophic conditions.</s><s>Reduced sulfur compounds or organic carbon sources can serve as electron donors.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is possible with sulfide, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, and sulfite.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, lactate, propionate, malate, succinate, and fumarate are used as organic carbon sources and electron donors.</s><s>Ketoglutarate and peptone also support growth.</s><s>Ammonia, dinitrogen, and glutamine are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Sulfate can be used as sole sulfur source.</s><s>Optimal growth is at 30–40°C and pH 7.5–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs between 0.5% and more than 10% salts, with an optimum at 2–6% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Major quinone components are Q-8 (Q-7) and MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G+C of the DNA of the type strain is 62.8 (Bd).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: DSM 241 (Matheron BA 1010).</s></p></content></protolog>