<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11581_nm.18616" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18616" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18616" rank="species">Herbidospora yilanensis</organism><reference id="rid.11581"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>G.-F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Herbidospora yilanensis sp. nov. and Herbidospora daliensis  sp. nov., from sediment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1168</fpage><lpage>1172</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014803-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667396</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Herbidospora yilanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Herbidospora yilanensis</em> (yi.lan.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>yilanensis</em> pertaining to Yilan county, Taiwan, where the micro-organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, non-acid-fast and mesophilic.</s><s>Produces branched and unfragmented substrate mycelia; no aerial hyphae are found.</s><s>Short spore-chains are borne on the tips of sporophores arising from the substrate mycelium.</s><s>Spore chains are composed of 10–20 non-motile, smooth-surfaced, oval spores.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is yellowish white to yellow.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Good growth occurs on most media, but sporulation only occurs on oatmeal-nitrate, yeast-extract-starch, oatmeal and glycerol-asparagine agars.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 40 °C; NaCl tolerance is 1 % on nutrient agar.</s><s>Decomposes starch but not adenine, aesculin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Fructose, fumaric acid, galactose, glucose, glycerol, dl-lactic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, succinic acid and trehalose are utilized.</s><s>Adonitol, l-arabinose, benzoic acid, cellobiose, cellulose, dulcitol, erythritol, l-malic acid, mucic acid, propionic acid, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-tartaric acid and xylose are not utilized.</s><s><em>p</em>-Aminobenzoic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol and thiamine are required for growth.</s><s>Biotin, nicotinic acid, pantothenic acid and pyridoxine are not required for growth.</s><s>Melanin is not produced.</s><s>Lysozyme sensitive.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, mannose, ribose and a trace amount of madurose occur in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-A<sub>2</sub>pm.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) and the minor components are MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids are PE, PME and GlcNU.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile contains 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (41.94 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (18.44 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (6.34 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (4.47 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (4.39 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (3.88 %) and C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (3.83 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.6 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 0351M-12<sup>T</sup> (=FIRDI 003<sup>T</sup> =BCRC 16875<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24337<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from sediment from Yilan, a county in the north of Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>