<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5965_nm.7524" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7524" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7524" rank="species">Planotetraspora mira</organism><reference id="rid.5965"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Runmao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guizhen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Junying</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new genus of actinomycetes, Planotetraspora gen. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>468</fpage><lpage>470</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planotetraspora mira</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planotetraspora mira</i> (mi'ra. L. fem. adj. <i>mira</i>, extraordinary, marvelous)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two cultures of the genus <i>Planotetraspora</i> were isolated, and strain NA9211028 was selected as the type strain of <i>P. mira</i>.</s><s>The vegetative mycelium (diameter of hyphae, about 0.3 to 0.6 μm) is well developed, with moderate, irregular branching; the mycelium penetrates the agar and forms on the agar surface compact, raised, tough colonies.</s><s>Fragmentation of hyphae does not occur on agar media.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is also well developed.</s><s>The mycelium of <i>P. mira</i> NA9211028<sup>T</sup> is gram positive and is not acid fast; the hyphae are approximately 0.2 to 0.4 μm in diameter.</s><s>Cylindrical to clavate sporangia (about 2.1 to 2.7 by 0.6 to 0.9 μm) are found on certain media that support aerial mycelium formation but are especially abundant on oatmeal agar medium A.</s><s>They are formed singly or in groups on the aerial mycelium (Fig. 1A).</s><s>When examined under an electron microscope at a higher magnification, the sporangia seem to have warty surfaces (Fig. 1B).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The sporangia are attached to the main hyphae by short sporangiophores that are approximately 0.2 to 0.8 μm long (Fig. 1A and B).</s><s>The sporangiospores are enveloped by a thin sporangial wall, which is difficult to see when a culture is examined superficially by light microscopy but is easily recognized by transmission electron microscopy (Fig. 1A, B, and E).</s><s>During the early developmental stages transverse septa divide each sporangium into four spores.</s><s>Mature spores are cylindrical or spherical (0.8 to 1.4 by 0.4 to 0.6 μm) and motile by means of single polar flagella (Fig. 1C and D).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cultural and physiological characteristics of the type strain of <i>P. mira</i> are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Additional physiological characteristics of strain NA9211028<sup>T</sup> are given below.</s><s>Milk is slowly peptonized and coagulated.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Little or doubtful growth is obtained with D-glucose, maltose, sucrose, D-xylose, galactose, inulin, dulcitol, D-mannitol, D-ribose, salicin, L-sorbose, D-sorbitol, L-rhamnose, lactose, melezitose, L-arabitol, melibiose, L-arabinose, and trehalose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The recognized genera of the <i>Actinomycetales</i> (7) that form sporangia with motile elements include the genera <i>Kineosporia</i>, <i>Actinoplanes</i>, <i>Ampullanella</i>, <i>Dactylosporangium</i>, <i>Pilimelia</i>, <i>Planomonospora</i>, <i>Planobispora</i>, <i>Spirillospora</i>, and <i>Streptoalloteichus</i>.</s><s>Morphologically, <i>P. mira</i> is closely related to the genus <i>Planobispora</i>.</s><s>The genus <i>Planobispora</i>, as currently described, contains strains that form two zoospores in each sporangium; the peptidoglycan of the cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, while madurose is the characteristic sugar of whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Since strains NA9211028<sup>T</sup> and NA9211036 have cylindrical sporangia which each contain four spores in a single row and their whole-cell hydrolysates lack madurose, they cannot be considered members of this genus.</s><s>Thus, the genus <i>Planotetraspora</i> should be considered a new genus of the order <i>Actinomycetales</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>