<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1411_nm.3921" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3921" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3921" rank="species">Clostridium colinum</organism><reference id="rid.1411"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Berkhoff</surname><given-names>H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium colinum sp. nov., nom. rev., the causative agent of ulcerative enteritis (quail disease) in quail, chickens, and pheasants.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-2-155</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridiurn colinum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium colinum</i> (co. li’ num. L. adj. <i>colinum</i> from the scientific name of bobwhite quail, <i>Colinus virginianus</i>, the avian species that is most susceptible to this anaerobe) cells are anaerobic, gram-positive straight rods that are 3 to 4 μm long by 0.6 to 1 μm wide. The rods appear singly or in pairs; chains are rarely seen. Spores are present in cultures on BAP, but they are few and hard to find; the spores are elliptical and subterminal. The sporing rods are at least twice as thick and long as the vegetative forms (Fig. 1 and 2). The spores resist a temperature of 80°C for 10 min, as well as octanol and chloroform. In broth cultures, spores are also rarely formed. The cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 3), and they have a cell wall that is typical of the cell walls of gram-positive species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On solid medium, colonies appear after 1 to 2 days of incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Surface colonies on BAP are small, round, semitranslucent, convex, and approximately 1 to 2 mm in diameter and have filamentous margins.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 35 to 42°C.</s><s>Growth in broth media can be detected as early as 12 to 16 h postinoculation.</s><s>When a culture is growing actively in broth, it produces gas.</s><s>Gas production continues for no more than 6 to 8 h.</s><s>After gas production has stopped, the growth settles in the bottom of the tube.</s><s>Figure 4 shows a normal growth curve of <i>Clostridium colinum</i> in CMC medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are fermented: glucose, mannose, raffinose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Fructose and maltose are weakly fermented.</s><s>Mannitol is fermented only by some strains.</s><s>The type strain does ferment mannitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are not fermented: arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, lactose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed; starch hydrolysis is usually negative.</s><s>Only two strains have been found to cause starch hydrolysis.</s><s>The type strain does not hydrolyze starch.</s><s>Nitrite and indole are not produced.</s><s>Milk is unchanged, and casein is not digested.</s><s>Good growth occurs in CMC broth.</s><s>Pyruvate and lactate are not utilized.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Catalase, urease, lipase, and lecithinase are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation products of this organism are acetic acid and formic acid (Fig. 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphologically, and to some extent biochemically, <i>Clostridium colinum</i> most closely resembles <i>Clostridium dificile, Clostridium barati, Clostridium carnis, Clostridium fallax</i>, and <i>Clostridium sticklandii</i> ((8, 15, 17, 18).</s><s>However, all of these species produce butyric acid and would not normally be confused with <i>Clostridiurn colinum</i> (8).</s><s>Two other previously described species that are similar to <i>Clostridium colinum</i> are <i>Clostridium clostridiiforme</i> and <i>Clostridium oroticum</i>.</s><s>However, in addition to morphological differences, <i>Clostridium oroticum</i> ferments rhamnose but not trehalose, and both <i>Clostridium clostridiiforme</i> and <i>Clostridium oroticum</i> ferment xylose, unlike <i>Clostridium colinum</i> (8). <i>Clostridium colinum</i> has been isolated only from necrotic liver lesions of quail, pheasants, and chickens dying with lesions typical of ulcerative enteritis (quail disease).</s><s>Animal assays for pathogenicity have shown that at least 10<sup>6</sup> viable bacterial cells administered orally are required to experimentally reproduce ulcerative enteritis in quail.</s><s>The bacterium is invariably reisolated from the livers of quail that die from experimentally induced ulcerative enteritis (2).</s><s>Cultures supplemented with 10% calcium chloride do not produce any pathogenic effects when they are inoculated into the hind legs of guinea pigs.</s><s>Cell-free culture filtrates are not toxic for mice.</s><s>Because infections recur year after year on the same premises, it is assumed that <i>Clostridium colinum</i> survives in the soil of infected premises (14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 43 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain 72042 (= ATCC 27770).</s></p></content></protolog>