<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12460_nm.21289" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21289" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21289" rank="species">Corynebacterium humireducens</organism><reference id="rid.12460"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>C.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhuang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>S.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F.-B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium humireducens sp. nov., an alkaliphilic, humic acid-reducing bacterium isolated from a microbial fuel cell</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>882</fpage><lpage>887</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020909-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495037</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium humireducens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium humireducens</em> [hu.mi.re.du′cens. L. n. <em>humus</em> soil, used to refer to humic substances; L. part. adj. <em>reducens</em> leading back (to a reduced oxidation state); N.L. part. adj. <em>humireducens</em> converting humic substances to a reduced oxidation state].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, non-motile, facultatively anaerobic, straight to curved rods (1.0–2.0 µm long and 0.5–0.7 µm wide).</s><s>Colonies on LB agar are uniformly round, 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, yellowish, dry and rough, with a distinct wrinkled morphology after 24 h.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37 °C, at pH 9.0 and with 10 % NaCl (aerobic conditions).</s><s>Positive for catalase but negative for oxidase, urease, reduction of nitrate and hydrolysis of urea, gelatin and tyrosine.</s><s>Produces acid from glucose and ribose, but not from arabinose, fructose, galactose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, pyrazinamidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, but not for leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase or β-galactosidase.</s><s>Grows with AQDS as the sole terminal electron acceptor at pH 7.0–11.0 (optimum pH 9.0) under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Available electron donors include formate, acetate, ethanol, lactate and sucrose, but not propionate, glycerol or citrate.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MFC-5<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 106098<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 2452<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 45392<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a microbial fuel cell fed with artificial wastewater and operated continuously at pH 10.0.</s></p></content></protolog>