<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9092_nm.14280" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14280" rank="species">Brevibacillus panacihumi</organism><reference id="rid.9092"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sathiyaraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pulla</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacillus panacihumi sp. nov., a β-glucosidase-producing bacterium.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1227</fpage><lpage>1231</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001248-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406823</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacillus panacihumi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacillus panacihumi</em> (pa.na.ci.hu′mi. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name of ginseng; L. n. <em>humus</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panacihumi</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive-staining, aerobic, motile rods, 0.3–0.6 μm in diameter and 4.0–10.0 μm long after growth on R2A agar or LB agar at 30 °C for 3 days.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 3 days are circular and pale yellow.</s><s>Ellipsoidal endospores occur subterminally.</s><s>Cells grow at 15–42 °C (optimum, 30 °C) but not at 4 °C and at pH 5–9 (optimum, pH 7) but not at pH 11.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by more than 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-negative but catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for the methyl red reaction and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Does not produce hydrogen sulfide, acid from d-glucose or indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin but not casein, gelatin or Tween 80.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis).</s><s>Negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, cystine arylamidase, DNase, lipase (C14), lysine decarboxylase, protease (gelatin hydrolysis), trypsin, urease, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase (starch hydrolysis), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (PNPG) and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, adipate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, gluconate, l-malate, phenylacetate, n-valerate, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-alanine, l-proline and l-rhamnose, but not caprate, citrate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, dl-lactate, malonate, propionate, suberate, l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, maltose, melibiose, d-ribose, sucrose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, l-histidine, l-serine, glycogen or salicin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the two known strains is 50.1–50.5 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The predominant quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DCY35<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13206<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15085<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea.</s><s>C17, isolated from a similar source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>