<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4228_nm.2948" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2948" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2948" rank="species">Vibrio aerogenes</organism><reference id="rid.4228"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shieh</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio aerogenes sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic marine bacterium that ferments glucose with gas production.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>321</fpage><lpage>329</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826819</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio aerogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio aerogenes</i> (a.e.ro'ge.nes. Gr. masc. n. <i>aer</i> air; Gr. v. <i>gennanio</i> to produce; M.L. adj. <i>aerogenes</i> gasproducing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight to slightly curved rod.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are 0.6-0.8 μm wide by 2-3 μm long.</s><s>Swarming does not occur on solid agar media while motility normally occurs by means of two sheathed, polar flagella when grown in liquid media.</s><s>Colonies produced on agar media are flat, circular, off-white and non-luminescent with an entire margin.</s><s>The species is a facultative anaerobe capable of both aerobic and anaerobic fermentative growth.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from fermentation of glucose and other carbohydrates such as cellobiose, galactose, inositol, mannitol, mannose, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>However, D-arabinose, dulcitol, lactose, sorbitol and trehalose are not fermented.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Accumulation of PHB inside the cells is not observed.</s><s>Catalase, arginine dihydrolase, amylase, caseinase, DNase, gelatinase and lipase are positive while oxidase, agarase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are negative.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The species is mesophilic, growing well at 20-35 °C but not at all at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>It is able to grow in a mineral medium containing glucose and ammonium or nitrate salts.</s><s>It grows at NaCl levels of 1-7% with optimal growth at about 4% while no growth occurs at 0 and 10% NaCl.</s><s>It is resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129 (10 or 150 μg per disc).</s><s>The most abundant cellular fatty acid is C12:0.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: cellobiose, galactose, glucose, sucrose, mannose, xylose, citrate, fumarate, pyruvate, inositol, mannitol, L-alanine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate and L-threonine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: D-arabinose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, acetate, β-hydroxybutyrate, DL-malate, malonate, tartrate, adonitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, L-arginine, L-glycine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-tryptophan and L-valine.</s><s>The species utilizes ammonium, nitrate and the L-form amino acids alanine, arginine, aspartate, glutamate, lysine, methionine, ornithine, phenylalanine, threonine, tryptophan and valine as sole nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>The DNA G+­C composition is about 46.0 mol%.</s><s>The species is found in coastal sediment.</s><s>The type strain is FG1<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700797<sup>T</sup> and in the Culture Center for Research and Collection, Taiwan as strain CCRC 17041<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>