<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4731_nm.3281" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3281" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3281" rank="species">Providencia rustigianii</organism><reference id="rid.4731"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hickman-Brenner</surname><given-names>F.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Providencia rustigianii: a new species in the family Enterobacteriaceae formerly known as Providencia alcalifaciens biogroup 3.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>1057</fpage><lpage>1060</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6874899</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Providencia rustigianii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Providencia rustigianii</i> (treated as a neo (modem) Latin genitive noun, <i>rustigianii</i> (rus tig i an' i i, pronounced rus tidge ee ahn' ee eye), meaning "of Rustigian," in honor of Robert Rustigian, who did early studies on the <i>Proteus</i> group (7, 8).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Providencia rustigianii</i> is proposed for the group of strains previously known as biogroup 3 of P. alcalifaciens (4).</s><s>Strain ATCC 33673 (CDC no. 0132-68) is proposed as the type strain (holotype) for this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A complete description of <i>P. rustigianii</i> is given in Tables 1, 2, 4, and 5 <i>P. rustigianii</i> shares the general characteristics of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (Table 2) and of the genus <i>Providencia</i>, which are as follows: positive tests for phenylalanine deaminase, acid production from D-mannose, tyrosine clearing, and indole production; resistance to colistin (8 of 11 strains); and negative tests for L-lysine and L-ornithine decarboxylase and L-arginine dihydrolase. <i>P. rustigianii</i> can be differentiated from other <i>Providencia</i> species because it produces acid from D-galactose but not from adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, and trehalose (Table 2).</s></p></content></protolog>