<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1705_nm.10643" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10643" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10643" rank="species">Burkholderia soli</organism><reference id="rid.1705"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia soli sp. nov., isolated from soil cultivated with Korean ginseng</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>125</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64471-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17220453</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are milky, convex and circular with clear margins.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.5–0.75 μm wide and 1.6–3.9 μm long.</s><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, rod-shaped and non-motile.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C (optimum, 28 °C), pH 4–8 (optimum, pH 6–7) and 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Negative for indole production and in the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Tween 80 and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but casein, chitin, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, gelatin, pectin and starch are not.</s><s>The following are oxidized: Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, itaconic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, urocanic acid, glycerol and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following are not oxidized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate (Biolog GN microplate).</s><s>Assimilates <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, lactic acid, l-alanine, glycogen, d-mannitol, d-glucose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, propionic acid, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and l-proline, but does not assimilate l-rhamnose, d-sucrose, d-maltose, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, d-melibiose, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid (API ID 32GN; bioMérieux).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (representing 71.2 % of the total).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GP25-8<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 11589<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18235<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in Korea from soil cultivated with Korean ginseng.</s></p></content></protolog>