<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1159_nm.7604" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7604" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7604" rank="species">Actinomadura macra</organism><reference id="rid.1159"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura macra sp. nov., the producer of antibiotics CP-47433 and CP-47434.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>565</fpage><lpage>568</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomadura macro</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(L. fem. adj. <i>macro</i> lean) refers to the poor, thin growth of this organism on many media used in the identification of similar organisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The production of short spore chains, the cultural characteristics, and the presence of <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid and madurose in the whole cell hydrolysates place strain Pfizer FD 25934 in the genus <i>Actinomadura</i> Lechevalier and Lechevalier.</s><s>When compared with descriptions of known species of <i>Actinomadura</i>, this strain most closely resembled <i>A. spadix</i> Nonomura and Ohara.</s><s>A culture of the type strain of <i>A. spadix</i> (ATCC 27298) was therefore used for comparison in this study.</s><s>Both strain Pfizer FD 25934 and <i>A. spadix</i> ATCC 27298 shared the following properties: production of grayish aerial mycelium, production of spores with a smooth surface, cultural characteristics on organic agar 2 of Gauze et al. and ISP medium 5, no production of melanin, and a positive nitrate reduction test.</s><s>On ISP medium 2, colonies of strain Pfizer FD 25934 were gray to grayish black and produced a brown soluble pigment, whereas those of <i>A. spadix</i> ATCC 27298 were white to pale yellow and did not produce soluble pigment.</s><s>On ISP medium 3, colonies of the former did not produce soluble pigment, whereas those of the latter produced a pink, soluble pigment.</s><s>On ISP medium 4 and mineral medium 1 of Gauze et al., colonies of strain Pfner FD 25934 were pale gray at the end of the streak, and those of <i>A. spadix</i> ATCC 27298 were cream colored.</s><s>In addition, <i>A. spadix</i> ATCC 27298 differed from strain Pfizer FD 25934 in that the former was positive for starch hydrolysis, negative for gelatin liquefaction, and positive for milk peptonization and showed slight growth at 45°C.</s><s>In carbohydrate utilization, <i>A. spadix</i> ATCC 27298 but not strain Pfizer FD 25934 utilized arabinose, fructose, mannitol, raffinose, and rhamnose.</s><s>Thus, strain Pfuer FD 25934 is considered to represent a heretofore undescribed species of the genus <i>Actinomadura</i>, for which the name <i>A. macra</i> sp. nov. is proposed.</s><s>Strain Pfizer FD 25934 is the type strain of <i>A. macra</i>; a culture of this strain has been deposited at the ATCC under the accession number ATCC 31286.</s><s>Since the description of <i>A. macra</i> given above is based on a single strain, the type strain, it also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>