<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1227_nm.7942" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7942" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7942" rank="species">Bacteroides cellulosolvens</organism><reference id="rid.1227"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sowden</surname><given-names>L.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colvin</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides cellulosolvens sp. nov., a cellulolytic species from sewage sludge.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>185</fpage><lpage>187</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides cellulosolvens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides cellulosolvens</i> (cell.u.lo.sol'vens. L. v. <i>solvere</i> to dissolve; N.L. adj. <i>cellulosolvens</i> cellulose dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are straight, rod-shaped, approximately 0.8 by 6 μm, and occur singly.</s><s>They are nonmotile, and no flagella are detected by staining or electron microscopy.</s><s>Extensions of the cell wall give this microbe a distinctive rough amorphous appearance when it is grown on insoluble cellulosic substrates.</s><s>An ultrastructure study has shown that these projections are extensions of the cell wall rather than capsular material.</s><s>The projections do not occur when the organism is grown in cellobiose broth.</s><s>Thin crosssections show the typical tripartite cell wall structure of gram-negative aerobes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are not demonstrated by malachite green staining of 1-week-old cultures or by treatment of cultures with 50% ethanol for 1 h.</s><s>Cultures grown in facial tissue broth that are 2 days old are still viable after being held for 10 min at temperatures up to 75°C ; however, heat tolerance decreases with culture age.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bright yellow, circular, convex colonies with rough margins are produced on cellobiose agar.</s><s>The colonies reach a maximum diameter of 1.0 to 1.25 mm after 5 days of growth at 35°C.</s><s>On Solka Floc agar, the colonies reach their maximum size after 10 days of growth and show zones ofcellulose clearing around the periphery of the colonies and in the agar below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 45.5°C, with optimum growth at 42°C.</s><s>Facial tissue squares in basal broth are hydrolyzed within 21 days at 20°C.</s><s>A bright yellow sediment is produced in cellulose broth and cellobiose broth at growth temperatures between 20 and 40°C, but not at temperatures above 40°C. <i>B . cellulosolvens</i> grows within a pH range of 5.7 to 8.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic medium is required for growth.</s><s>Of the substrates tested, only cellulose and cellobiose support growth. <i>B . cellulosolvens</i> ferments facial tissue, ball-milled pulp (Solka Floc), microcrystalline cellulose (Avicel), filter paper, absorbent cotton batting, cheesecloth, and steam-exploded aspen wood chips.</s><s>No growth occurs in basal medium supplemented with adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, dulcitol, esculin, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, xylan, xylose, Casamino Acids, casein, chopped meat, milk, peptone, yeast extract, hippurate, lactate, pyruvate, or urea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following fermentation products from cellobiose broth are detected after 3 days of incubation (in millimoles per liter): H<i>2</i>, 36.7; CO<sub>2</sub>, 30.0; acetic acid, 17.1; ethanol, 8.6; and lactic acid, 1.2.</s><s>The same products and yields are formed</s></p><p class="description"><s>after 5 days from fermentation of cellulose.</s><s>Acetylmethyl-carbinol is produced; ammonia, indole, catalase, urease, and gelatinase are not.</s><s>Sulfate and nitrate are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The addition of bile (2% oxgall) to cellobiose broth inhibits growth, whereas Tween 80, hemin, and vitamins B<sub>12</sub> and K<sub>1</sub> have no effect.</s><s>Rumen fluid increases metabolite formation and growth.</s><s>Unlike other species of <i>Bacteroides</i>, the addition of complex substances to the basal medium does not influence the formation of fermentation products by <i>B. cellulosolvens</i>.</s><s>Rumen fluid increases product yield but does not shift product ratios.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 43 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>B. cellulosolvens</i> type strain WM2 is deposited in the National Research Council of Canada culture collection as strain NRCC 2944.</s></p></content></protolog>