<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5700_nm.7427" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7427" rank="family">Streptosporangiaceae</organism><reference id="rid.5700"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical and chemical classification of Actinoplanes and some related actinomycetes</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptosporangiaceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptosporangiaceae</i> (Strep'to.spo.ran.gi.um. ML n. <i>Streptosporangium</i>, type genus of the family; -<i>aceae</i>, ending to denote a family; ML fem. pl. n. <i>Streptosporangiaceae</i>, the <i>Streptosporangium</i> family)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from the literature (Farina &#x0026; Bradley, 1970; Stackebrandt et al., 198 1 ; Goodfellow &#x0026; Cross, 1984; Goodfellow et al., 1988 ; Goodfellow, 1989).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast actinomycetes that form stable substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Aerial hyphae may carry chains of two (<i>Microbispora</i>) or more (<i>Microtetraspora</i>) spores or be differentiated into sporangia (spore vesicles) containing one (<i>Planomonospora</i>), two (<i>Planobispora</i>) or more spores (<i>Streptosporangium</i>).</s><s>Spores are either nan-motile (<i>Microbispora</i>, <i>Microtetraspora</i> <i>Streptosporangium</i>) or motile (<i>Planomonospora</i>, <i>Planobispora</i>).</s><s>Cell walls contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and N-acetylated muramic acid, but lack characteristic sugars.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the Aly type.</s><s>Lipid profiles typically contain saturated, <i>iso</i>- and <i>anteiso</i>- fatty acids, major proportions of unsaturated di- and hexahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units, and glucosamine-containing polar lipids.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA lies within the range 66-74 mol%.</s><s>Nucleic acid pairing and sequencing data serve to distinguish the family from other suprageneric groups of actinomycetes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comparative studies on well-chosen representative strains are needed to clarify the taxonomic structure of the family <i>Streptosporangiaceae</i>.</s><s>The constituent genera are still separated using morphological features (Goodfellow, 1989) but have also been distinguished in a numerical taxonomic survey of wall chemotype III sporoactinomycetes (Good fellow &#x0026; Pirouz, 1982).</s><s>Nevertheless, there is evidence that the genera <i>Microbispora</i> and <i>Microtetraspora</i> are closely related albeit heterogeneous taxa (Goodfellow &#x0026; Cross, 1984; Poschner et al., 1985).</s><s>Thus, <i>Microtetraspora viridis</i> has been transferred to the genus <i>Actinomadura</i> as <i>Actinomadura viridis</i> whereas the type species of the genus, <i>Microtetraspora glauca</i>, belongs to the family <i>Streptosporangiaceae</i> (Miyadoh et al., 1989).</s></p></content></protolog>