<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12453_nm.21281" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21281" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21281" rank="species">Pseudonocardia khuvsgulensis</organism><reference id="rid.12453"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsetseg</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daram</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ando</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia mongoliensis sp. nov. and Pseudonocardia khuvsgulensis sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>747</fpage><lpage>756</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019562-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20418406</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia khuvsgulensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia khuvsgulensis</em> (khuvs.gul.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>khuvsgulensis</em> of or belonging to Khuvsgul, referring to the isolation of the type strain from soil of Khuvsgul Lake, Khuvsgul province, Mongolia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, non-motile, non-endospore-forming, Gram-stain-positive actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelia that carry smooth-surfaced, rod-shaped spores.</s><s>Extensive acropetal budding of the aerial hyphae and the formation of blastospores are observed.</s><s>Good growth occurs on Bennett’s, YS, ISP 2, ISP 4, ISP 5, ISP 6 and ISP 7 agar media at 28 °C.</s><s>Forms white aerial mycelium and pale yellow to moderate yellowish brown substrate mycelium on the media tested.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>Grows at 15–30 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), at pH 5.0–11.0 (optimum pH 6.0–6.8) and at 0–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0–2.0 %).</s><s>Positive for urease and decomposition of hypoxanthine, tyrosine, calcium malate and arbutin, but negative for catalase, nitrate reduction, gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of starch and Tweens 20 and 80 and decomposition of casein and adenine.</s><s>According to the API ZYM enzyme assay, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase, weakly positive for lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), trypsin, α-galactosidase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase and β-glucuronidase and negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>According to the API Coryne enzyme assay, positive for pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucosidase and urease and hydrolysis of gelatin and negative for catalase, nitrate reduction and β-glucuronidase.</s><s>The cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern consists of galactose, glucose, arabinose, ribose, mannose and rhamnose (trace) (type IV cell wall).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The major fatty acid methyl esters are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MN08-A0297<sup>T</sup> ( = NBRC 105886<sup>T</sup>  = VTCC D9-26<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of Khuvsgul Lake, Khuvsgul province, Mongolia.</s></p></content></protolog>