<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7766" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7766" rank="genus">Chlamydia</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Chlamydia</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The genus <i>Chlamydia</i> previously included all known chlamydiae (Moulder, 1984). As emended, <i>Chlamydia</i> is one of two genera in the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> and includes <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>, <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> gen. nov., sp. nov. and <i>Chlamydia suis</i> gen. nov., sp. nov. The previous species, <i>Chlamydia pecorum</i>, <i>Chlamydia pneumoniae</i> and <i>Chlamydia psittaci</i>, have been transferred to the genus <i>Chlamydophila</i>. The complete 16s and 23s rRNA gene sequences of <i>Chlamydia</i> species that have thus far been examined are each ≥97% identical. To be included in this genus, 16s or 23s rRNA sequences of new isolates should be ≥95% identical to the type strain, A/Har13<sup>T</sup>. <i>Chlamydia</i> species are readily identified and distinguished from other species by signature sequences (Figs 3 and 4) or by any of several other genes. Glycogen is produced by <i>Chlamydia</i> species and has been characterized by Garrett (1975). Glycogen is easily detected in the human <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> serovars and is detectable to varying degrees in <i>Chlamydia muridarum</i> and <i>Chlamydia suis</i>. The <i>Chlamydia</i> genomes characterized thus far are 1.0-1.1 Mbp, somewhat smaller than <i>Chlamydophila</i> genomes (Fig. 5). <i>Chlamydia</i> genomes examined thus far have two identical ribosomal operons (Engel &#x0026; Ganem, 1987; Everett &#x0026; Andersen, 1997; Fukushi &#x0026; Hirai, 1993; Scieux et al., 1992). The majority of strains in this genus have extrachromosomal plasmids, but not all (Table 4). <i>Chlamydia</i> strains have varying inclusion morphology and varying sensitivity to sulfadiazine. The currently known strains in <i>Chlamydia</i> have an epitope in MOMP that matches the core epitopes NPTI, TLNPTI, LNPTIA or LNPTI, recognized by vs4 <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i> mAbs (see descriptions below) (Batteiger et al., 1996). The type species for the genus <i>Chlamydia</i> is <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>