<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7074_nm.2791" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2791" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2791" rank="species">Psychrobacter jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.7074"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter jeotgali sp. nov., isolated from jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>449</fpage><lpage>454</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02242-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710611</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychrobacter jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychrobacter</em> <em>jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, traditional Korean fermented seafood).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci (diameter 1·1–1·6 μm) on MA.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are cream in colour, smooth, glistening, low convex, irregular to slightly irregular.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 36 °C but not above 37 °C; optimum is 25–30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 6·0–7·5; no growth is observed below pH 5·0.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 2–3 % (w/v).</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>Biotin, <em>p</em>-aminobenzoic acid, thiamin hydrochloride and vitamin B<sub>12</sub> are not required for growth.</s><s>Catalase-, oxidase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Tween 80 and tyrosine are hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Tryptophan deaminase activity is negative.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase are present but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not.</s><s>Naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase is weakly present in strain YKJ-103<sup>T</sup> but absent in strain YKJ-105.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetate, pyruvate, butyrate, succinate and ethanol are utilized, but glucose, fructose, glutamate, citrate, lactate, formate, methanol and benzoate are not.</s><s>Utilization of malate is variable.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following sugars: adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, myo-inositol, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Predominant isoprenoid quinone is ubiquinone-8 (Q-8).</s><s>Major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Cellular polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and some unidentified polar lipids.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 43–44 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the traditional Korean fermented seafood, jeotgal.</s><s>Type strain is YKJ-103<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the Korean Culture Center of Microorganisms as KCCM 41559<sup>T</sup> and in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as JCM 11463<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Reference strain is YKJ-105.</s></p></content></protolog>