<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6852_nm.4753" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4753" rank="order">Entomoplasmatales</organism><reference id="rid.6852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laigret</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the class Mollicutes: proposed elevation of a monophyletic cluster of arthropod-associated mollicutes to ordinal rank (Entomoplasmatales ord. nov.), with provision for familial rank to separate species with nonhelical morphology (Entomoplasmataceae fam. nov.) from helical species (Spiroplasmataceae), and emended descriptions of the order Mycoplasmatales, family Mycoplasmataceae.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>378</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Entomoplasmatales</i> ord. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Entomoplasmatales</i> (En.to.mo.plas.ma.ta'les. M.L. neut. n. <i>Entomoplasma</i>, type genus of the family <i>Entomoplasmataceae</i>; -<i>ales</i> ending to denote an order; M.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Entomoplasmatales</i>, the <i>Entomoplasma</i> order)</s></p><p class="description"><s>order II of class <i>Mollicutes</i> (Edward and Freundt 1967)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells may be helical or nonhelical.</s><s>Helical cells are usually 100 to 200 nm in diameter and 3 to 5 pm in length during the logarithmic phase of growth.</s><s>Cells are motile, with flexional and twisting movements and rotatory directional motility.</s><s>Flagella, periplasmic fibrils, and cell wall structures are absent.</s><s>Cells may also occur as nonmotile pleomorphic coccoidal forms (300 to 500 nm in diameter) or short, branched or unbranched filaments, bounded by a single membrane.</s><s>Cells are filterable through membranes with an average pore diameter of 220 to 450 nm and are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Nonhelical organisms usually form fried-egg-type colonies on solid medium containing 0.8% Noble agar.</s><s>Helical organisms usually form diffuse colonies on 0.8% Noble agar, but fried-egg-type colonies can be seen on solid medium with 2.25% Noble agar.</s><s>The cells are chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Acid is usually produced from glucose, with evidence that members in both families possess a phosphoenolpyruvate-dependent sugar phosphotransferase system(s).</s><s>Arginine may or may not be hydrolyzed.</s><s>There is no hydrolysis of urea.</s><s>Colonies of some species may hemadsorb guinea pig erythrocytes.</s><s>Cells may or may not require serum or cholesterol for growth, with growth on serum-free broth medium occurring only in the presence of 0.04% Tween 80 (polyoxyethylene sorbitan).</s><s>The temperature range for growth varies from 10 to 43"C, with the optimum usually at 30 to 32°C.</s><s>The genome size ranges from 790 to 2,200 kbp, with the guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA varying from 24 to 30 mol%.</s><s>All organisms tested utilize the UGA codon as a tryptophan signal.</s></p></content></protolog>