<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1535_nm.2170" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2170" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2170" rank="species">Arhodomonas aquaeolei</organism><reference id="rid.1535"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Adkins</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Madigan</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arhodomonas aquaeolei gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, halophilic bacterium isolated from a subterranean brine.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>514</fpage><lpage>520</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-514</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347510</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arhodomonas aquaeolei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arhodomonas aquaeolei</i> (a.quae.o'le.i. L. n. <i>aqua</i>, water: L. n. <i>oleum</i>, oil; M.L. gen. n. <i>aquaeolei</i>, from water of oil, isolated from an oil field brine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in liquid cultures is uniformly turbid with a pellicle forming after 72 h of incubation.</s><s>Gram-negative, short, straight, rod-shaped cells that are 0.8 to 1.0 μm in diameter and 2.0 to 2.5 μm long and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Not spore forming and not encapsulated.</s><s>Colonies on complex medium containing 2.6 M NaCl are circular with entire margins, convex, and smooth; they are 0.5 mm in diameter after 72 h and nonpigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal NaCl concentration is 15%; grows in the presence of NaCl concentrations between 6 to 20%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20 to 45°C and pH 6 to 8; optimal growth occurs at 37°C and pH 7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Respiratory metabolism with O<sub>2</sub> as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Nitrite is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tween 20 and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Casein, DNA, esculin, gelatin, starch, and tyrosine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urease is produced.</s><s>Negative for arginine, lysine, and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>The following tests are negative: Simmons citrate, methyl red, Voges-Proskauer, indole, lecithinase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, phenylalanine deaminase, and phosphatase.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), penicillin G (10 U), and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Cells are resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), neomycin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), and vancomycin (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, butyrate, crotonate, ethanol, fumarate, gluconate, glycerol, lactate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, valerate, isovalerate, xylose, yeast extract, and Casamino Acids.</s><s>Acids are not produced from these compounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, allantoin, arabinose, benzoate, betaine, butanol, cellobiose, citrate, esculin, formate, fructose, fucose, galactose, glucose, glucosamine, glycolate, heptanoate, hexanoate, hippurate, inulin, inositol, isopropanol, lactose, malate, maleate, malonate, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, methanol, propanol, oxamate, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, saccharose, salicin, sorbose, starch, sucrose, tartarate, trehalose, turanose, and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glutamic acid and glutamine are used as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources.</s><s>The other common amino</s></p><p class="description"><s>acids do not support growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major components of the cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16:0</sub> acid (21.74%), C<sub>18:1</sub> acid (21.74%), C<sub>19:0</sub> acid (12.72%), C<sub>16:1</sub> acid (12.55%), and C<sub>18:0</sub> acid (11.20%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type and only strain is <i>Arhodomonas aquaeolei</i> HA-1, which was isolated from a petroleum reservoir production fluid; it has been deposited in the American Type Culture</s></p><p class="description"><s>Collection as strain ATCC 49307.</s></p></content></protolog>