<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6277_nm.1107" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1107" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1107" rank="species">Paracoccus seriniphilus</organism><reference id="rid.6277"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laroche</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulber</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus seriniphilus sp. nov., an L-serine-dehydratase-producing coccus isolated from the marine bryozoan Bugula plumosa.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>443</fpage><lpage>447</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710610</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus seriniphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus seriniphilus</em> (se.ri.ni′phi.lus. Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>seriniphilus</em> serine-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming cocci to rods, 0·5–1×0·7–1 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are circular and colourless to creamy white.</s><s>Growth occurs at 18–37 °C with an optimum of 30 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6·5–8.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth (1–9 %, optimum 3 %).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>No indole is produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Gelatin hydrolysis is not detected.</s><s>Grows on l-serine as sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>Cells in lag phase of growth tend to form aggregates.</s><s>Utilizes Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mellobiose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2,3-butanediol and glycerol.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, furanose, mono-methyl succinate, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alanimide, l-alanylglycine, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>In TSB medium the main fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (<em>cis</em>-11-octadecenoic acid; <em>cis</em>-vaccenic acid).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 63·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the North Sea bryozoan <em>Bugula plumosa</em>.</s><s>Type strain is MBT-A4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14827<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107400<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>