<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8275_nm.13679" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13679" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13679" rank="species">Vogesella perlucida</organism><reference id="rid.8275"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vogesella perlucida sp. nov., a non-pigmented bacterium isolated from spring water.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2677</fpage><lpage>2681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65766-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060039</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vogesella perlucida</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vogesella perlucida</em> (per.lu′ci.da. L. fem. adj. <em>perlucida</em> transparent, referring to the transparent and colourless colonies, which distinguish it from the type species <em>V. indigofera</em>, which forms blue-pigmented colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagellum.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are accumulated.</s><s>After 48 h growth on R2A agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is approximately 0.5×1.0–2.0 μm.</s><s>Visible, round, entire, convex and colourless colonies are formed.</s><s>The colony diameter is approximately 1.0–2.5 mm on R2A agar after 48 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4, 10, 15, 25, 30, 37, 42 and 45 °C, with 0–2 % NaCl and at pH 7–9.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C, 0.5 % NaCl and pH 7.5.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Positive for cytochrome oxidase, catalase, lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for DNase and for hydrolysis of starch, chitin and casein.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are listed in Table 2.</s><s>With the Biolog GN2 test system, the following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: d-fructose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-psicose, Tweens 40 and 80, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-glutamic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and urocanic acid.</s><s>Unable to oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, trehalose, turanose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, dl-carnitine, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Strain DS-28<sup>T</sup> is sensitive to tetracycline, kanamycin, rifampicin, gentamicin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, streptomycin, ampicillin and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DS-28<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17730<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24214<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a spring in southern Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain 61.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>