<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2755_nm.5067" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5067" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5067" rank="species">Virgibacillus picturae</organism><reference id="rid.2755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Diaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus carmonensis sp. nov., Virgibacillus necropolis sp. nov. and Virgibacillus picturae sp. nov., three novel species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings, transfer of the species of the genus salibacillus to Virgibacillus, as Virgibacillus marismortui comb. nov. and Virgibacillus salexigens comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Virgibacillus.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>501</fpage><lpage>511</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02371-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710619</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus picturae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus picturae</em> (pic.tu′rae. L. gen. n. <em>picturae</em> pertaining or belonging to a painting).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods (0·5–0·7×2–6 μm) that occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal, sometimes nearly spherical, endospores that lie in terminal positions in swollen sporangia (see supplementary material available in IJSEM Online at http://ijs.sgmjournals.org).</s><s>After 24 h on MA, colonies are 0·5–1 mm in diameter, low-convex, circular or spread out with entire margins, smooth, cream-coloured and slightly transparent at the edges (opaque after 2 days growth).</s><s>Strains do not grow in an anaerobic chamber at 37 °C and are catalase-positive.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 5–40 °C with optimal growth at 25–35 °C.</s><s>Weak growth without added salt and optimal growth at NaCl concentrations of 5 and 10 %.</s><s>In the API 20E kit, gives positive results for ONPG and nitrate reduction, very weak or negative reaction for gelatinase and negative results for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole and Voges–Proskauer.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is weakly positive.</s><s>Partial haemolysis on 5 % horse-blood agar and on this medium supplemented with 7 % NaCl, with faster growth on the latter medium.</s><s>In the API 50CHB gallery, using CHB suspension medium supplemented with 7 % NaCl, gives weakly positive (sometimes moderately positive) results for aesculin hydrolysis and for acid production from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, glycerol, d-mannose, mannitol and d-melibiose.</s><s>Weak acid production varies between strains for the following substrates: d-cellobiose, maltose, lactose, d-trehalose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose and turanose.</s><s>Growth on different sugars as sole carbon source only results in weakly positive results: raffinose can be used as a sole carbon source by all strains; dl-lactose, d-melibiose and d-trehalose can usually be used as sole carbon sources; use of sucrose varies between strains; d-glucose is not usually used as a sole carbon source; d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose and d-xylose are not used.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, present at about 60 % of the total fatty acids, while anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> respectively account for about 12 and 11 % of the total fatty acids.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present at ≥1 %: iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>/anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern, determined for the type strain, LMG 19492<sup>T</sup> (= DSM 14867<sup>T</sup>), and the most dissimilar strain, LMG 19416, contains predominant amounts of diphosphatidyl glycerol, moderate amounts of phosphatidyl glycerol, trace to moderate amounts of five phospholipids of unknown structure and minor amounts of two unknown polar lipids.</s><s>Presence of three other phospholipids is variable.</s><s>The main menaquinone type is MK-7.</s><s>The G+C content is 39·5 mol% for the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the variable characters listed above, the type strain is positive for growth on d-glucose as a sole carbon source and negative for growth on d-melibiose and sucrose, negative for gelatinase in the API 20E kit and negative for acid production from d-cellobiose, lactose, d-trehalose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose and turanose.</s></p></content></protolog>