<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1965_nm.10710" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10710" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10710" rank="species">Enterobacter turicensis</organism><reference id="rid.1965"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stephan</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lehner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter turicensis sp. nov. and Enterobacter helveticus sp. nov., isolated from fruit powder.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>820</fpage><lpage>826</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64650-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392213</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterobacter turicensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterobacter turicensis</em> (tu.ri.cens′is. L. masc. adj. <em>turicensis</em> from Turicum/Zurich, from where the species was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, coccoid rods that are facultatively anaerobic and motile.</s><s>Cells are 1.0 μm wide by 1.5–2.5 μm long and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>After 24 h aerobic incubation at 37 °C on TSA medium, colonies are yellow-pigmented and convex.</s><s>Catalase-positive and weakly oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies grow well at 10 °C (within 3 days) but poorly at 44 °C.</s><s>Positive for ornithine- and malonate decarboxylase reactions and negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase and lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Tests for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production and the Voges–Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following compounds: galacturonate, d-mannitol, d-maltose, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-trehalose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>No acid production is observed from l-arabitol, d-arabitol, 5-ketogluconate, phenol red, adonitol, palatinose, sucrose, inositol, d-cellobiose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates ONPG, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside and 4-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-maltopyranoside are hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: 5-bromo-3-indoxyl-nonanoate, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide or l-aspartic acid 4-nitroanilide.</s><s>Positive reaction in tests for the utilization of <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, d-galactose, d-trehalose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, maltotriose, maltose, <em>α</em>-lactose, 1-0-methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 1-0-methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, d-cellobiose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, 1-0-methyl <em>β</em>-D-glucopyranoside, aesculin, d-ribose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, dulcitol, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-turanose, d-saccharate, mucate, l-malate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-gluconate, dl-lactate, d-glucosamine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-proline, l-alanine and l-serine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: l-sorbose, sucrose, d-raffinose, lactulose, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, xylitol, d-tagatose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-sorbitol, adonitol, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, i-erythritol, 1-0-methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 3-0-methyl d-glucopyranose, l-tartrate, d-tartrate, <em>myo</em>-tartrate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, tricarballylate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, l-tryptophan, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, gentisate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, trigonelline, betain, putrescine, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-butyrate, histamine, caprate, caprylate, l-histidine, fumarate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, dl-<em>α</em>-amino-n-valerate, ethanolamine, tryptamine, itaconate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, malonate, propionate, l-tyrosine or 2-oxoglutarate.</s><s>The DNA G+C contents of strains 508/05<sup>T</sup> and 610/05 are 57.8 and 57.7 mol%, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 508/05<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23730<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18397<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from fruit powder.</s></p></content></protolog>