<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5525_nm.9834" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9834" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9834" rank="species">Colwellia aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.5525"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Colwellia aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat sediment in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>33</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63920-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403863</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Colwellia aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Colwellia aestuarii</em> (aes.tu.a′ri.i. L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of a tidal flat, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, curved rods, 0·4–0·5×1·8–3·1 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA and on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 32 °C with an optimum temperature range of 25–30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH range for growth is 7·0–8·0; growth occurs weakly at pH 5·0 but not at 4·5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2–3 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs in the presence of 6 % (w/v) NaCl but not in the presence of &#x003E;7 % NaCl.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, xanthine and l-tyrosine are not.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>d-Xylose and salicin are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Benzoate, formate, l-glutamate, d-mannose, pyruvate, succinate and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, d-xylose and maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-melezitose or d-raffinose.</s><s>Susceptible to carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B and streptomycin, but not to ampicillin, lincomycin or tetracycline.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 39·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SMK-10<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12480<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17314<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat sediment from Saemankum, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>