<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7320_nm.6049" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6049" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6049" rank="species">Microbacterium hominis</organism><reference id="rid.7320"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of six new species in the genus Microbacterium and transfer of Flavobacterium marinotypicum ZoBell and Upham to the genus Microbacterium as Microbacterium maritypicum comb. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>973</fpage><lpage>982</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-973</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734054</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium hominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium hominis</i> (ho'mi.nis. L. masc. n. <i>homo</i> man; L. gen. masc. n. <i>hominis</i> of man)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on solid media in air; colonies are 2-4 mm in diameter, circular, low convex with entire margins, opaque and moist.</s><s>Yellowish white pigment is produced.</s><s>In young cultures, small, slender rods are formed.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at angles, forming V shapes; primary branching is uncommon.</s><s>In older cultures, rods are shorter, but a marked rod-coccus growth cycle does not occur.</s><s>Gram-positive non-motile rods.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 28 °C, and growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2% NaCl, but is weak in the presence of 5 and 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Arabinose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, acetate, citrate, fumarate, gluconate, lactate, malate and propionate are assimilated, but adipate, caprate and phenyl acetate are not assimilated.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Methyl red test and Voges-Proskauer test are positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, galactose, glucose, mannose, melezitose, sucrose and trehalose, but is not produced from inulin, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose and xylose.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine, glutamate plus hydroxyglutamate, glycine and alanine.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are rhamnose, 6-deoxy-L-talose, galactose and mannose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15:0, anteiso-C17:0 and iso-C16:0.</s><s>Unsaturated menaquinones with 11 and 12 isoprene units are present.</s><s>The DNA G + C content of the type strain is 71.2 mol%.</s><s>Source is lung aspirate.</s><s>The type strain is IFO 15708<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>