<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.995_nm.7718" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7718" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7718" rank="species">Falcivibrio grandis</organism><reference id="rid.995"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hammann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kronibus</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Viebahn</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandis</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Falcivibrio grandis gen. nov. sp. nov., and Falcivibrio vaginalis gen. nov. sp. nov., new genus and species to accomodate anaerobic motile curved rods formerly described as Vibrio mulieris, Prevot 1940 Breed et al. 1948.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>96</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Falcivibrio grandis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Falcivibrio grandis</i> sp. nov. (gran'dis L. adj. <i>grandis</i> great)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinctly crescent curved rods, generally singular, seldom in pairs, then S- or U-shaped.</s><s>Cells 2.5-5 μm in length and 0.4-0.6 μm in width, and motile by means of one or two or more sub-polar, polar or bipolar flagella.</s><s>One strain owing motility to a maximum of four laterally inserted flagella.</s><s>Cells usually thicker towards the middle, with tapering ends.</s><s>Endospores not formed.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract-glucose-sheep blood agar or human blood-Columbia agar after 3 days of anaerobic incubation are gray to white, pin-point to 1 mm in diameter with a slight greening or weak beta-hemolysis of blood.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic, some strains able to grow in a partially reduced atmosphere with 5% O<sub>2</sub> after several transfers, but never in a candle-jar.</s><s>Various carbohydrates fermented.</s><s>Esculin never hydrolyzed, indole never formed, nitrates never reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase not present.</s><s>Growth stimulated by serum, blood and fumarate.</s><s>Fumarate reduced to succinate, and partially oxidized to malate.</s><s>Products of PYG broth cultures are acetic, lactic, and succinic acids; same products but smaller amounts in PY.</s><s>Traces of gas formed under a paraffin wax seal over a broth culture.</s><s>Gram stains are usually Gram-negative, but some Gram-positive stained cells or cell parts always present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 50-53 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from vaginal or cervical specimens of women with vaginitis, but role in pathogenicity not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They type strain is L 23-1b = DSM 2710 deposited in: Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroogranismen, Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>