<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1565_nm.10914" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10914" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10914" rank="species">Oenococcus kitaharae</organism><reference id="rid.1565"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Endo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oenococcus kitaharae sp. nov., a non-acidophilic and non-malolactic-fermenting oenococcus isolated from a composting distilled shochu residue</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2345</fpage><lpage>2348</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64288-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012559</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Oenococcus kitaharae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Oenococcus kitaharae</em> (ki.ta.ha′rae. N.L. gen. n. <em>kitaharae</em> of Kitahara, to honour the Japanese microbiologist Kakuo Kitahara, for his contribution to the systematics and classification of lactic acid bacteria and in the development of the study of lactic acid bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile and small ellipsoidal cocci measuring 0.2–0.4 by 0.5–0.8 μm.</s><s>Cells usually occur in pairs.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Growth on agar medium is enhanced under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Colonies are white, smooth and approximately 1 mm in diameter on MRS/BHI agar and less than 1 mm in diameter on MRS agar under aerobic conditions after incubation for 7 days at 30 °C.</s><s>However, on both media, colonies grown under anaerobic conditions are approximately 2 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>They are heterofermentative and produce lactic acid, carbon dioxide and ethanol or acetic acid from d-glucose. d-lactate and l-lactate are produced in the ratio 9 : 1.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, maltose, melibiose and d-trehalose and produced weakly from d-ribose, d-gluconate and raffinose, but not from l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, lactose, sucrose, d-melezitose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or starch.</s><s>Acid production from cellobiose and d-salicin is strain-dependent.</s><s>Dextran is not formed from sucrose. l-malate is not decarboxylated to l-lactate in the presence of a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Cells grow between 20 and 30 °C but not at 15 or 37 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>All strains grow at pH values ranging from 5.0 to 7.5; some strains grow at pH 4.5.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between 6.0 and 6.8.</s><s>Growth is not stimulated in the presence of tomato juice.</s><s>Growth is observed in MRS/BHI broth containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl but not 2.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth is also observed in broth containing 5 % (v/v) ethanol but not 10 % (v/v) ethanol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 41 to 43 mol% (type strain, 41 mol%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NRIC 0645<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13282<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17330<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>All known strains were isolated in 2003 from a composting distilled shochu residue collected at a shochu distillery in Miyazaki Prefecture in the southern Kyushu area of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>