<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.619_nm.5617" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5617" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5617" rank="species">Streptococcus cecorum</organism><reference id="rid.619"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dutta</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van de Kerckhove</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus cecorum, a new species isolated from chickens.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>772</fpage><lpage>776</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-772</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus cecorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus cecorum</i> (ce.co'um L. n. <i>cecum</i> sacculated diverticulum of the large intestine [cecum]; N.L. gen pl. n. <i>cecorum</i> of ceca)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci 1 to 1.3 μm in diameter and occur in pairs, short chains, or small groups.</s><s>Within the chains and groups the cells are arranged in pairs.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile and nonsporing.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire edges, low convex, partially translucent, and not pigmented and reach 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 20 h and 2 to 3 mm after 2 days at 37°C in CO<sub>2</sub> in air.</s><s>Growth is slower and less abundant in air.</s><s>The strains show good growth anaerobically in an H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere.</s><s>Uniform turbidity with a small deposit is formed in brain heart infusion broth and Todd-Hewitt broth.</s><s>Fermentative metablism.</s><s>Gas is not formed from glucose.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 45°C, but no growth occurs at 1O°C, in 6.5% NaCl, in 2.75% KSCN, in 0.4% K2Te203, on Slanetz medium, or on kanamycin-esculin-azide agar.</s><s>Growth at pH 9.6 is slower and less abundant than growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Slight inhibition by 40% bile.</s><s>Strains do not survive 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Hemolytic on sheep blood agar, producing greening.</s><s>Strains are negative in the CAMP reaction test, in tests for ammonia from arginine, pyrrolidonylarylaminidase, and gelatinase, tyrosinase, and in conventional and API hippurate tests.</s><s>The majority of the strains react in rapid hippurate tests (only strain A16 is negative).</s><s>Tetrazolium is not reduced.</s><s>Dextran and levan are not formed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch is variable; two strains (strains A6 and A28) are amylase positive in the Mueller-Hinton starch digestion test, but only strain A37 does not react in the API-amidon test.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylaminidase, β-glucuronidase, and Voges-Proskauer positive. α- and β-galactosidase tests are variable; only strains A16 and A39 are positive in these tests.</s><s>Most strains produce hyaluronidase and chondroitin sulfatase (only strain A16 is negative in these two tests).</s><s>Variable and not easily reproducible reactions occur in methylene blue-milk.</s><s>Acid is formed from N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, β-gentiobiose, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Variable reactions with glycogen (strains A29 and A60<sup>T</sup> react positively).</s><s>Some weak reactions occur with tagatose, 2-ketogluconate, and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is not formed from adonitol, D- or L-arabinose, D- or L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glycerol, inositol, lyxose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, turanose, xylitol, xylose, or β-methyl-xyloside.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 37 to 38 ± 1 mol% G+C.</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are hexadecanoic and octadecenoic (ω7) acids.</s><s>Lactobacillic acid is either absent or is present in only trace amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The eight strains of <i>S. cecorum</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Dairy Organisms as strains NCDO 2667 through 2674.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 2674 (=A60).</s><s>The reactions of strain NCDO 2674<sup>T</sup> are those of the majority of the strains, but this strain has acquired tetracycline (MIC, 16 μg/ml), erythromycin (MIC, &#x003E;128 μg/ml), lincomycin (MIC, &#x003E;128 μg/ml), and bacitracin (MIC, 4μg/ml) resistances.</s><s>The DNA base composition of strain NCDO 2674<sup>T</sup> is 37 mol% G+C.</s></p></content></protolog>