<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9290_nm.14578" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14578" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14578" rank="species">Bacteroides graminisolvens</organism><reference id="rid.9290"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishiyama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaku</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides graminisolvens sp. nov., a xylanolytic anaerobe isolated from a methanogenic reactor treating cattle waste</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1901</fpage><lpage>1907</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008268-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567576</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacteroides graminisolvens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacteroides graminisolvens</em> (gra.mi.ni.sol′vens. L. neut. n. <em>gramen</em> grass; L. v. <em>solvere</em> dissolve; N.L. part. adj. <em>graminisolvens</em> grass-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (0.4–0.6 μm wide and 1.2–4.5 μm long); some longer cells occur.</s><s>Produces thin, smooth-surfaced colonies with a pearl-like, iridescent lustre under light.</s><s>Growth is strongly stimulated by the addition of haemin; cobalamin (vitamin B<sub>12</sub>) slightly enhances growth.</s><s>Utilizes arabinose, xylose, fructose, galactose, glucose, mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, xylo-oligosaccharides, dextrin, glycogen, starch, pectin, xylan (birch wood), amygdalin and salicin.</s><s>Ribose, rhamnose, inulin, aesculin and pyruvate are utilized only weakly.</s><s>In the presence of haemin and cobalamin, acetate and propionate are produced from glucose, along with small amounts of succinate.</s><s>Propionate is the most abundant product from xylan in the presence of haemin and cobalamin.</s><s>In the presence of glucose and xylan, the final pH is 4.9 and 5.2–5.3, respectively.</s><s>Does not use sorbose, trehalose, melezitose, CM-cellulose, cellulose (filter-paper fragments and ball-milled powder), glycerol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, fumarate, lactate, malate or succinate.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.2.</s><s>The growth temperature range is 5–40 °C; the optimum is 30–35 °C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration range for growth is 0–4.0 % (w/v) in PYHG medium; optimum growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Does not have catalase, oxidase, nitrate-reducing or urease activities.</s><s>Does not produce hydrogen sulfide or indole.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and starch, but not gelatin.</s><s>Sensitive to bile.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and the major respiratory quinone is MK-10(H<sub>0</sub>).</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XDT-1<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15093<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19988<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rice-straw residue in a methanogenic reactor treating waste from cattle farms.</s></p></content></protolog>