<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6859_nm.1677" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1677" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1677" rank="species">Ralstonia insidiosa</organism><reference id="rid.6859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Baere</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verschraegen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wautersia gen. nov., a novel genus accommodating the phylogenetic lineage including Ralstonia eutropha and related species, and proposal of Ralstonia [Pseudomonas] syzygii (Roberts et al. 1990) comb. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>317</fpage><lpage>327</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02754-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023939</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Ralstonia insidiosa</em> Coenye <em>et al.</em> 2003</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ralstonia insidiosa</em> (in.si.di.o′sa. L. fem. adj. <em>insidiosa</em> deceitful, dangerous, referring to the fact that these seemingly harmless environmental organisms can be isolated from, and possibly cause infections in, humans).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the data of Coenye <em>et al.</em> (2003a) and this study.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, aerobic, non-fermentative, motile rods with one to three polar flagella.</s><s>Aerobic growth is observed at 28, 32 and 37 °C and on <em>Burkholderia cepacia</em>-selective agar.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, lipase, phosphatase, proline aminopeptidase, pyrrolidonyl aminopeptidase and <em>γ</em>-l-glutamyl aminopeptidase activities are present.</s><s>However, alkaline phosphatase is negative when Rosco tablets are used.</s><s>No lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, tryptophan aminopeptidase or <em>N</em>-benzyl-arginine aminopeptidase activities are detected.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>No acid is produced from sucrose or mannitol.</s><s>The original description (Coenye <em>et al.</em>, 2003a) mentions a lack of acid production from glucose, but in this study, oxidative acid production was observed from glucose, l-arabinose and xylose.</s><s>Acid production from lactose is variable.</s><s>Glucose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate and citrate are assimilated, but l-arabinose, mannose, mannitol and maltose are not.</s><s>Alkalinization occurs on minimal mineral agar with acetate, allantoin, lactate and malonate, but not with galacturonate, oxalate or maleate.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Resistant to colistin and desferrioxamine.</s><s>Two biovars can be distinguished: strains of biovar 1 are negative for acid production from and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gelatin hydrolysis and mucate on Simmons' base agar and positive for adipate on API 20NE; biovar 2 strains have the opposite characteristics.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 63·9–64·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21421<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46789<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the sputum of a patient with acute lymphoblastic leukaemia in the USA in 2001.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 64·3 mol%.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics are the same as described above for the species.</s><s>The type strain has no urease activity, does not assimilate <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and assimilates phenylacetate.</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is AF488779.</s></p></content></protolog>