<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4543_nm.2906" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2906" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2906" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas ulvae</organism><reference id="rid.4543"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Egan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmström</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kjelleberg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas ulvae sp. nov., a bacterium with antifouling activities isolated from the surface of a marine alga.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1499</fpage><lpage>1504</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491351</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoalteromonas ulvae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas ulvae</i> (ul'vae. N.L. gen. n. <i>ulvae</i> of Ulva, the generic name of the host alga, <i>U. lactuca</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells that are 1.75-2.5 μm in length and 1-1.5 μm in width.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Growth on VNSS medium results in small, dark-purple colonies, while growth on LB20 or TSB with 2% NaCl results in the formation of white colonies.</s><s>Does not ferment sugar in the Hugh-Leifson test.</s><s>Sodium ions are required for growth, with the optimum NaCl concentration being 1-2.5%.</s><s>Can grow within a pH range of 5.5-12; the optimum pH for growth is pH 8.</s><s>Slow growth occurs at 4 °C and no growth is detectable at 35 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Utilizes citrate, maltose, L-proline, glucose, mannose and Tween 20 but not trehalose, lactose, sucrose, fructose, glycerol, raffinose, sorbitol, melibiose, xylose, cellobiose, erythritol, L-glutamine, arabinose, rhamnose or DL-serine as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin and displays tryptophan deaminase activity.</s><s>Strains UL12<sup>T</sup> and UL13 are negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production and no β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or urease activity is detected.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, ampicillin, kanamycin, streptomycin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol and spectinomycin at 50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup> and sensitive to the vibriostatic agent O/129 at 150 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin G at up to 100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Isolated from the surface of a marine alga, <i>Ulva lactuca</i>, collected from the rocky intertidal zone off the eastern coast of Australia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, UL12<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of New South Wales as UNSW 095600T and in the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria, Aberdeen, UK, as NCIMB 13762<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Nucleotide sequences for the 16S rDNA genes of isolates UL12T and UL13 have been deposited in the DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank database under the accession numbers AF172987 and AF172988, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>