<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2778_nm.6181" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6181" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6181" rank="species">Cellulosimicrobium variabile</organism><reference id="rid.2778"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bakalidou</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berchtold</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuhnigk</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wenzel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>König</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cellulosimicrobium variabile sp. nov., a cellulolytic bacterium from the hindgut of the termite Mastotermes darwiniensis.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1185</fpage><lpage>1192</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01904-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148626</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cellulosimicrobium variabile</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cellulosimicrobium variabile</i> (va.ri.a'bi.le. L. neut. adj. <i>variabile</i> variable, because the cells form rods or cocci)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.3x0.7 μm), V-shaped or coccoid (diameter 0.25 μm) and non-motile.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Yellow, smooth colonies on TSA (Difco) about 2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 28 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Cellulolytic and xylanolytic activities are produced.</s><s>The murein contains the amino acids lysine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid and alanine in a molar ratio of 1.0:0.9:2.0:1.8 and belongs to the peptidoglycan type A4α.</s><s>N-Glycolylmuramic acid, mycolic acids and hydroxy fatty acids are absent.</s><s>The neutral sugars galactose, rhamnose and glucose are found in a molar ratio of 4:2:1.</s><s>The main quinone is menaquinone MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Major fatty acids are ai15:0 (53.6 mol%), i15:0 (17.0 mol%), 16:0 (7.2 mol%), i16:0 (6.0 mol%), ai17:0 (7.0 mol%), 14:0 (6.6 mol%), i14:0 (1.5 mol%), i17:0 (0.6 mol%) and 15:0 (0.5 mol%).</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-xylose, D-cellobiose, D-melibiose, D-arabitol and D-mannose.</s><s>No acid production is observed from sucrose, D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, maltose, methyl β-D-glucoside or erythritol.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole sources of carbon: N-acetyl D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, <i>p</i>-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, D-maltose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose, maltitol, mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, fumarate (weak), DL-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, L-histidine and L-proline.</s><s>N-Acetyl D-galactosamine, adonitol, inositol, putrescine, propionate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, glutarate, itaconate, L-malate, mesaconate, suberate, L-alanine, β-alanine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrolysis of the following chromogenic substrates is positive: aesculin, pNP β-D-galactopyranoside, pNP α-D-glucopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucopyranoside, pNP β-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxy-5'-pNP phosphate, L-alanine <i>para</i>-nitroanilide (pNA) and L-proline-pNA. pNP β-D-glucuronide is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 70-72 mol%.</s><s>The 16S rDNA sequence of isolate MX5<sup>T</sup> (accession number AJ298873) has high similarity to those of two as-yet undescribed isolates, strain SR 272 (99%; accession number X87317) and strain VPCX2 (`<i>Cellulomonas pachnodae</i>' ; host, larvae of the rose-chafer <i>Pachnoda marginata</i>) (97%; accession number AF105422) from the EMBL nucleotide sequence database.</s><s>Strains can be distinguished from <i>Cellulosimicrobium cellulans</i> and from <i>Cellulomonas</i> species by the phenotypic features compiled in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: hindgut contents of the Australian termite <i>Mastotermes darwiniensis</i> (Froggatt).</s><s>The type strain is MX5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 10177<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-303<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>