<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12740_nm.22519" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22519" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22519" rank="species">Echinicola jeungdonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12740"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>T.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Echinicola jeungdonensis sp. nov., isolated from a solar saltern</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2065</fpage><lpage>2068</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026765-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851907</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Echinicola jeungdonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Echinicola jeungdonensis</em> (jeung.do.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>jeungdonensis</em> of island Jeungdo, Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile and aerobic rods (0.7–0.8 µm wide and 1.4–1.5 µm long).</s><s>Colonies on MA are convex, circular, smooth and yellow–orange with entire margins, approximately 1 mm in diameter after 3 days at 25 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA.</s><s>No growth occurs on TSA, nutrient agar, blood agar, MacConkey agar, DNase test agar or skim milk.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2 % NaCl), at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 7) and at 15–42 °C (optimum 20 °C).</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, nitrate reduction and aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatinase.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>With API ZYM, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidases, α- and β-glucosidases and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are present, but esterase (C4), lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>With GN2 MicroPlates, utilizes as sole carbon sources α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, acetic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, uridine and α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, but does not utilize Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, α-, β- and γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>) and summed feature 9 (comprising iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and/or 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HMD3054<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23122<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7682<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a solar saltern in Jeungdo, Sinan, Jeolnam, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>