<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7068_nm.2929" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2929" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2929" rank="species">Shewanella marinintestina</organism><reference id="rid.7068"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Satomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oikawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella marinintestina sp. nov., Shewanella schlegeliana sp. nov. and Shewanella sairae sp. nov., novel eicosapentaenoic-acid-producing marine bacteria isolated from sea-animal intestines.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>491</fpage><lpage>499</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02392-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710618</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella marinintestina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella marinintestina</em> (ma.rin.in.tes′ti.na. L. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea; L. adj. <em>intestinus</em> of the intestine; N.L. fem. adj. <em>marinintestina</em> of the intestine from the sea, referring to the isolation of strains from the intestines of sea animals).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 2·0–3·0 μm long, motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Circular, opaque, ivory colonies are formed after 2 days on MA at 20 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs by anaerobic respiration with TMAO as electron acceptor.</s><s>Psychrophilic.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures from 4 to 30 °C, with an optimum of 20–25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6·0–10·0, with an optimum of pH 7·0–8·0.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs at concentrations of 1–5 % (w/v) and is optimal at 2·0–3·0 %.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, lipase, gelatinase, phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, DNase and RNase are positive.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein, hippurate and ONPG are also positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production and reduction of nitrate to nitrite occur.</s><s>Amylase, chitinase, alginase, agarase and urease are negative.</s><s>Haemolytic activity for sheep blood is negative.</s><s>Decarboxylation of ornithine, arginine and lysine is negative.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from d-ribose, d-glucosamine and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>d-Ribose is fermented.</s><s>No acid is produced from d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-xylose, lactose, melibiose, rhamnose, sucrose, maltose, inositol, d-mannitol, sorbitol or amygdalin.</s><s>The following energy sources are utilized: d-glucose, acetate, pyruvate, propionate, d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, valerate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamine, l-glutamate, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-serine and l-threonine.</s><s>Produces EPA.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinones are Q-7 and Q-8.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The type strain is IK-1<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 11558<sup>T</sup> =LMG 21403<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the intestine of a squid.</s></p></content></protolog>