<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6669_nm.9979" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9979" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9979" rank="species">Cohnella thermotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.6669"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cohnella thermotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov., and classification of 'Paenibacillus hongkongensis' as Cohnella hongkongensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>781</fpage><lpage>786</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63985-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585694</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cohnella thermotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cohnella thermotolerans</em> (ther.mo.tol′er.ans. Gr. n. <em>therme</em> heat; L. pres. part. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>thermotolerans</em> able to tolerate high temperatures).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Oxidase-positive and shows an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain comprises iso C16 : 0 (45·5 %), anteiso C15 : 0 (28·4 %), anteiso C17 : 0 (6·7 %), C16 : 0 (6·6 %), C18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (4·0 %), iso C15 : 0 (3·2 %), iso C14 : 0 (2·1 %), C15 : 0 (1·4 %), iso C17 : 0 (1·1 %), C14 : 0 (1·0 %) and C17 : 1<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1·0 %).</s><s>Aesculin and p-nitrophenol (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside are hydrolysed.</s><s>Arbutin, l-arabinose (weakly), d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose (weakly) and d-ribose are utilized as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>No acid production from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s>No hydrolysis of o-NP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine p-nitroanilide (pNA), l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pna or l-proline pNA.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, i-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 59 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 47242<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17683<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108492<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of industrial starch production in Sweden.</s></p></content></protolog>