<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12491_nm.21331" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21331" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21331" rank="species">Prevotella scopos</organism><reference id="rid.12491"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella fusca sp. nov. and Prevotella scopos sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>854</fpage><lpage>858</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023861-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495041</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella scopos</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella scopos</em> [sco′pos. L. masc. n. <em>scopos</em> (nominative in apposition) a mark, aim at which one shoots, referring to the ‘bullseye’ appearance of older colonies of the type strain].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on one strain.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, pigmented Gram-negative bacilli (0.7×0.9–3.0 µm).</s><s>After 4 days of incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, smooth, opaque and off-white, with a light orange pigment in the centre of the colonies.</s><s>On further incubation, colonies develop a distinct area of dark brown pigment in the centre of the colony to form a ‘bullseye’ colony.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces moderate turbidity that is enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are saccharolytic and ferment fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, raffinose and sucrose; arabinose, cellobiose, mannitol, melezitose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Moderate amounts of acetic acid, major amounts of succinic acid, and trace amounts of isovaleric and lactic acids are produced as end products of metabolism in PYG broth.</s><s>In addition to these acids, trace to minor amounts of isobutyric acid and moderate rather than trace amounts of isovaleric acid are produced as metabolic by-products in PY broth.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed; arginine, aesculin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The Rapid ID 32A profile is 4707 45 <sup>0</sup>/<sub>2</sub> 2 2 <sup>2</sup>/<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>The principal cellular long-chain fatty acids are ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, 3-OH i-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, 3-OH C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is W2052<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22613<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 57945<sup>T</sup>), isolated from an implant in the human oral cavity.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>