<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5381_nm.1116" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1116" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1116" rank="species">Rhodobaca bogoriensis</organism><reference id="rid.5381"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Milford</surname><given-names>A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achenbach</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>D.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Madigan</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobaca bogoriensis gen. nov. and sp. nov., an alkaliphilic purple nonsulfur bacterium from African Rift Valley soda lakes.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>174</volume><fpage>18</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030000166</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10985738</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Species description of <i>Rhodobaca bogoriensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobaca bogoriensis</i> (bo.gor.i.en'sis. L. adj. <i>bogoriensis</i> pertaining to Lake Bogoria, a soda lake in Kenya, Africa; <i>Rhodobaca bogoriensis</i> a red (rose) berry from Lake Bogoria Anoxygenic phototrophic purple nonsulfur bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative motile cocci to short rods measuring 0.8–1 μm × 0.8–1.5 μm.</s><s>Color of anaerobically grown cells is yellow to yellowish-brown.</s><s>In vivo absorption maxima of phototrophic cells, 871 nm.</s><s>Cells contain bacteriochlorophyll a and carotenoids of the spheroidene pathway; demethylspheroidenone is the major carotenoid in anoxic/light-grown cells.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic membranes of the vesicular type.</s><s>Light-harvesting (LH) I pigmentprotein complex present but an LH II system absent.</s><s>Grows photoheterotrophically and chemotrophically (oxic/darkness).</s><s>Carbon sources supporting excellent phototrophic growth include succinate, malate, pyruvate, fumarate, acetate, mannitol, butyrate, valerate, heptanoate, xylose, glucose, fructose, and sucrose.</s><s>Nitrogen sources utilized are ammonia, aspartate, glutamate, asparagine, glutamine, and casamino acids.</s><s>Biotin and thiamine are required growth factors; in defined medium vitamin B12 is not required but is growth stimulatory.</s><s>Best growth achieved in media containing 0.05–0.1% yeast extract.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; optimum growth occurs at pH 9 (pH range 7.5–10) in media containing 1–3% NaCl (however NaCl not required for growth).</s><s>Optimal growth temperature, 39 °C.</s><s>No evidence for autotrophic growth with H<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub>S+CO<sub>2</sub>, and nitrogen fixation not detected.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 58.8 mol%.</s><s>Phylogeny, a member of the α-Proteobacteria with its closest relatives residing in the <i>Rhodobacter/Rhodovulum</i> clade.</s><s>The type strain is LBB1<sup>T</sup>, isolated from water/sediment samples from Lake Bogoria, Kenyan district of African Rift Valley.</s><s>Deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 700920.</s><s>Genbank accession number of 16S rRNA gene sequence, AF248638.</s></p></content></protolog>