<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1730_nm.8807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8807" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8807" rank="species">Psychroflexus tropicus</organism><reference id="rid.1730"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Donachie</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alam</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychroflexus tropicus sp. nov., an obligately halophilic Cytophaga-Flavobacterium-Bacteroides group bacterium from an Hawaiian hypersaline lake</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>935</fpage><lpage>940</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02733-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143045</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychroflexus tropicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychroflexus tropicus</em> [trop′ic.us. L. masc. adj. <em>tropicus</em> tropical, of or pertaining to the tropic(s) or solstice, relating to its isolation from a subtropical lake].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-motile, straight to slightly curved rods 0·18–0·25 μm wide and 2·0–2·5 μm long.</s><s>Old cultures in MB produce ‘coccoid bodies’.</s><s>Orange, circular, butyrous, convex, opaque, entire, smooth, glistening colonies of 2–4 mm diameter on MA.</s><s>Gliding motility.</s><s>Grows aerobically on MA between 4 and 43 °C, but not at 50 °C, and on 50 % strength MA with 1–20 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, with optimal growth in 50 % strength MB at 30 °C with 7·5–10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth on MA in a CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere at 30 °C.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative; nitrate reductase expressed in the presence of 7·5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or with 3·2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Other characteristics are listed in Table 1.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), leucine, valine and cystine arylamidases, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and phosphohydrolase activities expressed in API ZYM.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, mono-methyl succinate and l-alaninamide are oxidized in Biolog GN in the presence of 7·5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of 2 or 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows on glycerol, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, sorbitol, trehalose, starch and d-arabitol in API 50 CH strips.</s><s>Acid produced from sucrose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The dominant fatty acids at 15 and at 30 °C are 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid and 13-methyl tetradecanoic acid, respectively.</s><s>The G+C content is 35±0·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LA1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-734<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15496<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from water collected at a depth of 0·3 m in hypersaline L.</s><s>Laysan on Laysan Island in the Northwestern Hawaiian Islands.</s><s>On the basis of the 16S rDNA sequence, <em>Psychroflexus torquis</em> ACAM 623<sup>T</sup> from Antarctic sea-ice is the closest described relative (94·4 % sequence identity over 1423 bases).</s><s>LA1<sup>T</sup> and <em>P. torquis</em> ACAM 623<sup>T</sup> share morphological and nutritional traits, but the fact that LA1<sup>T</sup> grows well at temperatures above 20 °C, together with genotypic differences, support the placement of LA1<sup>T</sup> as a novel species in <em>Psychroflexus</em> as <em>Psychroflexus tropicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>