<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2755_nm.5064" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5064" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5064" rank="species">Virgibacillus carmonensis</organism><reference id="rid.2755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Diaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus carmonensis sp. nov., Virgibacillus necropolis sp. nov. and Virgibacillus picturae sp. nov., three novel species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings, transfer of the species of the genus salibacillus to Virgibacillus, as Virgibacillus marismortui comb. nov. and Virgibacillus salexigens comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Virgibacillus.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>501</fpage><lpage>511</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02371-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710619</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus carmonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus carmonensis</em> (car.mo.nen′sis. N.L. adj. <em>carmonensis</em> of Carmona, referring to the mural paintings of the necropolis at Carmona, Spain, from where the strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods (0·5–0·7×2–7 μm), which mostly occur singly, sometimes in pairs and short chains.</s><s>They bear ellipsoidal, sometimes nearly spherical, endospores that lie in subterminal positions in swollen sporangia (see supplementary material available in IJSEM Online at http://ijs.sgmjournals.org).</s><s>After 24 h on MA, colonies are 0·5–1·0 mm in diameter, low-convex, circular with slightly irregular margins, smooth and transparent with larger colonies having a pink tint.</s><s>After 2 days, the colonies turn bright pink and opaque.</s><s>Strains do not grow in an anaerobic chamber at 37 °C and are catalase-positive.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–40 °C with optimal growth at 25–30 °C.</s><s>No growth without added salt and optimal growth at NaCl concentrations of 5 and 10 %.</s><s>In the API 20E kit, strains gave positive results for nitrate reduction and negative results for ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole, Voges–Proskauer and gelatinase.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis positive.</s><s>No haemolysis on 5 % horse-blood agar and no growth on this medium when supplemented with 7 % NaCl.</s><s>With the exception of very weak reactions for aesculin hydrolysis and acid production from 5-keto-d-gluconate, strains are unreactive in the API 50CHB gallery, even when the CHB suspension medium is supplemented with 7 % NaCl.</s><s>The following sugars can be used as sole carbon sources: cellobiose (weak growth), d-melibiose, raffinose, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s><s>No growth on d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, dl-lactose or d-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, present at about 65 % of the total fatty acids, while anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> accounts for about 10 % of the total fatty acids.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present at ≥1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>/anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern of the type strain contains predominant amounts of diphosphatidyl glycerol and phosphatidyl glycerol, minor amounts of three phospholipids and one polar lipid of unknown structure and trace amounts of two additional unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The main menaquinone type is MK-7.</s><s>The G+C content is 38·9 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG 20964<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14868<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>