<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1436_nm.1851" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1851" rank="genus">Rubrivivax</organism><reference id="rid.1436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>DeLey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Rhodocyclus gelatinosus to Rubrivivax gelatinosus gen. nov., comb. nov., and phylogenetic relationships with Leptothrix, Sphaerotilus natans, Pseudomonas saccharophila, and Alcaligenes latus.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>65</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-65</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rubrivivax</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rubrivivax</i> (Ru. bri. vi´vax. L. adj. <i>ruber</i>, red; L. adj. <i>vivax</i>, living; M. L. masc. n. <i>Rubrivivax</i>, red living organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based mainly on previously published descriptions by Weckesser et al. (43) and Imhoff and Triiper (15).</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 0.4 to 0.7 by 1 to 3 μm.</s><s>Irregularly curved cells up to 15 μm long may occur in older cultures.</s><s>Sheaths are not formed.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions in the light, photoheterotrophic growth with various organic substrates as electron donors or photoautotrophic growth in the presence of H<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, and growth factors is possible.</s><s>In the dark, chemoautotrophic growth with CO as a sole carbon and energy source (40) and aerobic chemoheterotrophic growth with various organic substrates are also possible.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids are present as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Small fingerlike invaginations of the cytoplasmic membrane represent photosynthetic membranes.</s><s>Nitrogen may be fixed under photoautotrophic growth conditions.</s><s>Colonies are pink to deep red because of photosynthetic pigments; heterotrophically grown colonies are initially faintly pink.</s><s>The G+C values of the DNA range from 70.0 to 72.5 mol%.</s><s>In DNA-rRNA hybridizations, <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> values of 77.0 to 81.5°C are obtained versus rRNA of <i>Rubrivivax gelatinosus</i> NCIB 8290<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rubrivivax gelatinosus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>