<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12181_nm.20179" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20179" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20179" rank="species">Adhaeribacter aerophilus</organism><reference id="rid.12181"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Son</surname><given-names>J.-A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ka</surname><given-names>J.-O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Adhaeribacter aerophilus sp. nov., Adhaeribacter
aerolatus sp. nov. and Segetibacter aerophilus
sp. nov., isolated from air samples</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2424</fpage><lpage>2429</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018374-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19946049</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Adhaeribacter aerophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Adhaeribacter aerophilus</em> (ae.ro.phi′lus. Gr. n. <em>aer</em> air; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>aerophilus</em> air-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.9–1.1 μm in diameter and 2.0–4.3 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular, convex and pink after 3 days at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Grows on LB, CM3-nutrient agar and WA (very weakly), but not on NA, TSA or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10−37 °C, at pH 6.5–8.5 and with 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase is weakly positive.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, chitin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Positive (in API 20NE and API ZYM strips) for hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (substrate <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Does not assimilate any of the carbohydrates tested (API 20NE and API ID 32GN).</s><s>Positive for assimilation of the following substrates: amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glutaric acid, glycogen, itaconate, lactose, malonate, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, oxalic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of the following substrates: acetate, adipate, d-adonitol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, citrate, dextran, dulcitol, erythritol, formate, d-fructose, d-fucose, l-fucose, gluconate, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, histidine, inositol, inulin, lactate, d-lyxose, malate, maleic acid, d-mannitol, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, pyruvic acid, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, succinic acid, d-tagatose, tartaric acid, xylitol and l-xylose.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 4 (comprising iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 6424S-25<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 14118<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 106134<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an air sample from Suwon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>