<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7884_nm.5083" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5083" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5083" rank="species">Pasteuria nishizawae</organism><reference id="rid.7884"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Noel</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Atibalentja</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domier</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Pasteuria nishizawae.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1681</fpage><lpage>1685</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63174-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014501</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Pasteuria nishizawae</em> Sayre <em>et al.</em> 1991</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the original description and observations of strains from Urbana, IL, USA, and the Tohoku National Agricultural Experiment Station, Kariwano, Akita, Japan.</s><s>Neither the original field population from Japan nor a subcultured greenhouse population could be obtained for this study (Nishizawa, 1984; Sayre <em>et al.</em>, 1991a).</s><s>Some observations are reported in Atibalentja <em>et al.</em> (2004b).</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>Pasteuria nishizawae</em> [(Firmicutes) NC; G+; M; NAS (AF134868 and AF516396), morphology (see following description); S (<em>Heterodera glycines</em> Ichinohe, 1952, pseudocoelom)].</s><s>Obligate endoparasitic bacterium of the pseudocoelom of <em>H. glycines</em>.</s><s>Microcolony shape is cauliflower-like initially and later fragments into clusters of elongated grape-like immature sporangia occurring in configurations of octets, quartets and doublets.</s><s>Sporangia are cup-shaped with light microscope (LM) diameter =5·3±0·03 μm, transmission electron microscope (TEM) diameter =4·4±0·03 μm, LM height =4·3±0·03 μm and TEM height =3·1±0·3 μm.</s><s>Sporangial wall and mother cell matrix of endospore disintegrate at maturity leaving the exosporium as the outermost layer of the endospore.</s><s>Surface of exosporium is velutinous to hairy.</s><s>The stem cell is observed occasionally.</s><s>The central body is oblate spheroid, ellipsoid to narrowly elliptical.</s><s>Orientation of major axis to sporangium base is horizontal with LM diameter =2·1±0·2 μm, TEM diameter =1·6±0·2 μm, LM height =1·7±0·1 μm and TEM height =1·3±0·1 μm.</s><s>The epicortical layer entirely surrounds the cortex.</s><s>A laminar inner spore coat with alternating layers of dense and light materials occurs between the outer spore membrane and epicortical layer.</s><s>The outer spore coat consists of several layers of electron-dense materials and is surrounded laterally and ventrally by microprojections.</s><s>Including the microprojections, the outer spore coat is thickest at the top of the central body and then tapers gradually to 0·2 μm at the spore equator and to 0·1 μm or less around a 0·3±0·1 μm-wide basal pore.</s><s>Parasporal structures consist of long primary fibres arising laterally from the outer spore coat and bending downwards to yield numerous secondary fibres arrayed ventrally.</s><s>Depending on the extent of invagination of the basal adhesion layer, additional partial hirsute layers may be present on the obverse face of the central body.</s><s>Spores attach to second-stage juveniles in soil but rarely to males in soil.</s><s>The cuticle and body wall are penetrated by a germ tube that develops after the infective second-stage juvenile penetrates the host plant root.</s><s>The life cycle is completed only in the pseudocoelom of females.</s><s>The only confirmed host is <em>H. glycines</em>.</s><s>Attachment of endospores to second-stage juveniles of <em>Globodera rostochiensis</em> [(potato cyst nematode) with endospores obtained from <em>H. elachista</em> (upland rice nematode)], <em>H. lespedezae</em> (lespedeza cyst nematode), <em>H. schachtii</em> (sugar beet cyst nematode) and <em>H. trifolii</em> (clover cyst nematode) indicates that these nematode species may be hosts.</s><s>Completion of the life cycle of <em>P. nishizawae</em> in these nematode species has not been confirmed.</s></p></content></protolog>