<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1718_nm.1862" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1862" rank="species">Thiomonas cuprina</organism><reference id="rid.1718"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchino</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amils</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the phylogenetic relationships of Thiomonas cuprina.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2720</fpage><lpage>2724</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65537-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978245</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Thiomonas cuprina</em> Moreira and Amils 1997</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The emended description here is essentially that of ‘<em>Thiobacillus cuprinus</em>’ given by Huber &#x0026; Stetter (1990), as emended by Moreira &#x0026; Amils (1997), Kelly &#x0026; Wood (2005) and in this study.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic rods, 1.0–4.0 μm long and 0.3–0.5 μm wide; motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Brownish-coloured colonies develop on complex media (yeast extract, peptone, Casamino acids, meat extract).</s><s>Temperature optimum is 30–36 °C; no growth at 15 or 50 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth on yeast extract or sulfidic ores is pH 3.0–4.0, with a typical range of pH 2.0–6.5; no growth at pH 1.0 or 7.4.</s><s>Some strains can grow on yeast extract or sulfide ores at pH 1.5–4.5.</s><s>Facultative chemolithoautotrophs; aerobic.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic growth on yeast extract, peptone, Casamino acids and meat extract; some strains grow on pyruvate.</s><s>No currently reported strains can grow on arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, mannose, raffinose, ribose, sorbose, sucrose, arginine, cysteine, glycine, l-glutamate, l-lysine, dl-serine, acetate, lactate, succinate, citrate or malate.</s><s>Chemolithoautotrophic growth on a defined mixture of sulfide ores, chalcopyrite or arsenopyrite, or H<sub>2</sub>S, and less efficiently on single sulfide ores (sphalerite, galena and synthetic CdS and FeS) or elemental sulfur.</s><s>No growth on the natural ores bornite, chalcocite, covellite, pyrite, pitchblende or cinnabar or the synthetic sulfides Ag<sub>2</sub>S, CuS, MoS, Sb<sub>2</sub>S<sub>3</sub>, SnS or ZnS.</s><s>Ferrous sulfate is neither oxidized nor used as a growth substrate.</s><s>Copper, zinc and uranium can be mobilized from ore mixtures and high levels of resistance are exhibited to cobalt, nickel and zinc, with significant tolerance of copper, arsenic and uranium.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-8 and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, but not rusticyanin.</s><s>Found in continental solfataric fields and mining environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Hö5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 5495<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102145<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102094<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 66.0±0.6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>, HPLC).</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is deposited under GenBank/EMBL/DDBJ accession numbers AB331954 and AB331953.</s></p></content></protolog>