<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1735_nm.8608" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8608" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8608" rank="species">Halomonas ventosae</organism><reference id="rid.1735"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martínez-Cánovas</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas ventosae sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, denitrifying, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>733</fpage><lpage>737</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02942-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143016</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas ventosae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas ventosae</em> (ven.to.sa′e. N.L. sb. gen. <em>ventosae</em> of Ventosa, named in honour of Professor A. Ventosa, a renowned expert on halophilic bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are capsulated, motile, Gram-negative rods, 1·2–1·4×0·7–0·8 μm, occurring either singly or in pairs.</s><s>They accumulate PHA.</s><s>On MY solid medium the bacteria grow in circular, convex, cream-coloured, mucoid colonies.</s><s>In liquid medium their growth pattern is uniform.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, capable of growing in salt concentrations (mixture of sea salts) of 3–15 % (w/v), whereas no growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Grow within the temperature range 15–50 °C and at pH values between 6 and 10.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, with oxygen, nitrate or nitrite as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Cells do not grow anaerobically in the presence of fumarate.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>They do not produce acids from sugars.</s><s>Indol, methyl-red and Voges–Proskauer are negative.</s><s>Selenite is reduced, phenylalanine deaminase is produced and tyrosine and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but not Tween 80, starch, urea, gelatin, DNA, lecithin or casein.</s><s>There is no growth on MacConkey agar and cetrimide agar.</s><s>Blood is not haemolysed.</s><s>The following can be used as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, d-galactose, d-gluconate, d-glucose, lactate, malonate, maltose, propionate, d-sorbitol and succinate, but not l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, ethanol and formate.</s><s>The following are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-histidine, isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine and l-valine.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to amoxycillin (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), polymyxin B (300 UI), rifampicin (30 μg), sulfonamide (250 μg) and trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1·25–23·75 μg).</s><s>The three strains were isolated from a saline soil in Jaén, south-eastern Spain.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72·6–74·3 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Al12<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5797<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15911<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>Additionally, this strain is able to grow in a medium containing 1 % (w/v) mixture of sea salts, although it grows best in 8 % (w/v).</s><s>It requires sodium but not magnesium or potassium; the optimum NaCl concentration is 1·38 M.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Phosphatase and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>The following can be used as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, d-fructose, fumarate, dl-glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol and d-trehalose, but not d-mannose, d-salicin, l-serine and starch.</s><s>Al12<sup>T</sup> is resistant to tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acids (up to 83 %) are 18 : 1 <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 16 : 0, 16 : 1 <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 15 : 0 iso 2-OH, and it has a ubiquinone with nine isoprene units.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 74·3 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p></content></protolog>