<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2869_nm.2306" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2306" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2306" rank="subspecies">Francisella tularensis holarctica</organism><reference id="rid.2869"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Olsufjev</surname><given-names>N.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meshcheryakova</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Subspecific taxonomy of Francisella tularensis McCoy and Chapin 1912</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>872</fpage><lpage>874</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Francisella tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> Olsufjev and Meshcheryakova 1982, 296. supsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Francisella tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> (hol.arc'ti.ca. Gr. prep. <i>holos</i> whole; Gr.n. <i>arctos</i> the great and little bear constellations [hence, the northern regions]; M.L. adj. <i>holarctica</i> generally distributed in the arctic regions)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The synonyms of <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> are <i>F. tularensis</i> var. <i>palaearctica</i> of Olsufjev et al. (8) and kind B of Jellison et al. (3).</s><s>Later, because of critical remarks in the literature claiming that the terms were inexact (2) and on the basis of geographical distribution, it was proposed that this taxon be named <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> (6, 10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology and principal characteristics are as described previously for the species (11).</s><s>The strains of this subspecies are characterized by the capacity to ferment glucose and maltose but not citrulline and glycerol (biovar japonica is an exception).</s><s>This subspecies is moderately pathogenic for domestic rabbits (lethal dose by subcutaneous inoculation, 10<sup>8</sup> to 10<sup>9</sup> cells).</s><s>Untreated cutaneous infections with this subspecies in humans are lethal in less than 0.5% of the cases.</s><s>The holarctic subspecies has been found to contain a greater quantity of C<sub>14:0</sub> of fatty acid (9 to 11%) and a lower quantity of C<sub>14:0</sub> acid (7 to 11%) than the other subspecies, as determined by gas-liquid chromatography (9).</s><s>The immunization of laboratory animals with the holarctic subspecies confers less effective protection against infection by the nearctic strain (7). <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> has the greatest geographical distribution of the recognized subspecies and occurs in Europe, Asia, and North America.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distribution of this causative agent of tularemia in nature is mediated mainly by <i>Rodentia</i> and <i>Lagomorpha</i>, as well as by ticks and water.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose strain GIEM 503 as the type strain; this strain was isolated from the tick <i>Dermacentor pictius</i> Herm. by N.</s><s>G.</s><s>Olsufjev in 1949 in the Moscow region, USSR.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains of the holarctic subspecies show some features which serve as the basis for infrasubspecific classification into three biovars. <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> biovar I Ery<sup>S</sup> (erythromycin susceptible) possesses the principal properties of the holarctic subspecies.</s><s>It is highly susceptible to minimum doses of erythromycin and other macrolide antibiotics (i.e., it does not grow in the presence of more than 10 to 25 μg/ml), as well as lincomycin.</s><s>This biovar has been isolated in the western and northern regions of Europe, in northern and eastern Siberia. in the Far East, in some parts of central Europe (USSR), and in Kazakhstan (4).</s><s>It is found in North America (United States, Canada), but less often than <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>tularensis</i>.</s><s>Reference strain GIEM c/a7 was isolated from humans by V.</s><s>F.</s><s>Sjaduk in 1976 in the Moscow region, USSR. <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> biovar II Ery<sup>S</sup> (erythromycin resistant) is resistant to considerable concentrations of erythromycin and other macrolide antibiotics, as well as to lincomycin (it grows in medium containing 3,200 to 6,400 μg of antiobiotic per ml) (4).</s><s>This biovar is found only in Eurasia, in central and eastern Europe, and in the Caucasus and is predominant in western Siberia and Kazakhstan (4).</s><s>Reference strain GIEM 503 is also the type strain of the subspecies. <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>holarctica</i> biovar japonica, which was described originally by Rodionova (12), differs from the other biovars in the ability to ferment glycerol.</s><s>This biovar is distributed on the Japanese islands, where the other biovars are not found.</s><s>Biovar japonica is susceptible to erythromycin, like biovar I Ery<sup>S</sup>.</s><s>Reference strain GIEM Miura was isolated from humans by Ohara in 1975.</s></p></content></protolog>