<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3847_nm.1705" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1705" rank="genus">Herbaspirillum</organism><reference id="rid.3847"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>V.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olivares</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Döbereiner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Herbaspirillum; inclusion of [Pseudomonas] rubrisubalbicans, a milk plant pathogen, as Herbaspirillum rubrisubalbicans comb. nov.; and classification of a group of clinical isolates (EF group 1) as Herbaspirillum species 3.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>802</fpage><lpage>810</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-802</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Herbaspirillum</i> (Baldani, Baldani, Seldin, and Dobereiner 1986)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Herbaspirillum</i> (Her.ba.spi'ril.lum. L. fem. n. <i>herba</i>, herbaceous seed-bearing plant that does not produce persistent woody tissue; M.L. dim. neut. n. <i>spirillum</i>, small spiral; <i>Herbaspirillum</i>, small spiral-shaped bacteria from herbaceous seed-bearing plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, generally vibroid, and sometimes helical.</s><s>The cells have one to three or more flagella on one or both poles.</s><s>The cell diameter is 0.6 to 0.7 μm, and the cell length varies with the medium from 1.5 to 5.0 μm.</s><s>The organism has a typical respiratory metabolism, and sugars are not fermented.</s><s>Some species fix atmospheric N<sub>2</sub> under microaerobic conditions and grow well with N<sub>2</sub> as a sole nitrogen source, even in up to 10% sucrose.</s><s>The organism is oxidase and urease positive; catalase is weak or variable.</s><s>Organic acids are the favored carbon sources for growth.</s><s>All species grow on glycerol, D- and L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, xylitol, D-lyxose, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, citrate, succinate, fumarate, L-leucine, L-threonine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, 2-ketoglutarate, adonitol, D-galactose, L-fucose, D- and L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, propionate, isobutyrate, <i>n</i>-valeratc: isovalerate, D- and L-malate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, butyrate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, aconitate, mesaconate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-proline, D-arabinose, 5-ketogluconate, acetate, caprate, amylamine, D-fucose, and tryptamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus constitutes a separate rRNA cluster within the β-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 60 to 65% (as determined by thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>H. seropedicae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>