<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12870_nm.22680" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22680" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22680" rank="species">Streptomyces sundarbansensis</organism><reference id="rid.12870"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arumugam</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitra</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pramanik</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gachhui</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces sundarbansensis sp. nov., an actinomycete that produces 2-allyloxyphenol</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2664</fpage><lpage>2669</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028258-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21148669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces sundarbansensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces sundarbansensis</em> [sun.dar.bans.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>sundarbansensis</em> pertaining to the Sundarbans (local language, Bangla, meaning the beautiful forest), the world's largest tidal mangrove forest, Republic of India, the geographical origin of the type strain].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive-staining, non-motile actinomycete.</s><s>Spores are borne in flexuous (<em>Rectiflexibiles</em>) chains of 15–30 smooth-surfaced spores, 0.66–0.86 µm long and 0.52–0.59 µm wide.</s><s>Grows well on: ISP 2 agar with olive green aerial mycelia and black (reverse side) substrate mycelia; ISP 3 agar with grey to olive green aerial mycelia and brown (reverse side) substrate mycelia; ISP 5 agar with olive green aerial mycelia and brown (reverse side) substrate mycelia; ISP 4 and ISP 7 agar with grey to olive green aerial mycelia and black (reverse side) substrate mycelia.</s><s>Does not produce diffusible pigments on the above media.</s><s>No melanoid pigments are produced.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain ll- diaminopimelic acid but no diagnostic sugars.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine and diphosphatidylglycerol are present as diagnostic phospholipids.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, sucrose and d-xylose as sole carbon source, but not arabinose, inositol, raffinose or rhamnose.</s><s>Utilizes asparagine, histidine and valine as sole carbon/nitrogen sources but not arginine, leucine methionine or tyrosine.</s><s>Positive for catalase activity, but negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Degrades adenine, casein, aesculin, gelatin and starch, but not cellulose or l-tyrosine.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimally in 3 % NaCl), at pH 4.5–8.5 (optimally at 7.5) and at 25–35 °C (optimally at 30 °C), but not with 0.1 % phenol or different concentrations of sodium azide.</s><s>Sensitive to streptomycin and rifampicin, but resistant to penicillin.</s><s>Produces 2-allyloxyphenol and 4a,8a-dimethyl-6-(2-methyl-propenyloxy)-3,4,4a,4b,5,6,8a,9-octahydro-1H phenanthren-2-one as antimicrobial compounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MS1/7<sup>T</sup> ( = MTCC 10621<sup>T</sup> = DSM 42019<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediments of the Sundarbans mangrove forest, India.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 71.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>