<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8510_nm.13243" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13243" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13243" rank="species">Blautia wexlerae</organism><reference id="rid.8510"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Clostridium coccoides, Ruminococcus hansenii, Ruminococcus hydrogenotrophicus, Ruminococcus luti, Ruminococcus productus and Ruminococcus schinkii as Blautia coccoides gen. nov., comb. nov., Blautia hansenii comb. nov., Blautia hydrogenotrophica comb. nov., Blautia luti comb. nov., Blautia producta comb. nov., Blautia schinkii comb. nov. and description of Blautia wexlerae sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1896</fpage><lpage>1902</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65208-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676476</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Blautia wexlerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Blautia wexlerae</em> (wex′ler.ae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>wexlerae</em> of Wexler, in honour of the American microbiologist Hannah M. Wexler, who has contributed significantly to our knowledge of anaerobic bacteria, particularly with regard to antimicrobial susceptibility testing and studies of mechanisms of antimicrobial resistance).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming coccobacilli that are 1.0–1.5×1–3 μm in size.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation at 37 °C under N<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> (80 : 20, v/v) gas phase, colonies on <em>Brucella</em> blood agar plates are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey with a white centre, umbonate and opaque with entire edges.</s><s>Grows well anaerobically, but no growth occurs in an atmosphere of 2 % or 6 % O<sub>2.</sub> Isolates are negative in tests for lecithinase, lipase, catalase and indole, but are positive for urease.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin is not.</s><s>Arabinose, glucose, mannose, ribose, and xylose are utilized as substrates when grown in PRAS carbohydrate broths, but glycogen is not utilized.</s><s>Reactions for amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose are variable.</s><s>End products of metabolism from peptone-yeast-glucose broth are acetate and succinate.</s><s>Long-chain cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types, with C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (major component), and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> dimethyl acetal acids predominating.</s><s>Using the API ZYM and Rapid ID32A systems, all isolates produce a similar profile.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase by both systems.</s><s>With the Rapid ID32A system, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase is positive and acid phosphatase is detected by the API ZYM system.</s><s>No activity was detected for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Urease results are variable by the Rapid ID32A system.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphohydrolase are variable using the API ZYM system.</s><s>The isolates are sensitive to vancomycin (5 μg) and kanamycin (1000 μg), but resistant to colistin (10 μg) identification discs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WAL 14507<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1564<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19850<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.<sub>.</sub></s></p></content></protolog>