<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12878_nm.22688" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22688" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22688" rank="species">Gramella gaetbulicola</organism><reference id="rid.12878"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chae</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>T.-U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gramella gaetbulicola sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from foreshore soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2654</fpage><lpage>2658</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027599-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21148671</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gramella gaetbulicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gramella gaetbulicola</em> (ga.et.bu.li′co.la. N.L. n. <em>gaetbulum</em> gaetbul, the Korean name for a tidal flat; L. suff. <em>-cola</em> from L. masc. or fem. n. <em>incola</em> a dweller, inhabitant; N.L. masc. n. <em>gaetbulicola</em> a dweller of a tidal flat).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile by gliding and rod-shaped (1.2–2.7×0.6–0.7 µm).</s><s>Colonies are yellow–orange, circular and convex with entire margins on marine agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–42 °C (optimum 30–37 °C), at pH 4–11 (optimum pH 7) and in 3–10 % (w/v) NaCl within 7 days (optimum 3–5 %).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Acetoin is produced (positive Voges–Proskauer test).</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced and indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60, and 80, but not casein or cellulose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>As determined by API ZYM and API 20 E strips, alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, tryptophan deaminase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and gelatinase activities are present, but lipase (C14), β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>Using Biolog GN2 MicroPlates, the following substrates are utilized: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and a summed feature (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>).</s><s>PE, unknown aminophospholipids and other unknown polar lipids are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RA5-111<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23022<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16528<sup>T</sup>  = NBRC 106272<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the foreshore soil in the Buan area, Jeonbuk, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>