<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6828_nm.2577" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2577" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2577" rank="species">Pseudomonas brenneri</organism><reference id="rid.6828"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baïda</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yazourh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singer</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas brenneri sp. nov., a new species isolated from natural mineral waters.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>152</volume><fpage>493</fpage><lpage>502</lpage><source id="143">Research in Microbiology</source><abbrev>Res Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0923-2508</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0923-2508(01)01223-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11446518</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas brenneri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas brenneri</i> (Bren'ner. i. M.L. masc. gen. n. <i>brenneri</i> of Brenner, in honor of D.J. Brenner, an American microbiologist, for his contributions to the taxonomy of the families <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and <i>Legionellaceae</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>4.1.1.</s><s>Cell and colony characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, asporogeneous, rod-shaped and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are smooth on nutrient agar, circular, nonpigmented and hemolytic when grown on blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>4.1.2.</s><s>Biochemical and physiological characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains of <i>P. brenneri</i> produce a fluorescent pigment on both the King B and on S1 medium [18].</s><s>They grow at 4°C but not at 41°C.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, catalase, oxidase, tween esterase, lecithinase, and tributyrin esterase are also produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Cells can reduce nitrate to nitrite, grow at low salt concentrations (0.8% and 3%) but not at the following upper salinities tested 5% and 7%.</s><s>Strains do not possess any DNase, coagulase, urease and elastase activities.</s><s>Fibrinolysis and acetyl-methylcarbinol (acetoin) tests were negative.</s><s>They are able to form levan from sucrose.</s><s>Acid is formed from starch.</s><s>Cells can grow with presence of 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium chloride (TTZ).</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>4.1.3.</s><s>Assimilation of carbon compounds Ninety percent or more of the strains utilize the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: α-D(+) glucose, β-D(+) fructose, D(+) trehalose, D(+) mannose, D(−) ribose, α-L-rhamnose, D(+) arabitol, L(−) arabitol, xylitol, glycerol, myo-inositol, D-mannitol, adonitol, i-erythritol, mucate, L(−) malate, cis-aconitate, citrate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, Nacetyl-D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, protocatechuate, (−) quinate, benzoate, putrescine, α-aminobutyrate, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, itaconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-serine, malonate, propionate, L-tyrosine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized by 90% or more of the strains: L(+) sorbose, α-D(+) melibiose, sucrose, D(+) raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, 1-O-methyl-β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-α-galactopyranoside, D(+) cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, 1-O-methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, aesculin, L(+) arabinose, D(+) xylose, palatinose, α-L-fucose, D(+) melezitose, dulcitol, D-tagatose, maltitol, D(+) turanose, D-sorbitol, hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide, D-lyxose, 1-O-methyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl-D-glucopyranose, D-saccharate, L(+) tartrate, D(−) tartrate, mesotartrate, trans-aconitate, tricarballylate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, L-tryptophan, phenylacetate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, histamine, L-histidine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>4.1.4.</s><s>Enzymatic tests Ninety percent or more of the strains possess the following enzyme activities: esterase (C4), esteraselipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, phosphatase acide.</s><s>None of the strains possess the following enzyme activities: cystine arylamidase, trypsine, α-chymotrypsine, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acethyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains have been isolated from natural mineral waters.</s><s>No clinical significance is known.</s><s>The type strain is CFML 97-391<sup>T</sup> and has been deposited in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur as CIP 106646<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 58 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>