<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7481_nm.5472" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5472" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5472" rank="species">Dolosicoccus paucivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7481"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez Jovita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dolosicoccus paucivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from human blood.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1439</fpage><lpage>1442</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1439</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555324</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dolosicoccus paucivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dolosicoccus paucivorans</i> (pau.ci'vo.rans. L. adj. <i>paucus</i> little; L. v. <i>vorase</i> to eat; N.L. adj. <i>paucivorans</i> eating little, relating to the observation that the organism utilizes few carbohydrates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, ovoid in shape, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are nonpigmented, α-haemolytic and non-motile.</s><s>Spores are not produced.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase-negative and catalase-negative.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 or 45°C or in broth containing 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Gas production in MRS broth and bile-aesculin reactions are negative.</s><s>Pyruvate is not utilized and 0.04% tellurite is not tolerated.</s><s>No dextrans or levans are formed on 5% sucrose agar or broth.</s><s>Using conventional heart-infusion base medium, acid is produced from D-raffinose, ribose, sucrose, lactose (weak reaction) and maltose (weak reaction).</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, glycerol, inulin, melibiose, sorbitol, L-sorbose or trehalose.</s><s>Using the API Rapid ID32 Strep and API ZYM systems, weak acid production is observed from mannitol and lactose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, melibiose, maltose, melezitose, N-acetylglucosamine, pullulan, D-raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, D-tagatose or methyl β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, esterase C4 (weak reaction) and ester lipase C8 (weak reaction) are produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, alanine-phenylalanine- proline arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine aminopeptidase, lipase C14, α-fucosidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, N-acetylglucosaminidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, valine arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>No acid or clot is formed in litmus milk.</s><s>Vancomycin sensitive.</s><s>The G + C content of DNA is 40.5 mol%.</s><s>The type and only strain of <i>Dolosicoccus paucivorans</i> is 2992-95<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 39307<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from a human blood sample.</s><s>Habitat is unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>