<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.80_nm.1557" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1557" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1557" rank="species">Pedomicrobium australicum</organism><reference id="rid.80"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gebers</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beese</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedomicrobium americanum sp. nov. and Pedomicrobium australicum sp. nov. from aquatic habitats, Pedomicrobium gen. emend., and Pedomicrobium ferrugineum sp. emend.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>303</fpage><lpage>315</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pedomicrobium australicum</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are oval (Fig. 8), tetrahedral, or short rod, bean, or spindle shaped (Fig. 9) and are up to 1.2 by 1.8 μm. Up to three hyphae of varying lengths originate laterally or polarly with similar frequency (Fig. 10). True branching of the hyphae occurs (Fig. 11 and 12). Multiplication is by budding at the hyphal tips (Fig. 8 through 10). Up to three buds per mother cell may occur at the same time (Fig. 11 and 12). Occasionally, intercalary buds are formed (Fig. 13). Mature buds separate from the mother hyphae as motile swarmers with one subpolar flagellum (Fig. 14).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells have a gram-negative cell wall structure (Fig. 15 and 16).</s><s>Extracellular polymers appear primarily on cell surfaces opposite the lateral hyphae (Fig. 15 and 17).</s><s>Deposition of iron compounds occurs when cells are grown on fulvic acid iron sesquioxide complexes or on PSM agar which contains 5 mg of FeSO<sub>4</sub>. 7H<sub>2</sub>O per liter.</s><s>Deposition of manganese(IV) oxides occurs on PSM agar which contains 1.54 mg of MnSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>,O per liter.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic membranes appear to form compartments within the cells (Fig. 17 and 18).</s><s>Involvement of these membranes in the oxidation or deposition of manganese remains questionable (13).</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid and polyphosphate occur in the cytoplasm (Fig. 19).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal growth temperature is 29 to 32°C; the temperature range is 15 to 36°C.</s><s>The pH for optimal growth in unbuffered media is 6.9 to 7.5; during growth, the pH increases (Table 4).</s><s>The optimal pH of buffered media is 7.3 to 7.6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The generation times in PSM or PYVM medium are 11to 26 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Stimulation or inhibition of growth by various carbon sources differs between strains (Table 5).</s><s>Good growth occurs with 0.05% yeast extract or 0.025% yeast extract plus 0.025% peptone; nitrate does not serve as a sole nitrogen source.</s><s>Within 6 days, strains IFAM ST-1306<sup>T</sup> and IFAM WD-1355 utilize 8 to 78% of the amino acids from PSM or PYVM culture broth (Table 6).</s><s>Strain IFAM WD-1355 does not use isoleucine and lysine.</s><s>Good growth of strain IFAM WD-1355 depends on the presence of 1 μg of cyanocobalamin per liter.</s><s>The presence of 0.1% NaCl stimulates the growth of strain IFAM WD-1355.</s><s>Both strains are positive for cytochrome oxidase and for reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains are susceptible to several antibiotics (Table 7); sulfanilamide causes only little inhibition of growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base compositions of strains IFAM ST-1306<sup>T</sup> and IFAM WD-1355 are 65 and 63 mol% G+C (T<sub>m</sub>method) (12), respectively.</s><s>The DNA relatedness of the strains is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both strains were isolated from a freshwater reservoir in New South Wales, Australia, by J.</s><s>T.</s><s>Staley (12, 25).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IFAM ST-1306 (= ATCC 43611).</s><s>The other strain which has been identified is strain IFAM WD-1355 (= ATCC 43614).</s></p></content></protolog>