<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2483_nm.9433" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9433" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9433" rank="species">Pseudomonas argentinensis</organism><reference id="rid.2483"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peix</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berge</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abril</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas argentinensis sp. nov., a novel yellow pigment-producing bacterial species, isolated from rhizospheric soil in Córdoba, Argentina</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1107</fpage><lpage>1112</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63445-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879241</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas argentinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas argentinensis</em> (ar.gen′tin.en.sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>argentinensis</em> pertaining to the Argentine, of the Argentine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, rod-shaped cells of 1·3–1·9 μm in length and 0·5–0·7 μm in diameter; motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, convex, yellow, translucent and usually 0·5–2·5 mm in diameter, within 2 days of growth at 25 °C.</s><s>Does not grow at 4 or 41 °C.</s><s>The metabolism is oxidative, and no sugars are fermented in peptone media.</s><s>A water-insoluble yellow pigment is produced on nutrient agar, with a major absorbance peak at 442 nm, and a fluorescent pigment is also produced at a low rate on King's B medium.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive, and does not hydrolyse casein, aesculin or gelatin.</s><s>The arginine dihydrolase system is not present.</s><s>Urease, tryptophan deaminase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Assimilates l-arabinose, galactose, glucose, d-fructose, mannose, mannitol, trehalose, d-fucose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, caprate, malate and citrate.</s><s>Utilization of glycerol, d-ribose, d-xylose, melibiose and d-arabitol as sole carbon source is strain-dependent.</s><s>Does not assimilate adipate, phenylacetate, d-arabinose, l-fucose, inositol, adonitol, l-arabitol, l-lyxose, xylitol, l-xylose, l-sorbose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, erythritol, sorbitol, dulcitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-turanose, d-tagatose or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CH01<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22563<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7010<sup>T</sup>), which has a G+C content of 57·5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>