<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7281_nm.5659" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5659" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5659" rank="species">Streptococcus macedonicus</organism><reference id="rid.7281"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsakalidou</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zoidou</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wassill</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalantzopoulos</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of streptococci from Greek Kasseri cheese and description of Streptococcus macedonicus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>519</fpage><lpage>527</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-519</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731293</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus macedonicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus macedonicus</i> (ma.ce.'do.ni .cus. M. L. adj. <i>macedonicos</i> from Macedonia, Northern Greece, from where the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are Gram-positive cocci and occur in pairs or in small groups.</s><s>Most strains show homogeneous growth in Brain Heart Infusion broth after 1 d incubation.</s><s>Growth at 42°C is similar to that at 37°C and definitely better than at 30°C.</s><s>After 1 d, very slight growth is seen at 25°C.</s><s>No growth occurs in 6.5% NaCl broth after 3 d at 37°C.</s><s>A slight growth enhancement is noted when plates are incubated in 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia blood agar of all strains except ACA-DC 256 and LMG 15061 are α-haemolytic.</s><s>The strains are not pigmented and non-motile.</s><s>All strains grow on Edward's medium but they do not lyse aesculin.</s><s>They grow as very small colonies on kanamycin aesculin azide agar, but produce no blackening on this medium.</s><s>Growth also occurs on Slanetz &#x0026; Bartley medium.</s><s>The small colonies appearing on this medium are slightly pink.</s><s>The strains are unable to grow on bile aesculin agar.</s><s>All strains are positive in the Voges-Proskauer and leucine arylamidase tests.</s><s>All except one (strain ACA-DC 207) are alanyl-phenylalanylproline-arylamidase-positive and all except strains ACA-DC 211 and LMG 15061 are α-galactosidase- positive.</s><s>All strains reduce litmus milk and produce strong clots after 1 d incubation.</s><s>All strains produce acid from D-glucose, galactose, D-fructose, D-mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, saccharose and D-raffinose, and are negative in tests for arginine dihydrolase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase, β-galactosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, hippurate, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, pmannosidase and urease.</s><s>All strains are negative in tests with adonitol, amidon, amygdalin, D- and Larabitol, D- and L-arabinose, β-gentiobiose, D- and L-ketogluconate, dulcitol, erythritol, D- and L-fucose, methyl α-D-glucoside, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, methyl α-D-mannoside, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, trehalose, D-furanose, D- and L-xylose, xylitol and β-methylxyloside.</s><s>Only strain LMG 15061 produces strong clearing reactions on starch, whilst most other strains show only a weak or delayed amylase reaction.</s><s>Variable reactions occur with arbutin (four strains positive).</s><s>Six react with salicin and eight with melibiose.</s><s>One strain is weakly positive with aesculin and three with methyl β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>Only LMG 15061 produces acid from starch, pullulan and glycogen.</s><s>All strains are sensitive to vancomycin, clindamycin, erythromycin and oxacillin.</s><s>The G + C content is 38 mol%.</s><s>Type strain is ACA-DC 206, isolated from Greek Kasseri cheese.</s></p></content></protolog>