<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1390_nm.5980" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5980" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5980" rank="species">Brachybacterium faecium</organism><reference id="rid.1390"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium faecium gen. nov., sp. nov., a coryneform bacterium from poultry deep litter.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>48</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brachybacterium faecium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brachybacterium faecium</i> (fae'ci.um. L. n.<i>faex</i>, <i>faecis</i> dregs; L. gen. pl. n. <i>faecium</i> dregs of feces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies are small, grey, white, or pale lemon, low convex, and smooth.</s><s>Cells vary in shape from coccoid forms in the stationary phase to rods (0.5 to 0.75 by 1.5 to 2.5 μm) in the exponential phase.</s><s>Both rods and coccoid cells are gram-positive, non-acid fast, and nonmotile.</s><s>Aerobic (but may show weak anaerobic growth).</s><s>Optimum temperature, 25 to 30°C.</s><s>No growth in the presence of thallous acetate (0.01%) or sodium azide (0.01%).</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, and mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, salicin, and sorbose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from cellobiose and sucrose.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Deoxyribonuclease, oxidase, phosphatase, and sulfatase negative.</s><s>Esculin and starch are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cellulose, chitin, gelatin, tyrosine, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Some strains degrade  arginine, hippurate, urea, uric acid, and casein.</s><s>Some strains reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>H,S is not produced.</s><s>Voges-Prosbiose  kauer negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan is based upon <i>meso</i>-DAP.</s><s>Galactose and glucose are the wall sugars.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The long chain fatty acids are primarily of the straight-chain saturated, iso- and anteiso-methyl branched types, with 12-methyltetradecanoic (anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>) and 14-methylhexadecanoic (anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>) acids predominating.</s><s>The major polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, a phospholipid, and several glycolipids.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 68 to 71.5 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Isolated from poultry deep litter.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCIB 9860 (= Schefferle 6-10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from cellobiose but not from sucrose; decomposes uric acid but not urea; reduces nitrate to nitrite; and does not hydrolyze arginine or hippurate.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 69.4 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p></content></protolog>