<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5915_nm.10113" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10113" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10113" rank="species">Rhodoblastus sphagnicola</organism><reference id="rid.5915"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kulichevskaya</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guzev</surname><given-names>V.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoblastus sphagnicola sp. nov., a novel acidophilic purple non-sulfur bacterium from Sphagnum peat bog.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1397</fpage><lpage>1402</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63962-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738120</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodoblastus sphagnicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodoblastus sphagnicola</em> (sphag.ni′co.la. N.L. n. <em>Sphagnum</em> generic name of sphagnum moss; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> from L. n. <em>incola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>sphagnicola</em> inhabitant of <em>Sphagnum</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, straight or slightly curved, 0.8–1.0 μm wide and 2.0–6.0 μm long, motile by polar flagella in young cultures and have a tendency to form rosette-like clusters in older cultures.</s><s>Cells reproduce by budding.</s><s>No tube or filament is formed between mother and daughter cells.</s><s>Cells contain lamellar intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes underlying, and parallel to, the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>The colour of anaerobic liquid cultures is purplish red.</s><s>Absorption spectra of living cells show maxima at 377, 463, 492, 527, 592, 806 and 867 nm.</s><s>The photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids.</s><s>Rhodopin and rhodopinal are major carotenoids, followed by lycopene, rhodopinol, lycopenal, rhodopinal glucoside and lycopenal glucoside.</s><s>Spirilloxanthin is absent from the carotenoid composition.</s><s>Preferred mode of growth is photoheterotrophic under anoxic conditions in the light with formate, acetate, butyrate, pyruvate, lactate, propionate, malate, malonate, succinate, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, caproate, lactate and malonate.</s><s>Best growth occurs on butyrate and propionate.</s><s>Methanol is utilized at a wide range of concentrations from 0.01 to 1 % (v/v).</s><s>No growth occurs with benzoate, glucose, fructose, tartrate, citrate or glutamate.</s><s>Nitrogen sources are N<sub>2</sub> and ammonia.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is possible with hydrogen as electron donor; sulfide and thiosulfate cannot be used.</s><s>Growth factors are not required, though yeast extract increases the growth rate.</s><s>No aerobic growth occurs in the dark.</s><s>The major phospholipid fatty acids are 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Contains ubiquinones Q-10 and Q-9.</s><s>Mesophilic, moderately acidophilic, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C and pH 5.2–5.5.</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 1 % (w/v).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 62.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RS<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16996<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2361<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an acidic <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog (Sosvyatskoe), Tver Region, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>