<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6827_nm.3936" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3936" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3936" rank="species">Clostridium frigoris</organism><reference id="rid.6827"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Merkhoffer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of novel psychrophilic clostridia from an Antarctic microbial mat: description of Clostridium frigoris sp. nov., Clostridium lacusfryxellense sp. nov., Clostridium bowmanii sp. nov. and Clostridium psychrophilum sp. nov. and reclassification of Clostridium laramiense as Clostridium estertheticum subsp. laramiense subsp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1019</fpage><lpage>1029</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02554-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892121</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium frigoris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium frigoris</em> (fri′go.ris. L. gen. n. <em>frigoris</em> of the cold).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (1·4–1·8×2·2–5·0 μm) and occur singly, in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Filamentous cells are occasionally present, especially in cultures grown on agar plates.</s><s>Motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Endospores are spherical and located at a terminal position; sporangium not swollen.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Colonies on sheep-blood agar are 1–2 mm in diameter, round with often coarsely granulated margins, smooth, slightly raised, cream-white to greyish, semi-transparent to opaque and non-haemolytic.</s><s>The temperature optimum for growth is 5–7 °C; the upper limit is 11 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5·5–7·5 (optimum 6·8–7·2).</s><s>Under optimal conditions, the doubling time is 13·0 h.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are utilized: amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, inositol (weak), inulin, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose (weak), salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are not utilized: mannitol, melezitose and sorbitol.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The fermentation products formed are butyrate, formate, lactate, acetate, ethanol, hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> dimethylacetal, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> and an unknown compound with an equivalent chain length of 14·777–14·783.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 31·9 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain D-1/D-an/II<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14204<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-579<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a microbial mat sample taken from a moated area around Lake Fryxell, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>