<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3375_nm.7569" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7569" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7569" rank="species">Thermomonospora fusca</organism><reference id="rid.3375"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McCarthy</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cross</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A taxonomic study of Thermomonospora and other monosporic actinomycetes</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>130</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermomonospora fusca</i> ex. Henssen, 1957 sp. nov. nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Type strain 190 Th (= ATCC 27730). Colonies on CYC agar with pale yellowish reverse and usually an abundant white aerial mycelium. Repeated sporophore branching to form clusters of single spores on the aerial hyphae, but spores on simple branched and unbranched sporophores also produced. Sporulation on the substrate mycelium or in submerged broth culture variable. Morphological features subject to modification by incubation temperature, pH and medium composition. Optimum temperature for growth 45 to 50 °C and optimum pH, 7.5 to 11.0. Catalase, strong positive; oxidase, negative; acid production from D-glucose, weak positive ; nitrate reduction, negative. Proteolytic activity evidenced by ability to hydrolyse casein, gelatin, keratin and elastin, The following compounds are also degraded: starch, agar, pectin, cellulose, xylan, arbutin and aesculin. Chitin, xanthine, hypoxanthine, guanine and tyrosine not degraded. Carbon source utilization pattern characterized by the ability to utilize D-galactose and lactose, but not D-ribose and D-xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>