<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3727_nm.10743" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10743" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10743" rank="species">Glaciecola psychrophila</organism><reference id="rid.3727"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glaciecola psychrophila sp. nov., a novel psychrophilic bacterium isolated from the Arctic.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2867</fpage><lpage>2869</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64575-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17158989</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glaciecola psychrophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glaciecola psychrophila</em> (psy.chro′phi.la. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; Gr. adj. <em>philus</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>psychrophila</em> cold loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, psychrophilic, motile rods, 0.5–0.8 μm by 1.2–4.5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, convex, circular and smooth with entire edges.</s><s>Grows aerobically and produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–15 °C and pH 5.0–10.0, with optimum growth at 12 °C and at approximately pH 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1–6 % (w/v) NaCl and no growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Indole production and Voges–Proskauer reaction are negative.</s><s>Negative results for the reduction of nitrate and production of hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Negative in tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, gelatinase, caseinase, agarase, chitinase, lecithinase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for trypsin, lipase (C14) and cystine arylamidase.</s><s>Tests for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, amylase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are positive.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: sucrose, maltose, lactose, galactose, gluconate and pyruvate.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from maltose and galactose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: glucose, d-mannose, mannitol, fructose, cellobiose, l-arabinose, xylose, l-rhamnose, d-melibiose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sorbinose, glycerol, melezitose, ribose, galactitol, inositol, erythritol, salicin, inulin, valine, glycine, cysteine, arginine, histidine, lysine, methionine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, acetate, fumarate, hippurate, lactate, malate, citrate, succinate, tartrate, alginate, capric acid, adipic acid, phenylacetic acid and uric acid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (38.31 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (13.59 %), C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH (6.47 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (6.23 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (5.48 %) and C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (2.73 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 170<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6130<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13954<sup>T</sup>), was collected from high latitude Arctic locations (77° 30′ N to approximately 81° 12′ N), including the Canadian Basin and Greenland Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>