<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2833_nm.7956" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7956" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7956" rank="species">Bacteroides heparinolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.2833"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Okuda</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shiozu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takazoe</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides heparinolyticus sp. nov. isolated from humans with periodontitis.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>438</fpage><lpage>442</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-438</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides heparinolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides heparinolyticus</i> (he.pa'ri.no.ly.ti.cus. Gr.n. <i>heparin</i> heparin; Gr. adj <i>lyticus</i> dissolving; <i>heparinolyticus</i> heparin dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A description of this species is given below.</s><s>After incubation for 4 days on blood agar, colonies of the type strain and five other strains of <i>B. heparinolyticus</i> are circular, entire, convex, smooth, translucent, and gray.</s><s>The strains do not grow under aerobic conditions or in air supplemented with 10% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No dark brown or black colonies are produced on hemolyzed rabbit blood agar.</s><s>Broth cultures are turbid and have a dense sediment.</s><s>Harvested cells are markedly viscous.</s><s>Cells grown in blood agar are gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporeforming rods 0.5 to 0.7 by 0.8 to 2.0 μm, with occasional cells 10 μm long or longer.</s><s>Thin sections of <i>B. heparinolyticus</i> strain HEP<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) and strain HR-6 are shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>The cell wall structure is typical of gram-negative bacteria.</s><s>The cytoplasmic and outer membranes exhibit a trilamellar structure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The outer wall of the strains is separated from the outer membrane by an electron-lucent layer.</s><s>By using phasecontrast microscopy with India ink negative staining, a distinctive capsular structure surrounding the cell was detected in all strains of <i>B. heparinolyticus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation for 5 days, the pH in broth containing 1% glucose is 5.4 to 5.6.</s><s>All strains produce indole.</s><s>The type strain and five other strains produce acid from glucose, fructose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, mannose, sucrose, salicin, xylose, starch, and esculin.</s><s>None of the strains ferments raffinose mannitol or sorbitol.</s><s>None reduces nitrate.</s><s>Sheep blood is not hemolyzed.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 20% bile.</s><s>No strain produces H<sub>2</sub>S, catalase, or gelatinase.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze starch and esculin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The acid products in PYG broth cultures are succinic acid and small amounts of acetic, propionic, and isovaleric acids.</s><s>All strains produce heparinase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase-lipase, acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-Pglucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase.</s><s>None of the strains produces collagenase, lipase, leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chemotrypsin, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, or α-mannosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 47 to 49 mol% (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>B. heparinolyticus</i> is strain HEP (= ATCC 35895).</s></p></content></protolog>