<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6886_nm.4357" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4357" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4357" rank="species">Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens</organism><reference id="rid.6886"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reysenbach</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strutz</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dreier</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens gen. nov., sp. nov., a thermophilic anaerobic dissimilatory Fe(III)-reducing bacterium from a continental hot spring.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>541</fpage><lpage>547</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103646</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoterrabacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoterrabacterium</i> (Ther.mo.ter.ra.bac.te'ri.um. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; L. n. <i>terra</i>, land, earth; Gr. neut. n. <i>bacterion</i>, a small rod; M. L. neut. n. <i>Thermoterrabacterium</i>, rod-shaped bacterium from heated land)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped, Gram-type-positive (eu)bacteria.</s><s>Anaerobic and thermophilic.</s><s>Neutrophilic.</s><s>Facultative Fe(III) reducers.</s><s>Able to couple the dissimilatory reduction of Fe(III) with oxidation of polyols and organic acids.</s><s>In the presence of Fe(III) organic substrates are oxidized incompletely to acetate as the main metabolic product.</s><s>Saccharolytic.</s><s>Do not reduce sulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of <i>Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens</i> (fer.ri.re.du'cens.</s><s>L.n. <i>ferrum</i>, iron; L. part. adj. <i>reducens</i>, converting to a different state; M.</s><s>L. adj. <i>ferrireducens</i>, reducing iron (III))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight to slightly curved rods, 0.3 to 0.4 by 1.6 to 2.7 μm with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells stain gram positive.</s><s>Occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Exhibits a tumbling motility.</s><s>Spores were not observed.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Grows on simple, defined medium.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 50 to 74°C with the optimum being 65°C.</s><s>The pH<sup>65C</sup> range for growth is from 5.5 to 7.6, with an optimum at 6.0 to 6.2.</s><s>Growth occurs in the NaCl concentration range of 0 to 1.0% (wt/vol).</s><s>In the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>, strain JW/AS-Y7<sup>T</sup> is able to grow with glycerol as the only organic carbon source.</s><s>Couples the oxidation of glycerol to reduction of amorphous Fe(III) oxide or Fe(III) citrate as an electron acceptor, forming Fe(II) as magnetite and siderite.</s><s>In the presence as well as in the absence of Fe(III), and in the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>, glycerol is oxidized incompletely to acetate as the only organic metabolic product, leading to a ratio of more than one acetate molecule produced per glycerol molecule consumed.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, lactate, 1,2-propanediol, glycerate, pyruvate, and yeast extract.</s><s>Grows weakly on glucose, fructose, and mannose, producing acetate as the only organic product.</s><s>In the presence of Fe(III) utilizes molecular hydrogen.</s><s>No growth occurs with formate, acetate, methanol, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, <i>i</i>-propanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, propionate, acetone, ethylene glycol, 1,3-propanediol, fumarate, succinate, phenol, benzoate, 9,10-anthraquinone-2,6-disulfoniaccid, starch, olive oil, elemental sulfur, sucrose, galactose, xylose, cellobiose, or arabinose, with or without Fe(III).</s><s>Reduces 9,10-anthraquinone-2,6-disulfonic acid, fumarate to succinate, and thiosulfate to elemental sulfur.</s><s>Does not reduce MnO,, nitrate, sulfate, sulfite, or elemental sulfur.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and rifampin at 100 pg/ml but not by ampicillin, streptomycin, or tetracycline.</s><s>DNA base composition is 41 mol% G+C (HPLC).</s><s>The habitat is freshwater hot springs such as Calcite Springs in Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and, so far, the only isolated strain is JW/AS-Y7<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH under accession number DSM 11255.</s></p></content></protolog>