<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9492_nm.14641" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14641" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14641" rank="species">Alishewanella jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.9492"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alishewanella jeotgali sp. nov., isolated from traditional fermented food, and emended description of the genus Alishewanella</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2313</fpage><lpage>2316</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007260-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620373</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alishewanella jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alishewanella jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile, rod-shaped, Gram-negative, facultative anaerobe with a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>Cells are 2–6 μm long and about 1 μm wide and are generally observed as single cells, although they can occur in pairs.</s><s>Colonies are 3–4 mm in diameter, circular and raised, initially light ivory in colour and dark ivory later.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–40 °C, in 1–2 % (w/v) NaCl and at pH 6.5–9.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C, in 1 % (w/v) NaCl and at pH 6.5–9.0.</s><s>Growth at 4 °C takes &#x003E;72 h.</s><s>Generally grows well for &#x003E;24 h on LA.</s><s>MA, NA and TSA are also suitable for growth.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not produce indole or l-arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for lipase (C<sub>4</sub>), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for reduction of nitrate to nitrite, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis) and protease (gelatin hydrolysis), but negative for production of indole, fermentation of d-glucose, l-arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Utilizes TMAO and thiosulfate as electron acceptors, but not nitrite, sulfite or ferric iron.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose and maltose, but not l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malate, trisodium citrate or phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Assimilates aesculin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch and glycogen, but not glycerol, erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, insulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate or 2- or 5-ketogluconate (API 50CH).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MS1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22429<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15561<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from gajami sikhae (jeotgal), a traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s></p></content></protolog>