<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4891" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4891" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4891" rank="species">Bacillus clausii</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus clausii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus clausii</i> (clau'si.i., ML gen. n. <i>clausii</i> of Claus; named after Dieter Claus, the German bacteriologist who made fundamental contributions to the taxonomy of <i>Bacillus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is taken from this study for DNA hybridization group 6 strains.</s><s>Colonies are white and filamentous with a filamentous margin.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5-0.7 x 2.0-4.0 μm), producing spores which are ellipsoidal (0.4-0.6 x 0.7-1.0 μm) and located subterminally to paracentrally in the sporangium, which may be slightly swollen.</s><s>Cells tend to occur in long chains which may carry spores.</s><s>The strains in this species are characterized by hydrolysis of casein, gelatin and starch, but not pullulan, Tween 20, 40 or 60 or MUG.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced but phenylalanine is not deaminated.</s><s>The pH optimum is about 8, and good growth is obtained at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth at temperatures from 15 to 50°C is observed, with salt tolerance up to about 10 % NaCl (strain PN-76 tolerates only 8% NaCl).</s><s>Carbohydrate utilization patterns show growth on L-arabinose, galactose, xylitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-tagatose or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Some strains grow on inositol.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 42.8 and 45.5 mol % G + C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-23 (= DSM 8716 = NCIMB 10309).</s></p></content></protolog>