<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4782_nm.10820" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10820" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2338" rank="species">Legionella pneumophila</organism><reference id="rid.4782"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Epple</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibb</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKinney</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Starnes</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colville</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Selander</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Edelstein</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella pneumophila serogroup Lansing 3 isolated from a patient with fatal pneumonia, and descriptions of L. pneumophila subsp. pneumophila subsp. nov., L. pneumophila subsp. fraseri subsp. nov., and L. pneumophila subsp. pascullei subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>1695</fpage><lpage>1703</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3053773</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Legionella pneumophila</i> (Brenner, Steigerwalt, and McDade 1979)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella pneumophila</i> (pneu.mo'phi.la; Greek noun <i>pneumo</i>, lung; Greek adjective, <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. adjective, <i>pneumophila</i>, lung loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Legionella pneumophila</i> is a gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, nonencapsulated, non-acid-fast rod, 0.3 to 0.9 μm wide and 2 to 20 μm or more long.</s><s>It is motile by one or more straight or curved polar or lateral flagella; occasional strains are nonmotile.</s><s>L-Cysteine hydrochloride and iron salts are required for growth.</s><s>It is weakly oxidase positive or negative.</s><s>It is catalase positive, and gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reduction, urease, and blue-white or red autofluorescence are negative.</s><s>It is chemoorganotrophic, using amino acids as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Carbohydrates are neither fermented nor oxidized.</s><s>A brown, diffusible pigment is formed in media containing tyrosine.</s><s>It produces β-lactamase and contains granules that stain with Sudan black B.</s><s>Branched-chain fatty acids predominate in the cell wall.</s><s>It contains major amounts of ubiquinones with more than 10 isoprene units in the side chain.</s><s>Most strains hydrolyze hippurate.</s><s>It has been isolated from human lung, sputum, and blood and from water and is the major causative agent of legionellosis.</s><s>G+C content is 38 to 41 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is Philadelphia 1 (ATCC 33152) isolated from human lung tissue (G+C content, 39 mol%).</s><s>Three subspecies have been described, and the characteristics of the subspecies are shown in Table 6.</s><s>See references 4 and 7 for the original description and additional information.</s></p></content></protolog>