<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5690_nm.3832" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3832" rank="genus">Helicobacter</organism><reference id="rid.5690"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bronsdon</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodwin</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chilvers</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schoenknecht</surname><given-names>F.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter nemestrinae sp. nov., a spiral bacterium found in the stomach of a pigtailed macaque (Macaca nemestrina)</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1995031</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Helicobacter</i> Goodwin et al.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of the genus <i>Helicobacter</i> is as previously given by Goodwin et al. (13) except for the following features: colonies are 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, and the G+C content ranges from 20 to 44 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>H. nemestrinae</i> can be identified with certainty in laboratories only by using the cellular fatty acid GLC profile or by using specific nucleic acid probes.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>H. nemestrinae</i> resembles members of the genus <i>Campylobacter</i> morphologically, but differs from them biochemically, especially from the urease-positive <i>Campylobacter</i> species (Table 3).</s><s>It is distinguished from the urease-positive variant of <i>Campylobacter laridis</i> by its failure to reduce nitrates, its susceptibility to cephalothin in vitro, and its failure to grow in the presence of 1.5% NaCl or to produce H<sub>2</sub>S in fresh TSI agar (26).</s><s>It is distinguished from the urease-positive nitrogen-fixing strains of <i>Campylobacter nitrofigilis</i> by its lack of association with plant roots, its intolerance of NaCl at any concentration, its resistance to nalidixic acid, its failure to produce pigment, and its ability to grow at 42°C (25).</s></p></content></protolog>