<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2235_nm.4389" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4389" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4389" rank="species">Anaerovibrio burkinabensis</organism><reference id="rid.2235"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ouattara</surname><given-names>A.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Traore</surname><given-names>A.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Anaerovibrio burkinabensis sp. nov., a lactate-fermenting bacterium isolated from rice field soils.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>390</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-390</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerovibrio burkinabensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerovibrio burkinabensis</i> (bur.ki.na.ben'sis. N. L. adj. <i>burkinabensis</i>, from Burkinabe, inhabitants of Burkina Faso, West Africa)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Curved, spiral-shaped cells that are 0.5 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Motile in young cultures.</s><s>Gram negative and non-spore forming.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Citrate, fumarate, malate, lactate, pyruvate, 1,2-propanediol, dihydroxyacetone, fructose, aspartate, glutamate, glycerol phosphate, yeast extract, Biotrypcase, and Casamino acids are used as energy sources.</s><s>Acetate is required for fermentation of malate, 1,2-propanediol, and amino acids, yeast extract is required for glycerol phosphate degradation, and yeast extract and Biotrypcase are required for 1,2-propanediol utilization.</s><s>Succinate is the main product of malate, fumarate, or aspartate fermentation, while acetate and propionate are the main products resulting from fermentations of other substrates.</s><s>Propanol is produced from 1,2-propanediol.</s><s>Glycerol is mainly degraded to 1,3-propanediol.</s><s>Traces of succinate, lactate (in sugar fermentations), and hydrogen are also produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vitamins are required for growth.</s><s>NaCl is not required.</s><s>Ferric iron is reduced.</s><s>Sulfate and nitrate are not reduced.</s><s>Cytochrome <i>b</i> is present.</s><s>Substrates that do not support growth include H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, methanol, ethanol, propanol, butanol, pentanol, 1,3-propanediol, ethylene glycol, sorbitol, mannitol, dulcitol, adonitol, glyceraldehyde, ribose, xylose, arabinose, glucose, galactose, sorbose, rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, cellulose, amylose, pectin, formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, succinate, maleate, choline, alanine, cysteine, lysine, serine, tyrosine, and gelatin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range for growth is 5.3 to 8.4; the optimum pH is around 6.8.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 13 to 43°C; the optimum temperature is around 35°C.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 0 to 1.2%; optimum growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of 0%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base ratio is 44.1 k 0.1 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat is anoxic sediments of rice field soils in the Kou Valley, Bama, Burkina Faso, West Africa.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain B,B, (= DSM 6283), has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>