<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.363_nm.7866" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7866" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7866" rank="species">Treponema maltophilum</organism><reference id="rid.363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wyss</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüpbach</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guggenheim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Göbel</surname><given-names>U.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema maltophilum sp. nov., a small oral spirochete isolated from human periodontal lesions.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>745</fpage><lpage>752</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-745</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782684</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema maltophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema maltophilum</i> (mal.to'phil.um. M.L. n. <i>maltosum</i>, maltose; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i>, loving, friendly to; M.L. adj. maltophilum, maltose loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Treponema maltophilum</i> is an obligately anaerobic, helically coiled, motile treponeme isolated from human subgingival plaque.</s><s>The cells are approximately 5 μm long and 0.2 μm wide and have a wavelength of 0.7 μm and an amplitude of 0.3 μm.</s><s>They have two periplasmic flagella; one flagellum originates at each cell end, and the flagella overlap in the central region of the cell.</s><s>In low-viscosity liquid media cellular rotation produces standing waves with amplitudes of up to 2 μm, but this results in no directional motility.</s><s>Translational movement, however, occurs in higher-viscosity media or when cells creep along a surface.</s><s>Cells can be stored frozen (in liquid nitrogen or in a mechanical  freezer) in OMIZ-Pat supplemented with 10 to 20% glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>When streaked onto OMIZ-Pat agarose, <i>T. maltophilum</i> forms within 5 days off-white diffuse subsurface colonies that are up to 3 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics. <i>T. maltophilum</i> does not grow in chemically defined OMIZ-W1 and requires the addition of yeast extract and/or Neopeptone (or fractions thereof).</s><s>Growth of most strains is strictly dependent on the presence of GlucNac and at least one additional sugar.</s><s>The most commonly used second sugars are D-arabinose, L-fucose, D-maltose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-sucrose, and D-trehalose, while D-glucose may be totally ineffective.</s><s>Some strains without α-fucosidase activity may not depend on GlucNac.</s><s>Growth is not influenced by D-cellobiose, D-fucose, D-lactose, D-mannitol, L-sorbose, and L-xylose.</s><s>FBS at concentrations as low as 0.1% (vol/vol) prevents growth in OMIZ-Pat.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>As determined with API ZYM strips, all strains exhibit alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphtholphosphohydrolase, C<sub>4</sub> esterase, C<sub>8</sub> esterase, and α-glucosidase activities, and most strains are also positive for α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>Within the species there are prominent differences in α-fucosidase and β-glucuronidase activities.</s><s>Strains with β-glucuronidase activity are able to grow on glucuronic acid.</s><s>Immunoblotting with patient sera reveals an antigen that can be detected only in strains with α-fucosidase activity.</s><s>All strains are resistant to 1 mg of rifampin per liter and 100 mg of fosfomycin per liter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type and reference strains.</s><s>Strain BR is the type strain of <i>T. maltophilum</i>.</s><s>This strain exhibits α-fucosidase activity but not β-glucuronidase activity.</s><s>Reference strains that differ markedly phenotypically from the type strain are strain HO2A, which exhibits β-glucuronidase activity but not α-fucosidase activity, and strain PNA1, which exhibits neither α-fucosidase activity nor β-glucuronidase activity.</s><s>Strains BR<sup>T</sup>, HO2A, and PNA1 have been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strains ATCC 51939 , ATCC 51940, and ATCC 51941, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat. <i>T. maltophilum</i> has been detected only in subgingival plaque samples of patients with periodontal disease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>T. maltophilum</i> is a species that is genetically distinct from previously described treponemes as determined by a phylogenetic comparison of 16s rRNA sequences.</s><s>As determined by SDS-PAGE, its protein and antigen patterns can be easily distinguished from those of other cultivable treponemes, although more conventional criteria can also be used to distinguish it from the four previously (characterized oral spirochetes.</s><s>Size, morphology, enzyme activities, and growth characteristics clearly distinguish <i>T. maltophilum</i> from <i>T. vincentii</i>. <i>T. maltophilum</i> also differs from the asaccharolytic organism T. denticola by its lack of trypsin activity and from <i>T. pectinovorum</i> by its lack of a requirement for either glucuronic acid or galacturonic acid.</s><s>Differentiation from <i>T. socranskii</i> is based on the wide spectrum of glycosidases produced by <i>T. maltophilum</i>, as well as on the spectrum of carbohydrates used.</s><s>α-Glucosidase activity is characteristic of <i>T. maltophilum</i> and has never been observed in <i>T. socranskii</i>, although many strains of this species can ferment maltose.</s><s>A distinctive phenotypic trait found in all strains of all subspecies of <i>T. socranskii</i> but not in <i>T. maltophilum</i> or any other oral spirochete is the formation of intensely yellow colonies (or cell pellets after growth in liquid medium) in OMIZ-Pat agarose (data not shown).</s><s>This includes an oral <i>Treponema</i> strain of uncertain classification described by Mink (19) and obtained from the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 43242, which we identified by protein, antigen, MI ZYM, and sugar utilization analyses as <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> (data not shown).</s><s>Yellow colonies have been described by Umeda et al. (30), but they were not identified as <i>T. socranskii</i> colonies.</s><s>Furthermore, live cells of <i>T. socranskii</i> can be recognized microscopically, since cells that are rotating around their axes have both cell tips markedly deflected, which gives the appearance of propellers on both ends of a straight helix (data not shown).</s></p></content></protolog>