<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9920_nm.14887" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14887" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14887" rank="species">Nocardioides ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.9920"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3045</fpage><lpage>3050</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010025-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643897</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. ginsengum, ginseng; L. n. solum, soil; N.L. gen. n. ginsengisoli, of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, and short-rod-shaped, 0.2–0.4 μm in diameter and 0.8–1.2 μm in length after culture on R2A agar for 3 days.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar (Difco) for 3 days are smooth, circular, light yellow–white and convex.</s><s>Grows well at 15–37 °C and pH 5.0–8.5, but not at 4, 42 or 45 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 5.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 6.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase and Voges–Proskauer reaction are positive.</s><s>Does not produce any acid or gas from glucose.</s><s>Does not produce indole from tryptophan and does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S from sodium citrate.</s><s>Degrades DNA, but not xylan, chitin or cellulose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: d-fructose, d-lyxose, l-xylose, pyruvic acid, acetate, propionate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, phenylacetate, benzoic acid, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malate, oxalic acid, gluconate, alanine, arginine, asparagine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, glutamine, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine and valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: ethanol, l-sorbose, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, formic acid, caprate, maleic acid, salicin, malonate, glutaric acid, tartaric acid, itaconate, adipate, suberate, dulcitol, inositol, xylitol, amygdalin, methanol, glycogen, inulin, dextran, cysteine and methionine.</s><s>Utilizes <em>N</em>-nitrophenol (50 p.p.m.) and dibenzofuran (50 p.p.m.–150 p.p.m.).</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone, and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> are the major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 70.2 mol%.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan of strain Gsoil 1124<sup>T</sup> contains ll-DAP.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 1124<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19135<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52478<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17921<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field of Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>