<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6307_nm.2632" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2632" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2632" rank="species">Pseudomonas lini</organism><reference id="rid.6307"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Delorme</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lemanceau</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Corberand</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas lini sp. nov., a novel species from bulk and rhizospheric soils.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>513</fpage><lpage>523</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01966-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931164</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas lini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas lini</i> (li'ni. L. n. <i>linum</i> flax; L. gen. n. <i>lini</i> of flax, referring to the plant genus, <i>Linum</i>, from which the type strain CFBP 5737<sup>T</sup> was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from stationary-phase culture of CFBP 5737<sup>T</sup> are straight rods (0.5-1.0 by 1.5-5.0 μm), Gram-negative, motile by several polar flagella.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 36 °C, but not at 41 °C.</s><s>The white-yellowish colonies on solid KB are smooth, circular with regular margins and moderately convex, and, after 2 days, produce a yellow-green fluorescence with UV light (365 nm).</s><s>Aerobic growth, oxidase-positive, arginine dihydrolase-positive, not pectinolytic.</s><s>Produces no hypersensitive reaction on tobacco leaves.</s><s>The species reduces nitrogen oxides under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, but not DNA and aesculin.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 80 is variable.</s><s>Acid produced from mannitol, sorbitol and sucrose, but not from erythritol.</s><s>Results obtained with Biotype 100 strips indicate that the strains are able to assimilate the following substrates: <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, D-alanine, L-alanine, DL-α-amino-n-butyrate, L-arabinose, L-aspartate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, citrate, diaminobutane, β-D-fructose, fumarate, L-glutamate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, L-histidine, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, D-galactose, D-gluconate, α-D-glucose, glycerol, DL-lactate, L-malate, D-mannitol, D-mannose, mucate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-proline, protocatechuate, quinate, D-saccharate, L-serine, D-sorbitol, succinate, sucrose and D-trehalose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, L-arabitol, D-cellobiose, <i>m</i>-coumarate, dulcitol, erythritol, aesculin, α-L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gentisate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide, histamine, itaconate, alactose, lactulose, D-lyxose, maltose, maltotriose, D-melezitose, α-D-melibiose, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, 1-O-methyl-α-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-β-galactopyranoside, maltitol, 5-keto-D-gluconate, 3-O-methyl-D-glucopyranose, 1-O-methyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, D-raffinose, α-L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, D-turanose, D-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Assimilation of N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, DL-α-aminon-valerate, D-arabitol, benzoate, ethanolamine, dgalacturonate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucuronate, α-ketoglutarate, D-malate, malonate, propionate, D-ribose, D-D-tartrate, L-tartrate, L-tryptophan and L-tyrosine is variable.</s><s>Type strain is strain DLE411J<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited in the Collection Française de Bactéries Phytopathogénes (CFBP, UMR de Pathologie Végétale, INRA-INH/Université, 49071 Beaucouzé cedex, France) under the number CFBP 5737<sup>T</sup> and in the International Collection of Microorganisms from Plants (ICMP, Auckland, New Zealand) under the number ICMP 14138<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>