<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.270_nm.4360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4360" rank="species">Heliobacterium chlorum</organism><reference id="rid.270"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gest</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Favinger</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Heliobacterium chlorum, a anoxygenic brownish-green photosynthetic bacterium containing a new form of bacteriochlorophyll.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>11</fpage><lpage>16</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00415602</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Heliobacterium</i> gen. nov., Gest and Favinger 1983.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Heliobacterium</i> (He.li.o.bac.te'.ri.um. Gr. n. <i>helios</i> sun; Gr. neut. dim. n. <i>bakterion</i> a small rod.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rod-shaped cells, frequently slightly bent, ca. 1 μm wide and of variable length (7-10 μm or longer).</s><s>On complex medium agar, colonies have irregular margins due to wavy protrusions of cell masses in palisade formations, typical of gliding bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately phototrophic; strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Grows photoheterotrophically over a temperature range of 20-41°C (optimum at 35-37°C); biotin required.</s><s>As cultures age, cells show a pronounced tendency to spheroplast and</s></p><p class="description"><s>lyse.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen sources: N<sub>2</sub> or ammonium salts</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photosynthetic pigments: bacteriochlorophyll gag is the major pigment (in vivo, the main absorbancy peak is at 788 nm; relatively small peaks are also observed at 575 and 670 nm).</s><s>Chlorosomes absent.</s><s>In addition to bacteriochlorophyll g<sub>Gg</sub>, cells contain a low concentration of a neurosporene-like carotenoid.</s><s>Young cultures are brownish-green, and later become emerald-green in coloration.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA G + C content: 52 mol %</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: surface soil collected in front of Jordan Hall of Biology, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain : Gest/Favinger.</s><s>The strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC) as number 35205.</s></p></content></protolog>