<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2435_nm.11310" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11310" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11310" rank="species">Segetibacter koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.2435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Segetibacter koreensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the phylum Bacteroidetes, isolated from the soil of a ginseng field in South Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1828</fpage><lpage>1833</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64803-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684266</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Segetibacter koreensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Segetibacter koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>koreensis</em> of Korea, from where the novel organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 1.0–1.3×1.6–2.0 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar plates at 30 °C are circular, convex, non-luminescent and yellow.</s><s>On R2A agar medium, the strain is able to grow at 15–30 °C, but not at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5 and at NaCl concentrations of up to 3 %; growth is optimal at pH 7.0 in the absence of NaCl. <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-fucose, glucose, histidine, maltose, mannose, d-melibiose, l-proline, rhamnose and salicin are assimilated.</s><s>Positive for the hydrolysis of aesculin, urea and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Negative reactions are observed for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity, indole production, glucose fermentation and the assimilation of acetate, adipate, l-alanine, l-arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactate, malate, malonate, mannitol, phenylacetate, propionate, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, suberate, sucrose and valerate.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, gives a positive reaction in tests for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and leucine arylamidase; weakly positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase and negative for chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 40.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 664<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12655<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18137<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>