<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2286_nm.9715" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9715" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9715" rank="species">Paenibacillus assamensis</organism><reference id="rid.2286"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mondal</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bhattacharya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus assamensis sp. nov., a novel bacterium isolated from a warm spring in Assam, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2577</fpage><lpage>2581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63846-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280530</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus assamensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus assamensis</em> (as.sam.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>assamensis</em> pertaining to Assam, a north-eastern state in India, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-variable, strictly aerobic, mesophilic, sporulating, motile rods occurring as single cells or in pairs.</s><s>Cells measure 1·0–2·5 μm in length and 0·5–0·6 μm in width.</s><s>Colonies are round, convex with undulated margins and light yellowish-white in colour, spreading as single colonies over the entire plate.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal and subterminal, occurring in bulging sporangia.</s><s>The strain can grow at temperatures between 20 and 37 °C, at pH values in the range 6·8–12·0 and can tolerate NaCl at concentrations of up to 2·5 %.</s><s>It is oxidase-, catalase-, gelatinase- and arginine dihydrolase-positive but negative for urease, DNase, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, nitrate reduction, in the Voges–Proskauer test and for gas production from glucose but gives a positive result in the methyl red test.</s><s>Cannot utilize acetate, citrate or propionate.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, aesculin and casein but not tyrosine, ONPG or Tweens 20, 40 and 80.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose, glycerol, gentiobiose, glycogen, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, produces acid weakly from d-amygdalin, cellobiose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Can grow in the presence of 0·001 % lysozyme but not 0·01 % lysozyme.</s><s>Cannot degrade chitin or xylan.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso, followed by C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> anteiso and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol.</s><s>The cell-wall amino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The diagnostic menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41·2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GPTSA 11<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 6934<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13186<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a warm-spring water sample from Assam, India.</s></p></content></protolog>