<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10366_nm.16886" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16886" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16886" rank="species">Flavobacterium caeni</organism><reference id="rid.10366"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium caeni sp. nov., isolated from a sequencing batch reactor for the treatment of malachite green effluents</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>417</fpage><lpage>421</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010603-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium caeni</em> (cae′ni. L. gen. n. <em>caeni</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic and heterotrophic.</s><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, non-flagellated and non-spore-forming rods, 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter and 0.8–1.2 μm in length.</s><s>Abundant growth occurs on YP agar, R2A and 0.1× TSA; weak growth occurs on TSA, MA and NA.</s><s>Colonies are orange, circular, smooth with entire margins and about 2–3 mm in diameter after incubation on R2A at 30 °C for 2 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C (optimum, 20–25 °C), at pH 5.5–9.5 (optimum, pH 6.5–7.5) and in the presence of 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0.5 %).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase activity is absent.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>l-Tyrosine, starch and Tweens 20 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 40 and 60 are weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, pectin, carboxymethylcellulose, agar, DNA and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>A brown pigment is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>No precipitate is formed on egg yolk agar.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are present, but extracellular glycans are absent.</s><s>In the API ZYM test, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acidic phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), <em>α-</em>galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In GN2 MicroPlate assays, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, turanose, succinic acid monomethylester, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-threonine, uridine, l-alanyl glycine and l-proline are utilized; all other substrates in the MicroPlate are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin and produced weakly from maltose, d-lactose, starch and glycogen in the API 50CH strip; acid is not produced from the other substrates in the strip.</s><s>Sensitive (μg per disc unless otherwise stated) to vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10), carbenicillin (100), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30), ampicillin (10), erythromycin (15), novobiocin (30), novobiocin (5), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), corfloxacin (10), rifampicin (5) and penicillin (10 U); intermediate resistance is observed for polymixin B (300 U) and kanamycin (30).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LM5<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7031<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104239<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge from a sequencing batch reactor for the treatment of malachite green effluents.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52±0.6 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>