<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6633_nm.5774" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5774" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5774" rank="species">Actinomyces bowdenii</organism><reference id="rid.6633"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bergström</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Greko</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces bowdenii sp. nov., isolated from canine and feline clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1873</fpage><lpage>1877</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1873</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555371</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Actinomyces bowdenii sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Actinomyces bowdenii (bow.den.i.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>bowdenii</i> of Bowden, to honour George Bowden, a contemporary British microbiologist, for his contributions to actinomycete microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods (2-4 μm in length) some of which exhibit branching.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive, are non-acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are non-haemolytic, greyish-white, rounded and approximately 2 mm in diameter after 24-48 h aerobic incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Growth is not enhanced by increased concentration of CO<sub>2</sub> 1.5- 10 % .</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>Succinic acid is the major product of glucose metabolism, together with acetic and lactic acids.</s><s>Using API systems acid is produced from D-glucose, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, lactose, D-raffinose, ribose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, mannitol, pullulan, sorbitol, tagatose or D-xylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from tagatose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin and hippurate are not.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, pyrazinamidase, β-galacturonidase and leucine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, α-fucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C 14, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, trypsin, valine arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Activities for alkaline phosphatase, pyrazinamidase and α-glucosidase, may or may not be detected.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) is the major menaquinone.</s><s>Isolated from clinical material from dogs and a cat.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 37421<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>