<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9152_nm.14345" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14345" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14345" rank="species">Tessaracoccus lubricantis</organism><reference id="rid.9152"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Warfolomeow</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tessaracoccus lubricantis sp. nov., isolated from a metalworking fluid.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1545</fpage><lpage>1549</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006841-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502351</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tessaracoccus lubricantis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tessaracoccus lubricantis</em> [lu.bri.can′tis. L. v. <em>lubricare</em> to lubricate; N.L. n <em>lubricans</em> -<em>antis</em> (from L. part. adj. <em>lubricans</em>) a lubricant; N.L. gen. n. <em>lubricantis</em> of/from a (coolant) lubricant].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (approx. 0.5–1 μm wide and 0.8–2 μm long).</s><s>Gram-positive-staining and oxidase-negative, showing an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar, TSA, nutrient agar and MacConkey agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Yellow, translucent and shiny colonies with entire edges form within 24 h, with a diameter of approximately 0.5 mm.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid in the peptidoglycan is ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The quinone system consists mainly of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polyamine pattern includes spermidine and spermine as major compounds.</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, an unknown glycolipid and an unknown polar lipid.</s><s>In addition, minor amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine, three unknown glycolipids, two unknown aminolipids and two unknown polar lipids and only trace amounts of phosphatidylinositol are present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile contains large amounts of ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and moderate amounts of i-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Can be differentiated from other <em>Tessaracoccus</em> species by its polar lipid and fatty acid profiles (Tables 1 and 2) and by physiological tests.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole sources of carbon: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adipate, 2-oxoglutarate and dl-lactate, on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: d-gluconate, <em>α</em>-melibiose, sucrose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, l-malate, mesaconate, pyruvate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, putrescine, azelate, suberate, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, rhamnose, maltose and galactose.</s><s>No acids are produced from sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s><em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) and l-proline pNA are hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, <em>bis</em>-pNP phosphate, <em>bis</em>-pNP phenylphosphonate, <em>bis</em>-pNP phosphorylcholine and <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KSS-17Se<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19926<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 55516<sup>T</sup>), isolated in Giessen, Germany, from a metalworking fluid.</s></p></content></protolog>