<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.785" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.785" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.802" rank="species">Chlorobium luteolum</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chlorobium luteolum</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Pelodictyon luteolum</em> (Schmidle 1901) Pfennig and Trüper 1971 (Approved Lists 1980).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species description is as given by Pfennig &#x0026; Overmann (2001b) for <em>Pelodictyon luteolum</em>, with the following modifications.</s><s>Cells are straight or curved rods or vibrioid, 0·6–0·9 μm wide, non-motile and may form gas vesicles.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is green, and photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>c</em> and <em>d</em> with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and sulfur as photosynthetic electron donors.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required for growth.</s><s>Brackish water and marine bacteria that require at least 1 % NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 57·1–58·1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 273<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is Y08107.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is a representative of group 2, according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>As outlined above, <em>Pelodictyon luteolum</em> must be assigned to another genus.</s><s>As proposed by Imhoff (1999) and due to its phylogenetic relationship, the type strain of <em>Pelodictyon luteolum</em>, DSM 273<sup>T</sup>, is transferred to the genus <em>Chlorobium</em> and becomes the type strain of the novel species <em>Chlorobium luteolum</em>.</s><s>Almost-identical 16S rRNA and <em>fmo</em> gene sequences, together with a similar DNA G+C content (57·1 mol%, compared to 58·1 mol% of the type strain) strongly support the inclusion of <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> DSM 262 in this species.</s></p></content></protolog>