<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1486_nm.7667" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7667" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7667" rank="species">Kineococcus aurantiacus</organism><reference id="rid.1486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineococcus aurantiacus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new aerobic, Gram-positive, motile coccus with meso-diaminopimelic acid and arabinogalactan in the cell wall.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>52</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kineococcus aurantiacus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kineococcus aurantiacus</i> (au.ran.ti‘a.cus. M. L. n. <i>aurantium</i>, generic name of orange; M. L. adj. <i>aurantiacus</i>, orange colored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical and 1.0 to 1.5 μm in diameter and occur in pairs, in tetrads, or in clusters.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>The motile cells have tufts of flagella.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Colonies are circular and rough and may be cream colored to orange.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and urease positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>The cells do not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-xylose, D-fructose, sucrose, and L-arabinose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, D-ribose, D-arabinose, raffinose, maltose, D-galactose, D-mannose, inositol, L-rhamnose, mannitol, or trehalose.</s><s>Esculin, starch, gelatin, and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemical characteristics, such as amino acid composition of the cell wall peptidoglycan, menaquinone system, mycolic acids, cellular fatty acids, and polar lipids, are the same as the chemical characteristics described above for the genus.</s><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 73.9 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>Distribution: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain RA 333 which has been deposited in the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, as strain IFO 15268.</s></p></content></protolog>