<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6797_nm.5357" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5357" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5357" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus curvatus melibiosus</organism><reference id="rid.6797"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Torriani</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Reenen</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reuter</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. curvatus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. melibiosus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. sake subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. carnosus subsp. nov., new subspecies of Lactobacillus curvatus Abo-Elnaga and Kandler 1965 and Lactobacillus sake Katagiri, Kitahara, and Fukami 1934 (Klein et al. 1996, emended descriptions), respectively.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1158</fpage><lpage>1163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1158</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus curvatus</i> subsp. <i>melibiosus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus curvatus</i> subsp. <i>melibiosus</i> (me.li.bi. o'sus. M. L. adj. <i>melibiosus</i>, pertaining to melibiose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved, bean-shaped rods that have rounded ends (0.7 to 0.9 by 1 to 2 μm) and occur in pairs or short chains; horseshoeshaped or closed rings are frequently observed.</s><s>Usually nonmotile.</s><s>Some strains are motile, but lose their motility when they are subcultured.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45°C, but most strains grow at 42 and 4°C; some strains grow at 2°C.</s><s>Facultatively heterofermentative.</s><s>m-Lactic acid is produced, and often there is an excess of the L-(+) isomer.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, mannose, melibiose, ribose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from salicin.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from cellobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and xylose.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced from glucose.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 42 to 44 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from fermented meat products, vacuum-packaged meat, sauerkraut, and silage.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain R 60 (= CCUG 34545).</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the subspecies.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from cellobiose.</s></p></content></protolog>