<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7060_nm.5807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5807" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5807" rank="species">Actinomyces vaccimaxillae</organism><reference id="rid.7060"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inganäs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces vaccimaxillae sp. nov., from the jaw of a cow</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>603</fpage><lpage>606</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02439-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710633</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces vaccimaxillae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces vaccimaxillae</em> (vac.ci.ma′xil.lae. L. n. <em>vacca</em> cow; L. n. <em>maxilla</em> jaw; N.L. gen. n. <em>vaccimaxillae</em> of a cow's jaw).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-positive, cocco-bacillary to short diphtheroid-shaped rods.</s><s>Non-acid-fast.</s><s>After 48 h anaerobic incubation on Fastidious Anaerobe Agar with 5 % horse blood, colonies are &#x003C;1 mm diameter, convex, smooth, entire-edged, opaque white and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Lactic and succinic acids, together with minor amounts of acetic acid, are the end products of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Using conventional tests, aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Indole is negative and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>With the API Rapid ID 32Strep system, acid is formed from l-arabinose, ribose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from d-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, d-raffinose, sorbitol, or tagatose.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Alanine–phenylalanine–proline arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase or urease.</s><s>With the API Rapid ID32A system, acid is not produced from mannose or raffinose, indole is not formed and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Activity is detected for alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl-glycine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, serine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl-glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase or urease.</s><s>With the API Coryne kit, acid is formed from glucose, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, ribose and d-xylose, but not from maltose or sucrose; aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin is not, and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and pyrazinamidase are detected, whereas <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and urease are not.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, acid phosphatase (weak reaction), <em>α</em>-fucosidase and leucine arylamidase are detected, but alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phosphoamidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, cysteine arylamidase and valine arylamidase are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from pus from a lesion in the jaw of a cow.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 46091<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107423<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>