<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1958_nm.8844" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8844" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8844" rank="species">Shewanella marisflavi</organism><reference id="rid.1958"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yeo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>I.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella marisflavi sp. nov. and Shewanella aquimarina sp. nov., slightly halophilic organisms isolated from sea water of the Yellow Sea in Korea.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2347</fpage><lpage>2352</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63198-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545482</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella marisflavi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella marisflavi</em> (ma.ris.fla′vi. L. gen. neut. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; L. masc. adj. <em>flavus</em> yellow; N.L. gen. n. <em>marisflavi</em> of the Yellow Sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0·8–1·1×2·0–3·5 μm on MA.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, glistening, circular, flat to slightly raised, light brown in colour and 2·0–4·0 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 30 °C on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 42 °C, but not above 43 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 5·0, but not at pH 4·5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2–3 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of more than 9 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA.</s><s>Casein, tyrosine and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, hypoxanthine, urea, xanthine and xylan (birch wool) are not hydrolysed.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are present and leucine arylamidase is weakly present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, d-glucose, maltose and d-ribose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Both menaquinones and ubiquinones are present; the predominant menaquinone is MK-7 and the predominant ubiquinones are Q-7 and Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acid is iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 51 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (SW-117<sup>T</sup>=KCCM 41822<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12192<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from sea water of the Yellow Sea in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>