<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4080_nm.10874" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10874" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5821" rank="species">Mobiluncus curtisii</organism><reference id="rid.4080"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spiegel</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mobiluncus gen. nov., Mobiluncus curtisii subsp. curtisii sp. nov., Mobiluncus curtisii subsp. holmesii subsp. nov., and Mobiluncus mulieris sp. nov., curved rods from the human vagina.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>177</fpage><lpage>184</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-177</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mobiluncus curtisii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mobiluncus curtisii</i> (cur.ti'si.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>curtisii</i> named after A. H. Curtis, who isolated the first strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, gram variable, curved, nonsporing, rod shaped, and motile by means of multiple subterminal flagella.</s><s>The cells are &#x003C;0.5 μm wide and have a mean length of 1.7 μm (Fig. 2A).</s><s>Cells migrate through soft (0.25%) agar.</s><s>Colonies are colorless, translucent, smooth, convex, and entire and reach a maximum diameter of 2 to 3 mm after 5 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is stimulated by arginine.</s><s>Starch and hippurate are hydrolyzed in the absence of serum.</s><s>Citrulline, ornithine, and ammonia are produced from arginine.</s><s>Weakly (pH 5.5 to 6.5) to strongly (pH 4.5) saccharolytic (Table 2).</s><s>Cultures are more turbid in PY broth supplemented with rabbit serum and glycogen or maltose than in PY broth supplemented with glucose and rabbit serum or rabbit serum alone.</s><s>Other biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The fermentation products from glycogen include succinate (&#x003E; 1 meq/lOO ml), trace amounts of fumarate (&#x003C;1 meq/100 ml), and moderate amounts of acetate (&#x003C;1 meq/100 ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alpha-glucosidase (10 to 30 nmol of product), phosphoamidase (≤5 nmol), and leucine aminopeptidase (5 to 10 nmol) are produced.</s><s>Esterase lipase (4 nmol) is produced by five of six strains, acid phosphatase is produced by one strain, α-galactosidase is produced by two strains, and alkaline phosphatase is produced by one strain.</s><s>Butyrate esterase, lipase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosdase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase are not produced at 35 or 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>A weak CAMP reaction (Fig. 3) is produced on brucella agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood when <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> ATCC 25923 is used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 51 to 52 mol%, as determined by the thermal melting method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human vaginae; associated with bacterial vaginosis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain BV345-16 (= ATCC 35241).</s></p></content></protolog>