<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1201_nm.4392" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4392" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4392" rank="species">Centipeda periodontii</organism><reference id="rid.1201"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Males</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dougherty</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berthold</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Listgarten</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Centipeda periodontii gen. nov., sp. nov. from human periodontal lesions.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>628</fpage><lpage>635</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-628</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Centipeda periodontii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Centipeda periodontii</i> (per.i.o.don'ti.i. M.L. n. [T.Gr.] <i>periodontium</i> periodontium; M.L. gen.n. <i>periodontii</i> of the periodontium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular morphology and ultrastructure.</s><s>Cells of freshly isolated strains are gram negative, slightly serpentine, long, and rod-shaped with three or more curves and bluntly tapered ends.</s><s>The amount of cell curvature is variable among strains and is reduced after repeated passage in culture.</s><s>The cell diameter is 0.65 μm, and the cell length ranges from 4 to 17 μm or longer in older cultures.</s><s>The cells occur singly or occasionally in chains; occasional budding gives rise to branched forms.</s><s>Multiple sets of flagellar bundles are present on each side of the cell.</s><s>The number of flagellar bundles increases with increasing cell length.</s><s>The bundles originate alternately from the concave areas along the curved cell body.</s><s>Higher magnifications of negatively stained cells show a spiral path of insertion of the individual flagella from which the bundles are formed.</s><s>This flagellar pattern is distinct from the one-sided patterns of <i>Selenomonas</i> and <i>Pectinatus</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in 24-h broth cultures are actively motile.</s><s>Motility is accompanied by flexion of the entire cell in a snakelike motion and by rotation around the long axis of the cell body.</s><s>Tumbling is observed occasionally.</s><s>Changes in direction of motility are preceded by a period of twitching motion in which the cells are nearly stationary; the flagellar bundles of the cells are fully extended and rotate erratically.</s><s>In 5-day broth cultures few cells are motile, and cytoplasmic granules are visible when cells are examined by dark-field microscopy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negatively stained preparations of cell surfaces exhibit the typical brainlike contour reported for many other gram-negative bacteria.</s><s>Cellular cross-sections reveal a typical gram-negative cell wall structure.</s><s>The outer and inner membranes consist of two electron-dense layers separated by an electron-lucent layer.</s><s>The outer membrane has an irregular, undulating profile, whereas the cytoplasmic membrane is relatively smooth and in direct contact with the moderately electrondense peptidoglycan layer.</s><s>Nucleoid areas are dispersed throughout the cytoplasm, which contains rod-shaped, electron-dense inclusions.</s><s>Specialized regions of the peripheral cytoplasm approximately 30 by 130 to 220 nm occur along the inner membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>During initial isolation on blood agar, strains form flat, tranparent colonies approximately 2 mm in diameter with irregular borders.</s><s>After subculturing, the colonies are gray, transparent, and flat or thinly raised with finely granular surfaces.</s><s>Growth spreads rapidly and after 3 days of incubation covers the entire surface of a plate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in broth is turbid, forming a dense, white, sediment which may be 2 to 3 cm deep after 24 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>Cultures grow on complex media (e.g., blood agar and Todd-Hewitt broth).</s><s>The organisms are strict anaerobes and produce no growth aerobically or in atmospheres containing increased concentrations of CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth occurs between 32 and 37°C; the optimum temperature is 35°C.</s><s>Growth is not enhanced by bile.</s><s>The addition of a fermentable carbohydrate to a broth culture enhances growth.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the fermentation of carbohydrates.</s><s>All strains ferment fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, sorbitol, and sucrose.</s><s>Fermentation of adonitol, cellobiose, mannose, melezitose, rhamnose, salicin, trehalose, and xylose is variable among strains.</s><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, dulcitol, esculin, glycogen, inositol, inulin, sorbose, and starch are not fermented.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed; esculin hydrolysis varies among strains.</s><s>Arginine is not utilized.</s><s>The final pH in peptone-yeast extract broth containing 1% glucose</s></p><p class="description"><s>is 4.2 to 5.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. periodontii</i> strains produce 1.2 and 2.2 meq of propionic acid per 100 ml of medium in peptone-yeast extract broth and peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth, respectively; smaller amounts of succinic acid and lactic acid are also produced.</s><s>Lactate may be converted to succinate.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, urease, H<sub>2</sub>S, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, and <i>o</i>-nitronitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside is utilized.</s><s>Propionate is not produced from threonine, gelatin is not liquified, and no hemolysis occurs on sheep blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pathogenicity of <i>C. periodontii</i> has not been determined, although members of this species have been isolated from human periodontal lesions and have not been detected in healthy subjects.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 53 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method; the G+C contents of two other strains tested are 52 and 54 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LL2383, which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 35019.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA sequence homology and base composition.</s><s>We compared nine strains of <i>C. periodontii</i> with the type strains of <i>F. plauti</i> (<i>E. plautii</i>), <i>S. sputigena</i>, and <i>S. ruminantium</i> by a sequence homology test and found no measurable homology among the four species.</s><s>Erratic and unusually low DNA hybridization values occurred among some strains of <i>C. periodontii</i>.</s><s>Our difficulty in obtaining reliable hybridization data for some strains probably reflects differences among the isolates in the proportions of contaminating material (most likely polysaccharide, which remains behind in purified DNA preparations.</s><s>However, repeated attempts to extract DNAs of greater purity from these isolates did not improve the reproducibility of our results.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In view of the morphological and biochemical data, as well as the similarities in DNA G+C contents, we placed all nine of our strains in the same species.</s><s>Characteristics that may help differentiate some phenotypically similar species are shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>