<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7246_nm.1571" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1571" rank="genus">Starkeya</organism><reference id="rid.7246"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McDonald</surname><given-names>I.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for the reclassification of Thiobacillus novellus as Starkeya novella gen. nov., comb. nov., in the alpha-subclass of the Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1797</fpage><lpage>1802</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034489</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Starkeya</i> (ex Starkey 1935a) gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Starkeya</i> (Star.ke'ya. M.L. n. <i>Starkeya</i> of Starkey, referring to Robert L. Starkey, who made important contributions to the study of soil microbiology and sulfur biochemistry)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short rods, coccoidal or ellipsoidal cells 0.4-0.8 μm x 0.8-2.0 μm, occurring singly and, occasionally, in pairs.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies grown on thiosulfate agar (with biotin) are small, smooth, circular, round and opalescent, becoming white with sulfur.</s><s>Thiosulfate liquid medium (lacking biotin) becomes turbid and sulfur precipitates during static incubation: thiosulfate is incompletely used; and the pH falls from 7.8 to 5.8.</s><s>This poor development is due to the requirement for biotin exhibited by the type strain.</s><s>The organism is facultatively chemolithoautotrophic, but optimal autotrophic development requires biotin, and optimal heterotrophic growth requires yeast extract or biotin or other additions such as pantothenate, depending on the organic substrate.</s><s>Autotrophic growth is also observed with formate, when high levels of ribulose 1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase are expressed.</s><s>Some strains may degrade methylated sul®des.</s><s>This organism is strictly aerobic, both autotrophically and heterotrophically, and is incapable of denitri®cation.</s><s>Oxidizes and grows on thiosulfate and tetrathionate but not on sulfur or thiocyanate.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrates, urea and glutamate are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 25-30 °C; the temperature for growth is in the range 10-37 °C (with no growth occurring at 5 or 42 °C).</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.0; the pH for growth is in the range 5.7-9.0.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are octadecenoic acid and cyclopropane acid of C<sub>19</sub>; lacks a major hydroxy-fatty acid.</s><s>LPS lacks heptoses and has only 2,3-diamino-2,3-dideoxyglucose as the backbone sugar.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 67.3-68.4 mol% (Bd, <i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Member of the α-2 subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Isolated from soil and presumably widely distributed.</s></p></content></protolog>