<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2799_nm.3083" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3083" rank="genus">Anaerobiospirillum</organism><reference id="rid.2799"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Malnick</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerobiospirillum thomasii sp. nov., an anaerobic spiral bacterium isolated from the feces of cats and dogs and from diarrheal feces of humans, and emendation of the genus Anaerobiospirillum.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>384</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103625</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Anaerobiospirillum</i> Davis, Cleven, Brown, and Balish 1976.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-negative helical rods with rounded ends, usually 0.6 to 0.8 μm in diameter and 3 to 15 μm long, although some cells are up to 32 μm long. Motile by means of bipolar tufts of flagella. Cells usually occur singly. Endospores are not formed. Strictly anaerobic. Catalase and oxidase negative. Does not hydrolyze esculin, hippurate, or urea and does not reduce nitrate. Carbohydrate metabolism is fermentative. The major products from glucose metabolism are succinic and acetic acids; traces of lactic and formic acids may also be formed. The optimal growth temperature is 37 to 42°C. Found in feces of dogs and cats and as a pathogen in humans, causing septicemia and/or diarrhea. The DNA G+C content range is 39 to 44 mol%. The type species is <i>A. succiniciproducens</i> (type strain, NCTC 11536 [= ATCC 29305]).</s></p></content></protolog>