<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9259_nm.14537" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14537" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14537" rank="species">Zhihengliuella alba</organism><reference id="rid.9259"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>L.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zhihengliuella alba sp. nov., and emended description of the genus Zhihengliuella</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2025</fpage><lpage>2032</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007344-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567565</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Zhihengliuella alba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Zhihengliuella alba</em> (al′ba. L. fem. adj. <em>alba</em> white, referring to the white colour of colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, short rods, 0.5–0.9×1.3–1.8 μm in size, non-motile and without flagella.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth and white on modified ISP 5 medium.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl, with good growth at 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–45 °C and pH 5.0–9.0, with optimum growth at 28–37 °C and pH 6.0–8.0.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Negative for milk peptonization, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests, H<sub>2</sub>S production, nitrate reduction, and hydrolysis of starch, urea, cellulose, casein, chitin and Tween 20.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin, Tween 40 and Tween 80.</s><s>Enzyme activities (API ZYM) are observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced (API 50CHB) from erythritol, d-ribose, dl-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, amygdalin, maltose, sucrose and starch, but not from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-mannose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, turanose, arbutin, aesculin, cellobiose, salicin, d-lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon or nitrogen and energy sources (Biolog GP2): dextrin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, l-asparagine, l-serine, glycerol, 2′-deoxyadenosine and thymidine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, starch, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, lactulose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl-d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, turanose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>ρ</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, dl-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, inosine, uridine, adenosine-5′-monophosphate, thymidine-5′-monophosphate, uridine-5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Peptidoglycan type is A4<em>α</em>, l-Lys–l-Ala–l-Glu.</s><s>Major cell sugars contain tyvelose and mannose; minor amounts of glucose, rhamnose and galactose are also detected.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-10 (64.0 %) and MK-9 (32.7 %); a minor amount of MK-8 (3.3 %) is also detected.</s><s>Polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, an unknown phospholipid and two unknown glycolipids.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>; minor amounts of C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> are also detected.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 90734<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19375<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21143<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil sample collected from Ganjiahu Suosuo Forest National Nature Reserve in Xinjiang province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>