<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5365_nm.5914" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5914" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5914" rank="species">Rarobacter incanus</organism><reference id="rid.5365"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tadenuma</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on yeast-lysing bacteria, and a new species Rarobacter incanus</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>272</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rarobacter incanus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rarobacter incanus</i> (in.ca'nus L. masc. adj. <i>incanus</i>, grayish white)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristicsfgiven for the genus, the characteristics of <i>Rarobacter incanus</i> are as follows.</s><s>Facultative anaerobic.</s><s>Hemin or hemoproteins are required as growth factors under aerobic condition.</s><s>Carbon dioxide but not hemin or hemoproteins are required for anaerobic growth.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient-catalase agar are pale grayish cream, opaque, circular, convex, entire and smooth.</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically and anaerobically from D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, maltose, dextrin, arbutin and salicin, but not from L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-galactose, L-sorbose, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, inulin, glycerol, erythritol, adonitol, mannitol, dulcitol, D-sorbitol, or α-methyl-D-glucoside.</s><s>The type strain does not produce hydrogen sulfide, and produces acid from cellobiose; however, some strains produce hydrogen sulfide, and do not produce acid from cellobiose.</s><s>DNase, urease and catalase were negative.</s><s>DNA base composition is 64.6-65.5 mol% G + C (determined by the high-performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) method).</s><s>Amino acid composition of cell wall peptidoglycan is D-Ala : L-Ala : D-Glu : L-Orn (1:1:2:1).</s><s>The bacterial cells adhere to viable yeast cells of the genera <i>Saccharomyces</i> and <i>Hansenula</i>, agglutinate with them, and lyse them.</s><s>Type strain is YLM-32 (JCM 6350).</s><s>DNA base composition of the type strain is 65.2 mol % G + C.</s><s>The other description of the type strain is the same as that of the species <i>R. incanus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>