<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1441_nm.9155" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9155" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6684" rank="species">Pseudoamycolata halophobica</organism><reference id="rid.1441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobritsa</surname><given-names>S.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoamycolata halophobica gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>457</fpage><lpage>461</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoamycolata halophobica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoamycolata halophobica</i> (ha.lo.pho'bi.ca. Gr. n. <i>hals</i>, salt, the sea; Gr. n. <i>phobos</i>, fear, dread; L. fem. adj. <i>halophobica</i>, salt-fearing, referring to the inability to grow in the presence of 3% NaCl)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology, chemotaxonomy , and general characteristics are as given above for the genus.</s><s>In addition, swollen hyphal segments (up to 3 μm long) with transverse and longitudinal septa may be observed in cultures.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white to cream colored, and the substrate mycelium ranges from yellowish orange to brown, depending on the medium (the color of the substrate mycelium on peptone-yeast extract agar is orange).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, L-rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>Acid production from glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, maltose, sorbitol, and sucrose is variable.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, L- and D-arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, melibiose, <i>a</i>-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, ribitol, ribose, salicin, and trehalose.</s><s>Decarboxylates aconitate, formate, lactate, malate, malonate, propionate, pyruvate, sebacate, succinate, and <i>trans</i>-aconitate but not citrate, maleate, and salicylate.</s><s>Decarboxylation of benzoate is variable.</s><s>No growth on D-gluconate and D-glucuronate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Hydrolyzes arbutin, esculin, xanthine, urea, Tween 40, Tween 60, and gelatin but not allantoin and starch; variable results are obtained for hydrolysis of casein.</s><s>Alanine, arginine, hydroxyproline, ornithine, phenylalanine, proline, threonine, tryptophan, and valine but not glycine, histidine, leucine, lysine, and tyrosine are assimilated as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Production of nitrate reductase is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth in the presence of 3% NaCl, 0.001% sodium azide, or 0.000001% crystal violet.</s><s>Susceptible to roseofungin (10 μg/ml), polymyxin B (20 μg/ml), fucidin (1 μg/ml), metacycline (1 μg/ml), lincomycin (10 μg/ml), penicillin (10 μg/ml), tetracycline (10 μg/ml), and novobiocin (50 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VKM Ac-1069 (= DSM 43089 = IMRU 1300 = M.</s><s>P.</s><s>Lechevalier SS1/1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, with the following differences: acid is produced from glycerol and <i>meso</i>-inositol but not from maltose, sorbitol, and sucrose; nitrate reductase negative; no decarboxylation of benzoate; and no hydrolysis of casein.</s></p></content></protolog>