<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1407_nm.61" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.61" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.61" rank="species">Hyperthermus butylicus</organism><reference id="rid.1407"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zillig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holz</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wunderl</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hyperthermus butylicus gen. nov., sp. nov., a hyperthermophilic, anaerobic, peptide-fermenting, facultatively H2S-generating archaeobacterium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>169</fpage><lpage>170</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hyperthermus butylicus</i> Zillig, Holz, and Wunderl sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyperthermus butylicus</i> (bu.ty´li.cus. N. L. masc. adj. <i>butyficus</i>, butylic, referring to production of butanol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shape and size as described above for the genus (Fig. 1).</s><s>About 1% diploforms (Fig. 1).</s><s>Projections, probably pili and not flagella, extend from the whole surface.</s><s>Often there are short "tails", which are probably remnants from division.</s><s>About 25% of late-log-phase cells grown at 107 to 108°C have long appendages.</s><s>Many cells in the late log phase of growth have vacuoles (Fig. 1).</s><s>The lattice constant of the hexagonal S-layer is 25.9 nm and is distinct from the lattice constants of other archaebacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Grows by fermentation of proteolysis products (e.g., tryptones and gelatin).</s><s>The products are CO<sub>2</sub> (2.6 mmol/g [dry weight]) and <i>n</i>-butanol, (33 mmol/g [dry weight]), as well as acetic acid, propionic acid, and phenylacetic acid (equal amounts).</s><s>Growth is stimulated about 10-fold by S<sup>o</sup> plus H<sub>2</sub>, with massive production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>No stimulation by CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No chemolithoautotrophic growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth occurs with 6 g of tryptone (Difco) per liter, 10 g of S<sup>o</sup> per liter under CO<sub>2</sub> or N<sub>2</sub> containing 20% (vol/vol) H<sub>2</sub>, and 17 g of NaCl per liter at pH 7 between 95 and 107°C.</s><s>The generation times are 2 to 3 h; at 85°C, the generation time is 4.5 h.</s><s>No growth occurs at 75°C.</s><s>Slow growth occurs at 108°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain DNA-dependent RNA polymerase which is not sensitive to rifampin and is stable at 102°C.</s><s>The component pattern is distinct on the basis of the apparent molecular weights of the components but corresponds in principle to the component patterns of other thermophilic sulfur archaebacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The polyisoprenoid tetraether lipids of the membrane consist of only two major components (mainly tetraether lipids with 0 to 2 cyclopentane rings in isoprenoid chains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 56 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetically (as determined by DNA-rRNA cross-hybridization experiments [1]), <i>H. butyficus</i> forms a long lineage between the genera <i>Thermoproteus</i> and <i>Sulfolobus</i> and is distinguished from members of the genera <i>Desulfurococcus</i> and <i>Pyrodictium</i> by its S-layer structure, its RNA polymerase component pattern, its mode of growth, and its morphology.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 5456.</s></p></content></protolog>