<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1720_nm.4651" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4651" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4651" rank="species">Mycoplasma cricetuli</organism><reference id="rid.1720"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma cricetuli, a new species from the conjuctivas of chinese hamsters.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>113</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-113</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplusmu cricetuli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Colonies were visible after 2 to 3 days of incubation under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions. Although the colonies showed the “fried egg” appearance, the centers were usually very small (Fig. 1). Growth characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the isolates reverted to bacteria when subcultured onto medium without bacterial inhibitors.</s><s>Their colonies rapidly became stained with Diene stain, indicating that these isolates were true mycoplasmas and not bacterial L-forms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No motility was noticed under dark-field microscopy.</s><s>Liquid cultures stained with Giemsa stain showed short filaments and ring forms.</s><s>The organisms were typical of mycoplasmas when viewed by the electron microscope and were bounded by a membrane (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration of the mycoplasmas showed that of 2.5 x 10<sup>6</sup> organisms per ml in the original dilution, reduced numbers passed through the 450-nm (2.5 x 10<sup>4</sup>) and 300-nm (4 X 10<sup>2</sup>) membranes, and no organisms passed through the 220-nm membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms were shown to require cholesterol (1 μg/ml) for growth.</s><s>They were susceptible to digitonin and sodium polyanetholsulfonate with 8- to 9-mm- and 6- to 8-mm-zones of growth inhibition respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Chinese hamster mycoplasmas belong to the genus <i>Mycoplasma</i>, as they are dependent upon sterol for growth and are susceptible to digitonin and sodium polyanetholsulfonate, and because urease could not be demonstrated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical activity is shown in Tables 2 and 3.</s><s>The isolates metabolized some carbohydrates, i.e., fructose, glucose, maltose, mannose, raffinose, and sucrose.</s><s>They did not hydrolyze arginine.</s><s>The mycoplasmas lysed but did not adsorb erythrocytes.</s><s>They agglutinated sheep erythrocytes, but not human or guinea pig erythrocytes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The electrophoretic protein patterns are shown in Fig. 3.</s><s>All four strains gave a similar pattern and were distinct from the rodent mycoplasmas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological techniques showed a high level of cross-reactions among the four isolates (Tables 4 through 6).</s><s>As high cross-reactions were demonstrated between the four isolates CH, SH, LE, and HO in all of the serological tests and as the isolates have similar characteristics, they belong to the same species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No cross-reactions were detected with any of the species in Table 1 .</s><s>Because the species showed no serological cross-reactions with any of the named <i>Mycoplasma</i> spp., it is therefore a new species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is suggested that the species be named <i>Mycoplasma cricetuli</i> type strain CH, NCTC 10190.</s></p></content></protolog>