<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6914_nm.4851" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4851" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4851" rank="species">Holdemania filiformis</organism><reference id="rid.6914"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and phylogenetic characterization of some Eubacterium-like isolates containing a novel type B wall murein from human feces: description of Holdemania filiformis gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1201</fpage><lpage>1204</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1201</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336928</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Holdemania filiformis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Holdemania filiformis</i> (fi.li.for'mis. L. n. <i>filum</i>, thread; L. n. <i>forma</i>, shape; M. L. adj. <i>filiformis</i>, filiform)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on the study of three strains isolated from the feces of healthy humans.</s><s>Cells are short-to-long, gram-positive bacilli that decolorize easily and occur in pairs and short chains.</s><s>The longer cells may have central to terminal swellings, but neither spores nor heat resistance has been demonstrated.</s><s>Colonies on brain heart infusion agar streak tubes incubated in an anaerobic atmosphere are 1.0 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, and translucent, with a granular appearance.</s><s>There is no growth on the surface of solid medium incubated in air enriched to 10% with CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Broth cultures in PYT-glucose medium are turbid with a smooth, white sediment.</s><s>In broth media, growth is enhanced by 0.2% (vol/vol) Tween 80.</s><s>There is good growth in PYT broth medium containing esculin, fructose, glucose, salicin, or sucrose, even though the pH is only 5.8 to 6.2 in this medium.</s><s>Growth in PYT broth without carbohydrate and PYT with amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, starch, trehalose, or xylose is marginal; the pH of cultures in this medium is 6.2 to 6.5.</s><s>Moderate growth sometimes is observed in peptone-yeast extract broth with lactose or maltose.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced; indole and catalase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin and meat are not digested, and milk is unchanged.</s><s>Arginine is not deaminated.</s><s>Acids detected in PYT-glucose broth cultures acidified to pH 2.0 (in milliequivalents per milliliter of culture) are acetic acid (0.8), lactic acid (0.9), and succinic acid (0.2); formic acid is sometimes detected.</s><s>Methylated cellular lipid constituents are <i>cis</i>9 fatty methyl ester (50% of total acids + 11.48% SD), <i>cis</i>9 dimethyl acetal (12% + 4.51% SD), C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>cis</i>9 fatty acid methyl ester (6% + 3.43% SD), C<sub>10:1</sub> <i>cis</i>9 fatty acid methyl ester (5% + 4.03% SD), C<sub>16:0</sub> fatty acid methyl ester (4% + 3.24% SD), and C<sub>16:0</sub> dimethyl acetal (4% + 0.65% SD).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 38 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain of <i>H. filiformis</i> is strain J1-31B-1 (= ATCC 51649).</s><s>Isolated from human feces.</s></p></content></protolog>