<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.732_nm.9440" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9440" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9440" rank="species">Alcanivorax dieselolei</organism><reference id="rid.732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alcanivorax dieselolei sp. nov., a novel alkane-degrading bacterium isolated from sea water and deep-sea sediment</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1181</fpage><lpage>1186</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63443-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879252</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alcanivorax dieselolei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alcanivorax dieselolei</em> (die.sel.o′le.i. N.L. masc. n. <em>dieselius</em> latinized family name of Rudolf Diesel; L. gen. neut. n. <em>olei</em> of oil; N.L. gen. neut. n. <em>dieselolei</em> of diesel oil, the sole carbon source used in the isolation procedure of the two strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0·8–2·0 μm long and 0·3–0·7 μm wide, motile, lophotrichous, non-spore-forming, Gram-negative rods.</s><s>Colonies on HLB agar are characteristically small, translucent, non-pigmented and slightly raised in the centre, with irregular, transparent and halo-like peripheries.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Growth temperature ranges from 15 to 45 °C (optimum 28 °C).</s><s>NaCl is required for growth; cells grow in 1–15 % NaCl (optimum 3–7·5 %).</s><s>Actively degrades Tween 80; catalase- and oxidase-positive, but negative for agarase, arginine dihydrolase, amylase and gelatinase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Among the 95 carbon sources in the Biolog system, positive for Tweens 40 and 80, methyl pyruvate, mono-methyl succinate, acetic acid, citric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxy phenyl acetic acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, bromo succinic acid and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Negative for all carbohydrates using Biolog GN.</s><s>Good growth occurs in SM1 medium with citrate, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetate, pyruvate, lactate or n-alkane as carbon source.</s><s>Sensitive to neomycin, kanamycin, amikacin and polymyxin B.</s><s>Cells are able to degrade n-alkanes with chain length C<sub>5</sub> to C<sub>36</sub>.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3OH.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is 62·1–62·5 mol%.</s><s>Table 2 shows characteristics used to distinguish strain B-5<sup>T</sup> from other members of the genus <em>Alcanivorax</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B-5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16502<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.3690<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an oil-contaminated sea water at the Yellow River dock of Shengli oilfield, Bohai Sea.</s><s>Strain NO1A was isolated from a deep-sea sediment sample in the Pacific nodule region A station (5027 m water depth).</s></p></content></protolog>