<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8288_nm.14126" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14126" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14126" rank="species">Actinomyces massiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.8288"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Renvoise</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces massiliensis sp. nov., isolated from a patient blood culture.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>540</fpage><lpage>544</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001503-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244437</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces massiliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces massiliensis</em> (mas.si.li.en′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>massiliensis</em> of Massilia, the old Greek and Roman name for Marseille, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, Gram-positive, straight rods that are catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>After 48 h growth on sheep-blood agar, surface colonies are pinpoint.</s><s>The rods are 0.5–1.7 μm in length and 0.35–0.74 μm in diameter, as estimated by electronic microscopy.</s><s>By using API ZYM, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are detected.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chemotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>By using API 50 CH strips after an incubation time of 24 h, acid is produced from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, maltose, lactose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>After an incubation time of 48 h, acid is produced from d-xylose, melezitose, turanose and d-lyxose.</s><s>After an incubation time of 48 h, acid is produced weakly from d-ribose and d-mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabinol, l-arabinol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>By using API Rapid ID 32 A, the following tests were positive: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, reduction of nitrates, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Mannose fermentation and tyrosine arylamidase were weakly positive.</s><s>The remaining tests were negative: urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase 6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, raffinose fermentation, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, indole production, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histamine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by the presence of C12 : 0, C14 : 0, C16 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C16 : 0, a mix of C18 : 2<em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em> and C18 : 0 anteiso, C18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C18 : 0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from a human blood sample, is 4401292<sup>T</sup> (=CSUR P18<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53522<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>