<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1514_nm.654" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.654" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.654" rank="species">Prochloron didemni</organism><reference id="rid.1514"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Florenzano</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balloni</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Materassi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nomenclature of Prochloron didemni (Lewin 1977) sp. nov., nom rev., Prochloron (Lewin 1976) gen. nov., nom. rev., Prochloraceae fam. nov., Prochlorales ord. nov., nom. rev. in the class Photobacteria Gibbons and Murray 1978.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>351</fpage><lpage>353</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prochloron didemni</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prochloron didemni</i> (di.de' mni. M.L. of <i>Didemnum</i> Lewin 1976)</s></p><p class="description"><s>synomym <i>Synechocystis didemni</i> Schulz-Baldes and Lewin 19761 [24]</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on the type material, because no pure cultures have been maintained in the laboratory for more than two or three transfers.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Prochloron didemni</i> are nonmotile, spherical, gram-negative cells, measuring 7 to 14 μm in diameter, multiplying by binary fission.</s><s>Depending on conditions and host, cells may occur as green patches on the outer surfaces of animal colonies or in their common cloacal cavities, embedded in the material of the tunic.</s><s>The symbiosis seems to be obligate.</s><s>Thylakoids are either dispersed through the cell or concentrically arranged in the outer zones, around the thylakoid-free central body, and are generally appressed in pairs.</s><s>The surfaces of thylakoids are smooth internally and externally.</s><s>Ratios of chlorophyll <i>a</i> to chlorophyll <i>b</i> range from 2.6 to 10, according to various sources.</s><s>Carotenoid complement is made up of β-carotene (about 70%), an unidentified xanthophyll similar to zeaxanthin (25%), and in smaller amounts, several other carotenoids.</s><s>Habitat is on or within the colonies of different ascidian didemnids in subtropical or tropical coastal waters, where the temperature rarely falls below 20°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A rational basis for differentiation of other species should await further work with cell chemistry and physiology of future isolates.</s></p></content></protolog>