<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6844_nm.992" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.992" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.992" rank="species">Ehrlichia canis</organism><reference id="rid.6844"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dumler</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbet</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bekker</surname><given-names>C.P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dasch</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palmer</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ray</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rikihisa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rurangirwa</surname><given-names>F.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of genera in the families Rickettsiaceae and Anaplasmataceae in the order Rickettsiales: unification of some species of Ehrlichia with Anaplasma, Cowdria with Ehrlichia and Ehrlichia with Neorickettsia, descriptions of six new species combinations and designation of Ehrlichia equi and 'HGE agent' as subjective synonyms of Ehrlichia phagocytophila.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2145</fpage><lpage>2165</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Ehrlichia canis</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The most recent description of <i>E. canis</i> is that of Ristic &#x0026; Huxsoll (1984). In addition, cells are Gram-negative, coccoid to ellipsoidal, often pleomorphic, intracytoplasmic bacteria that infect canid and perhaps human cells of bone marrow derivation (Perez et al., 1996), predominantly cells in the monocytic lineage. The predominant tick vector is <i>Rhipicephalus sanguineus</i>. The major constitutionally produced protein antigen varies between 28 and 32 kDa in molecular size and is expressed on the outer membrane (Yu et al., 1999a; Ohashi et al., 1998b; Reddy et al., 1998; McBride et al., 1999). The amino acid sequences of the major outer-membrane proteins are similar to those of <i>E. chaffeensis</i>, <i>E. ruminantium</i>, <i>A. marginale</i>, <i>A. phagocytophila</i> and <i>W. pipientis</i>. The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain Oklahoma<sup>T</sup> is deposited in GenBank under accession no. M73221.</s></p></content></protolog>