<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5308_nm.129" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.129" rank="genus">Methanosphaera</organism><reference id="rid.5308"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolin</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanosphaera stadtmaniae gen. nov., sp. nov.: a species that forms methane by reducing methanol with hydrogen.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>122</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00423270</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3994486</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanosphaera</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanosphaera</i> (Me. tha. no. sphae'ra Modern chem. comb. form. <i>methano</i>- relating to methane; Gr. fem. N. <i>sphaira</i> a sphere; N. L. fem. n. <i>Methanosphaera</i> a methane-producing sphere)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Round cells, usually occurring in pairs, tetrads and clusters, about 1.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Resting cells, such as spores are not known.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Cell walls are composed of pseudomurein.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Optimum temperature, near 37°C.</s><s>Optimum pH 6.5 to 6.9.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies are opaque to transluscent, effuse, circular or elliptical with entire margins and light tan.</s><s>Colonies in uncrowded roll tubes may reach a diameter of 2 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Energy for growth is obtained by using one tool of H<sub>2</sub> to reduce one mol of methanol to one tool of CH<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Methane is not produced from methanol in the absence of H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, sulfate, fumarate, choline or nitrate do not substitute for methanol.</s><s>Methane is not produced from acetate, methylamines or formate with or without H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No growth or methane is obtained with H<sub>2</sub> and ethanol.</s><s>Easily visible pigments are not produced and cytochromes are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbon dioxide and acetate are required for growth.</s><s>NH<sup>+</sup> and one or more amino acids may be major sources of cell nitrogen.</s><s>One or more B vitamin may be required for or stimulatory to growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol % G + C is 26 (T<sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Methanosphaera stadtmaniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>