<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4826_nm.831" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.831" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.831" rank="species">Inquilinus limosus</organism><reference id="rid.4826"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spilker</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>LiPuma</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of unusual bacteria isolated from respiratory secretions of cystic fibrosis patients and description of Inquilinus limosus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>2062</fpage><lpage>2069</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12037065</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Inquilinus limosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Inquilinus limosus</i> (li.mo'sus. L. masc. adj. <i>limosus</i>, full of slime, slimy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>I. limosus</i> is the same as for the genus.</s><s>The type strain, AU0476<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from the respiratory secretions of a CF patient in the United States in 1998.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as for the species.</s><s>In addition, the type strain has the following characteristics: oxidase, β-galactosidase, and γ-L-glutamyl aminopeptidase activity are present; no urease, gelatinase, or α-glucosidase activity is present; there is no acid production from sucrose or lactose; there is no growth in 6% NaCl; there is growth on BCSA at 32°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 70.3%, and the GenBank accession number for its 16S rDNA sequence is AY043374. <i>I. limosus</i> AU0476<sup>T</sup> was deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection (University of Ghent, Ghent, Belgium) as LMG 20952<sup>T</sup> and in the CCUG Culture Collection (University of Goteborg, Goteborg, Sweden) as CCUG 45653<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>In addition, <i>Inquilinus</i> sp. strain AU1979 was deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection as LMG 20953.</s></p></content></protolog>