<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12225_nm.20224" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20224" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20224" rank="species">Sphingopyxis bauzanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12225"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingopyxis bauzanensis sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2618</fpage><lpage>2622</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018218-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20023054</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingopyxis bauzanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingopyxis bauzanensis</em> (bau.zan.en′sis. M.L. fem. adj. <em>bauzanensis</em> referring to Bauzanum, the medieval Latin name for Bozen/Bolzano, a city in South Tyrol, Italy, where the type strain was first found).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped (0.4–0.6×0.8–1.1 μm) and motile.</s><s>Colonies on R<sub>2</sub>A agar are yellow, round, convex and with entire margin; colony diameter is approximately 1 mm after 6 days at 20 °C on R<sub>2</sub>A agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in liquid R<sub>2</sub>A medium and on agar plates at 1–30 °C; growth rate is fastest at 25 °C and absent at 37 °C; good growth occurs at 1–5 °C.</s><s>On R<sub>2</sub>A agar plates, grows at pH 6–8 and in the presence of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and for activities of alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, production of indole (tryptophan deaminase activity) and H<sub>2</sub>S, citrate utilization, and hydrolysis of urea, starch, gelatin and Tween 80.</s><s>Negative for activities of arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase, ornithine dihydrolase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, maltose and malic acid, but does not assimilate l-arabinose, citrate, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid or phenylacetic acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose, glycogen, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), penicillin G, tetracycline, chloramphenicol, rifampicin and trimethoprim (each 100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), but resistant to streptomycin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and cyclosporin A (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Growth in presence of kanamycin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) is delayed.</s><s>Q-10 is the major ubiquinone.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>Major polar lipids are sphingoglycolipids, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>Spermidine is the major polyamine.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 64.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BZ30<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22271<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.8959<sup>T</sup> =CIP 110136<sup>T</sup>) and was isolated from hydrocarbon-contaminated soil in Bozen, South Tyrol, Italy.</s></p></content></protolog>