<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12323_nm.20344" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20344" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20344" rank="species">Streptomyces lacticiproducens</organism><reference id="rid.12323"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces lacticiproducens sp. nov., a lactic acid-producing streptomycete isolated from the rhizosphere of tomato plants</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>35</fpage><lpage>39</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019125-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173013</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces lacticiproducens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces lacticiproducens</em> (lac.ti.ci.pro′du.cens. N.L. n. <em>acidum lacticum</em> lactic acid; L. part. adj. <em>producens</em> producing; N.L. part. adj. <em>lacticiproducens</em> producing lactic acid).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive actinomycete that forms a yellowish white aerial mycelium and greyish brown substrate mycelium.</s><s>Verticillate chains of cylindrical smooth-surfaced spores are produced.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on ISP 7.</s><s>Very good growth occurs on ISP 2, ISP 4 and potato dextrose agar; moderate growth on ISP 5 and glucose-asparagine agar; poor growth on Gause's synthetic agar media; no growth on ISP 3 or starch agar media.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is greyish brown on ISP 2, greenish yellow on ISP 4 and ISP 5, yellow on glucose-asparagine agar, yellowish white on Gause's synthetic agar and greyish yellow on potato dextrose agar.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-DAP (cell wall type I).</s><s>No inhibitory activity is observed against <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 6538, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> ATCC 6633 or <em>Candida albicans</em> ATCC 10231, but inhibitory activity is observed against <em>Penicillium citrinum</em> AS3.2788.</s><s>Melibiose, glucose, d-fructose, xylose, inositol and arabinose are utilized as sole carbon source.</s><s>Negative for production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GIMN4.001<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC M208214<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24800<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of tomato plants grown in Guangzhou, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.91 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>