<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4545_nm.2627" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2627" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2627" rank="species">Pseudomonas kilonensis</organism><reference id="rid.4545"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sikorski</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wackernagel</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas kilonensis sp. nov., a bacterium isolated from agricultural soil.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1549</fpage><lpage>1555</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491357</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas kilonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas kilonensis</i> (ki.lo.nen'sis. L. adj. <i>kilonensis</i> of Kiel, after <i>Civium Kilonensis</i>, the ancient Latin name of the town of Kiel, Germany)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from stationary culture of strain 520-20<sup>T</sup> are motile rods, 1.0-2.0 μm in length and about 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>The white-yellowish colonies on King B medium are smooth with regular margins and, after 2-3 d, produce a yellow diffusible pigment giving a light yellow-green fluorescence when irradiated with UV light (254 nm).</s><s>After 2-3 weeks, colonies on King B medium produce a dark brown pigment that colours the colony and the agar.</s><s>Results obtained with API20 NE strips indicate that strains have the following enzyme activities: hydrolysis (protease) and oxidase.</s><s>All other enzymic activities included in the API20 NE strips are negative.</s><s>Results obtained with API20 NE strips indicate that strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glucose, malate, mannitol and mannose.</s><s>All other substrates included in the API20 NE strips were not utilized.</s><s>Results obtained with API50 CH strips indicate that strains oxidize the following substrates: L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-fucose, galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, melibiose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>Results obtained with BIOLOG GN microplates indicate that strains oxidize the following substrates: acetic acid, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanyl-glycine, γ-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, bromosuccinic acid, DL-carnitine, citric acid, formic acid, D-fructose, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galactose, α-D-glucose, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycerol, glycyl L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, β-hydroxybutyric acid, χ-hydroxybutyric acid, phydroxyphenyl acetic acid, hydroxy-L-proline, inosine, <i>m</i>-inositol, α-ketoglutaric acid, DL-lactic acid, L-leucine, malonic acid, D-mannitol, D-mannose, methylpyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, L-proline, propionic acid, putrescine, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, L-serine, D-sorbitol, succinic acid, sucrose, D-trehalose, L-threonine, Tween 40, Tween 80, uridine and urocanic acid.</s><s>Oxidation of the other organic substrates included in BIOLOG GN microplates is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 520-20<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13647<sup>T</sup>=CFBP 5372<sup>T</sup>), isolated from agricultural soil near Kiel, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>