<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3224_nm.11778" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11778" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1372" rank="species">Bartonella schoenbuchii</organism><reference id="rid.3224"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dehio</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lanz</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pohl</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Behrens</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bermond</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Piémont</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pelz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sander</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bartonella schoenbuchii sp. nov., isolated from the blood of wild roe deer.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1557</fpage><lpage>1565</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bartonella schoenbuchii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bartonella schoenbuchii</i> (schoen.buch'i.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>schoenbuchii</i> from Schönbuch, a nature park near Tuübingen in south-west Germany where most of the roe deer analysed in this study were shot)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth obtained on Columbia agar base supplemented with 5% defibrinated sheep blood in a moist atmosphere containing 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Colonies appear in primary culture within 4-6 d as firm adherent, deeply invaginated, cauliflower-like colonies which upon passaging may switch to amore rapidly growing, shiny and smooth colony phenotype.</s><s>The Gram-negative, monopolar politrichous flagellated rods are approximately 1.2x0.5 μm, aerobic and negative for oxidase, indole, catalase and urea hydrolysis.</s><s>The code for preformed enzymes obtained in the RapID ANA II system is 000 671.</s><s>The biotype code using Rapid ID 32A was 0000 0737 05 or 0000 0337 05, depending on the strain analysed.</s><s>The major fatty acids are <i>cis</i>-11-octadecanoic acid (C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>), octadecanoic acid (C<sub>18:0</sub> and hexadecanoic acid (C<sub>16:0</sub>, similar as observed for other <i>Bartonella</i> species.</s><s>The four strains thus far isolated from the blood of healthy roe deer display phenotypic and genotypic differences but belong to a single new species.</s><s>This new species is distinguished from previously known <i>Bartonella</i> species by the total protein profiles in SDS-PAGE, the banding patterns in the ERIC-PCR, the <i>gltA</i> and 16S rRNA gene sequences, and by whole-DNA hybridization analysis.</s><s>Type strain is R1<sup>T</sup>, isolated from the blood of a 4-month-old female wild roe deer.</s><s>Deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures as NCTC 13165<sup>T</sup> and the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as DSM 13525<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>