<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1819_nm.4243" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4243" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4243" rank="species">Eubacterium coprostanoligenes</organism><reference id="rid.1819"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Freier</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beitz</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartman</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Eubacterium coprostanoligenes sp. nov., a cholesterol-reducing anaerobe.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>137</fpage><lpage>142</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-137</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123557</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium coprostanoligenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium coprostanoligenes</i> (co.pro.stan.ol.i' gen.es. L. adj. <i>coprostanoligenes</i>, producing coprostanol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The coccobacilloid cells are 0.5 to 0.7 μm in diameter and 0.7 to 1.0 μm long and occur singly and in pairs.</s><s>The cells are nonmotile, gram positive, and non-spore forming.</s><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic MLA plates are small, white, and circular with a powdery texture.</s><s>Growth and coprostanol production are optimal at pH 7.0 to 7.5 and at 35°C.</s><s>Growth and coprostanol production do not occur at pH 5.5 or 8.0 or at incubation temperatures of 25 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerotolerant anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Phosphatidylcholine is metabolized and is required for growth.</s><s>Cholesterol is reduced to coprostanol, but is not required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, and indole is not produced.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Esculin and indoxylacetate are hydrolyzed, and cells produce β-glucosidase.</s><s>Much acid is produced by the fermentation of amygdalin, lactose, and salicin.</s><s>L-Arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, mannose, and melibiose are weakly fermented.</s><s>Moderate amounts of H<sub>2</sub> and small amounts of CO<sub>2</sub> are produced.</s><s>Acetic, formic, and succinic acids are produced.</s><s>No alcohols are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA of the type strain, strain HL, has a G+C content of 41 mol%.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from anoxic material from a hog sewage lagoon in Ames, Iowa.</s><s>Strain HLT has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strain ATCC 51222<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>