<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6801_nm.5381" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5381" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5381" rank="species">Lactobacillus ingluviei</organism><reference id="rid.6801"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus ingluviei sp. nov., isolated from the intestinal tract of pigeons.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>133</fpage><lpage>136</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02206-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656164</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus ingluviei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus ingluviei</em> (in.glu′vi.ei. L. n. <em>ingluvies</em> crop sac; L. gen. n. <em>ingluviei</em> of a crop sac).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, very short, plump rods, rapidly decolorizing in the Gram-stain procedure.</s><s>Cells mostly occur singly or in pairs, and some appear to be slightly longer than others.</s><s>They are non-sporulating and catalase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are white and smooth or crumbly and dry.</s><s>Growth is enhanced under anaerobic conditions and also slightly in the presence of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>, compared with aerobic growth.</s><s>Better growth is obtained at 42 °C than at 37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25 °C and growth is poor at 30 °C.</s><s>The strains grow as non-haemolytic streptococcus-like colonies on Columbia blood agar with diameters of up to 0·5 mm.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, ribose, sucrose and d-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, glycogen, methyl α-d-glycoside, inositol, inulin, lactose, d-lyxose, mannitol, methyl α-d-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, trehalose, d-turanose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>Acidification of aesculin, gluconate (weak reaction), d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose and d-raffinose is variable.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 49 mol% and the characteristic tDNA-PCR fingerprint is composed of fragments with lengths of 162·5, 176·5, 185·5 and 255·2 bp, as determined by fluorescent capillary electrophoresis.</s><s>The habitat is pigeon crop and intestines.</s><s>The type strain is strain KR3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 20380<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 45722<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>