<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6292_nm.9179" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9179" rank="genus">Oribaculum</organism><reference id="rid.6292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oribaculum catoniae gen. nov., sp. nov.; Catonella morbi gen. nov., sp. nov.; Hallella seregens gen. nov., sp. nov.; Johnsonella ignava gen. nov., sp. nov.; and Dialister pneumosintes gen. nov., comb. nov., nom. rev., Anaerobic gram-negative bacilli from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186083</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Oribaculum</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Oribaculum</i> (0.ri.ba'cu.lum. L. n. <i>os</i>, <i>oris</i>, mouth; L. neut. n. <i>baculum</i>, stick, rod; N. L. neut. n. <i>Oribaculum</i>, mouth rod, because the organism was first isolated from the human mouth)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Oribaculum</i> cells are obligately anaerobic, gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporing rods that ferment carbohydrates and produce major to moderate (usually major) amounts of propionic acid and moderate amounts of acetic, succinic, and lactic acids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids in cells grown in PYG broth are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, and iso-C<sub>13:0</sub> (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i><i>Oribaculum catoniae</i></i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type species is 49 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus can be differentiated from phenotypically similar taxa by the G+C content of its DNA, its production of large amounts of propionic acid in PYG cultures, and its distinctive pattern of cellular fatty acids.</s></p></content></protolog>