<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6657_nm.11361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11361" rank="species">Modestobacter versicolor</organism><reference id="rid.6657"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potrafka</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Pichel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Modestobacter versicolor sp. nov., an actinobacterium from biological soil crusts that produces melanins under oligotrophy, with emended descriptions of the genus Modestobacter and Modestobacter multiseptatus Mevs et al. 2000</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2014</fpage><lpage>2020</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64932-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766865</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Modestobacter versicolor</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Modestobacter versicolor</em> (ver.si.co′lor. L. masc. adj. <em>versicolor</em> that changes its colour, of changeable colour, of various colours, particoloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are dark brown on oligotrophic medium and pink to white on copiotrophic medium, 1–4 mm in diameter, convex, entire, smooth to rugose and slightly mucoid.</s><s>Cells are short, small rods (straight, lightly curved, irregular or even tapering), often developing into multiseptate cells, occurring singly or in pairs, sometimes remaining aggregated and only rarely forming filaments longer than several cells (Fig. 3).</s><s>Single rods are 0.5–1.0×1.0–3.0 μm.</s><s>Short filaments are up to 7.0 μm long.</s><s>Septation is transversal (orthogonal to the long cellular axis) and apical cells may resemble buds.</s><s>Motility is variable, by means of polar flagellation.</s><s>Growth is observed at 4–30 °C (but not at 37 °C) and pH 5–9, with optimum growth at 25 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Produces copious melanins under oligotrophic conditions.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl at concentrations less than 3 %.</s><s>Cells are positive for catalase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, phosphatase, urease and lipase, but negative for oxidase, gelatinase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and phenylalanine deaminase.</s><s>Negative for methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and indole tests.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein and aesculin, but not cellulose or starch.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S gas and cannot grow on DNase or Simmons' citrate test plates.</s><s>Utilizes a wide variety of sugars, low-molecular-mass organic acids and amino acids and all four nitrogenous bases.</s><s>Dinitrogen fixer.</s><s>Respiratory quinones and cell-wall peptidoglycan, fatty acid and polar lipid compositions are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CP153-2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1040<sup>T</sup> =DSM 16678<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a biological soil crust.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73±2.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>