<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5091_nm.6590" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6590" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6590" rank="species">Dactylosporangium matsuzakiense</organism><reference id="rid.5091"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amano</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Totsugawa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niwa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inouye</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niida</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Studies on a new aminoglycoside antibiotic, dactimicin. I. Producing organism and fermentation.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>924</fpage><lpage>930</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7192278</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dactylosporangium matsuzakiense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Morphology</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of strain SF-2052 are compact, tough and somewhat leathery.</s><s>Vegetative mycelia are long, irregularly branched, twisted and penetrating into the agar.</s><s>Fragmentation of hyphae does usually not occur both on agar and in submerged condition.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerial mycelium is not formed on any of the media used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SF-2052 is characterized by the formation of finger-shaped sporangia.</s><s>Sporangia are formed abundantly on inorganic salts-starch agar and sometimes on glycerol-asparagine agar, tyrosine agar and oatmeal agar.</s><s>They appear after 10~15 days of incubation at 28°C singly or in clusters on surface of agar media (Plate 1).</s><s>Sporangia are 0.9-1.4 by 4.0-6.0 It in size, and are formed on short sporangiophores (0.5- 1.5 μ) which emerge from the vegetative hyphae.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Under the scanning electron microscope a cluster of sporangia can be vividly observed on the background of vegetative mycelia as shown in Plate 2.</s><s>Each sporangium contains usually three spores, rarely four, arranged always in a single row inside a sporangium.</s><s>The naked sporangiospores are shown in Plate 3, which was fortunately taken when the sporangial membrane was broken.</s><s>Spores are cylindrical, others oblong, and are 0.8~1.3 by 1.1~1.6 μ in size.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The spore release was observed by flooding the surface of sporangia-formed cultures with sterile water or soil extract solution.</s><s>Spores are motile, but there is a time lag (up to 30 minutes) before they became highly active.</s><s>While the motile spore could be observed as vigorous swimmers, flagella staining was not successful as yet.</s><s>Formation of globose bodies was not clearly observed in strain SF-2052.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural and Physiological Characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics on various media were observed during the cultivation of strain SF-2052 at 28°C for 2-3 weeks, and the results are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Aerial mycelium and soluble pigments (except for tyrosine agar) were not formed in any of the media tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature ranges from 25 to 35°C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 45°C, minimal growth at 15°C and 42°C.</s><s>Sodium chloride tolerance of strain SF-2052 is very low, and it does not grow even in 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>Other physiological properties including utilization of carbon sources are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemical Analysis of Cell Constituents</s></p><p class="description"><s>Analysis of cell wall hydrolysates by paper chromatography demonstrated the presence of 3-hydroxy-diaminopimelic acid, which gave the same greenish color with ninhydrin reagent as diaminopimelic acid (DAP) but moved more slowly than meso-DAP.</s><s>In addition to 3-hydroxy-DAP, the hydrolysates also contained large amounts of muramic acid, glutamic acid, glycine, alanine and a trace of meso-DAP as the amino acid composition.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Whole cell hydrolysates contained xylose, glucose, mannose, galactose and glucosamine as the major carbohydrates, and a trace of arabinose.</s><s>Qualitative differences of carbohydrate composition were not found between cell wall and whole cell as shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Consequently, strain SF-2052 is assigned to cell wall type II and to whole cell sugar pattern D according to the classification of LECHEVALIER et al.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comparisons with Known Species</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SF-2052, because of its formation of finger-shaped sporangia and motile spores as well as cell wall composition, can doubtlessly be assigned to the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> THIEMANN.</s></p><p class="description"><s>THIEMANN have described two species, <i>Dactylosporangium aurantiacum</i> and <i>D. thailandense</i>.</s><s>Thereafter, <i>D. variesporum</i> and <i>D. salmoneum</i>, which have been reported to produce capreomycins and a new polyether antibiotic CP-44,161, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comparative studies of strain SF-2052 with these four species of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> showed that strain SF-2052 is a new species by the reasons described below: <i>D. salmoneum</i> can be clearly differentiated from strain SF-2052 in that the color of growth is cream to salmon, while that of strain SF-2052 is orange. <i>D. variesporum</i> produces reddish orange soluble pigment on yeast extract-malt extract agar and sucrose-nitrate agar, whereas no soluble pigments on the same media are observed in strain SF-2052.</s><s>In addition, the best medium for formation of sporangia is yeast extract-malt extract agar in <i>D. variesporum</i>, while that of strain SF-2052 is inorganic salts-starch agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>With respect to the growth color (orange) and the lack of distinctive soluble pigments, strain SF-2052 is similar to <i>D. aurantiacum</i> and <i>D. thailandense</i>.</s><s>Therefore, standard strains of these two species were compared with strain SF-2052 by simultaneous cultivation, and the results are shown in Tables 1 and 2.</s><s>The growth colors of these three strains are all orange by rough observation, but are different each other in details as shown in Table 1. <i>D. aurantiacum</i> and <i>D. thailandense</i> form abundant sporangia on Ca-malate agar, whereas strain SF-2052 forms no or only trace of sporangia on the same medium.</s><s>Furthermore, <i>D. aurantiacum</i> and strain SF-2052 differ in physiological properties such as gelatin liquefaction and nitrate reduction. <i>D. thailandense</i> grows moderately on potato plug, but strain SF-2052 does not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In view of the above-described characteristics and its ability of producing dactimicin, strain SF-2052 is considered a new species of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> and named <i>Dactylosporangium matsuzakiense </i> sp. nov.</s><s>SHOMURA et NIIDA from the place where the soil was collected.</s><s>The type strain, SF-2052, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, and in Fermentation Research Institute, Japan, and accessioned as ATCC 31570 and as FERM-P 4670, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation of Dactimicin</s></p><p class="description"><s>A typical time-course of dactimicin production in a 300-liter fermentor is shown in Fig. 2.</s><s>As is the case with the production of many secondary metabolites including antibiotics, the synthesis of dactimicin also begins toward the end of the trophophase.</s><s>The production of dactimicin was maximum at 98 hours after inoculation, reaching 70 μg/ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because of the unstability of dactimicin in alkaline condition, the pH control during fermentation was indispensable.</s><s>The pH was continuously kept below pH 7.0 from 50 hours corresponding with the start of antibiotic production to the end of fermentation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the fermentation by <i>Dactylosporangium</i> strain is that there is a time lag in the course of seed preparations, and that a large inoculum size is necessary.</s><s>In the course of production, however, no difference is recognized as compared with that by <i>Streptomyces</i> strain.</s></p></content></protolog>