<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.373_nm.3882" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3882" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3882" rank="species">Clostridium acetireducens</organism><reference id="rid.373"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Örlygsson</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krooneman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschal</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium acetireducens sp. nov., a novel amino-acid-oxidizing, acetate-reducing anaerobic bacterium.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>454</fpage><lpage>459</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-454</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium acetireducens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium acetireducens</i> (a.ce.ti.re.dúcens. L. neut. n <i>acetum</i>, vinegar; L. pres. parti. <i>reducens</i>, reducing; L. neut. adj. <i>acetireducans</i>, vinegar or acetic acid reducing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristic of the species is its ability to use acetate as an electron acceptor during growth on leucine, valine, isoleucine, and alanine.</s><s>The reduced product is butyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. acetireducens</i> cells are strictly anaerobic, straight rods that are 1 μm in diameter and 6 μm long.</s><s>The organism is nonmotile, and no flagella or spores are observed.</s><s>Gram reaction positive, as confirmed by electron micrographs showing a thin S-layer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0 to 8.2, and the optimal pH is 6.4 to 7.6.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 30 to 45°C, and the optimal temperature is 39 to 43°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>C. acetireducens</i> requires yeast extract for growth.</s><s>It grows on leucine, valine, isoleucine, and alanine only in the presence of acetate.</s><s>Other substrates utilized are peptone (a pancreatic digest of casein), serine, threonine, α-ketobutyrate, α-ketoisocaproate, α-keto-3-methylvalerate, and α-ketoisovalerate. <i>C. acetireducens</i> does not grow on saccharides, citrate, succinate, propionate, H<sub>2</sub>-acetate, ethanol, or other amino acids, and it cannot use fumarate, sulfate, sulfite, nitrate, nitrite, or oxygen as an electron acceptor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain 30A (= DSM 7310) is the type strain of <i>C. acetireducens</i>.</s><s>G+C content of <i>C. acetireducens</i> is 28.5 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p></content></protolog>