<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1597_nm.10992" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10992" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10992" rank="species">Rhizobium lusitanum</organism><reference id="rid.1597"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Valverde</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Igual</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peix</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cervantes</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium lusitanum sp. nov. a bacterium that nodulates Phaseolus vulgaris</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2631</fpage><lpage>2637</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64402-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082403</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium lusitanum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium lusitanum</em> (lu.si.ta′num. L. neut. adj. <em>lusitanum</em> of <em>Lusitania</em>, the Roman name of Portugal, where the strains reported in this study were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, as for the other species of the genus.</s><s>Colonies are small, pearl white on YMA at 28 °C, which is the optimal growth temperature.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7–7.5.</s><s>Strains may grow between 10 and 37 °C, pH 5 and 8 and weakly up to 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Denitrification is carried out by the strains from this study.</s><s>The strains produce <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease and hydrolyse aesculin in the API 20NE system.</s><s>They also produce <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-arabinosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-galactosidaminidases, <em>β</em>-cellobiases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-xylosidases, <em>α</em>-maltosidases and <em>β</em>-glucosaminidases using chromogenic <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl substrates.</s><s>They do not produce indole, arginine dihydrolase or gelatinase in API 20NE.</s><s>They use glucose, melezitose, ethanol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, l-arabinose, mannose, fructose, galactose, l-rhamnose, xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, sucrose, cellobiose, raffinose, melibiose, trehalose, salicin, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, malate, gluconate and citrate as carbon sources.</s><s>They grow on l-histidine, aspartate, glutamate and betaine as carbon and nitrogen sources.</s><s>They grow weakly on l-lysine, xylitol and l-sorbose.</s><s>They do not grow on caprate, adipate, phenylacetate, glucuronate, propionate, valine or l-alanine.</s><s>All strains are resistant to ampicillin, erythromycin, cloxacillin, penicillin, cefuroxime and oxytetracycline.</s><s>They do not grow in the presence of ciprofloxacin, polymyxin B or gentamicin.</s><s>Growth is weak in the presence of neomycin.</s><s>The G+C content of strain P1-7<sup>T</sup> is 65.15 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P1-7<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22705<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7016<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from effective nodules of <em>Phaseolus vulgaris</em> in Portugal.</s></p></content></protolog>