<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3574_nm.9856" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9856" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9856" rank="species">Arenibacter palladensis</organism><reference id="rid.3574"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shevchenko</surname><given-names>L.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenibacter palladensis sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium isolated from the green alga Ulva fenestrata, and emended description of the genus Arenibacter</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>160</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63893-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403881</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenibacter palladensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenibacter palladensis</em> (pal.la.den′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>palladensis</em> pertaining to Pallada Bay, where the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells range from 0·4 to 0·5 μm in width and from 1·6 to 2·3 μm in length, and move by means of gliding.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are 2–4 mm in diameter, circular with entire edges and dark orange in colour.</s><s>Growth is observed at 4–38 °C.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 23–25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse agar, casein, gelatin, alginate, starch, Tween 20, DNA, urea, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Forms acid from d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose and d-sucrose, but not from l-arabinose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, citrate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose and d-mannose, but not mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, malonate or citrate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction), arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are not produced.</s><s>According to the results of testing with the Biolog GN2 Microplate system, the type strain utilizes dextrin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, methylpyruvate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-glutamic acid, l-threonine and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 40 or 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, psicose, l-rhamnose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, uronic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids in the type strain are straight-chain saturated and unsaturated and branched-chain unsaturated fatty acids C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (15·0 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (8·7 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (12·7 %), iso-C<sub>17</sub> 3-OH (17·4 %) and summed feature 3 (11·1 %; comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39–40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KMM 3961<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21972<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108849<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the green alga <em>U. fenestrata</em>, collected in Pallada Bay, Sea of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>