<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7082_nm.3604" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3604" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3604" rank="species">Desulfofustis glycolicus</organism><reference id="rid.7082"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Friedrich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic positions of Desulfofustis glycolicus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Syntrophobotulus glycolicus gen. nov., sp. nov., two new strict anaerobes growing with glycolic acid.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1065</fpage><lpage>1069</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1065</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfofustis glycolicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfofustis glycolicus</i> (gly.co'li.cus. M. L. n. <i>acidum glycolicum</i>, glycolic acid, glycolicus, referring to glycolic acid as the key substrate of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria, straight to slightly curved, 2.0 to 4.5 by 0.55 μm in size, occurring typically as single cells.</s><s>Motile by one subterminally inserted flagellum, no spore formation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic bacteria, growing chemotrophically by oxidation of glycolate, glyoxylate, L-lactate, L-malate, fumarate, succinate, yeast extract, or hydrogen (in the presence of carbon dioxide and traces of acetate), with sulfate as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Other substrates (formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, valerate, caproate, 3-methylbutyrate, fructose, glucose, oxalate, pimelate, glutarate, glycolaldehyde, glyceraldehyde, simple aliphatic alcohols, betaine, choline, cysteine, triethanolamine, glycine, indol, and benzoate) not oxidized.</s><s>Sulfite and elemental sulfur reduced with glycolate as electron donor, thiosulfate or nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Cells contain menaquinone-5(H<sub>2</sub>), desulforubidin, and cytochromes b and c, no desulfoviridin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Organic substrates other than glycolate are typically incompletely oxidized, but part of acetyl intermediates may be oxidized, as well, to various extents.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range, 6.7 to 8.3; optimum pH, 7.3.</s><s>Temperature range, 15 to 37°C; optimum temperature, 28°C.</s><s>Growth optimal in marine medium with 340 mM NaCl-14 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth possible also in brackish-water medium with one-third of this salt concentration; no growth in freshwater medium.</s><s>DNA base ratio, 56.2 ± 0.1 mol% G+C (determined by high-pressure liquid chromatography analysis).</s><s>Habitat, anoxic marine sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain, PerGlyS (DSM 9705), deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen.</s></p></content></protolog>