<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8756_nm.13349" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13349" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13349" rank="species">Halomonas caseinilytica</organism><reference id="rid.8756"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huo</surname><given-names>Y.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>X.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas caseinilytica sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a saline lake on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1259</fpage><lpage>1262</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65381-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450724</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas caseinilytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas caseinilytica</em> (ca.se.i.ni.ly′ti.ca. N.L. n. <em>caseinum</em> casein; Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lytica</em> dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>caseinilytica</em> casein-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, short rods or oval in shape, 0.8–2.0×0.4–0.6 μm, and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies on complex agar medium are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, elevated and light yellow after 2 days.</s><s>Moderately halophilic.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>The total salts concentration for growth is 0.5–15 % (w/v), with an optimum at 3–5 %.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–9.0 and 4–48 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0–8.0 and 30 °C).</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate, nitrite or fumarate.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar, but not on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Produces exopolysaccharide and poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, Tween 20 and tyrosine are hydrolysed.</s><s>DNA, starch and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for gluconate oxidation, indole production, phenylalanine deamination, lecithinase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease.</s><s>Positive for lysine decarboxylase, ONPG, in the methyl red test and for fermentation of d-glucose.</s><s>Reduces selenite and nitrate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is formed from thiosulfate or l-cysteine.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, rhamnose, l-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, acetate, citrate, fumarate, gluconate, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, l-cysteine, ethanol, formate, malonate, l-methionine, ribose, sorbose and starch.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, rhamnose, l-sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, nitrofurantoin, polymyxin B, rifampicin and tetracycline, but not to ampicillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, erythromycin, penicillin, novobiocin, nystatin or streptomycin.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>/C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.0±0.1 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AJ261<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.6773<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14802<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from a salt lake on the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, China.</s></p></content></protolog>