<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1837_nm.8576" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8576" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8576" rank="species">Enterococcus italicus</organism><reference id="rid.1837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fortina</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ricci</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mora</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manachini</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Molecular analysis of artisanal Italian cheeses reveals Enterococcus italicus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1717</fpage><lpage>1721</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63190-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388734</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus italicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus italicus</em> (i.ta′li.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>italicus</em> from Italy, where the bacterium was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming, catalase-negative, non-pigmented, Gram-positive cocci that occur in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Colonies are whitish-grey, circular and smooth, with entire margins; 1 mm in diameter after 3 days growth on M17 glucose agar.</s><s>Growth is enhanced slightly by cultivation in a 5 % CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere and is optimal at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 42 °C, but is weak at 10 °C.</s><s>The ability to grow at 45 °C is variable among the strains.</s><s>Strains grow at pH 9·6 and in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>A few strains are positive for growth in 6 % NaCl; no growth is seen in 6·5 % NaCl.</s><s>The strains do not grow on kanamycin/aesculin/azide agar, show <em>α</em>-haemolysis on blood agar and are able to grow in skimmed-milk medium, where they cause clotting within 48 h incubation.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to vancomycin.</s><s>Homofermentative, producing lactic acid and no gas.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside (often delayed), <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, salicin, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose and starch.</s><s>Weak reactions can occur on cellobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, amygdalin, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Strain-dependent reactions are observed with mannitol (4/7 strains), <em>β</em>-gentiobiose (3/7 strains), d-tagatose (3/7 strains), arbutin (3/7 strains) and sorbitol (5/7 strains).</s><s>Positive results are obtained in API tests for acetoin production, aesculin hydrolysis, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Strains are negative for hippurate hydrolysis, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 39·9 to 41·1 mol%, as determined by melting temperature.</s><s>The strains form a distinct relatedness group, as determined by DNA–DNA hybridization.</s><s>The strains can also be differentiated from the other species of <em>Enterococcus</em> by their unique intergenic transcribed spacer profile and the sequence of their 16S rRNA genes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from dairy products in Piedmont, Italy.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 15952<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22039<sup>T</sup>)</s></p></content></protolog>