<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6920_nm.2912" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2912" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2912" rank="species">Psychromonas marina</organism><reference id="rid.6920"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kawasaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hishinuma</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nodasaka</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yumoto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychromonas marina sp. nov., a novel halophilic, facultatively psychrophilic bacterium isolated from the coast of the Okhotsk Sea.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1455</fpage><lpage>1459</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01919-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Psychromonas marina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Psychromonas marina</i> (ma.ri'na. L. adj. <i>marina</i> of the sea, marine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are roD-shaped (1.5-2.0x0.8-1.2 μm), Gram-negative and have a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex and colourless with an entire margin.</s><s>The species is positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>It ferments D-glucose, D-fructose, D-maltose, sucrose, D-xylose, D-mannitol and D-galactose ; gas production is not detected during fermentation.</s><s>Growth is not observed in the absence of NaCl in the culture medium; however, growth occurs in a medium supplemented with 3-5% NaCl, but not in a medium with salinity higher than 7% NaCl.</s><s>Does not require an organic nitrogen source, amino acids or vitamins for growth.</s><s>Susceptible to the vibriostatic compound O/129 (10 and 150 μg).</s><s>Growth occurs between 0 and 25 °C, but not at temperatures higher than 26 °C.</s><s>The organism is positive for the production of H<sub>2</sub>S, the ONPG test and the reduction of NO<sub>3</sub> to NO<sub>2</sub>, but negative for indole production.</s><s>It hydrolyses starch, DNA, alginic acid, tributyrin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, but not casein, chitin or gelatin.</s><s>The organism utilizes D-glucose, glycerol, D-fructose, lactose, D-maltose, sucrose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl glucosamine, dgalactose and D-cellobiose as sole carbon and energy sources for growth, but not L-arabinose, D-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sorbitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-rhamnose or trehalose.</s><s>The whole-cell fatty acids consist predominantly of C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, C<sub>18:1</sub>, C<sub>14:1</sub> and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>The polyunsaturated fatty acid C<sub>22:6</sub> is also present (1.6%).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43.5 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The type strain is strain 4-22<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10501<sup>T</sup>=IAM 14899<sup>T</sup>= NCIMB 13792<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>