<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7764" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7764" rank="order">Chlamydiales</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the order <i>Chlamydiales</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>We emend the description of the order <i>Chlamydiales</i> to include obligately intracellular bacteria that have a chlamydia-like developmental cycle of replication, Gram-negative or Gram-positive infectious EBs (elementary bodies), &#x003E;80% 16s rRNA gene sequence identity), and/or &#x003E;80% 23s rRNA gene sequence identity with <i>Chlamydiales</i> spp. Currently, the order <i>Chlamydiales</i> includes the families <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> and <i>Simkaniaceae</i>, which have Gram-negative EBs, and <i>Parachlamydiaceae</i>, which has variable Gram staining of EBs. The EB form has an inner and an outer membrane and a variable periplasmic space. EBs are round, highly electron-dense, 0.2-0.6 μm in diameter, and metabolically inactive. The chlamydial cycle of replication is initiated when EBs are endocytosed by eukaryotic cells. During this stage, EBs reside within cytoplasmic inclusions where they differentiate by enlarging to 0.6-1.5 μm, becoming less electron-dense RBs (reticulate bodies), and undergoing binary fission. Inclusions are unique vacuoles that do not undergo acidification or lysosomal fusion. Inclusions that have been studied in detail do not correspond to canonical endocytic vesicles, being essentially dissociated from the endocytic pathway and having some similarities with recycling endosomes (Hackstadt et al., 1997; van Ooij et al., 1997; Taraska et al., 1996). Over a period of days, RBs condense into EBs and chlamydiae are released by host cell rupture or by fusion of the inclusion membrane with the host cell plasma membrane. No alternate host vector is required. Many species of <i>Chlamydiales</i> coexist in an asymptomatic state within specific hosts, and it is widely believed that these hosts provide a natural reservoir for these species. The type genus for <i>Chlamydiales</i> is <i>Chlamydia</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>