<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9496_nm.14648" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14648" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14648" rank="species">Pantoea anthophila</organism><reference id="rid.9496"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engelbeen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pantoea vagans sp. nov., Pantoea eucalypti sp. nov., Pantoea deleyi sp. nov. and Pantoea anthophila sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2339</fpage><lpage>2345</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009241-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620357</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pantoea anthophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pantoea anthophila</em> (an.tho′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>anthos</em> flower; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>anthophila</em> flower-loving, pertaining to the source of isolation of known strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0.9×1.2–2.5 μm) occurring singly or in pairs, motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are beige to yellow, round, convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Acetoin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are produced.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and urease are not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose and d-arabitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C within 3–6 days: l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltotriose, l-rhamnose, inositol, aesculin, glycogen, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, sucrose, glycerol, succinate, fumarate, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, l-proline, d- and l-alanine, l-serine, malonic acid, Tweens 40 and 80 and citric acid.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 28 °C within 3–6 days: erythritol, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, amygdalin, inulin, raffinose, lactose, lactulose, xylitol, turanose, d-tagatose, l-arabitol, l-tartrate, 2-ketoglutarate, 5-ketogluconate, l-fucose, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl-d-glucopyranose, d-tartrate, l-tryptophan, l-histidine, glutarate, malonate, propionate, gentiobiose and l-tyrosine.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 57.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 2558<sup>T</sup> (=BD 871<sup>T</sup> =NCPPB 1682<sup>T</sup>), isolated from <em>Impatiens balsamina</em> in India.</s><s>Strains belonging to this species have been isolated from flowering shrubs.</s></p></content></protolog>