<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4070_nm.6341" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6341" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6341" rank="species">Mycobacterium doricum</organism><reference id="rid.4070"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Piersimoni</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montoya-Burgos</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reischl</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giacometti</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Emler</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium doricum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2007</fpage><lpage>2012</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760941</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium doricum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium doricum</i> (do'ri.cum. L. adj. <i>doricum</i> of Dorica civitas, the ancient name of the Italian city of Ancona, from where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped and alcohol-acid-fast.</s><s>Growth is achieved on Lowenstein-Jensen medium within about 2 weeks at 25-37 °C.</s><s>The colonies, which are strongly yellow-pigmented, are scotochromogenic and smooth.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reductase, tellurite reductase and urease, but negative for niacin, b-glucosidase, 68 °C catalase, Tween 80 hydrolysis and 3-d arylsulfatase.</s><s>Produces less than 45 mm of foam in a semiquantitative catalase test.</s><s>Does not grow on MacConkey agar or on media supplemented with sodium chloride, <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoate, thiacetazone, hydroxylamine, isoniazid or oleate.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited on medium containing thiophene-2-carboxylic acid.</s><s>The strain is susceptible to amikacin, azithromycin, clarithromycin, ciprofloxacin, clofazimine, ethambutol, isoniazid, ofloxacin, rifabutin, rifampicin, sparfloxacin and streptomycin.</s><s>The lipid composition is characterized by the presence of amycolates, ketomycolates and wax esters.</s><s>The HPLC profile of mycolic acid bromophenacyl esters is unique.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is composed of hexadecanoic acid (27%), hexadecenoic acids (13%), octadecenoic acids (26%) and tuberculostearic acid (16%).</s><s>Two alcohols, C18:0 (13%) and C20:0 (1%), are also found.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66.5 mol%.</s><s>The 16S rDNA sequence demonstrates that strain FI-13295<sup>T</sup> is phylogenetically related (sharing a similar sequence profile) to the thermotolerant species <i>M. thermoresistibile</i>, <i>M. flavescens</i> and <i>M. smegmatis</i>, and to <i>M. tusciae</i> which, in contrast, do not present the insertion pattern characteristic of thermotolerant mycobacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain FI-13295<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44339<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106867<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>