<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5200_nm.6296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6296" rank="species">Gordonia namibiensis</organism><reference id="rid.5200"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brandão</surname><given-names>P.F.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maldonado</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bull</surname><given-names>A.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordonia namibiensis sp. nov., a novel nitrile metabolising actinomycete recovered from an African sand.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>510</fpage><lpage>515</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11876358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordonia namibiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gordonia namibiensis</i> (na.mi.bien'sis. N.L. adj. <i>namibiensis</i> referring to Namibia, the country of origin of the soil sample from which the strains were recovered)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, slightly acid-alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycetes which form short rods and coccoid elements and produce orange or red-pink coloured colonies on glucose yeast extract agar.</s><s>Neither aerial hyphae nor diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>The organisms utilize D(–) arabinose, D(+) cellobiose, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol (weak), ethanol, D(–) fucose, D(–) fructose, D(+) galactose, glycerol (weak), glycogen, D(+) glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D(+) lactose, D(+) maltose, D(+) mannose, D(+) melezitose, D(+) melibiose, α-methyl- D-glucoside, raffinose, D(–) ribose, D(+) trehalose, D(+) xylose, xylitol, <i>iso</i>-butanol (weak), n-propanol (all at 1%, w/v), acetate, fumarate, gluconate, m-hydroxybenzoic acid, p-hydroxybenzoic acid, H-malate, pyruvate and succinate (0.1%, w/v) as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth, but not adonitol, inulin, salicin, D(+) sucrose, <i>iso</i>-amyl alcohol (all at 1%, w/v), benzoate or butyrate (at 0.1%, w/v).</s><s>Acetamide, gelatin and L-glutamate are used as sole carbon and nitrogen sources, but not L-alanine, L-aspartic acid, L-leucine, monooleic ethanolamine, L-proline, L-phenylalanine, urea, uric acid or L-valine (all at 0.1%, w/v).</s><s>The organisms grow in the presence of oleic acid (at 0.1%, w/v) and zinc chloride (at 0.001%, w/v) and from 20 °C to 40 °C and between pH 4.5 and 9.5.</s><s>The microorganisms were isolated from a Kalahari sand, Central Namibia.</s><s>The type strain is NAM-BN063A<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44568<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13780<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain NAM-BN063B (=DSM 44569=NCIMB 13781) gave identical results to strain NAM-BN063A<sup>T</sup> in the phenotypic tests, except for the colony morphological characteristics on glucose yeast extract agar and its inability to grow in mineral medium supplemented with 0.1% (v/v) acetonitrile.</s><s>The two strains can also be differentiated by their colony colour which is orange for NAM-BN063A<sup>T</sup> and red-pink for strain NAM-BN063B.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Gordonia namibiensis</i> strain NAM-BN063A<sup>T</sup> was able to grow in mineral salts medium containing acetonitrile or benzonitrile at 0.1% (v/v) as the sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>In contrast, strain NAM-BN063B grew only in mineral salts medium containing 0.1% (v/v) benzonitrile.</s><s>Both strains were capable of growing in CMM supplemented with 0.2% (v/v) butyronitrile and valeronitrile but could not grow on propionitrile, succinonitrile or acrylonitrile.</s><s>Biotransformation tests have shown the presence of a nitrile-hydratase/amidase metabolic pathway in both strains of <i>G. namibiensis</i> (BRANDÃO and BULL, unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In recent years the metabolic diversity of gordoniae has been recognised and their potential deployment for bioremediation explored.</s><s>For example, <i>G. aichiensis</i> (FINKEL'SHTEIN et al., 1999), <i>G. amicalis</i> (KIM et al., 2000), <i>G. desulfuricans</i> (KIM et al., 1999) and <i>Gordonia</i> sp. strain CYSK1 (RHEE et al., 1998) possess desulphurisation pathways for the degradation of benzothiophenes in diesel fuels; <i>G. alkanivorans</i> is able to grow in hexadecane (KUMMER et al., 1999); <i>G. polyisoprenivorans</i> has the ability to degrade natural rubber substrates (LINOS et al., 1999, 2001); <i>G. nitida</i> can metabolise alkylpyridines, 3-ethylpyridine and 3-methylpyridine (YOON et al., 2000); while strains of <i>G. terrae</i> can grow on ethyl t-butyl ether and catalyse co-metabolic conversions of methyl t-butyl ether and t-amyl methyl ether to t-butyl alcohol and t-amyl alcohol, respectively (HERNANDEZPEREZ et al., 2001).</s><s>In addition to their bioremediation potential, gordoniae are being assessed for commercially useful synthetic activities.</s><s>DE MIGUEL et al. (2000) isolated a strain labelled "<i>G. jacobaea</i>" which accumulated several carotenoids and is a promising candidate for the industrial production of canthaxanthin, while an acetylene utilising strain of <i>G. bronchialis</i> has been screened for the production of fine chemicals (KYRIACOU et al., 1997).</s><s>Thus, the discovery of nitrile metabolising microorganisms belonging to the genus <i>Gordonia</i>, such as <i>G. namibiensis</i> NAM-BN063A<sup>T</sup> and NAM-BN063B, is another significant step in the search for novel biocatalysts that can have applications in the synthesis of important chemicals and bioremediation of toxic wastes.</s></p></content></protolog>