<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1865_nm.9612" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9612" rank="genus">Tetrathiobacter</organism><reference id="rid.1865"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bagchi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandal</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dam</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel mesophilic, neutrophilic, tetrathionate-oxidizing, facultatively chemolithotrophic betaproteobacterium isolated from soil from a temperate orchard in Jammu and Kashmir, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1779</fpage><lpage>1787</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63595-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166666</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tetrathiobacter</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tetrathiobacter</em> (Tet.ra.thi.o.bac′ter. Gr. adj. <em>tetra</em> four; Gr. n. <em>thium</em> sulfur; N.L. masc. n. <em>bacter</em> from Gr. neut. n. <em>bakterion</em> a rod; N.L. masc. n. <em>Tetrathiobacter</em> a tetrathionate-oxidizing bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-flagellated, oval to coccoid-shaped bacteria occurring singly or in pairs, chains, branched chains or clusters.</s><s>Capsular coverings are present around cells of some strains.</s><s>Cells are approximately 1·0–1·8 μm long and 0·6–1·5 μm broad.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, smooth, opaque and creamy white and develop central dark mounds that sometimes turn rusty red.</s><s>Growth is observed between 10 and 42 °C and between pH 4·5 and 8·5.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and urease activities are observed, but not gelatinase activity.</s><s>Facultatively chemolithoautotrophic organisms that use thiosulfate or tetrathionate as electron and energy source.</s><s>Thiocyanate, soluble sulfides, elemental sulfur, sulfite and arsenite are not utilized as chemolithotrophic substrates.</s><s>The DNA G+C content, as determined by HPLC, is 54–55·2 mol%.</s><s>The genus belongs to the ‘<em>Betaproteobacteria</em>’ and is phylogenetically closest to <em>Alcaligenes defragrans</em>, <em>Taylorella equigenitalis</em>, <em>Pelistega europaea</em> and <em>Pigmentiphaga kullae</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis</em>.</s><s>Until further taxa are identified, the genus comprises a single species.</s></p></content></protolog>