<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12428_nm.21259" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21259" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21259" rank="species">Chryseobacterium chaponense</organism><reference id="rid.12428"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fallschissel</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Avendaño-Herrera</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium chaponense sp. nov., isolated from farmed Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>497</fpage><lpage>501</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022004-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20363929</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium chaponense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium chaponense</em> (cha.po.nen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>chaponense</em> pertaining to Lake Chapo, Chile, from which the Atlantic salmon harbouring the two isolates was obtained).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, aerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods ∼1×2 μm.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs after 48 h of incubation at 11–36 °C on nutrient agar, R2A agar and tryptic soy agar (Oxoid).</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey's agar (Oxoid) at 28 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at temperatures below 4 °C and above 37 °C.</s><s>Cells grow in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges when grown on nutrient agar.</s><s>A yellow pigment (KOH test-negative) is non-diffusible and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, trehalose, d-mannitol, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Negative for indole production, hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine, hydrogen sulphide production and urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG) activities.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: d-glucose, maltose, acetate, propionate and l-proline.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: acetate, propionate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltitol, <em>α</em>-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3- and 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phenyl phosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-2′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide are hydrolysed. <em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside and p-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The major hydroxylated fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Sa 1147-06<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 23145<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7737<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Atlantic salmon (<em>Salmo salar</em>) farmed in Lake Chapo, Chile.</s></p></content></protolog>