<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6129_nm.9322" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9322" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9322" rank="species">Syntrophomonas erecta</organism><reference id="rid.6129"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophomonas erecta sp. nov., a novel anaerobe that syntrophically degrades short-chain fatty acids</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>799</fpage><lpage>803</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63372-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Syntrophomonas erecta</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Syntrophomonas erecta</em> (e.rec′ta. L. fem. adj. <em>erecta</em> erect).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods with Gram-negative cell wall, 0·6–0·8×2·0–8·0 μm, non-spore-forming and with 2–5 flagella, usually occurring in the subpole of cells.</s><s>Straight-chain fatty acids with 4–8 carbon atoms can serve as substrates for the species in co-culture with <em>M. hungatei</em> DSM 864<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Even-numbered fatty acids are degraded into acetate and presumably H<sub>2</sub>, whereas odd-numbered ones are degraded into propionate, acetate and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Straight-chain fatty acids shorter than C<sub>4</sub> (acetate and propionate), longer than C<sub>8</sub> (caprate, laurate, myristate, palmitate, stearate, oleate, linoleate and arachidate), branched-chain fatty acids (isobutyrate and isovalerate) and benzoate do not support the co-culture.</s><s>Fumarate, sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfur and nitrate cannot act as electron acceptors for butyrate oxidation.</s><s>Crotonate is the only tested substrate that supports growth of the type strain in pure culture, whereas butyrate plus pentenoate supports growth of SB9-1.</s><s>Yeast extract, tryptone, peptone, maltose, glucose, fructose, ribose, xylose, pentenoate, fumarate and pyruvate alone do not support growth.</s><s>The type strain can grow at pH 6·0–8·8, 25–47 °C and in 0–500 mM NaCl.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids of the type strain contain mainly C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (29·74 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (17·00 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (16·63 %) and isoC<sub>17 : 1</sub> I (15·34 %).</s><s>ll-Diaminopimelic acid exists in the cellular peptidoglycan.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 43·2–43·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GB4-38<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.5013<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16215<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the granular sludge of a UASB reactor for treating bean-curd farm wastewater in Beijing, China.</s></p></content></protolog>