<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11704_nm.19315" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19315" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19315" rank="species">Roseovarius nanhaiticus</organism><reference id="rid.11704"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseovarius nanhaiticus sp. nov., a member of the Roseobacter clade isolated from marine sediment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1289</fpage><lpage>1295</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012930-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667376</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseovarius nanhaiticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseovarius nanhaiticus</em> (nan.hai′ti.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nanhaiticus</em> referring to Nanhai, the South China Sea, the site from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-staining-negative, non-spore-forming and ovoid to rods with a size of 0.58–0.84×1.42–3.37 μm (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells show predominantly tumbling motion.</s><s>Flagella are not found.</s><s>On M2 agar plates, small, wettish, smooth, beige or faint pink colonies develop that are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter within 3–5 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 30 °C, at salinities of 2.0–4.0 % and at pH values between 7.8 and 9.3.</s><s>There is an absolute requirement for sodium ions.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is not detected.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of starch, Tween 20, 40 and 80, gelatin liquefaction and urease activity are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive.</s><s>Tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and tryptophan deaminase are negative.</s><s>In assays with API ZYM strips, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase are positive, but lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Cells are fastidious and grow well on seawater-based complex medium, i.e. with yeast extract, tryptone and potato peptone as the substrates.</s><s>According to the API 20NE strip, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, citrate and phenylacetic acid are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose or amygdalin in the API 20E system.</s><s>In addition, the type strain is susceptible to cefoperazone, ciprofloxacin, ceftriaxone, erythromycin, cephalexin, ampicillin, kanamycin, norfloxacin, cephazolin, minocycline, carbenicillin, streptomycin, ofloxacin, rifampicin, piperacillin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, cephradine and gentamicin, but resistant to polymyxin B, clindamycin, lincomycin, furazolidone, doxycycline hydrochloride, tetracycline, metronidazole, vancomycin, trimethoprim, oxacillin and neomycin.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are (&#x003E;5 % of total fatty acids): C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11-methyl and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology of cells of strain NH52J<sup>T</sup> grown on an M2 agar plate for 24 h at 30 °C. (a) Phase-contrast micrograph; bar, 10 μm. (b–c) transmission electron micrographs of negatively stained cells; bars, 1 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NH52J<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24840<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB 208317<sup>T</sup>=MCCC 1A03543<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sandy sediment sample of the South China Sea at a depth of 157 m.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>