<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8352_nm.13525" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13525" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13525" rank="species">Pedobacter composti</organism><reference id="rid.8352"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter composti sp. nov., isolated from compost.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>345</fpage><lpage>349</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003061-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196776</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter composti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter composti</em> (com.pos′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>composti</em> of compost).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-motile and 0.2–0.3×1.2–1.6 μm after cultivation for 4 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar (Difco) for 3 days are smooth, circular, convex and pale orange in colour.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15–37 °C, at pH 5.0–8.0 and in 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Unable to reduce nitrate.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>In addition, utilizes l-arabinose, glucose, maltose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and salicin as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize acetate, adipate, l-alanine, caprate, citrate, l-fucose, gluconate, glycogen, l-histidine, 3- or 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, lactate, malate, malonate, mannitol, melibiose, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, rhamnose, ribose, l-serine, sorbitol, suberate, sucrose or valerate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>In API 50CH tests, acid is produced only from aesculin; acid is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, fructose, galactose, gentiobiose, glucose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose or d- or l-xylose.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, valine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, weakly positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, and tests negative for lipase (C14), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TR6-06<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12638<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23490<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from compost near Daejeon city, South Korea.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>