<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1834_nm.8840" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8840" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8840" rank="species">Serinicoccus marinus</organism><reference id="rid.1834"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serinicoccus marinus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel actinomycete with L-ornithine and L-serine in the peptidoglycan</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1585</fpage><lpage>1589</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03036-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Serinicoccus marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Serinicoccus marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of or belonging to the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, it has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0–14 % (w/v), the optimum being 2–3 %.</s><s>The pH range for growth is between pH 6 and 11, the optimum being pH 8.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–35 °C, with the optimum being 35 °C.</s><s>Extended incubation (up to 20 days) is required at 5 °C.</s><s>Cells are cocci with diameters of 0·5–0·9 μm.</s><s>Colonies on MA are yellow, circular, convex, entire, glistening, opaque and butyraceous.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1 mm in diameter after 3 days (on MA at 30 °C) and reach the maximum diameter of 3∼4 mm after 5 days.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Does not show arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity is weakly present.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S on TSI agar, acid from glucose in API 20NE kit or indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Casein, DNA, aesculin, gelatin, starch, Tween 80 and tyrosine are decomposed; adenine, alginate, cellulose, chitin, hypoxanthine, urea and xanthine are not.</s><s>Tested by the API ZYM enzyme assay, strain JC1078<sup>T</sup> is positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase; variable for trypsin and <em>β</em>-glucosidase; negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes acetate, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, glycerol and sucrose as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Does not utilize acetamide, benzoate, citrate, d-ribose, ethanol, glycine, inulin, 2-propanol, lactose, l-arginine, l-ascorbate, l-lysine, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, polyethylene glycol, salicylate or tartrate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are i-15 : 0, i-16 : 0, i-17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, i-17 : 0, ai-15 : 0 and ai-17 : 0.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JC1078<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 14026<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 9980<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15273<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sea-water sample from the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>