<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5893_nm.8201" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8201" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8201" rank="species">Vitellibacter vladivostokensis</organism><reference id="rid.5893"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vysotskii</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vitellibacter vladivostokensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the phylum Cytophaga-Flavobacterium-Bacteroides</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1281</fpage><lpage>1286</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130007</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vitellibacter vladivostokensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vitellibacter vladivostokensis</em> (vla.di.vo.sto.ken′sis. N.L. adj. <em>vladivostokensis</em> pertaining to Vladivostok, a city in Asian Russia, where the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are otherwise the same as those given for genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are 0·3–0·5 μm wide and 3–10 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are 2–4 mm in diameter, circular, shiny, convex, with entire edges on solid media containing high nutrient components.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–43 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 28 °C.</s><s>Growth is detected at 1–6 % NaCl.</s><s>Decomposes gelatin, casein, DNA, elastin, Tween 20 and Tween 40.</s><s>Do not hydrolyse cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper), chitin, agar, starch, alginate, urea, Tween 60 and Tween 80.</s><s>Does not form acid from arabinose, cellobiose, fucose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbose, sucrose, xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine or citrate.</s><s>Glycerol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, acetate, citrate, malonate, tartrate and alanine are utilized.</s><s>Arabinose, glucose, lactose, mannose, sucrose, inositol, mannitol and sorbitol are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production are negative.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is deposited in Collection of Marine Microorganisms (KMM) of Pacific Institute of Bioorganic Chemistry of Far-Eastern Branch of Russian Academy of Sciences, Vladivostok, Russia, as KMM 3516<sup>T</sup>, and in NITE Biological Resource Center (formerly Institute for Fermentation Osaka; IFO), Chiba, Japan, as NBRC 16718<sup>T</sup>; isolated from the holothurian <em>Apostichopus japonicus</em>, collected in Troitsa Bay in the Gulf of Peter the Great (Sea of Japan).</s></p></content></protolog>