<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6683_nm.10170" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10170" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10170" rank="species">Leeuwenhoekiella blandensis</organism><reference id="rid.6683"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pinhassi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lekunberri</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomez-Consarnau</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pedrós-Alió</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leeuwenhoekiella blandensis sp. nov., a genome-sequenced marine member of the family Flavobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1489</fpage><lpage>1493</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64232-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825617</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leeuwenhoekiella blandensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leeuwenhoekiella blandensis</em> (blan.den′sis. L. fem. adj. <em>blandensis</em> pertaining to Blande or Blanda, the name the Romans used for the city of Blanes, which has given its name to the Bay of Blanes, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics are as given for the genus by Nedashkovskaya <em>et al.</em> (2005).</s><s>In addition, cells range from 0.4 to 0.7 μm in diameter and from 1.5 to 4 μm in length.</s><s>On marine agar colonies are round, 2–3 mm in diameter and yellow-pigmented with a shiny surface.</s><s>Growth is observed at 10–41 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 28–30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–17 % NaCl, with optimal growth at 2–4 % NaCl. <em>β</em>-Galactosidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) production are negative.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not detected.</s><s>Decomposes casein, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse agar, DNA, urea, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Forms acid from d-glucose, dl-xylose and glycerol, but not from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, l-raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-lactose, d-mannose and sucrose, but not inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, malonate or citrate.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), it produces <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase lipase (C8), leucine and valine arylamidases, trypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but not naphthol-AS-BI-glucuronidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Susceptible to lincomycin, doxycycline, erythromycin, chloramphenicol and tetracycline; resistant to benzylpenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin and polymyxin B.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42.5 mol%, a value that expands the range of G+C content of members of the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MED 217<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7118<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 51940<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface seawater sample enriched with inorganic phosphate, from the Bay of Blanes in the north-western Mediterranean Sea on the coast of Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>