<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4919" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4919" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4919" rank="species">Bacillus halodurans</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus halodurans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus halodurans</i> ('<i>Bacillus alcalophilus</i> subsp. <i>halodurans</i>', Boyer et al., 1973) ha.lo.du.rans. Gr. n. <i>hals</i> salt; L pres. part. <i>durans</i> enduring; ML adj. <i>halodurans</i> salt-enduring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is taken from this study for strains of DNA hybridization group 5 and Fritze et al. (1990) and corresponds largely with the original description.</s><s>Colonies are white and circular with a slightly filamentous margin.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5-0.6 x 3.0-4·0 μm) and produce spores which are ellipsoidal (0.5-0.6 x 0.8-1.2 μm) and located subterminally in the sporangium, which is slightly swollen.</s><s>Cells tend to occur in long chains frequently bearing spores.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 40 and 60, casein, gelatin, starch and pullulan is obtained.</s><s>Most strains do not hydrolyse Tween 20 (strains PN-62 and PN-80 positive) or hippurate (strain PN-31 positive), and do not reduce nitrate (strains PN-31 and PN-42 positive).</s><s>MUG is not hydrolysed and phenylalanine is not deaminated.</s><s>Most strains grow at pH 7.0 (strains PN-31 and PN-42 do not) but optimal growth is obtained around pH 9-10.</s><s>Growth temperature range is 15-55 °C.</s><s>Strains show moderate halotolerance; good growth is obtained up to 12% NaCl.</s><s>Carbohydrate utilization pattern shows growth on L-arabinose, galactose, xylitol, inositol, mannose, N-acetylglucosamine or 2-ketogluconate, but not with dulcitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside or D-tagatose.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 42.1 and 43.9 mol % G + C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-80 (= DSM 497).</s></p></content></protolog>