<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2665_nm.6700" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6700" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6700" rank="species">Actinopolyspora iraqiensis</organism><reference id="rid.2665"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Al-Tai</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Z.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinopolyspora iraqiensis sp. nov., a New Halophilic Actinomycete Isolated from Soil</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>759</fpage><lpage>763</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-759</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinopolyspora iraqiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinopolyspora iraqiensis</i> (ira.qi.ensis M.L. adj. <i>iraqiensis</i>, referring to Iraq, the source of the soil sample from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth occurs when a liquid medium is supplemented with 10 to 15% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25% (wt/vol) NaCl or when NaCl is absent.</s><s>Lower growth efficiencies are observed at 5 and 20% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>The organism is moderately halophilic according to the definition of Kushner (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal growth temperature is between 30 and 35°C.</s><s>Poor growth occurs at 16 and 40°C.</s><s>At 42°C, no growth occurs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are small (2 to 4 mm in diameter), thin, elevated or convex.</s><s>The spore mass is white and appears abundant on solid medium containing NaCl (10 or 15% [wt/vol]).</s><s>On the reverse side of the culture growth, the colony is yellow to brownish.</s><s>No distinctive pigment is present.</s><s>Substrate mycelia (0.5 to 0.7 μm in diameter) are well developed and branched, rarely fragmented in both solid and liquid media.</s><s>The aerial mycelium forms short chains of spores (1 to 15 conidia).</s><s>The spores are spheroidal (diameter of 1 μm) and have smooth surfaces (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains primarily <i>meso</i>-DAP trace amounts of L-DAP.</s><s>The whole-cell hydrolysate contains arabinose, galactose, and ribose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9 (H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids include phosphatidyl choline, lysophosphatidyl glycerol, phosphatidyl glycerol, and diphosphatidyl glycerol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism utilizes glucose, maltose, mannitol, sucrose, fructose, L-arabinose, inositol, raffinose, and galactose.</s><s>It does not grow on L-rhamnose, D-xylose, or mannose.</s><s>Acid production occurs on mannitol and raffinose.</s><s>Tyrosinase is produced, as is amylase, capable of hydrolyzing starch.</s><s>Xanthine and Tween 80 are decomposed or hydrolyzed, while urea, esculin, and cellulose are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is sensitive to a number of antibiotics, including lysozyme, amoxycillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, cephalexin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and novobiocin.</s><s>Resistance is exhibited only against clindamycin, oxacillin, and vancomycin.</s><s>The organism also shows antimicrobial activity against <i>S. pombe</i>.</s><s>Its habitat is saline soil.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Actinopolyspora iraqiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>A. iraqiensis</i> (IQ-H1<sup>T</sup>) has been deposited in the culture collection of the Institute of Microbiology, Academia Sinica, as strain A.S. 4.1193.</s></p></content></protolog>