<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2000_nm.10657" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10657" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10657" rank="species">Chromobacterium subtsugae</organism><reference id="rid.2000"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gundersen-Rindal</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackburn</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buyer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromobacterium subtsugae sp. nov., a betaproteobacterium toxic to Colorado potato beetle and other insect pests</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>993</fpage><lpage>999</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64611-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473247</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chromobacterium subtsugae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chromobacterium subtsugae</em> (sub.tsu′gae. L. pref. <em>sub</em> under; N.L. n. <em>Tsuga</em> scientific name of hemlocks; N.L. gen. n. <em>subtsugae</em> under <em>Tsuga</em>, because the type strain was found in soil under a hemlock tree).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies start to form as cream coloured, but turn deep violet, starting from the centre, in 24–48 h in the presence of oxygen on peptone-based media.</s><s>This colouration is due to the production of violacein, a violet di-tryptophan derivative.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, regular and raised on L agar.</s><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped eubacteria.</s><s>The mean cell dimensions are 0.7×2.4 μm.</s><s>Acid is produced from fermentative metabolism of glucose, fructose and trehalose.</s><s>While growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl, there is no growth in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–28 °C, with sparse growth at 10 and 40 °C and no growth at 42 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH range for growth is 6.5–8.0, and growth is inhibited below pH 4.5 and above pH 9.0.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed and a lecithinase and lipase are produced on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Not haemolytic on sheep blood.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content is 64.5 mol% (sd 0.1) (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Using Biolog GN plates, the type strain oxidizes amino acids including d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, d-serine, l-serine and l-threonine.</s><s>Sugars utilized included d-glucose, d-fructose and d-trehalose.</s><s>Acids utilized included acetic acid, lactic acid, bromosuccinic acid and propionic acid.</s><s>Other compounds found to be utilized as sole carbon sources are Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, monomethyl succinate, inosine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Toxic to Colorado potato beetle, corn rootworm, small hive beetle, sweet potato whitefly, southern green stink bug and diamondback moth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is PRAA4-1<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-30655<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17043<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil in the Catoctin Mountain region of Maryland, USA, from under a stand of hemlock trees (<em>Tsuga canadensis</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>