<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3483_nm.1917" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1917" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1917" rank="species">Neisseria dentiae</organism><reference id="rid.3483"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barrett</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of Neisseria from the dental plaque of the domestic cow, Neisseria dentiae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>355</fpage><lpage>358</lpage><source id="152">Letters in Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Lett Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0266-8254</issn><essn>1472-765X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1472-765X.1996.tb00207.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8987719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Neisseria dentiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Neisseria dentiae</i> (M.L. fem. gen. sing. noun <i>dentiae</i>, of [Dr] Dent; group I cluster 1, Dent 1982; phenon 23 Barrett and Sneath 1994. Named for Dr Vija E. Dent (Mrs Pratley) in recognition of her pioneering work on neisserias from dental plaque)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small cocci about 1 μm in diameter, arranged mainly as diplococci with occasional tetrads, but without diplobacilli.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Endospores not observed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic, optimal temperature close to 35°C, no growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on horse blood agar are round, transparent and domed, without obvious yellow pigment, about 1 mm in diameter after 24 h growth at 35°C, without haemolysis.</s><s>Weak haemolysis on sheep blood is occasionally found.</s><s>Oxidase-positive, catalase-positive, indole-negative, gelatin-negative.</s><s>An occasional strain shows weak urease and DNase activity.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, but most strains reduce nitrite.</s><s>Attack on carbohydrates is oxidative ; acid is produced in API 50CH galleries from D-glucose, D-gluconate, sucrose and usually fructose, sometimes from maltose and salicin, although not from lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose or trehalose.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>About a third of the strains hydrolyse starch.</s><s>Enzyme reactions (API Zym and API FGN) are positive in about two-thirds of the strains for gamma-glutamyl.a2, leucine.a and acid phosphatase, and in about a third of strains for glycine.a and lysine.a.</s><s>Some strains are positive for serine.a and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Occasional strains are positive for aspartyl-alanine.a, phenylalanyl-proline.a, prolylarginine. a and seryl-methionine.a which are less reproducible tests.</s><s>About a third of the strains show lipase activity to butyrate, caprylate and tributyrin.</s><s>Sensitive to colistin and penicillin.</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar and in the presence of tweens, but most strains do not grow in the presence of 0.5% sodium taurocholate.</s><s>About two-thirds of the strains synthesize polysaccharide from sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from dental plaque of dairy cows.</s><s>Distinguished from <i>Neisseria iguanae</i> by showing few tetrads, no haemolysis on horse blood, weak or no haemolysis on sheep blood, in usually acidifying fructose, and seldom positive for glycine.a, lysine.a and serine.a enzyme tests, and by not reducing nitrates and by growing on nutrient agar.</s><s>Distinguished from <i>Neisseria animalis</i> and <i>N. canis</i> by acidifying D-gluconate, D-glucose, sucrose and usually fructose.</s><s>Distinguished from <i>N. canis</i> by being usually positive for the enzyme gammaglutamyl.a2, and in not reducing nitrate.</s><s>Distinguished from <i>N. weaveri</i> by not being coccobacillary, oxidizing D-glucose, D-gluconate, sucrose and usually fructose, in being negative for hydroxyproline.a, ornithine.a and proline.a enzyme tests and seldom DNase-positive, and commonly synthesizing polysaccharide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is V33 = Dent SH1/3848.</s><s>In our hands this strain gave the majority reactions for phenon 23 in Table 3 of Barrett and Sneath (1994), except for producing detectable DNase activity (after 5 d) and growth on 0.5% sodium taurocholate (after 2 d).</s></p></content></protolog>