<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6754_nm.2504" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2504" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2504" rank="species">Halomonas halocynthiae</organism><reference id="rid.6754"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas halocynthiae sp. nov., isolated from the marine ascidian Halocynthia aurantium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1767</fpage><lpage>1772</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02240-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361285</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Halomonas halocynthiae sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Halomonas halocynthiae (ha.lo.cyn'thi.ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>halocynthiae</i> of <i>Halocynthia aurantium</i>, the ascidian from which the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, oxidase- and catalase-positive, non-pigmented, encapsulated, nonspore- forming, ovoid cells, 0.6-0.9 μm in diameter.</s><s>Able to form fimbria-like structures.</s><s>No flagella are observed.</s><s>Moderate halophilic.</s><s>Sea water or sodium ions are required for growth.</s><s>Growth in 0.5-15% (w/v) NaCl with an optimum of 3-6% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth at 7-35 °C with an optimum at 25-28 °C.</s><s>No growth at 4, 37 or 40 °C.</s><s>Growth at pH 5.0-11.0 with an optimum of pH 7.5-8.5.</s><s>Colonies on MA are whitish, circular with an entire margin, convex, 2-3 mm in diameter.</s><s>In addition to the physiological properties indicated in Table 1, acid is produced from D-glucose, sucrose, L-arabinose and lactose; Biolog reactions are positive for Tween 40 (weak), methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, β-hydroxybutyric acid, acetic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, L-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid and bromosuccinic acid.</s><s>API 20NE and Biolog substrate reactions are negative for hydrolysis of gelatin, acid production from D-galactose and mannitol, sucrose, chitinase, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, aesculin, L-arabinose, N-acetyl glucosamine, caprate, adipate, malate, phenylacetate, α-cyclodextrin, dextran, glycogen, adonitol, cellobiose, erythritol, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, <i>m</i>-inositol, D-lactose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-glucuronic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, hydroxy-lproline, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, D-serine, dlcarnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), carbenicillin (25 μg), lincomycin (15 μg), oleandomycin (15 μg), streptomycin (30 μg), neomycin (15 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), erythromycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 ED), tetracycline (30 μg) and benzylpenicillin (10 IU).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub><i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> and C<sub>18:1</sub><i>ω</i>9<i>c</i>.</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylserine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 54 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from gill tissues of the ascidian <i>Halocynthia aurantium</i>, collected from coastal sea water of the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s><s>The type strain is strain KMM 1376<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14573<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>