<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7051_nm.1625" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1625" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1625" rank="species">Burkholderia caribensis</organism><reference id="rid.7051"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barakat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martel</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia caribensis sp. nov., an exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium isolated from vertisol microaggregates in Martinique.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>787</fpage><lpage>794</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-787</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319504</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia caribensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia caribensis</i> (ca.ri.ben'sis. M.L. adj. <i>caribensis</i> pertaining to the Caribbean Islands, named after the once-indigenous Caribe Indians, where the strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short rods (1-2 x 0-5 μm), Gram-negative, motile and pleiomorphic in actively growing cultures (LB medium).</s><s>Cells produce large amounts of EPS when grown on sugar-enriched agar media (2% glucose, xylose, fructose, sorbitol, arabinose, xylose, mannitol or inositol).</s><s>Colonies are about 3 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation on tenfold-diluted TSA medium at 28 °C.</s><s>They are white, smooth and mucoid.</s><s>No diffusible or fluorescent pigment was observed.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and pgalactosidase are produced but protease is not produced.</s><s>The following are oxidized: Tweens 40 and 80, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, adonitol, L-arabinose, Darabitol, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, α-D-glucose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, psicose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, D-trehalose, xylitol, methylpyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucoronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydr oxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-keto-glutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebatic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucoronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-pyroglutamicacid, D-serine, L-threonine, DL-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, DL-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, N-acetyl-D-gluconic acid, lactulose, palatinose, D-ribose, sahcin, D-tagatose, D-xylose, lactamide, D-lactic acid methyl ester, D-malic acid, L-malic acid, pyruvic acid, N-acetyl-L-glutamic acid, adenosine, 2'-deoxyadenosine, AMP, fructose 6-phosphate, N-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, urease and β-galactosidase are produced.</s><s>The following are not oxidized: α-cyclodextrin, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, cellobiose, i-erythritol, gentiobiose, alactose, melibiose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, sucrose, turanose, malonic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, inulin, amygdalin, arbutin, α-D-lactose, maltotriose, D-melezitose, 3-methylglucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, <i>p</i>-methyl-D-mannoside, palatinose, stachyose, TMP, UMP, nitrate, tryptophan, esculin and adipate.</s><s>The G+C content is 63.1 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Burkholderia caribensis</i> is MWAP64<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Culture Collection as LMG 18531<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The characteristics of this strain are identical to those described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>