<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.741_nm.9459" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9459" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9459" rank="species">Pedobacter himalayensis</organism><reference id="rid.741"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chaturvedi</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suresh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter himalayensis sp. nov., from the Hamta glacier located in the Himalayan mountain ranges of India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1083</fpage><lpage>1088</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63532-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter himalayensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter himalayensis</em> (him.a.lay.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>himalayensis</em> pertaining to Himalaya).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on nutrient agar medium are round (1·6–2 mm in diameter), convex with complete margins, mucoid and pale white.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, psychrotolerant, Gram-negative and non-motile.</s><s>Grows between 4 and 25 °C and pH 6–10.</s><s>Optimum temperature and pH for growth are 22 °C and pH 7, respectively.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5·8 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey's medium, Ayers' agar, R<sub>2</sub>A medium, TSA medium, LB and minimal medium.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, phosphatase, gelatinase, arginine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, heparinase, tryptophan deamination and aesculin hydrolysis; negative for urease, lipase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, methyl red test, indole test, Voges–Proskauer test, hydrolysis of starch and reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-xylose, d-mannose, sorbitol, mannitol and inositol, but not from d-arabinose, d-ribose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-rhamnose, sucrose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-cellobiose, d-melibiose, trehalose, d-raffinose or adonitol.</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-xylose, d-ribose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, l-fucose, l-melibiose, d-cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, lactose, d-maltose, d-raffinose, cellulose, starch, inulin, arbutin, salicin, d-mannitol, glycerol, adonitol, d-sorbitol, citrate, malonate, lactic acid, hydroxybutyric acid, hydroxybenzoic acid, sodium gluconate, sodium fumarate, sodium acetate, sodium succinate, succinic acid, pyruvate, polyethylene glycol, sodium thioglycolate, l-alanine, l-valine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamine, l-asparagine, l-methionine, l-cysteine, l-tyrosine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, l-proline and l-creatinine; but not l-sorbose, dextran, glycogen, dulcitol, erythritol, xylitol, inositol, l-malate, sodium formate, dl-malic acid, citric acid, l-glycine, l-lysine or l-histidine as sole carbon source.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc): norfloxacin (10), lomefloxacin (30), tobramycin (15), amikacin (30), vancomycin (30), co-trimoxazole (25), sulfamethoxazole (50), doxycyclin (100), clindamycin (50) and trimethoprim (50), but resistant to roxithromycin (30), ciprofloxacin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), penicillin (10), cefoperazone (75), cefuroxime (20), lincomycin (2), cephotaxime (30), colistin (10), cefazolin (30), kanamycin (30), novobiocin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), tetracycline (30), amoxicillin (100), erythromycin (15), streptomycin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 mol%.</s><s>The major menaquinones present are MK-7 (68 %), MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) (5 %), MK-8 (6 %), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) (13 %) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) (8 %).</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (33 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1·5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (7·3 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (20 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (4 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (6 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HHS 22<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12171<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 6384<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a glacial water sample.</s></p></content></protolog>