<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.546_nm.8622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8622" rank="species">Hydrogenophaga atypica</organism><reference id="rid.546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schulze</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jäckel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Malik</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amann</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenophaga defluvii sp. nov. and Hydrogenophaga atypica sp. nov., isolated from activated sludge</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>341</fpage><lpage>344</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03041-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653898</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hydrogenophaga atypica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hydrogenophaga atypica</em> (Gr. pref. <em>a</em>-, <em>an</em>- not; L. adj. <em>typicus</em>, -<em>a</em>, -<em>um</em> from Gr. adj. <em>tupikos</em> typical; N.L. fem. adj. <em>atypica</em> atypical).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, motile and 1·5 μm long by 0·5 μm wide, with rounded ends.</s><s>Oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Unable to grow chemolithoautotrophically on H<sub>2</sub> under the conditions described.</s><s>Thiosulfate is not oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is characterized by the presence of the fatty acids typical of the genus <em>Hydrogenophaga</em> with the hydroxylated fatty acid 8 : 0 3-OH and also 9 : 0 3-OH.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the species is a member of the genus <em>Hydrogenophaga</em>.</s><s>On YPG agar at 25 °C, colonies are circular, entire, slightly convex, smooth and pale yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37 °C but not at 10 °C.</s><s>Only a few organic compounds can be used as sole sources of carbon: gluconate, glutarate, lactate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, phenylalanine, l-proline, 3-hydroxybenzoate and 4-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Furthermore, tests for hydrolysis of l-alanine pNA are positive.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, adipate, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, suberate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, itaconate, d-malate, mesaconate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-leucine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-tryptophan or phenylacetate as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>Tests for hydrolysis of pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pNP-ester and l-proline pNA are negative.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 64 mol%.</s><s>Characteristics used for differentiation from the other <em>Hydrogenophaga</em> species are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BSB 41.8<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15342<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108118<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge in Munich, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>