<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6777_nm.6488" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6488" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6488" rank="species">Rhodococcus maanshanensis</organism><reference id="rid.6777"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus maanshanensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete from soil</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>2121</fpage><lpage>2126</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02253-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508878</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus maanshanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodococcus maanshanensis</i> (ma.an.shan.en'sis. N.L. adj. <i>maanshanensis</i> referring to Maanshan, the source of the soil from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-motile actinomycete that forms a branched substrate mycelium that fragments into rod- and coccoid-like elements.</s><s>Convex, cream-coloured colonies with slightly irregular edges are formed on Bennett's and TSB agars.</s><s>Neither aerial hyphae nor diffusible pigments are formed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and catalase and urease are produced but the organism is oxidase-negative.</s><s>Does not metabolize 2,4- dinitrophenol, 2,4,6-trichlorophenol or phenol.</s><s>Adenine, aesculin, arbutin and Tweens 20, 60 and 80 are degraded but not casein, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Acid is formed from D-fructose, D-glucose and glycerol but not from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, inulin, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose (weak), D-raffinose, D-ribose (weak), α-L-rhamnose, starch, dsucrose, D-trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>D-Fructose, D-glucose, D-melezitose, salicin, sodium fumarate and sodium propionate are used as sole carbon and energy sources but adonitol, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, D-fucose, D-raffinose, starch, xylitol, formate, hippurate and tartrate are not.</s><s>Utilization of other substrates as sole carbon and energy sources is given in Table 1.</s><s>L-Alanine is used as a sole carbon and nitrogen source but not acetamide, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, D-glucosamine or L-serine.</s><s>Grows well between 25 and 30 °C and between pH 6.0 and 8.5, but not in the presence of lysozyme.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations up to 5%, but not at 6 or 7% (w/v).</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA of the type strain is 66.2 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a soil sample collected from Maanshan Mountain, Anhui Province, China.</s><s>The type strain is strain M712<sup>T</sup> (=AS 4.1720<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11374<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>