<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5732_nm.9965" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9965" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9965" rank="species">Pectinatus haikarae</organism><reference id="rid.5732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Juvonen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suihko</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Megasphaera paucivorans sp. nov., Megasphaera sueciensis sp. nov. and Pectinatus haikarae sp. nov., isolated from brewery samples, and emended description of the genus Pectinatus.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>695</fpage><lpage>702</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63699-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585679</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pectinatus haikarae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pectinatus haikarae</em> (hai.ka′rae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>haikarae</em> of Haikara, named after Dr Auli Haikara for her many contributions to the characterization and detection of <em>Pectinatus</em> species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, straight or slightly curved, flexible rods with rounded ends, 0·6–0·8×3–50 μm or more in size.</s><s>They usually occur singly and occasionally in pairs.</s><s>Stationary-phase cells may form long, helical filaments and round and loop-shaped formations or have club-shaped, distended ends.</s><s>Young cells are motile, following an X-like pattern.</s><s>Old cells exhibit slow, snake-like movements or are non-motile.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Grows at 15–30 °C, but not at 10 or 37 °C.</s><s>The optimum lies between 20 and 30 °C.</s><s>Good growth (3+ or 4+ on a scale of 0 to 4+) is obtained in PYF, PYG, MRS and SMMP media after 1–2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Weak growth on supplemented brucella blood agar and PY medium.</s><s>Colonies on PYF and PYG plates after 3 days at 30 °C are convex to pyramidal, glossy, opaque, cream to grey in colour and circular with entire margins and a diameter of 0·5–2·5 mm.</s><s>Major products of fructose fermentation are propionic and acetic acids.</s><s>Acetoin and H<sub>2</sub>S are also produced.</s><s>Differential characteristics compared with other <em>Pectinatus</em> species are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VTT E-88329<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16980<sup>T</sup>), with the DNA G+C content of 38·8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>), isolated from a brewery bottling hall in Finland.</s><s>Strains have also been isolated from spoiled German and Finnish beers.</s></p></content></protolog>