<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6260_nm.3481" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3481" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3481" rank="species">Desulfovibrio dechloracetivorans</organism><reference id="rid.6260"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sanford</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Desulfovibrio dechloracetivorans sp. nov., a marine dechlorinating bacterium growing by coupling the oxidation of acetate to the reductive dechlorination of 2-chlorophenol.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>2408</fpage><lpage>2413</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10831418</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfovibrio dechloracetivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfovibrio dechloracetivorans</i> (de.chlor.a.ce.ti.vo'rans. L. pref. <i>de</i>, off, away; Gr. n. <i>chloro</i>, referring to the group VII element chlorine; L. n. <i>acetum</i>, vinegar; L. part. adj. <i>vorans</i>, consuming; M. L. part. adj. <i>dechloracetivorans</i>, removing chlorine and consuming acetate, referring to the characteristic of coupling acetate oxidation to reductive dechlorination for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, anaerobic, motile, short curved rods 1 to 4 μm long by 0.4 to 0.6 μm wide.</s><s>Cells are able to grow by coupling the oxidation of acetate to the reductive dechlorination of 2-CP.</s><s><i>ortho</i>-Chlorophenols, sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, nitrate, and fumarate are used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Acetate, fumarate, lactate, propionate, pyruvate, alanine, and ethanol are used as electron donors for reductive dechlorination.</s><s>Lactate and pyruvate are incompletely oxidized to acetate during growth on sulfate or nitrate.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.16 to 2.5%.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 30°C.</s><s>Colonies grown on LB agar medium, lactate-plus-sulfate medium and 2-CP–plus–acetate medium are white and round with a diameter of 1 to 2 mm after 1 week of growth.</s><s>The type strain is SF3.</s><s>The organism was isolated from San Francisco Bay sediment.</s><s>It has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 700912.</s></p></content></protolog>