<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8180_nm.13398" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13398" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13398" rank="species">Luteimonas marina</organism><reference id="rid.8180"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Luteimonas marina sp. nov., isolated from seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2904</fpage><lpage>2908</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000281-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060080</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Luteimonas marina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Luteimonas marina</em> (ma.ri′na. L. fem. adj. <em>marina</em> of or belonging to the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-flagellated (Supplementary Fig. S2, in IJSEM Online), rod-shaped, 0.5–0.6 μm in width and about 1.4–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Cells grow on TSA, NA and MA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies on TSA at 30 °C (pH 7) are light yellow, circular, convex, smooth, opaque, with entire edges and approximately 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter after 4 days incubation.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–42 °C (optimum, 30 °C), but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–10 (optimum, pH 8.0), but not at pH 5.0 or 11.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically on MA or TSA.</s><s>Accumulates poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Casein, l-tyrosine and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but DNA, xylan and starch are not.</s><s>Acid is not produced from 0.5 % (w/v) glucose or maltose.</s><s>Negative for haemolysis of sheep blood and utilization of citrate.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (positive with the Biolog GN2 system): <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, gentiobiose, d-glucose, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, maltose, melibiose, l-proline, l-serine, succinic acid and Tween 40.</s><s>Utilization of the following carbon sources is weakly positive (Biolog GN2 system): acetic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-alanine, bromosuccinic acid, d-glucose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-ornithine, l-threonine and Tween 80.</s><s>Other substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized.</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20E and 20NE systems) are obtained for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, aesculin hydrolysis and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arabinose, citrate, glucose, malate and maltose, but negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, H<sub>2</sub>S production, production of acetoin and indole, oxidation of amygdalin, arabinose, inositol, mannitol, rhamnose, sorbitol and sucrose, fermentation of glucose, and assimilation of adipate, caprate, gluconate, mannitol, mannose and phenylacetate.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for activities of <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase, but negative for cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and lipase (C14).</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300 IU), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30), but resistant to ampicillin (10), gentamicin (10), penicillin (10 IU) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>Additional physiological characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (the complete fatty acid composition is given in Table 2).</s><s>Ubiquinone-8 is the predominant quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.6 %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FR1330<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12327<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12488<sup>T</sup>=IMSNU 60306<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater near Ganghwa Island, the Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>