<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1734_nm.8497" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8497" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8497" rank="species">Bacillus gelatini</organism><reference id="rid.1734"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanhoutte</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anoxybacillus contaminans sp. nov. and Bacillus gelatini sp. nov., isolated from contaminated gelatin batches</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>946</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02960-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143046</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus gelatini</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus gelatini</em> (ge.la.ti′ni. N.L. neut. gen. n. <em>gelatini</em> from gelatin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, round-ended, Gram-variable, strictly aerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative and feebly motile rods that form long chains or occasionally appear singly.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·5–0·9 μm; cell length is 4–10 μm.</s><s>Endospores are oval, lie paracentrally and subterminally and do not swell sporangia.</s><s>Colonies on TSA incubated at 30 °C for 4 days are cream-coloured, darker in the centre, smooth, have slightly irregular borders and are waxy in appearance, with eggshell-textured (not glossy, not matte) surfaces.</s><s>They are slightly convex, but older colonies are flatter with concave, transparent centres.</s><s>Colony diameter ranges from 1 to 4 mm.</s><s>Maximum temperature for growth lies between 58 and 60 °C and optimum temperature lies between 40 and 50 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs at pH 5–8; minimum pH for growth is 4–5 and maximum is 9–10.</s><s>Good growth occurs in nutrient broth with 15 % NaCl added.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, hydrolysis of gelatin is positive.</s><s>All strains are negative for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase reactions, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, Voges–Proskauer reaction and nitrate reduction.</s><s>In the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium, hydrolysis of aesculin is positive and acid without gas is produced, often weakly, from the following carbohydrates: d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, mannitol, d-mannose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Most strains show very weak production of acid from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose and ribose.</s><s>The more reactive strains may produce acid from d-cellobiose, d-galactose, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-melezitose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, methyl d-glucoside and d-turanose.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, d-melibiose, methyl d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, d-raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, l-xylose or xylitol.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 60, 13 and 10 % of total fatty acids).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts: anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 9, 4 and 2 % of total fatty acids).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21880<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15865<sup>T</sup>); the DNA G+C content of this strain is 41·5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>