<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10571_nm.17818" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17818" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17818" rank="species">Tatumella morbirosei</organism><reference id="rid.10571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pantoea citrea, Pantoea punctata and Pantoea terrea to the genus Tatumella emend. as Tatumella citrea comb. nov., Tatumella punctata comb. nov. and Tatumella terrea comb. nov. and description of Tatumella morbirosei sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>484</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012070-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tatumella morbirosei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tatumella morbirosei</em> (mor.bi.ró.se.i. L. n. <em>morbus</em> disease; L. adj. <em>roseus</em> rosy pink; N.L. gen. n. <em>morbirosei</em> of the pink disease, referring to the causal agent of pink disease of pineapple).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0.8–1.2×1.0–3.0 μm) occurring singly or in pairs, non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are pale beige, round, convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and glucose dehydrogenase, gluconate dehydrogenase and 2-ketogluconate dehydrogenase are produced.</s><s>Indole and urease are negative, whereas phenylalanine deaminase is positive and arginine dihydrolase is weakly positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from starch, l-arabinose, d-fucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, 5-ketogluconate, melibiose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-tagatose and trehalose, but not from raffinose or sucrose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, citrate, dextrin, erythritol, formic acid (weak), d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucose, 5-ketogluconate, d-malate, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, pyruvic acid methyl ester (weak), succinic acid, d-tagatose, trehalose and trigonelline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 28 °C: <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, l-alanine, l-arabitol, betaine, cellobiose, dulcitol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, glutarate, histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, melibiose, l-proline, propionate, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-serine, l-tartrate and <em>meso</em>-tartrate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 23360<sup>T</sup> (=BD 878<sup>T</sup>=NCPPB 4036<sup>T</sup>=CMC6<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from pineapple in the Philippines.</s></p></content></protolog>