<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1481_nm.4893" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4893" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4893" rank="species">Bacillus cohnii</organism><reference id="rid.1481"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spanka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus cohnii sp. nov., a new, obligately alkaliphilic, oval-spore-forming Bacillus species with ornithine and aspartic acid instead of diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>150</fpage><lpage>156</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-150</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8323866</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus cohnii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus cohnii</i> (coh'nii. M.L. gen. n. from Cohn; named after the German botanist and bacteriologist Ferdinand Cohn, who described the genus <i>Bacillus</i> in 1872)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from overnight cultures are gram positive (no lysis by KOH; no aminopeptidase activity).</s><s>Cell width, 0.6 to 0.7 μm; peritrichously flagellated.</s><s>Spores oval and terminally located; sporangia swollen.</s><s>Colonies are cream white on alkaline meat extract-peptone medium.</s><s>After incubation at 45°C for 2 days the diameter of the colonies is 1 to 2 mm.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Obligately alkaliphilic.</s><s>Minimum temperature of growth, 10°C; maximum temperature of growth, 47°C (one strain negative).</s><s>Growth at 5% NaCl; no growth at 10% NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>MUG is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch, pullulan (one strain negative), hippurate, Tween 20 (three strains negative), Tween 40 (three strains negative), Tween 60, Tween 80 (one strain negative), gelatin, and casein (one strain negative) occurs.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolyzed; phenylalanine is not deaminated.</s><s>The cell wall is an A<sub>4</sub>P-murein with ornithine as the diamino acid and aspartic acid as the interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The main proportion of the polar lipids consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The main quinone is menaquinone 7 (96 to 100%) (one strain exhibits significant amounts of menaquinone 3: 28%): C<sub>15:0</sub> iso and anteiso fatty acids represent the main fraction of fatty acids (46 to 54%).</s><s>The proportion of unsaturated fatty acids amounts to 22 to 27%.</s><s>The G+C content is 33.9 to 35.0 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method (strain RSH<sup>T</sup>, 34.6 mol% G+C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most of the strains were isolated from soil samples and feces collected in Denmark and in Germany.</s><s>One strain was found as a contaminant on an agar plate in Great Britain.</s><s>The type strain is strain RSH (= DSM 6307).</s></p></content></protolog>