<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.669_nm.7548" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7548" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7548" rank="species">Nocardiopsis mutabilis</organism><reference id="rid.669"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shearer</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colman</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis mutabilis, a new species of nocardioform bacteria isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>374</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis mutabilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis mutabilis</i> (mu.ta'bi.lis. L. adj. <i>mutabilis</i> changeable, variable, inconstant, referring to the variety of colony morphology observed, particularly on rich organic media)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup> belongs to the group of organisms described as nocardioform by Prauser (19).</s><s>Nocardioform actinomycetes reproduce solely by fragmentation of either all of their hyphae, or more or less accidently involved parts of their hyphae, into irregular to rodlike to coccoid elements.</s><s>However, the generic placement of strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup> presents problems.</s><s>Before the introduction of chemotaxonomy, this organism would most likely have been placed in the genus <i>Nocardia</i> because of the extensive fragmentation which occurs in its vegetative mycelium, but its type III cell wall and complete lack of mycolic acids now preclude this grouping.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of chemotaxonomy alone, the creation of a new genus might have been justified, as no nocardioform organism with the combination of a type III cell wall and a type PIV phospholipid pattern has been described previously.</s><s>This was considered unwise because only one strain was available for description and this one strain possesses no distinctive reproductive structures or other morphological features that would make the new genus either easy to describe definitively or easy to recognize readily.</s><s>However, strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup> can be accommodated in the genus <i>Nocardiopsis</i> as described by Meyer (15), and it is this more conservative approach that we have taken.</s><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup> was compared with the one species previously placed in this genus (22), <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i>, by using the neotype strain, <i>N . dassonvillei</i> ATCC 23218 (15).</s><s>Although the most obvious difference between these two organisms was the variety of colony morphologies that were usually present in plate cultures of strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup>, they also differed in several other morphological, physiological, and chemotaxonomic characteristics (Table 1).</s><s>Therefore, we regard strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup> as a new species, for which we propose the name <i>Nocardiopsis mutabilis</i>.</s><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-AAA025<sup>T</sup>, the type strain of <i>N. mutabilis</i>, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville , Md., as strain ATCC 31520.</s></p></content></protolog>