<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12250_nm.20250" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20250" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20250" rank="species">Brevibacterium salitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.12250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>T.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Z.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium salitolerans sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from salt-lake sediment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2991</fpage><lpage>2995</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020214-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118289</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium salitolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium salitolerans</em> (sa.li.to′.le.rans. L. n. <em>sal</em>, <em>salis</em> salt; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>salitolerans</em> salt tolerating, originating from a saline habitat).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-positive, aerobic, non-motile rods, approximately 1.3–1.8×0.6–1.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies are 2.0–3.5 mm in diameter, smooth, circular and whitish-yellow when grown, in the dark or in the light, on ISP 5 medium with 2 % (w/v) NaCl, 1 % (w/v) KCl and 0.5 % (w/v) MgCl<sub>2</sub> for 5 days.</s><s>An apparent rod–coccus growth cycle is not observed after 5 days of growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–50 °C (optimum 28–40 °C), at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5) and in concentrations of 0–18 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum 3–8 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>No growth occurs at 10 or 52 °C or in 20 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed but Tweens 20, 60 and 80 and starch are not.</s><s>Negative for milk coagulation and peptonization, cellulose hydrolysis, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>In the API Coryne system, tests are positive for pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis) activities, gelatin hydrolysis and acid production from d-ribose; tests are negative for nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and urease activities and acid production from d-glucose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose and glycogen.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: l-fucose, d-gluconic acid, Tween 80, d-malic acid, succinic acid, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine and thymidine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, trehalose, turanose, putrescine, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-ribose, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, glycerol, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg unless stated otherwise) streptomycin (10), amoxicillin (25), chloramphenicol (30), cefoxitin (30), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), nitrofurantoin (300), ampicillin (10), sulfamide (250), cefotaxime (30), erythromycin (15), polymyxin B (300 UI), rifampicin (30) and carbenicillin (100), but resistant to tobramycin (10) and trimethoprim–sulfamethoxazole (1.25–23.75).</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>Cell-wall sugars contain galactose, xylose and ribose and the phospholipids include phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The menaquinones are MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-6(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8, MK-7 and MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TRM 415<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15900<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AB 208328<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19616<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sediment sample from a hypersaline lake habitat in Xinjiang province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>