<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9237_nm.14498" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14498" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14498" rank="species">Marinobacter lacisalsi</organism><reference id="rid.9237"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aguilera</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiménez-Pranteda</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kharroub</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>González-Paredes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Durban</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteoliva-Sánchez</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter lacisalsi sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from the saline-wetland wildfowl reserve Fuente de Piedra in southern Spain</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1691</fpage><lpage>1695</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007518-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542119</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter lacisalsi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter lacisalsi</em> (la.ci.sal′si. L. n. <em>lacus</em> lake; L. adj. <em>salsus</em> salted, salt; N.L. gen. n. <em>lacisalsi</em> of a salt lake, the habitat from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.6–0.9×1.9–2.4 μm in size.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MH medium are yellowish, circular, smooth and convex.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3–15 % (w/v) NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 7.5 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–40 °C, with optimum growth at 30–35 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.0; growth is observed at pH 5.0–9.0.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose and trehalose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-salicin or xylose.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed, but DNA, casein, aesculin, gelatin, starch and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase test is positive, but indole, methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, urease and phenylalanine deaminase tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production from cysteine, haemolysis and growth on cetrimide agar are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy source: acetate, citrate, formate, gluconate, hydroxybutyrate, lactate, oxalate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate and tartrate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy source, or as carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, fumarate, malonate, adonitol, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, dl-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin (25 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), penicillin G (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU) and rifampicin (30 μg), but resistant to erythromycin (15 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> when grown on MH medium containing 7.5 % (w/v) total salts.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FP2.5<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7297<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24237<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hypersaline water sample collected in the saline-wetland wildfowl reserve Fuente de Piedra (Málaga, southern Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>