<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2224_nm.3138" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3138" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3138" rank="species">Citrobacter murliniae</organism><reference id="rid.2224"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janda</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aldova</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ageron</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schindler</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abbott</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Biochemical identification of Citrobacter species defined by DNA hybridization and description of Citrobacter gillenii sp. nov. (formerly Citrobacter genomospecies 10) and Citrobacter murliniae sp. nov. (formerly Citrobacter genomospecies 11).</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>2619</fpage><lpage>2624</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10405411</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Citrobacter murliniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Citrobacter murliniae</i> (mur.lin'i.ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>murliniae</i>, to honor Alma C. McWhorter-Murlin, an American microbiologist, who, during her 39-year career at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, made substantial contributions to our knowledge of Salmonella serotyping and Citrobacter and to the taxonomy of a number of species in the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> [3, 4, 9, 10])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formerly called <i>Citrobacter</i> genomospecies 11.</s><s>It is positive or delayed positive for production of indole and growth on citrate, usually delayed positive for production of arginine dihydrolase, and negative for production of ornithine decaraboxylase.</s><s>Other biochemical tests useful for differentiation are acid production from dulcitol and esculin (delayed), growth on sodium acetate (usually delayed) but not on malonate, and the ability to utilize dulcitol, D-lyxose, 1-O-CH<sub>3</sub>-α-galactoside (delayed), and L-tyrosine, but not malonate and protocatechuate, as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Complete results of routine biochemical reactions are given in Table 2, and complete carbon source utilization reactions are given in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Known sources of isolation are human stool (five strains); human wound (two strains); and human blood, human urine, and food (one strain each).</s><s>There is insufficient information to speculate on the pathogenicity of <i>C. murliniae</i>.</s><s>The type strain is CDC 2970-59 (ATCC 51118 and CCUG 30797), which was isolated from an unknown source in Illinois.</s></p></content></protolog>