<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2121_nm.4439" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4439" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4439" rank="species">Sporomusa silvacetica</organism><reference id="rid.2121"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kuhner</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frank</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grießhammer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmittroth</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Acker</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gößner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drake</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sporomusa silvacetica sp. nov., an acetogenic bacterium isolated from aggregated forest soil.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>352</fpage><lpage>358</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-352</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103621</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sporomusa silvacetica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sporomusa silvacetica</i> (sil.va.ce'ti.cum. L. n. <i>silva</i>, forest; L. fem. adj. <i>acetica</i>, pertaining to vinegar, acetic acid; N. L. fem. adj. <i>silvacetica</i>, a forest organism producing acetic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on 16s rDNA analysis data, strain DG-1<sup>T</sup> is most closely related to the genus <i>Sporomusa</i> in the <i>Clostridium</i> subphylum of the gram-positive bacteria.</s><s>Cells are weakly gram-positive, motile rods that are slightly curved (approximately 3.5 by 0.7 μm), occur singly or in pairs, and form round, terminal spores.</s><s>The cell wall is multilayered, and flagella are laterally inserted on the concave side of each cell.</s><s>Colonies growing on fructose are shiny, beige to slightly yellow, and 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>The optimum temperature and optimum pH for growth are 25 to 30°C and 6.8, respectively; under these conditions and with fructose as the substrate, the doubling time is 14 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Uses the acetyl-CoA pathway for acetate synthesis.</s><s>Grows with ferulate, vanillate, fructose,  fumarate, betaine, 2,3-butanediol, pyruvate, lactate, glycerol, ethanol, methanol, formate, and H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Reduces fumarate and the aromatic acrylate group of ferulate.</s><s>Does not require yeast extract for growth.</s><s>Does not grow by dissimilation of nitrate or sulfate.</s><s>Nitrogen is not fixed.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Contains a membranous type <i>b</i> cytochrome.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is approximately 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain DG-1, was isolated from the mineral horizon of a beech forest soil in Bavaria, Germany, and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSMZ 10669.</s></p></content></protolog>