<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5935_nm.8626" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8626" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8626" rank="species">Idiomarina seosinensis</organism><reference id="rid.5935"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Idiomarina seosinensis sp. nov., isolated from hypersaline water of a solar saltern in Korea</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>379</fpage><lpage>383</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63365-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653904</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Idiomarina seosinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Idiomarina seosinensis</em> (se.o.sin.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>seosinensis</em> referring to the Seosin region in Korea, where the type strain was found).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic and straight or slightly curved rods that are approximately 0·3–0·6 μm wide and 1·0–1·9 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>On MA solid medium, colonies are slightly yellowish, entire circular, convex, opaque and shiny.</s><s>After 3 days on MA at 30 °C, colonies are approximately 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>They grow within the temperature range 4–40 °C (optimum of 30–35 °C) and at pH values between 6 and 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in sea salt concentrations of 1–20 % (w/v) (optimum of 5–10 %), whereas no growth occurs in media containing NaCl as the only salt.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, DNase, gelatinase and nitrate reductase activities but negative for amylase activity.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15 : 0 iso (17·1 %) and 17 : 0 iso (15·2 %).</s><s>Minor amounts of C<sub>19 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> cyclo (3·5 %), C<sub>14 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (1·4 %) and C<sub>18 : 3</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1·2 %) are also found.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, cells are positive for nitrate reductase activity and hydrolysis of aesculin, but negative for indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatinase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, cells are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4 and C8) and leucine arylamidase activities, but negative for valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and naphthol-phosphohydrolase activities.</s><s>In Biolog tests, the following substrates are utilized: glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-proline and L-threonine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 45·0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CL-SP19<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12296<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12526<sup>T</sup>), isolated from hypersaline water from a solar saltern located in Seosin, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>