<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1217_nm.5103" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5103" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5103" rank="species">Listeria seeligeri</organism><reference id="rid.1217"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rocourt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Listeria welshimeri sp. nov. and Listeria seeligeri sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>866</fpage><lpage>869</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-866</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Listeria seeligeri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Listeria seeligeri</i> (see.li.ger'i. M. L . gen. n. <i>seeligeri</i> of Seeliger, honoring Heinz P. R. Seeliger, German bacteriologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small (0.4 to 0.8 by 0.5 to 2.5 μm), asporogenous, gram-positive rods which are motile at 28°C by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on tryptose agar are small (1 to 2 mm diameter after 1 or 2 days of incubation at 37°C), regular, and smooth with a blue-green color when they are examined with obliquely transmitted light.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4°C within 5 days.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase is produced, the oxidase test is negative, and nitrates are not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid, but no gas, is produced from D-glucose and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-mannitol or L-rhamnose.</s><s>Most strains do not produce acid from α-methyl-D-mannoside.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests are positive.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed in 1 day.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolyzed, and indole is not produced.</s><s>The CAMP test is positive when <i>S . aureus</i> CIP 5710 is used and negative when <i>R . equip</i> CIP 5869 is used.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolyzed, and H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>The strains presently assigned to <i>L . seeligeri</i> belong to serovars 1/2b, 4c, and 4d (these serovars also occur in <i>L . monocytogenes</i>), 6b (this serovar also occurs in <i>L. innocua</i> and <i>L. welshimeri</i>), and undesignated serovars.</s><s>These strains are nonpathogenic for holoxenic pathogen-free mice (50% lethal dose, more than 10<sup>8</sup> colony-forming units per ml).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 36 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from plants, soil, and animal feces (sheep) in Europe.</s><s>The type strain, strain SLCC 3954 ( = CIP 100100 = Weis 1120), was isolated in Germany from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the type strain is the same as the description for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain does not produce acid from α-methyl-D-mannoside and belongs to serovar 1/2b.</s></p></content></protolog>