<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8458_nm.13397" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13397" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13397" rank="species">Luteimonas aquatica</organism><reference id="rid.8458"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>N.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Luteimonas aquatica sp. nov., isolated from fresh water from Southern Taiwan.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2051</fpage><lpage>2055</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65684-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768603</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Luteimonas aquatica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Luteimonas aquatica</em> (a.qua′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>aquatica</em> found in water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are not accumulated.</s><s>After 24 h growth on R2A agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is about 0.5 μm in width and 0.8–1.0 μm in length.</s><s>Forms visible colonies that are round with umbonate elevation, smooth-edged and yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1.2–1.8 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 72 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at 15, 25, 30 and 37 °C, 0–3 % NaCl and pH 7–8.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25 °C, 0 % NaCl and pH 7.0.</s><s>Positive for the following: catalase (weak), cytochrome oxidase and hydrolysis of starch, casein and Tweens 20 (weak), 40 (weak), 60 (weak) and 80 (weak).</s><s>Negative for DNase and lipase (corn oil) activities.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;20 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources (in the Biolog GN2 test system): dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Does not oxidize the remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 test panel.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin, penicillin G and streptomycin, but sensitive to gentamicin, rifampicin, tetracycline, ampicillin, novobiocin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RIB1-20<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17731<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24212<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a freshwater sample from southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>