<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7117_nm.1988" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1988" rank="genus">Vogesella</organism><reference id="rid.7117"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grimes</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>MacDonell</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Systematic study of the genus Vogesella gen. nov. and its type species, Vogesella indigofera comb. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-19</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995797</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vogesella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vogesella</i> (Vo.ges.el'la. German proper name <i>Voges</i>; M.L. dim. ending -<i>ella</i>; M.L. fem. n. <i>Vogesella</i>, named for Otto Voges to honor his original isolation of [<i>Bacillus indigoferus</i>] on gelatin plates inoculated with tap water from the central water supply system in Kiel, Germany, in 1893 [47])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped eubacteria.</s><s>The average cell dimensions are 0.5 by 3.5 μm.</s><s>Cells occur primarily as individual bacilli, but also as pairs of rods and short chains; occasional vibrioid rods are also observed.</s><s>When grown on nitrogen-limiting agar, most strains form filamentous rods and long chains, and there is evidence of extensive PHB granule formation; cells grown on PCA have markedly less PHB deposition.</s><s>Other types of inclusion bodies have not been detected.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum; the cells exhibit very rapid darting or zig-zagging motility.</s><s>The colors of colonies formed by <i>Vogesella</i> strains are striking; the colonies begin as translucent slightly yellowish colonies at early stages of growth (Le., 16 to 20 h), then assume a faint bluish hue (24 h), and finally become a very deep royal blue with a metallic copper-colored sheen (36 to 48 h).</s><s>The basis for this blue color is indigoidine (C<sub>10</sub>H<sub>8</sub>N<sub>4</sub>O<sub>4</sub> or 5,5'-diamino-4,4'-dihydroxy- 3,3'-diazadiphenoquinone- [ 2,2']). <i>Vogesella</i> strains are nonfermentative; they catabolize a few monosaccharides under aerobic conditions, but not under low-oxygen conditions.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed, and neither pectin nor sugars associated with pectin (i.e., arabinose and galactose) are metabolized. <i>Vogesella</i> strains are not lipolytic and are not able to hydrolyze casein and gelatin; several amino acids and peptides are utilized, although they are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Indole is produced from tryptophan catabolism, and <i>Vogesella</i> strains are capable of denitrification.</s><s>Citrate is utilized, and a wide variety of single carbon sources support growth.</s><s>Thermal denaturation (<sub>T<i>m</i></sub>) studies (based on 70 melts) of <i>Vogesella</i> DNA have shown that the G+C content range for the genus is 65.4 to 68.8 mol%.</s><s>The results of analyses of ribonucleotides (5s and 16s rRNAs) place <i>Vogesella</i> on a branch with other members of the beta subdivision of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, closely related to the genus <i>Chromobacterium</i>.</s><s>Four <i>Vogesella</i> strains isolated in this study have been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC 35906, ATCC 35907, ATCC 35908, and ATCC 35909).</s><s>The type species is <i>V. indigofera</i>S.</s></p></content></protolog>