<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2347_nm.3208" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3208" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3208" rank="species">Klebsiella ornithinolytica</organism><reference id="rid.2347"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakazaki</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kosako</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshizaki</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Klebsiella ornithinolytica sp. nov., formerly known as ornithine-positive Klebsiella oxytoca.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01570291</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Klebsiella ornithinolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Klebsiella ornithinolytica</i> (or.ni.thino.ly'ti.ca, Eng.n. <i>ornithine</i> an amino acid; Gr.adj. <i>lyticus</i> dissolving; M.L.fem.adj. <i>ornithinolytica</i>, ornithine dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>K. ornithinolytica</i> are Gram-negative, encapsulated, nonmotile rods conforming to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>They give positive reactions in the Voges-Proskauer test, in tests for indole production, citrate utilization (Simmons' and Christensen's media), urease (Christensen's agar), lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, utilization of acetate and malonate, growth in KCN broth, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, β-galactosidase, β-xylosidase, esculin hydrolysis, acid and gas production from glucose, and acid from fermentation of L-arabinose, cellobiose, L-fucose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, lactose, levulose, maltose, mannose, malibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, D-arabitol, glycerol, myo-inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, arbutin, α-methyl-D-glucoside, salicin, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, and mucate.</s><s>They give negative reactions in tests for H<sub>2</sub>S production (triple sugar iron agar), arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, gelatinase, Tween 80 hydrolysis, DNase (25°C) pectinase, D-tartrate utilization (Kauffmann-Petersen's medium), and fermentation of D-arabinose, D-fucose, lyxose, melezitose, tagatose, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, and xylitol.</s><s>They can grow at 4°C as well as at 42°C They do not produce soluble brown pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>K. ornithinolytica</i> is NIH 90-72 (JCM 6096).</s><s>It was isolated from a urine specimen from a woman with urinary tract infection.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the type strain are those of the species, as shown in Table 2.</s><s>The base composition of its DNA is 57 ± 1 tool%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the 21 strains of this species examined, 17 were isolated from clinical materials, including urine (7), throat swabs (3), sputa (4), stool (2), and pus (1), but their clinical significance is unknown.</s><s>It may also be found in food.</s></p></content></protolog>