<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3863_nm.8976" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8976" rank="family">Bacteriovoracaceae</organism><reference id="rid.3863"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davidov</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jurkevitch</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Diversity and evolution of Bdellovibrio-and-like organisms (BALOs), reclassification of Bacteriovorax starrii as Peredibacter starrii gen. nov., comb. nov., and description of the Bacteriovorax-Peredibacter clade as Bacteriovoracaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1439</fpage><lpage>1452</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02978-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacteriovoracaceae</em> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacteriovoracaceae</em> (Bac.te.ri.o.vo′ra.ca′ce.ae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Bacteriovorax</em> the genus of Gram-negative, aerobic, predators of Gram-negative bacteria, the type genus of the family; suffix <em>acaeae</em> denoting a family; N.L. fem. pl. n. <em>Bacteriovoracaceae</em> the <em>Bacteriovorax</em> family – the feminine gender was chosen).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Bacteriovoracaceae</em> is based on the description of the genus <em>Bacteriovorax</em> by Baer <em>et al.</em> (2000) and our own data.</s><s>Gram-negative, comma-shaped rods, 0·5–1·4 μm in length.</s><s>Wild-type cells, which are obligate predators of Gram-negative bacteria, exhibit a biphasic life cycle, including a periplasmic stage within the prey.</s><s>Cells in their free-swimming stage are motile by means of a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>Predator-independent mutants can grow saprophytically in rich nutrient medium.</s><s>They are pleomorphic, exhibiting a range of cell shapes, from simple rods to long, tightly spirally shaped cells.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Some predator-independent mutants may demonstrate variable catalase activity as some strains have been shown to lose this ability upon repeated transfer.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>The G+C content ranges from 41·0 to 43·5 mol%.</s><s>Members of the family exhibit no DNA–DNA hybridization (&#x003C;4 %) with the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’, although they were previously considered to belong to that family.</s><s>Members of the family are found in terrestrial and aquatic environments, including marine habitats, while the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’ are not found in halophilic environments.</s><s>Some members of the family grow optimally below 20 °C, while the optimal temperature of others is around 30 °C.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence analysis shows that the members of the genera <em>Bacteriovorax</em> and <em>Peredibacter</em> are more related one to another (maximum divergence&#x003C;17 %) than to the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’ clade (minimum divergence&#x003E;20 %).</s><s>Together, the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’ and the <em>Bacteriovoracaceae</em> do not form a monophyletic group.</s><s>Secondary structures of the 16S rRNA (<em>Escherichia coli</em> positions 198–219 and 446–488) are typical of the <em>δ</em>-<em>Proteobacteria</em> and differ from those found in the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’.</s><s>Total genomic restriction digest patterns (PFGE) for <em>Bacteriovorax stolpii</em> Uki2<sup>T</sup> and <em>Peredibacter starrii</em> A3.12<sup>T</sup> exhibit little similarity to the patterns produced by members of the ‘<em>Bdellovibrionaceae</em>’.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type genus is <em>Bacteriovorax</em> Baer <em>et al.</em> 2000.</s></p></content></protolog>