<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.154_nm.1608" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1608" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1608" rank="species">Rhodobium orientis</organism><reference id="rid.154"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Satoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new genus of marine budding phototrophic bacteria, Rhodobium gen. nov., which includes Rhodobium orientis sp. nov. and Rhodobium marinum comb. nov.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>226</fpage><lpage>234</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-226</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537056</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodobium orientis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobium orientis</i> (orien'tis. L. part. adj. <i>orientis</i>, of the orient)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The basic morphological fine-structure, physiological, and chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those described above for the genus.</s><s>Cells are rod shaped, 0.7 to 0.9 μm wide, and 1.5 to 3.2 μm long.</s><s>The absorption maxima of cell extracts are at 377, 468, 500, 530, 591, 802, and 870 nm.</s><s>Biotin andp-aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors, and growth is stimulated considerably by 0.05% yeast extract.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 to 35°C, at pH 7.0 to 7.5, and in the presence of 4 to 5% NaCl; growth occurs in the presence of 2 to 8% NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth in the dark with nitrate as a terminal electron acceptor is possible; denitrification occurs.</s><s>Good carbon sources are acetate, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, malate, fructose, glucose, peptone, and yeast extract.</s><s>Moderate growth occurs with butyrate, valerate, caproate, xylose, mannitol, and sorbitol.</s><s>Formate, propionate, caprylate, citrate, tartrate, benzoate, arabinose, galactose, mannose, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, and Casamino Acids are not utilized.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth with thiosulfate as the electron donor occurs in the presence of 0.01% yeast extract.</s><s>Ammonium salts are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Sulfate is assimilated.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 65.2 to 65.7 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats: seawater pools and similar marine environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain MB312, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, RIKEN, Wako, Japan, as <i>Rhodobium orientis</i> JCM 9337.</s></p></content></protolog>