<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6637_nm.477" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.477" rank="genus">Marinitoga</organism><reference id="rid.6637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wery</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lesongeur</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pignet</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Derennes</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cambon-Bonavita</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Godfroy</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinitoga camini gen. nov., sp. nov., a rod-shaped bacterium belonging to the order Thermotogales, isolated from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>504</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321096</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Marinitoga</i> gen. nov. <i>Marinitoga</i> (Ma.ri.ni.to'ga. L. n. marinus of the sea; L. fem. n. toga Roman outer garment; N.L. fem. n. <i>Marinitoga</i> a marine toga, referring to the marine isolation of the organism and the presence of a `toga'-like sheath). Cells are rod-shaped with a sheath-like outer structure, motile with polar flagella and stain Gram-negative. Cell division occurs by constriction. Moderate thermophile, adapted to the pH and salinity of ocean. Anaerobic, chemo-organotrophic and able to ferment a broad spectrum of carbohydrates and proteinaceous substrates. Sulfur is not essential for growth. The presence of sulfur prevents inhibition by H<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>S is produced. The G+C content is 29 mol%. 16S rDNA sequence comparisons locate <i>Marinitoga</i> in the bacterial domain, within the order <i>Thermotogales</i>, close to the <i>Geotoga/Petrotoga</i> lineage. The type species is <i>Marinitoga camini</i>.</s></p><p class="etymology" /></content></protolog>