<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6875_nm.2652" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2652" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2652" rank="species">Pseudomonas nitroreducens</organism><reference id="rid.6875"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Griese</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steffen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of 'Pseudomonas azelaica' DSM 9128, leading to emended descriptions of Pseudomonas citronellolis Seubert 1960 (Approved Lists 1980) and Pseudomonas nitroreducens Iizuka and Komagata 1964 (Approved Lists 1980), including Pseudomonas multiresinivorans as its later heterotypic synonym.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>878</fpage><lpage>882</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64849-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392224</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Pseudomonas nitroreducens</em> Iizuka and Komagata 1964 (Approved Lists 1980)</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology and colonies are as described by Iizuka &#x0026; Komagata (1964).</s><s>Fluorescence may be present in early stages of isolation but was absent in all cultures studied here.</s><s>Positive reactions for denitrification of nitrate to dinitrogen, arginine dihydrolase and utilization of hydroxyl-l-proline.</s><s>Grows at 4 °C according to Prakash <em>et al.</em> (2007), but no growth was observed at 4 °C in this study; weak or no growth at 41 °C.</s><s>Negative reactions for ornithine decarboxylase, indole production from tryptophan, hydrolysis of gelatin and aesculin, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and lecithinase.</s><s>No utilization of malonate, 2-ketogluconate, <em>o</em>-aminobenzoate or benzylformate.</s><s>Utilizes a wide range of organic acids and amino acids but a limited spectrum of carbohydrates (Table 2 and Supplementary Table S3).</s><s>Main fatty acids are octadecenoic acid (35–37 %), summed feature 3 (including hexadecenoic acid; 21–27 %) and hexadecanoic acid (21–24 %).</s><s>The hydroxylated fatty acids 3-OH C<sub>10 : 0</sub>, 2-OH C<sub>12 : 0</sub> and 3-OH C<sub>12 : 0</sub> are present in amounts of 3–6 %.</s><s>According to Prakash <em>et al.</em> (2007), shows positive reactions for growth in the presence of 5 % NaCl, hydrolysis of Tween 80 and hypoxanthine, urease and acid production from fructose and glycerol and negative reactions for degradation of citronellol and acid production from adonitol, dulcitol, glucose, mannitol, ribose, xylose, galactose and arabinose.</s><s>According to Stolz <em>et al.</em> (2007), the species is positive for assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>trans</em>-aconitate and mesaconate, utilization of fumarate, glutarate, pyruvate and 4-hydroxybenzoate, acid formation from glucose and hydrolysis of bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) phosphate, pNP phosphorylcholine, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), l-glutamate-3-carboxy pna and l-proline pna and negative for assimilation of d-galactose and utilization of acetate and propionate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P-6<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14399<sup>T</sup>=IAM 1439<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106747<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an oil brine in Japan by enrichment with kerosene and crude oil as the sole source of carbon and energy.</s></p></content></protolog>