<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4336_nm.9827" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9827" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9827" rank="species">Pilibacter termitis</organism><reference id="rid.4336"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Higashiguchi</surname><given-names>D.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Husseneder</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grace</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berestecky</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pilibacter termitis gen. nov., sp. nov., a lactic acid bacterium from the hindgut of the Formosan subterranean termite (Coptotermes formosanus)</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63543-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403859</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pilibacter termitis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pilibacter termitis</em> (ter′mi.tis. L. n. <em>termes</em> a worm that eats wood, a woodworm, and in zoology the scientific name of a genus of termite; N.L. gen. n. <em>termitis</em> of a termite).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given above for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are cream coloured and alpha-haemolytic when grown on blood agar.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>No growth is observed in 6·5 % NaCl.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but not DNA, gelatin, hippurate, starch, urea or l-PYR.</s><s>Positive for methyl red but negative for the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Resistant to optochin.</s><s>Susceptibility to bacitracin varies.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-trehalose and gentiobiose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-melibiose, sucrose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The production of acid from methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside is variable.</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acids are C16 : 0, C18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> DMA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TI-1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1030<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49613<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the hindgut of the Formosan subterranean termite, <em>Coptotermes formosanus</em> Shiraki (Isoptera: Rhinotermitidae).</s></p></content></protolog>