<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.604_nm.8702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8702" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8702" rank="species">Methylobacterium populi</organism><reference id="rid.604"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Aken</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peres</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lafferty Doty</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schnoor</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium populi sp. nov., a novel aerobic, pink-pigmented, facultatively methylotrophic, methane-utilizing bacterium isolated from poplar trees (Populus deltoides x nigra DN34).</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1191</fpage><lpage>1196</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02796-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium populi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium populi</em> (po′pu.li. L. gen. n. <em>populi</em> of poplar).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, asporogenous rods (0·8–1·0×1·0–10·0 μm) that occur singly, in pairs or in rosettes.</s><s>Cells are motile by one single polar or lateral flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are pink to red, slow-growing and 0·1–0·2 mm in diameter after 4 days at 28 °C on LB or nutrient agar (NA) plates.</s><s>The pink pigment is water-insoluble and has absorption maxima at 390, 473, 505 and 534 nm in chloroform/methanol (1 : 1).</s><s>Positive for the following enzymic reactions: catalase, oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterases (C<sub>4</sub> and C<sub>8</sub>), valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized are d-fructose, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, formate, acetate, succinate, lactate, tartrate, pyruvate, fumarate, salicylate, formaldehyde, methylamine, methane and betaine.</s><s>Grows on LB and NA plates at 28 °C.</s><s>Does not use d- or l-arabinose, d-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-xylose, sucrose, propan-2-ol, n-butanol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, glycine, citrate, sebacate, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, chloromethane, dichloromethane, cyanate or thiocyanate.</s><s>Nitrogen sources utilized are ammonium, nitrate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, glycine, l-tryptophan and methylamine.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are: hexadecanoate (palmitic acid, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>), 6·4±0·4 % (<em>n</em>=3); <em>cis</em>-9-octadecenoate (oleic acid, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 9), 81·6±2·1 % (<em>n</em>=3); and octadecanoate (stearic acid, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>), 11·9±0·3 % (<em>n</em>=3).</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7·0; does not grow at pH 4·0 or 9·0.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 20–30 °C; does not grow at 15 or 40 °C.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 2·0 % NaCl.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 70·4±0·3 mol% (<em>n</em>=3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BJ001<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-705<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13946<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from internal poplar tissues (<em>Populus deltoides</em>×<em>nigra</em> DN34) obtained from Hramoor Nursery (Manistee, MI, USA).</s></p></content></protolog>