<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9080_nm.14260" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14260" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14260" rank="species">Corynebacterium lubricantis</organism><reference id="rid.9080"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Warfolomeow</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium lubricantis sp. nov., isolated from a coolant lubricant.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1112</fpage><lpage>1115</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006379-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406802</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium lubricantis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium lubricantis</em> [lu.bri.can′tis. L. v. <em>lubricare</em> to lubricate; N.L. n. <em>lubricans</em> -<em>antis</em> (from L. part. adj. <em>lubricans</em>) a lubricant; N.L. gen. n. <em>lubricantis</em> of/from a (coolant) lubricant].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (approx. 1 μm long).</s><s>Gram-positive, oxidase-negative, showing an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar, TSA, nutrient agar and MacConkey agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Yellow, translucent and shiny colonies with entire edges form within 24 h, with a diameter of approximately 0.5 mm.</s><s>The lipid profile consists of the major compounds phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid, moderate amounts of phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol, two unknown glycolipids, three unknown aminolipids and an unknown polar lipid and minor amounts of two glycolipids, an aminolipid and a polar lipid.</s><s>Polyamines are present in small amounts; the major compounds are spermidine and spermine.</s><s>The quinone system is composed of significant amounts of menaquinones MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The characteristic peptidoglycan diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The fatty acid profile contains large amounts of C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The novel species can be differentiated from <em>C. pilosum</em> through its fatty acid profile and by physiological tests (Tables 1 and 2).</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole sources of carbon: d-fructose, d-glucose, acetate, fumarate and dl-lactate on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adipate, 2-oxoglutarate, d-gluconate, melibiose, sucrose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, propionate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, l-malate, mesaconate, pyruvate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, putrescine, azelate, suberate, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose and trehalose.</s><s>No acids are produced from sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, lactose, rhamnose, maltose, galactose, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s><em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, bis-pNP phosphate and bis-pNP phenylphosphonate are hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphorylcholine, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), l-proline pNA and <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KSS-3Se<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45231<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 56567<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7546<sup>T</sup>), isolated in Giessen, Germany, from a coolant lubricant.</s><s>Strains KSS-4Se and KSS-10Se are additional strains of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>