<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2432_nm.11306" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11306" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11306" rank="species">Ruegeria pelagia</organism><reference id="rid.2432"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choo</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ruegeria pelagia sp. nov., isolated from the Sargasso Sea, Atlantic Ocean</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1815</fpage><lpage>1818</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65032-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684263</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ruegeria pelagia</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ruegeria pelagia</em> (pe.la′gi.a. L. fem. adj. <em>pelagia</em> of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and non-motile short rods that are 0.8–2.1 μm in length and 0.7-1.2 μm in width (see Supplementary Fig. S1 available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, butyrous or (sometimes) viscous with entire margins and dark brown-coloured.</s><s>Dark-brown precipitates are observed around the colonies.</s><s>Growth occurs at 16–42 °C (optimally at 30–37 °C), pH 4–12 (optimally at pH 5–6) and 0–10 % NaCl (optimally at 3.5 %).</s><s>NaCl is not essential for growth.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic and facultatively aerobic.</s><s>No bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is present.</s><s>Does not produce poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate granules.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, aesculin hydrolysis and acid production from glucose, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, urease, arginine dihydrolase and gelatin liquefaction.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activity, but negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galatosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activity.</s><s>In tests with Biolog GN2 microplates, the following carbon substrates produce positive results: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The following carbon substrates produce negative results in Biolog GN2 plates: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, i-erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenlyacetic acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, phenylethylamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), rifampicin (50 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg), but resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile comprises C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (52.5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH (13.5 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 11-methyl <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (12.2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH (6.8 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2.9 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2.0 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.0 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0.9 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.5 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub> 2-OH (0.4 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0.3 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (0.3 %) and C<sub>20 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (0.3 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58.4 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HTCC2662<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42378<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102038<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Bermuda Atlantic Time Series Station in the western Sargasso Sea, Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>