<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6836_nm.2552" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2552" rank="genus">Pseudomonas</organism><reference id="rid.6836"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fluorescent pseudomonads associated with the phyllosphere of grasses; Pseudomonas trivialis sp. nov., Pseudomonas poae sp. nov. and Pseudomonas congelans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1461</fpage><lpage>1469</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02567-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>General description of novel <em>Pseudomonas</em> species and strains of genotype E1</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that occur as single cells. Colonies on King A and B media are white-yellowish, smooth with regular margins and produce a pigment with light yellow-green fluorescence on irradiation with UV light. Metabolism is respiratory. Optimal growth temperature is 21 °C. Growth can be observed at 4 °C, but none of the isolates is able to grow at 41 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Each species is positive for catalase, aesculin hydrolysis and aerobic acid formation from glucose.</s><s>The following characteristics are negative: hydrolysis of starch, formation of levan from sucrose, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, denitrification, arginine dihydrolase, DNase, indole production, formation of H<sub>2</sub>S from sodium thiosulphate, utilization of d-tartrate and <em>β</em>-haemolysis of sheep blood.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results obtained with Biolog GN MicroPlates show that the species oxidize the following substrates: l-arabinose, d-arabitol, bromosuccinic acid, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>m</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, itaconic acid, l-leucine, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, Tween 80, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine and glycerol.</s><s>None of the strains assimilated <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, l-fucose, gentiobiose, glucose 1-phosphate, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, turanose, xylitol, sebacic acid, l-phenylalanine, thymidine, phenylethylamine or 2,3-butanediol.</s></p></content></protolog>