<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7992_nm.3054" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3054" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3054" rank="species">Aeromonas encheleia</organism><reference id="rid.7992"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Esteve</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutiérez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas encheleia sp. nov., isolated from European eels.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>462</fpage><lpage>466</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-462</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590673</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas encheleia</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas encheleia</i> (en.che'le.ia. Gr. n. <i>enchelys</i>, eel; M. L. adj. <i>encheleia</i>, from eels)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, straight, motile rods.</s><s>Colonies develop within 24 h at 28°C on TSA (Oxoid) and are not pigmented.</s><s>Old cultures (10 to 15 days), however, contain colonies with light brown pigmented centers.</s><s>No brown water-soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar but not on thiosulfate-citrate-bile salts-sucrose agar.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Three of the four strains produce gas from glucose (Table 4).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Resistant to vibriostatic agent 0/129.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0 to 3% (wt/vol) NaCl, at temperatures between 4 and 37°C, and under alkaline (pH 9.0) conditions.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and indole positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase negative.</s><s>Three of the four strains are Voges-Proskauer negative (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from salicin, maltose, D-mannose, D-trehalose, D-galactose, and D-mannitol, but not from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, lactose, D-xylose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, <i>myo</i>- erythritol, dulcitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, or D-sorbitol.</s><s>Three of the four strains produce acid from sucrose and L-rhamnose but not from glycerol (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains hydrolyze esculin, arbutin, gelatin, casein, collagen, chitin, Tween 80, egg yolk, and DNA, but not chondroitin sulfate, elastin, keratin, or urea.</s><s>SDS-alkyl sulfatase negative.</s><s>Three of the four strains hydrolyze fibrinogen and starch but not mucin (Table 4).</s><s>Human erythrocytes are hemolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>A. encheleia</i> strains use the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: sucrose, salicin, maltose, D-mannose, D-trehalose, L-proline, L-serine, L-malate, fumarate, and D-mannitol.</s><s>Three of the four strains utilize L-hystidine (Table 4).</s><s>None of the strains uses the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, L-rhamnose, lactose, D-raffinose, L-arginine, L-citrulline, L-leucine, L-alanine, glycine, L-glutamine, L-tyrosine, citrate, L-aspartate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, propionate, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate, α-ketoglutarate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, <i>myo</i>-erythritol, dulcitol, ethanol, and putrescine.</s><s>Three of the four strains do not utilize L-glutamate and D-galactose (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to amikacin, streptomycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, tobramycin, erythromycin, nitrofurantoin, nalidixic acid, oxolinic acid, polymyxin B, rifampin, tetracycline, and chloramphenicol.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin V, ampicillin, amoxicillin, carbenicillin, sulfanilamide, sulfadimethoxine, phosphomycin, novobiocin, and trimethoprim.</s><s>Additional characteristics which vary among strains are shown in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content is 59.4 to 60.8 mol% as determined by the T<sub>m</sub> method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from healthy European eels (<i>Anguilla anguilla</i>) reared in a freshwater farm located in Valencia, Spain.</s><s>Mostly avirulent for eels.</s><s>Not pathogenic for mice, which are currently used to assess pathological significance for humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain S181.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain S181<sup>T</sup> has all of the properties given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, gas is produced from glucose, acid is produced from sucrose and L-rhamnose, and the organism utilizes L-histidine, ϒ-aminobutyrate, succinate, and glycerol and hydrolyzes starch and fibrinogen (Table 4).</s><s>Also, the Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative, acid is not produced from glycerol, mucin is not hydrolyzed, and D-galactose and L-glutamate are not utilized (Table 4).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 60.0 mol%.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the Colección Española de Cultivos Tipo, Valencia, Spain, as strain CECT 4342.</s></p></content></protolog>