<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1417_nm.2634" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2634" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2634" rank="species">Pseudomonas luteola</organism><reference id="rid.1417"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kodama</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kimura</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two new species of Pseudomonas: P. oryzihabitans isolated from rice paddy and clinical specimens and P. luteola isolated from clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>467</fpage><lpage>474</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-467</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas luteola</i> Kodama, Kimura, and Komagata sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas luteola</i> (lu. te' o. la. L. dim. adj. <i>luteola</i> yellowish)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods 0.8 by 2.5 μm and have rounded ends.</s><s>The cells occur singly, rarely pairs, and are motile by means of polar multitrichous flagella (Fig. 2).</s><s>A small number of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules accumulate in the cells.</s><s>Endospores are not formed in the cells.</s><s>Gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on 0.5% glucose nutrient agar are smooth or wrinkled, entire or erose, flat or convex, light yellow or pale yellow, and 3 mm in diameter after 2 days of incubation at 30°C.</s><s>A pellicle is formed on the surface of 0.5% glucose nutrient broth.</s><s>A water-insoluble yellow pigment is produced.</s><s>No water-soluble fluorescent pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar and SS agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory.</s><s>Oxidative, but not fermentative.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite (succinate-nitrate medium).</s><s>Nitrate respiration is negative.</s><s>Urease and DNase are produced.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Starch and Tween 80 are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin, esculin, and ONPG are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid and alkaline phosphatases and arginine dihydrolase are produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and phenylalanine deaminase are not produced.</s><s>Gluconate is not oxidized.</s><s>Good growth occurs on Simmons citrate agar.</s><s>Growth does not occur in medium containing 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 42°C.</s><s>Methionine is not required for growth.</s><s>Cleavage of protocatechuate is of the <i>ortho</i> type.</s><s>Agar is not decomposed.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, L-rhamnose, maltose, trehalose, mannitol, inositol, and salicin oxidatively, but not from sucrose, lactose, cellobiose, adonitol, sorbitol, or inulin.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-xylose, D-ribose, D-glucose, Dfructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, trehalose, mannitol, glycerol, acetate, pyruvate, malonate, DL-β-<i>n</i>-hydroxybutyrate, fumarate, 2-ketogluconate, gluconate, succinate , <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and glutamate are utilized, but sucrose, lactose, raffinose, inulin, starch, phenol, ohydroxybenzoate, and <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrogen is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 55.4 mol% G+C (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular fatty acids consist of large amounts of even-numbered straight-chain C<sub>18:1</sub> acid, C<sub>16:0</sub> acid, and C<sub>16:1</sub> acid, and small amounts of even-numbered straight-chain C<sub>12:0</sub> acid, 3-OH-C<sub>10:0</sub> acid, 3-OH-C<sub>12:0</sub> acid, and 2-0H-C<sub>12:0</sub> acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ubiquinone is ubiquinone Q-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cytochrome difference spectra do not show absorption at 551 to 554 and 522 to 524 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain KS0921 (= Gilardi 4239 = IAM 13000 = JCM 3352), which was isolated from a clinical specimen by G.</s><s>L.</s><s>Gilardi.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given above is based on the characteristics of type strain KS0921, and variations in the characteristics among the strains of the species are shown in Tables 1 through 4 and 6.</s></p></content></protolog>