<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3754_nm.11003" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11003" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11003" rank="species">Ruania albidiflava</organism><reference id="rid.3754"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pásciak</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gamian</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ruania albidiflava gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the suborder Micrococcineae</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>809</fpage><lpage>814</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64635-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392211</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ruania albidiflava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ruania albidiflava</em> (al.bi.di.fla′va. L. adj. <em>albidus</em> white; L. fem. adj. <em>flava</em> yellow; N.L. fem. adj. <em>albidiflava</em> whitish yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.5–0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are convex and moist, with a pale yellow colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–37 °C with an optimum at 28 °C, and at a wide initial pH range of 5.5–12.5 with an optimum at pH 6.5–10.5.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>The methyl red test is positive, but indole and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Potato starch is decomposed, but adenine, casein, aesculin, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from arbutin, salicin, d-ribose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-fructose, aesculin, d-maltose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, d-lyxose and l-fucose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, dl-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon sources: acetate, d-lactose, d-melezitose, l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-proline, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, oxalate, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-glutamic acid, d-maltose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, glycerol, l-arginine, l-fucose and sucrose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: citrate, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-inulin, d-lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-sorbose, d-xylose, dulcitol, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, l-arabinose, l-leucinamide, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine, l-valine, malate, malonate, nicotinamide, salicin and succinate.</s><s>In the API ZYM assay, tests are positive for cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), trypsin, chymotrypsin and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (15 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>Not susceptible to nitrofurantoin (300 μg) or oxacillin (1 μg).</s><s>Whole-cell sugars are galactose and glucose.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 69.8 mol%.</s><s>Other chemotaxonomic characteristics are as described for the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 3-6<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.3142<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18029<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13910<sup>T</sup>=PCM 2644<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from farmland soil collected in Shandong Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>