<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7085_nm.7273" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7273" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7273" rank="species">Streptomyces speibonae</organism><reference id="rid.7085"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Meyers</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Porter</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Omorogie</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pule</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwetane</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces speibonae sp. nov., a novel streptomycete with blue substrate mycelium isolated from South African soil</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>801</fpage><lpage>805</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02341-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807203</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces speibonae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces speibonae</em> (spei.bo′nae. L. n. <em>spes</em> -<em>ei</em> hope; L. adj. <em>bonus</em> good; N.L. masc. adj. <em>speibonae</em> of good hope, to indicate Cape Town, the Cape of Good Hope, South Africa, the geographical location from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive actinomycete that forms a grey aerial mycelium and a blue substrate mycelium.</s><s>The colour of the substrate mycelium is not pH sensitive.</s><s>Verticils are not present.</s><s>The mycelium does not fragment. <em>Spirales</em>-type spore chains with hairy spore sheaths are produced.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced on glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP medium no. 5) or on any other medium.</s><s>Melanin pigment is produced on both peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP medium no. 6) and tyrosine agar (ISP medium no. 7).</s><s>Although growth on inorganic salts-starch agar (ISP medium no. 4) is initially slow, very good growth with profuse sporulation is observed on this medium after 14 days.</s><s>Very good growth occurs on yeast extract-malt extract agar (ISP medium no. 2).</s><s>Good growth is observed on oatmeal agar (ISP medium no. 3) and moderate growth on Czapek solution agar (Atlas, 1993).</s><s>Growth on glycerol-asparagine agar is poor.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is blue on yeast extract-malt extract agar and oatmeal agar, but light grey on the Czapek and glycerol-asparagine media.</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-DAP (cell wall type I).</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern contains no diagnostic sugars.</s><s>No antibiosis is exhibited against <em>Enterococcus faecium</em> (clinical isolate), <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922 or <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> ATCC 27853.</s><s>Grows in the presence of (μg ml<sup>−1</sup> unless stated otherwise): cefotaxime (100), cephaloridine (100), d-cycloserine (50), lincomycin (100), oleandomycin (100), penicillin G (10 IU ml<sup>−1</sup>), phenol (0·1 %), 2-phenylethanol (0·1 %), sodium chloride (10 %) and vancomycin (50) and at 45 °C but not at 4 °C, pH 4·3 or in the presence of sodium azide (0·01 %), capreomycin (20), gentamicin (100), kanamycin (10), neomycin (50), rifampicin (50), streptomycin (100), tobramycin (50) or viomycin (8).</s><s>Uses dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>n</em>-butyric acid, 4-amino-<em>n</em>-butyric acid, l-arginine, dl-citrulline, l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-methionine, dl-ornithine, potassium nitrate, l-serine, l-threonine and l-valine as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-hydroxyproline or l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Uses l(+)-arabinose, d(+)-cellobiose, d(−)-fructose, d(+)-galactose, glycerol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d(+)-mannose, l(+)-rhamnose, d(−)-ribose, sodium acetate, sodium butyrate, sodium dl-malate, sodium malonate, sodium propionate, sodium pyruvate, sodium succinate, sucrose (weak growth), trehalose and d(+)-xylose as sole carbon sources but not adonitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, inulin, d(+)-melezitose, d(+)-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, sodium benzoate, sodium citrate, sodium formate, sodium maleate, sodium oxalate, sodium salicylate, sodium l(+)-tartrate, l(−)-sorbose or xylitol.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reductase and the production of H<sub>2</sub>S are positive, but pectin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Lipase and lecithinase are produced on egg-yolk agar, but protease activity is not seen on this medium after the recommended 2 days of incubation (there is weak activity after 6 days).</s><s>Degrades casein, DNA, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch (weakly), Tween 80, l-tyrosine, xanthine and xylan but not adenine, allantoin or urea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain, strain PK-Blue<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 41797<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-411<sup>T</sup>), is 73·4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>