<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6981_nm.2386" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2386" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2386" rank="species">Legionella wadsworthii</organism><reference id="rid.6981"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Edelstein</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Francis</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>W.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella wadsworthii species nova: a cause of human pneumonia.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>97</volume><fpage>809</fpage><lpage>813</lpage><source id="371">Annals of Internal Medicine</source><abbrev>Ann Intern Med</abbrev><issn>0003-4819</issn><essn>1539-3704</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella wadsworthii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella wadsworthii</i> (wads'.wor.thi.i, M.L. gen. n. <i>wadsworthii</i> of VA Wadsworth Medical Center, named after James Wadsworth, and the location where the patient was hospitalized and the bacterium was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Wadsworth 81-716A (ATCC 33877).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Wadsworth isolate 81-716A is clearly a new species of <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>The isolate shares with all other recognized <i>Legionella</i> species a growth requirement for L-cysteine and a relatively large content of branched chain fatty acids.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid composition of Wadsworth 81-716A is essentially identical to that found for <i>L. jordanis</i>, <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, and <i>L. gormanii</i> (8, 19).</s><s>The isolare differs from the cellular fatty acids found in <i>L. micdadei</i> only by the absence of anteiso-17:1 fatty acied, which appears to be unique to <i>L. micdadei</i>.</s><s>The fatty acid composition differs quantitatively from that found with <i>L. pneumophila</i> and <i>L. longbeachae</i>, which contain i-16:0 as the major fatty acid.</s><s>The new isolate shares only with <i>L. micdadei</i> an inability to produce browning on L-tyrosine supplemented media (8).</s><s>All recognized <i>Legionella</i> species are motile, with a single polar flagellum, as is Wadsworth 81-716A (1-8).</s><s>The new isolate shared many other phenotypic characteristics with the described <i>Legionella</i> species.</s><s>Phenotypically, this organism closely resembles other <i>Legionella</i> species, with the major exception of nonreactivity with direct fluorescent antibody reagents directed against the other species.</s><s>This is not unusual for a new species of <i>Legionella</i>, because the only known major cross-reaction between species is that seen with <i>L. bozemanii</i> and <i>L. jordanis</i> (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA-relatedness measurements show that Wadsworth 81-716A is unique when compared to other recognized <i>Legionella</i> species.</s><s>However, the phenotypic similarities with other <i>Legionella</i> species, and DNA relative binding ratios in the range of 22% to 30% at 60°C for some of the <i>Legionella</i> species argue for inclusion of this isolate in the family Legionellaceae and in the genus <i>Legionella</i>.</s><s>The isolate's guanine-plus-cytosine content of the 42 moles % is consistent with the DNA base ratios of other <i>Legionella</i> species.</s><s>As discussed in other papers, the decision to place new species in the family Legionellaceae and in the genus <i>Legionella</i> is an arbitrary one because of the lack of agreement about the degree of DNA relatedness needed for such classifications.</s><s>However, because all these species share very similar  guanine-plus-cytosine contents, phenotypic characteristics, and clinical significance, it appears logical to group them in the sam genus and family (7, 8).</s></p></content></protolog>