<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8191_nm.13565" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13565" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13565" rank="species">Rhizobium fabae</organism><reference id="rid.8191"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>C.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>T.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>C.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium fabae sp. nov., a bacterium that nodulates Vicia faba.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2871</fpage><lpage>2875</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000703-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060074</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium fabae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium fabae</em> [fa′bae. L. gen. n. <em>fabae</em> of a bean, referring to the isolation of the first strains from broad bean or fava bean (<em>Vicia faba</em>)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, aerobic, non-spore-forming rods, 0.5–0.7 μm wide by 2.0–2.5 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex and pearl white on YMA at 28 °C and pH 7, the optimal growth temperature and pH.</s><s>Strains grow at 10–37 °C and pH 5–8 (pH 5–9.4 for CCBAU 23123) and grow weakly up to 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tests for catalase, urease, oxidase and litmus milk acid production, acid coagulation and peptonization are positive.</s><s>Tests negative for nitrate reductase, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production and hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, DNA and Tween 80.</s><s>Reduces litmus milk and methylene blue, but methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Utilizes d-amygdalin, d-arabinose, calcium gluconate, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inositol, lactose, sodium malate, maltose, d-mannose, turanose, sodium pyruvate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid and l-proline as carbon sources.</s><s>Grows on dl-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-cystine, l-glutamic acid, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, glycine and l-hydroxyproline and grows weakly on d-glutamic acid, l-isoleucine, l-valine and l-threonine as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Test strains are resistant to (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) ampicillin (5), chloramphenicol (5), kanamycin (5), neomycin (5), streptomycin (100), bacitracin (100) and erythromycin (5).</s><s>The major fatty acids of <em>Rhizobium</em> species, 16 : 0, 18 : 0, 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and summed features 3 and 7, are detected; 15 : 0 2-OH, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, 11-methyl 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 18 : 0 3-OH are also found.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 61.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCBAU 33202<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23997<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14381<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from effective nodules of <em>Vicia faba</em> in Nanchang, Jiangxi province, China.</s><s>Strain CCBAU 33201, isolated from Yifeng in Jiangxi province, and CCBAU 23123 (=LMG 23998 =JCM 14382), CCBAU 23122, CCBAU 23127 and CCBAU 23132, isolated from Taihu, Huaibei, Bengbu and Lujiang in Anhui province, all isolated from <em>V. faba</em>, are reference strains.</s></p></content></protolog>