<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5663_nm.10990" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10990" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2049" rank="species">Quadricoccus australiensis</organism><reference id="rid.5663"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maszenan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Quadricoccus australiensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a beta-proteobacterium from activated sludge biomass.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>223</fpage><lpage>228</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11858148</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Quadricoccus australiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Quadricoccus australiensis</i> (aus.tra.li.en'sis. N.L. nom. fem. adj. <i>australiensis</i> of Australia, where the isolate originated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are utilized : α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, cellobiose, <i>i</i>-erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, minositol, α-D-lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, acetic acid, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenyl acetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, hydroxy-L-proline, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, γ-aminobutyric acid, inosine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, arbutin, maltotriose, melezitose, palatinose, D-ribose, xylose, lactamide, pyruvic acid, N-acetyl-L-glutamic acid, adenosine, 2'-deoxyadenosine, fructose 6-phosphate, AMP and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Substrates not utilized by <i>Quadricoccus australiensis</i> include: N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, cis-aconitate, citrate, formate, D-galactonic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, L-histidine, L-pyroglutamic acid, D-serine, DL-carnitine, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, DL-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, inulin, mannan, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-mannosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, arabitol, L-fucose, lactulose, methyl α-D-galactoside, methyl β-D-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl α-dglucoside, methyl β-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-mannoside, psicose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, dtagatose, turanose, xylitol, D-lactic acid methyl ester, L-lactic acid, DL-lactic acid, D-malic acid, L-malic acid, malonic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, 2,3-butanediol, TMP, UMP and DL-α- glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Enzyme activities detected with API ZYM include esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BIphosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>No alkaline phosphatase, lipase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase or α-fucosidase are detected.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase activities are not detected with the Microbact 24E system and gelatin liquefaction is observed.</s><s>Cells of <i>Quadricoccus australiensis</i> are H<sub>2</sub>S-, indole- and Voges-Proskauer-negative but urease-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs between 25 and 30 °C and pH values of 7.5 and 8.5.</s><s>Natural habitat is activated sludge.</s><s>Type strain is Ben 117<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 13738<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107055<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>