<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6292_nm.4135" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4135" rank="genus">Catonella</organism><reference id="rid.6292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oribaculum catoniae gen. nov., sp. nov.; Catonella morbi gen. nov., sp. nov.; Hallella seregens gen. nov., sp. nov.; Johnsonella ignava gen. nov., sp. nov.; and Dialister pneumosintes gen. nov., comb. nov., nom. rev., Anaerobic gram-negative bacilli from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186083</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Catonella</i> gen. nov. <i>Catonella</i> (Ca.to.nel'la. N. L. fem. n. <i>Catonella</i>, in honor of Elizabeth P. Cato, a United States microbiologist)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Catonella</i> cells are obligately anaerobic, gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporing rods that ferment carbohydrates and produce major amounts of acetate and smaller amounts of formate and lactate. The major cellular constituents include C<sub>14:0</sub> fatty acid, C<sub>14:0</sub> dimethyl acetal, and C<sub>16:0</sub> fatty acid, as determined by examining a concentrated extract obtained from two to three 10-ml PYG broth cultures (containing no serum) incubated for 2 to 4 days (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i><i>Catonella morbi</i></i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type species is 34 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <i>Catonella</i> is differentiated from other genera of anaerobic, gram-negative, rod-shaped organisms by the G+ C content of its DNA, its fermentation products, and its cellular fatty acids.</s></p></content></protolog>