<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7264_nm.4906" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4906" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4906" rank="species">Bacillus fumarioli</organism><reference id="rid.7264"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Syme</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wynn-Williams</surname><given-names>D.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aerobic endospore-forming bacteria from geothermal environments in northern Victoria Land, Antarctica, and Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago, with the proposal of Bacillus fumarioli sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1741</fpage><lpage>1753</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034482</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus fumarioli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus fumarioli</i> (fum.a.rio'li. M. L. adj. <i>fumarioli</i> from L. masc. n. <i>fumariolum</i> a smoke vent; whence fumarole, a hole emitting gases in a volcanic area, referring to the habitat from which the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from geothermal soils and active and inactive fumaroles in north Victoria Land, Antarctica, and Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago.</s><s>Cells are feebly motile, Gram-positive, round-ended rods (0.5-0.8 by 4-8 μm) occurring singly and in pairs and chains on BFA medium at pH 5.5.</s><s>On TSA MnSO<sub>4</sub> the rods tend to become pleomorphic and then ghost cells after 48-72 h incubation.</s><s>Endospores may be formed in small numbers on TSAMnSO% and in large numbers on BFA medium at pH 5.5; they are ellipsoidal to cylindrical, lie paracentrally and subterminally, and do not swell the sporangia (Fig. 5).</s><s>After 2-3 d on TSA colonies are 5-10 mm in diameter, low convex, circular and slightly irregular, butyrous, brownish-cream and opaque with a smooth, glossy and sometimes slightly iridescent appearance; on BFA medium colonies are 3-8 mm in diameter, low convex, circular and slightly irregular, with some trailing along streak lines, butyrous, creamy-brown (sometimes darker with age in their centres), and opaque with a smooth, glossy appearance.</s><s>Minimum temperature for growth lies between 25 and 30 °C, the optimum temperature for growth is 50 °C, and the maximum growth temperature is 55 °C.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 4.0 and 5.0, the optimum pH for growth is 5.5, and the maximum pH for growth lies between 6.0 and 6.5.</s><s>Organisms are strictly aerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, Voges-Proskauer reaction is positive, and gelatin is hydrolysed; reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and nitrate reduction are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and of casein negative.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates: D-fructose, D-glucose, mannitol, D-mannose, N-acetylglucosamine (weak), sucrose, trehalose (weak).</s><s>Acid production from the following carbohydrates is variable: galactose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, methyl α-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, ribose and D-turanose.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, D- and L-arabinose, D- and L-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, D- and L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, 2-keto-dgluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, D-lyxose, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl-xyloside, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, D-tagatose, xylitol, and D- and L-xylose.</s><s>Sensitive to disks of the following antibiotics: ampicillin (25 μg), chloramphenicol (50 μg), colistin sulphate (100 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (50 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and tetracycline (100 μg); resistant to nalidixic acid (30 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid is iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, present at a level of about 50% of the total fatty acids, while iso-C<sub>17:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> appear in roughly equal amounts and account for about 30%of the total fatty acids.</s><s>The G+­C content is 40.7 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG17489 (Rcp Sm1); the 16S rRNA sequence of this strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJ250056.</s><s>In the variable characters listed above, the type strain produces acid without gas from glycerol, maltose, D-melezitose, D-raffinose, D-turanose; and not from galactose, lactose, D-melibiose, methyl α-D-glucoside and ribose.</s></p></content></protolog>