<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9943_nm.14920" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14920" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14920" rank="species">Brachymonas chironomi</organism><reference id="rid.9943"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Halpern</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shakèd</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachymonas chironomi sp. nov., isolated from a chironomid egg mass, and emended description of the genus Brachymonas</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3025</fpage><lpage>3029</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007211-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643891</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brachymonas chironomi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brachymonas chironomi</em> [chi.ro′no.mi. N.L. gen. n. <em>chironomi</em> of <em>Chironomus</em>, named after the non-biting midge insect from the genus <em>Chironomus</em> (<em>Chironomidae</em>: <em>Diptera</em>) from which the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, catalase and oxidase-positive, non-motile coccobacilli or rods measuring 0.75–1.2 μm in width and 1.0–3.0 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs, sometimes in chains.</s><s>After 48 h incubation on LB agar at 30 °C, beige coloured colonies are circular, smooth, convex and opaque with entire margins.</s><s>After a few days incubation, the colony colour changes to brown–beige.</s><s>Good growth occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth is not observed under anaerobic conditions even after 8 days incubation.</s><s>Growth is observed after 48 h incubation at 18–37 °C (optimum 30 °C), with 0–2.5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0.5 % NaCl) and at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum pH 6.0–8.0).</s><s>Growth is observed on Zobell marine (Himedia) and MacConkey (weak growth) agars, but not on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>The following results are obtained from API 20NE after 48 h of incubation at 30 °C: nitrate is reduced to nitrite; phenylacetic acid is assimilated.</s><s>The following results are obtained from API 20E strips after 48 h of incubation at 30 °C: nitrate is reduced to nitrite; acetoin is produced; H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced; urea and gelatin are not hydrolysed; citrate is not utilized; and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine- and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>In API 50CH strips incubated for 48 h at 30 °C, acid is not produced from any of the carbohydrate substrates.</s><s>In API ZYM strips incubated for 4.5 h at 30 °C, weakly positive activities are observed for the following enzymes: alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids of the type strain are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The main isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylserine occur as polar lipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AIMA4<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24400<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19884<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a chironomid egg mass in Israel.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>