<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12665_nm.22398" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22398" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22398" rank="species">Pelagibacterium halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.12665"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huo</surname><given-names>Y.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>H.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vedler</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pelagibacterium halotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov. and Pelagibacterium luteolum sp. nov., novel members of the family Hyphomicrobiaceae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1817</fpage><lpage>1822</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023325-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20817840</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pelagibacterium halotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pelagibacterium halotolerans</em> (ha.lo.to′le.rans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> salt; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>halotolerans</em> salt-tolerating, referring to the organism’s ability to tolerate high salt concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.4–0.6 µm wide and 2–3 µm long.</s><s>Motile by means of several polar flagella.</s><s>Young cultures consist of slightly curved rods.</s><s>Colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, circular, smooth, elevated, semi-transparent and light yellowish after 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–13.0 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth at 3.0–4.0 % (w/v).</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.5 and 10–42 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0 and 30 °C).</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin and casein are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin, DNA, starch and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Gluconate oxidation, glucose fermentation, β-galactosidase and urease activities are positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, indole production and lecithinase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: acetate, l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, cellobiose, citrate, ethanol, d-galactose, gluconate, glucose, glycerol, l-glutamine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactate, malate, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, l-ornithine, pyruvate, ribose, rhamnose, salicin, l-serine, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: l-arginine, l-cysteine, glycine, formate, fumarate, l-histidine, isoleucine, lactose, l-lysine, malonate, l-methionine, propionate, raffinose, sorbitol and sorbose.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, ethanol, d-galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, ribose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc unless otherwise stated) amoxicillin (10), ampicillin (10), bacitracin (0.04 IU), cefotaxime (30), cefoxitin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), novobiocin (30), penicillin (10), rifampicin (5) and tetracycline (30), but not to kanamycin (30), nystatin (100), polymyxin (300 IU), streptomycin (10) or tobramycin (10).</s><s>In the API ZYM system, acid and alkaline phosphatases, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α- and β-glucosidases, leucine arylamidase (weak reaction), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin activities are present, whereas α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidases, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase and valine arylamidase activities are absent.</s><s>In addition to the major polar lipids described for the genus, contains a third unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>Trace amounts of nine unidentified lipids are detected.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω8<em>c</em>, 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.3 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B2<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.7692<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 15775<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample collected from the East China Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>