<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.725_nm.11707" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11707" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3954" rank="species">Clostridium intestinalis</organism><reference id="rid.725"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>W.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujisawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawamura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium intestinalis sp. nov., an aerotolerant species isolated from the feces of cattle and pigs.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>334</fpage><lpage>336</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-334</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Clostridium intestinalis sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Clostridium intestinalis (in.test.in.al' is. M.L. adj. intestinalis, pertaining to the intestine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in broth cultures are gram positive, motile, peritrichous, sporeforming, aerotolerant, straight or slightly curved rods (0.3 to 0.4 by 1.4 to 5.4 μm) that occur singly, in pairs, or occasionally in short chains.</s><s>Spores are large, terminal, slightly oval, and 0.9 to 1.1 by 1.5 to 2.0 μm in size (Fig. 1b).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although optimal growth is achieved by incubation under anaerobic conditions, the species is aerotolerant and grows on the surface of EG agar incubated in air at 37°C for 3 days.</s><s>Spores are formed readily in most media under anaerobic conditions but not under aerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on the surface of EG agar incubated anaerobically are 2 to 4 mm in diameter, circular, convex, undulate, rough, translucent, grayish white, and beta-hemolytic (Fig. 1a).</s><s>Surface colonies after aerobic incubation are 1 mm in diameter, circular with entire edges, convex, smooth, translucent, and yellowish white.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in PYFG broth grow well and are turbid, with a smooth, ropy, or flocculent sediment.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Abundant gas is produced in PYFG deep-agar cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid, with a final pH of 5.0 to 5.2, is produced from glucose, mannose, fructose, galactose, sucrose, cellobiose, lactose, trehalose, mannitol, sorbitol, salicin, and amygdalin but not from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, sorbose, ribose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, inulin, glycerol, erythritol, inositol, adonitol, dulcitol, and esculin.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed, but starch is not.</s><s>Indole, lecithinase, lipase, and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced; nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Beta-hemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Products of metabolism from PYFG broth include large amounts of acetic and butyric acids and small amounts of lactic, formic, and succinic acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the feces of cattle and pigs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 26 to 28 mol% (melting temperature).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Catt39 (=ATCC 49213 and JCM 7506).</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics described above except that galactose is fermented weakly (pH 5.5 to 5.9) and succinic acid usually is not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic characteristics differentiating <i>C. intestinalis</i> from other aerotolerant <i>Clostridium</i> species having low guanine-plus-cytosine contents are shown in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>