<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12260_nm.20261" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20261" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20261" rank="species">Terribacillus aidingensis</organism><reference id="rid.12260"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Terribacillus aidingensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2940</fpage><lpage>2945</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017228-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118295</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Terribacillus aidingensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Terribacillus aidingensis</em> (ai.ding.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>aidingensis</em> from Aiding salt lake, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.3–0.7×1.2–3.5 μm, Gram-positive, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains, and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Non-swollen ellipsoidal endospores are located mainly in a central position; subterminal endospores observed occasionally.</s><s>Colonies on solid complex medium are circular, smooth, entire, slightly raised, pale yellow and 1–3 mm in diameter after 3 days.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0.5–21 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 3–7 % total salts), at 4–48 °C (optimum 30–37 °C) and at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 6–7).</s><s>With API 20E and conventional methods, urease and oxidase are produced, but catalase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are not.</s><s>Tween 80, gelatin and casein are hydrolysed, but tyrosine is not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction (acetoin) is negative.</s><s>With API 50CHB, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, lactose, d-mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, trehalose, and sucrose, but not from dl-arabinose, dl-fucose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, turanose, dl-xylose, gluconate, glycogen, inulin, salicin, d-adonitol, dulcitol, dl-arabitol, erythritol, glycerol, inositol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The diamino acid in the murein is <em>m</em>-DAP and the menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 44.6–45.0 mol% and the DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YI7-61<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.8913<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 105790<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the Aiding salt lake in Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>