<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6797_nm.11817" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11817" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5428" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus sake sake</organism><reference id="rid.6797"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Torriani</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Reenen</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reuter</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. curvatus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. melibiosus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. sake subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. carnosus subsp. nov., new subspecies of Lactobacillus curvatus Abo-Elnaga and Kandler 1965 and Lactobacillus sake Katagiri, Kitahara, and Fukami 1934 (Klein et al. 1996, emended descriptions), respectively.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1158</fpage><lpage>1163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1158</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus sake</i> subsp. <i>sake</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus sake</i> subsp. <i>sake</i> (Sa'ke. M. L. n. sake, Japanese alcoholic beverage made by fermenting rice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped with rounded ends (0.6 to 0.8 by 2 to 3 μm); cells are often slightly curved or irregular, especially during the stationary growth phase, and occur in short chains or singly.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45°C, but most strains grow at 42 and 4°C, and some strains grow at 2°C.</s><s>Facultatively heterofermentative.</s><s>DL-Lactic acid is produced, and often there is an excess of the L-(+) isomer.</s><s>A few strains produce inactive lactic acid.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, mannose, melibiose, ribose, and sucrose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from cellobiose, salicin, and trehalose.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from lactose and maltose.</s><s>A few strains do not produce acid from arabinose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, inositol, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and xylose.</s><s>Ammonia is always produced from arginine.</s><s>Most strains grow in the presence of 10% NaCl and produce acetoin from glucose.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 42 to 44 mol%.</s><s>Originally isolated from sake starter.</s><s>Regularly found in fermented meat products, vacuum-packaged meat, sauerkraut, and other fermented plant material.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 15521 (= DSM 20017).</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from lactose, maltose, salicin, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from cellobiose.</s></p></content></protolog>