<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8350_nm.13802" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13802" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13802" rank="species">Zavarzinella formosa</organism><reference id="rid.8350"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kulichevskaya</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baulina</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bodelier</surname><given-names>P.L.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rijpstra</surname><given-names>W.I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Damsté</surname><given-names>J.S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zavarzinella formosa gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel stalked, Gemmata-like planctomycete from a Siberian peat bog.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>357</fpage><lpage>364</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002378-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196778</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Zavarzinella formosa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Zavarzinella formosa</em> (for.mo′sa. L. fem. adj. <em>formosa</em> beautiful, beautifully formed, finely formed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are pink.</s><s>Mature cells are 2.0–2.5×2.5–3.2 μm in size.</s><s>Crateriform pits are scattered over the whole cell surface.</s><s>Catalase- and cytochrome oxidase-positive, but urease-negative.</s><s>Dissimilatory nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Contains high amounts of bound saturated and mono-unsaturated C<sub>26</sub>–C<sub>32</sub> (<em>ω</em>-1) hydroxy fatty acids.</s><s>Carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v) include glucose, galactose, lactose, cellobiose, maltose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, sorbose, xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, pyruvate and salicin.</s><s>Does not utilize fructose, mannose, fucose, glycerol, gluconate, methanol, ethanol, galacturonate, acetate, benzoate, caproate, citrate, formate, formaldehyde, fumarate, glutarate, lactate, malate, succinate, propionate, mannitol, tartrate, alanine, arginine, asparagine, aspartate, cysteine, cystine, glutamine, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, norleucine, ornithine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine or valine.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing laminarin, pectin, chondroitin sulfate, aesculin, starch, gelatin, lichenan and xylan.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, chitin or cellulose.</s><s>Has the following enzymic activities: alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Nitrogen sources (0.05 %, w/v) are nitrate, ammonia, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, Bacto peptone, Bacto yeast extract, Casamino acids, alanine, aspartate, asparagine, glutamine, leucine, threonine and tryptophan.</s><s>Growth factors are required.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, lincomycin, and novobiocin, but sensitive to kanamycin, neomycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 3.8–7.2 (optimum, pH 5.5–6.0) and at temperatures between 10 and 30 °C (optimum, 20–25 °C).</s><s>Highly sensitive to NaCl.</s><s>Growth is inhibited at concentrations of NaCl above 0.6 % (w/v).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 62.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acidic wetlands are the main habitat.</s><s>The type strain, A10<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19928<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2478<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar, Tomsk region, West Siberia.</s></p></content></protolog>