<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8593_nm.13629" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13629" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13629" rank="species">Streptococcus caballi</organism><reference id="rid.8593"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Milinovich</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burrell</surname><given-names>P.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pollitt</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trott</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus henryi sp. nov. and Streptococcus caballi sp. nov., isolated from the hindgut of horses with oligofructose-induced laminitis.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>262</fpage><lpage>266</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65063-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus caballi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus caballi</em> (ca.bal′li. L. gen. n. <em>caballi</em> of an inferior riding- or pack-horse; named in recognition of the domestic horse, <em>Equus caballus</em>, which, of the seven species of Equidae, suffers most from laminitis).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile ovoids, typically occurring in pairs or chains commonly over 20 cells long.</s><s>Anaerobic growth for 24 h on sheep blood agar produces flat, shiny, off-white, round, <em>α</em>-haemolytic colonies, 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies have a tendency to imbed into sheep blood agar.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Cells do not react with streptococcal group A-, B-, C-, D-, F- or G-specific antisera.</s><s>Cells are able to grow in the presence of 40 % bile and 0.016 % potassium tellurite, but not 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>In API 20 Strep and Rapid ID32 Strep kits, cells are able to produce acid from starch, glycogen, inulin, maltose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, ribose, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Cells do not hydrolyse arginine or hippurate, but do hydrolyse aesculin and are able to produce acetoin (Voges–Proskauer-positive).</s><s>Positive for alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and leucine aminopeptidase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and urease.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 151<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1485<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19004<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rectum of a horse with oligofructose-induced laminitis.</s></p></content></protolog>