<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8319_nm.13522" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13522" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13522" rank="species">Patulibacter americanus</organism><reference id="rid.8319"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Pichel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Patulibacter americanus sp. nov., isolated from biological soil crusts, emended description of the genus Patulibacter Takahashi et al. 2006 and proposal of Solirubrobacterales ord. nov. and Thermoleophilales ord. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>87</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64185-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126730</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Patulibacter americanus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Patulibacter americanus</em> (a.me.ri.ca′nus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>americanus</em> American, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the Colorado Plateau).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are pink-pigmented, convex, entire, smooth and slightly mucoid.</s><s>Cells are short rods that stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Motility is variable and, when present, occurs through jerking cellular motions.</s><s>Growth is observed at 10–30 °C (but not at 37 °C), with an optimum at 25 °C, and at pH 5–9, with an optimum at pH 7.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl concentrations of less than 3 %.</s><s>Tests positive for catalase and lipase but negative for oxidase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, phenylalanine deaminase and arginine, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Also negative for the methyl red test, Voges–Proskauer reaction, indole production and growth on Simmons' citrate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, cellulose, aesculin or starch and can not produce H<sub>2</sub>S or reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, inulin, d-laevulose, melibiose and sucrose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Can not grow on acetate, citrate, dextran, ethanolamine, d-fructose, glycerol, pyruvate, succinate, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, adenine, cytosine, guanine, thymidine, nicotinic acid, tartaric acid, adonitol, dulcitol, fumaric acid, lactose, lactic acid, raffinose, l-sorbose, trehalose, l-asparagine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-threonine, l-valine, oxalate, phenanthrene or indole.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc unless indicated) bacitracin (10 U), ceftriaxone (30), doxycycline (30), gentamicin (10), novobiocin (30), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (30), streptomycin (10) and vancomycin (30) and resistant to azithromycin (50), carbenicillin (100), ciprofloxacin (5), colistin (10), ethambutol (50), nitrofurantoin (150), penicillin (10 U), sulfathiazole (300) and trimethoprim (5).</s><s>Additional characteristics are listed in Table 2.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid with alanine and glutamic acid in the ratio of 1 : 2 : 1 and MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) as the sole respiratory quinone.</s><s>Methanol extracts exhibit absorption maxima at 327, 395, 434, 459 and 488 nm.</s><s>Fatty acids are listed in Supplementary Table S2.</s><s>Polar lipids include unknown phospholipid 1, unknown phospholipid 2, which co-migrated with phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol (cardiolipin).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CP177-2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1038<sup>T</sup> =DSM 16766<sup>T</sup>), isolated from BSC from the Colorado Plateau, USA.</s><s>Strain CP153-3 (=ATCC BAA-1037), isolated from the same source, is a reference strain.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the type strain are the same as those described above for the species; differences between strains CP177-2<sup>T</sup> and CP153-3 are listed in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>