<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7014_nm.2626" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2626" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2626" rank="species">Pseudomonas jinjuensis</organism><reference id="rid.7014"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Go</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas koreensis sp. nov., Pseudomonas umsongensis sp. nov. and Pseudomonas jinjuensis sp. nov., novel species from farm soils in Korea.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>21</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02326-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656147</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas jinjuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas jinjuensis</em> (jin.ju.en′sis. N.L. adj. <em>jinjuensis</em> referring to Jinju Region in Korea, where the bacteria were first found).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods approximately 1×2 μm in size, motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are circular and white-yellow on LB agar.</s><s>No fluorescent pigments are produced on King B or PAF media.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Strains show denitrification and hydrolysis of arginine.</s><s>There is no hydrolysis of gelatin, Tween 80 or starch and no acidification of glucose is observed.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Lecithinase, urease and β-galactosidase reactions are negative.</s><s>Strains grow at 41 °C but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in media supplemented with 3 % NaCl, but not at a salinity higher than 5 %.</s><s>Results obtained with Biolog GN2 microplates indicate that strains utilize Tweens 40 and 80, α-d-glucose, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine and glycerol.</s><s>Utilization of acetic acid and hydroxy-l-proline is variable among strains.</s><s>The other organic substrates included in the Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>The test using the API 20 NE strip shows that the strains assimilate glucose, gluconate, caprate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Assimilation of adipate is variable among strains.</s><s>The strains do not assimilate arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine or maltose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain Pss 26<sup>T</sup> is 66·9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain Pss 26<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 10760<sup>T</sup> =LMG 21316<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>