<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6286_nm.9924" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9924" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9924" rank="species">Pseudonocardia ammonioxydans</organism><reference id="rid.6286"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia ammonioxydans sp. nov., isolated from coastal sediment</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>555</fpage><lpage>558</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63878-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514026</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia ammonioxydans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia ammonioxydans</em> (N.L. n. <em>ammonia</em> ammonia; N.L. part. adj. <em>oxydans</em> oxidizing; N.L. part. adj. <em>ammonioxydans</em> oxidizing ammonia).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive.</s><s>Forms branched, brown substrate mycelium and white aerial mycelium on TSB and LB agar.</s><s>The mycelium fragments into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Smooth spores are borne in short chains by acropetal budding from the substrate mycelium.</s><s>No pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on MNM and ammonia is oxidized to nitrate as the sole energy source.</s><s>Ammonia is also oxidized to nitrate during growth on a blend of MNM and LB media.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations ranging from 0 to 8 % with an optimum at 3·5 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-ribose, d-arabitol, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid and glycerol, but not from <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, arbutin, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltotriose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-gagatose, turanose or xylitol.</s><s>Uses acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid mono-methyl ester, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, but not <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-malic acid or pyruvic acid.</s><s>Other physiological properties are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The cell-wall chemotype is type IV.</s><s>Predominant menaquinone is MK-8 (H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>It contains phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and diphosphatidylglycerol, but does not contain glucosamine-containing phospholipids or mycolic acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-hexadecanoic acid (16 : 0-iso, 41·1 %), iso-hexadecenoic acid (16 : 1-iso, 15·7 %) and heptadecenoic acid (17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, 12·1 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69·6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, H9<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.1877<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12462<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal sediment collected from Jiao-Dong peninsula near Qingdao, Shandong province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>