<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6437_nm.5358" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5358" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5358" rank="species">Lactobacillus cypricasei</organism><reference id="rid.6437"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Papademas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wacher</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus cypricasei sp. nov., isolated from Halloumi cheese.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>45</fpage><lpage>49</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus cypricasei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus cypricasei</i> (cy.pri.ca'se.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <i>cypricasei</i> of cheese from Cyprus, referring to the original isolation source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, rodshaped and occur as single cells, pairs or short chains.</s><s>The rods are 0.6-0.8 μm wide x 3-5 μm long, with rounded ends.</s><s>When grown on MRS agar, colonies are small, entire and cream-coloured.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>No growth is observed at 15 or 45 °C in MRS broth after 48 h incubation.</s><s>The optimum pH range is 5.5-7.5.</s><s>Homofermentative.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Acid is produced from arbutin, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose and salicin but not from D-arabinose, D-arabitol, adonitol, cyclodextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycogen, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, sorbitol, tagatose, D-raffinose, xylitol or D-xylose.</s><s>Acidification of L-arabinose, lactose, maltose, sucrose and trehalose is variable.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, aglucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (weak reaction) and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4, ester lipase C8, α-fucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycine-tryptophan arylamidase, lipase C14, β-mannosidase, trypsin and urease.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for acid phosphatase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Isolated from Halloumi cheese, a cheese prevalent in Cyprus.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 42961<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106393<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>