<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1952_nm.9308" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9308" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9308" rank="species">Microbacterium hydrocarbonoxydans</organism><reference id="rid.1952"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schippers</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bosecker</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium oleivorans sp. nov. and Microbacterium hydrocarbonoxydans sp. nov., novel crude-oil-degrading Gram-positive bacteria</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>655</fpage><lpage>660</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63305-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774639</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium hydrocarbonoxydans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium hydrocarbonoxydans</em> (hy′dro.car.bon.ox′y.dans. N.L. part. adj. <em>hydrocarbonoxydans</em> oxidizing hydrocarbons).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligate aerobic, Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, motile, irregular rods 0·3–1·5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, translucent and yellow pigmented with a maximum colony diameter of 5 mm after 2 weeks.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30 and 37 °C and at 2 and 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Crude oil is used as substrate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced, arginine is not hydrolysed, urease is not present and the Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from rhamnose, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, adonitol, inositol or sorbitol.</s><s>The following are utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycogen, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, l-xylose, d-mannitol, acetate, propionate, citrate, fumarate, dl-lactate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-proline, l-serine, putrescine, phenylacetate and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine.</s><s>The following are not utilized: <em>α</em>-d-galacturonate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, adonitol, i-inositol, sorbitol, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, suberate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and l-ornithine.</s><s>The following are hydrolysed: pNP <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactosaminide, pNP <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, pNP <em>α</em>-l-arabinopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-cellopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-lactoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-maltoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, bis-pNP phosphate, benzolphosphonacid-pNP ester, pNP phosphocholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine pNA, glycine pNA, l-leucine pNA, l-lysine pna and l-proline pNA.</s><s>The following are not hydrolysed: pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pna and l-valine pNA.</s><s>The type strain does not contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid in its cell wall and the peptidoglycan-type is B2<em>β</em>, [l-hsr] d-glu(hyg)–gly–d-Orn.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-11 and MK-12.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BNP48<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16089<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 14002<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an oil-contaminated soil in Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>