<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.695_nm.5653" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5653" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5653" rank="species">Streptococcus intestinalis</organism><reference id="rid.695"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stromley</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Varel</surname><given-names>V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus intestinalis, a new species from the colons and feces of pigs.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>245</fpage><lpage>248</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-245</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus intestinatis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus intestinatis</i> (in.test.in.al'is. M.L. adj. <i>intestinalis</i>, pertaining to the intestine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolates designated <i>S. intestinalis</i> are aerotolerant, nonmotile, nonsporing, gram-positive cocci that occur in long chains.</s><s>Cells are often elongated, and cells of unequal size are found in pairs.</s><s>Colonies from growth on brain heart infusion agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood are pinpoint to 1 mm in diameter, circular, entire, flat to convex, and translucent.</s><s>Colonies on rumen fluid-based anaerobic roll tube medium (1) are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, and white.</s><s>A precipitate is formed in broth cultures. <i>S. intestinalis</i> is fermentative, producing mainly lactic acid from glucose.</s><s>D-Cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, maltose, D-mannose, salicin, and sucrose are fermented.</s><s>D-Arabinose, glycerol, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, trehalose, and D-xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Urea and esculin are hydrolyzed, but casein, gelatin, hippurate, and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 45"C, but not at pH 9.6, in 40% bile, or in 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Cultures survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Strains are β-hemolytic and catalase negative, The hemolytic zones surrounding colonies are much more closely defined on aerobic plates than on plates incubated anaerobically.</s><s>The strains which have been tested are inhibited by penicillin (2 U/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), rifampin (0.5 μg/ml), and vancomycin (3 μg/ml).</s><s>Antigens extracted from 29 of 123 Iowa strains react with group G antisera.</s><s>The remaining Iowa strains do not react with any Lancefield group antisera.</s><s>None of the Nebraska strains or Virginia strains reacts with any of the Lancefield antisera.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 39 to 40 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s><s>The habitat is the intestines and feces of pigs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 76-84-1 (= ATCC 43492), was isolated from the contents of the colon of a pig in Iowa.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 39 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>Strain 76-84-1<sup>T</sup> has all the properties given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain readily produces urease when it is grown in a medium that contains high levels of complex nitrogen.</s><s>Extracted antigens from this strain react with group G antiserum.</s></p></content></protolog>