<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8484_nm.13513" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13513" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13513" rank="species">Paenibacillus septentrionalis</organism><reference id="rid.8484"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khianngam</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akaracharanya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus siamensis sp. nov., Paenibacillus septentrionalis sp. nov. and Paenibacillus montaniterrae sp. nov., xylanase-producing bacteria from Thai soils.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>130</fpage><lpage>134</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65851-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126736</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus septentrionalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus septentrionalis</em> (sep.ten′tri.o.na′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>septentrionalis</em> northern, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the northern province, Nan, Thailand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive rods, 0.5–0.8×2.0–12 μm.</s><s>Central or subterminal ellipsoidal endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows at pH 7–9, at 15–45 °C, in 3 and 5 % NaCl and under anaerobic conditions; does not grow at pH 5–6, 10 °C or 50–60 °C.</s><s>Positive for catalase, the Voges–Proskauer reaction, urease and hydrolysis of aesculin, starch and Tween 80; negative for oxidase, the methyl red test, DNase, indole production, growth on Simmons' citrate and TSI agar, nitrate reduction, dihydroxyacetone production and hydrolysis of l-arginine, casein, gelatin and l-tyrosine.</s><s>Acid production from aesculin, d-glucose, glycogen and starch.</s><s>No acid production from adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d- or l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, glycerol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, salicin, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose or d-tagatose.</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.3 mol%.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is X13-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13039<sup>T</sup> =PCU 280<sup>T</sup> =TISTR 1830<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>