<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6883_nm.5780" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5780" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5780" rank="species">Actinomyces europaeus</organism><reference id="rid.6883"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alvarez</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akervall</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sabbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schouls</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces europaeus sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>687</fpage><lpage>692</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-687</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226901</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces europaeus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces europaeus</i> (eu.ro.pae'us. L. adj. <i>europaeus</i>, European, referring to the fact that six different European laboratories contributed to this study)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the results of a study of 10 strains.</s><s>Cells are short (length, 0.5 to 1.5 μm) gram-positive rods that sometimes are arranged in clusters.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies are circular and smooth with a translucent grayish appearance and are not more than 0.5 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation in a 5% CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere at 37°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, galactose, and D-fructose.</s><s>Fermentation of sucrose, ribose, adonitol, Dmannose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, melibiose, trehalose, melezitose, amidon, glycogen, and D-turanose is variable.</s><s>Acid is not produced from mannitol, xylose, L-arabinose, β-methyl-xyloside, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, inulin, D-raffinose, β-gentiobiose, and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolyzed, and esculin hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>β-Galactosidase, α-glucosidase, esterase, esterase-lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, and α-galactosidase activities are present, whereas pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucosidase, and α-mannosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Succinic acid is the main end product of fermentation.</s><s>Palmitic and stearic acids are the main straight-chain cellular fatty acids, while oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge in the peptidoglycan is L-lysine-L-lysine-D-glutamic acid (type A5α) .</s><s>The DNA base composition is 61 to 63 mol% G+C.</s><s>Strains are isolated mainly from human abscesses.</s><s>The habitat of the strains is unknown.</s><s>Type strain CCUG 32789A has been deposited in Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg, Göteborg, Sweden.</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics described above for the species.</s><s>It does not hydrolyze esculin and does not ferment sucrose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 62 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>