<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12346_nm.20378" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20378" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20378" rank="species">Larkinella bovis</organism><reference id="rid.12346"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anandham</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gandhi</surname><given-names>P.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jee</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Larkinella bovis sp. nov., isolated from fermented bovine products, and emended descriptions of the genus Larkinella and of Larkinella insperata Vancanneyt et al. 2006</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>30</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020453-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20139284</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Larkinella bovis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Larkinella bovis</em> (bo′vis. L. gen. n. <em>bovis</em> of a cow, of bovine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-reaction-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive rods (1.2–3.2 μm long and 0.9–1.2 μm wide), that lack flagella and are motile by gliding.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are reddish pink, and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>The temperature, pH and NaCl concentration ranges for growth are 10–35 °C, pH 6.0–7.0 and 0–1 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, R2A agar and nutrient agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses CM-cellulose, tyrosine, aesculin, starch and Tween 20, but not casein, chitin, DNA, hypoxanthine, pectin, gelatin or xanthine.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production and glucose fermentation.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose, salicin, maltose, glycogen and melibiose, but not d-mannose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-proline.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>Weakly positive for trypsin and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Negative for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities.</s><s>Susceptible to rifampicin, ampicillin, oleandomycin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline and novobiocin, but resistant to streptomycin, spectinomycin, kanamycin, trimethoprim, hygromycin, polymyxin B and nystatin.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M2T2B15<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 14040<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 106324<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from fermented bovine products, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>