<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.989_nm.3155" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3155" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3155" rank="species">Enterobacter cowanii</organism><reference id="rid.989"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Inoue</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sugiyama</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kosako</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakazaki</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamai</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter cowanii sp. nov., a new species of the family Enterobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>417</fpage><lpage>420</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002840010160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11080391</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter cowanii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter cowanii</i> (The specific name "<i>cowanii</i>" is derived from the surname of S. T. Cowan, an English bacteriologist, and honors him for his significant contributions to bacterial taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, fermentative rods that are motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>Strains grow well on MacConkey agar and are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>They give negative results in tests for the production of indole, urease, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine, and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase, and for the utilization of malonate.</s><s>They give positive reactions in Voges-Proskauer, citrate utilization, and esculin hydrolysis tests.</s><s>They ferment lactose, sucrose, raffinose, sorbitol, dulcitol, and salicin, but not inositol nor D-arabitol.</s><s>A complete description of <i>E. cowanii</i> is given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of its DNA ranges from 52.5% to 53.6%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>E. cowanii</i> is 888-76 (JCM 10956).</s><s>It was isolated by blood culture from a patient with gastric cancer.</s><s>The phenotypic properties of the type strain are also shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the nine strains studied, eight were isolated respectively from urine (4), sputum (2), blood (1), and pus (1), but their clinical significance is unknown.</s><s>It may also be found in foods.</s></p></content></protolog>