<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4430_nm.4490" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4490" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4490" rank="species">Dethiosulfovibrio marinus</organism><reference id="rid.4430"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Surkov</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dubinina</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glöckner</surname><given-names>F.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dethiosulfovibrio russensis sp. nov., Dethosulfovibrio marinus sp. nov. and Dethosulfovibrio acidaminovorans sp. nov., novel anaerobic, thiosulfate- and sulfur-reducing bacteria isolated from 'Thiodendron' sulfur mats in different saline environments.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>337</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321077</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dethiosulfovibrio marinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dethiosulfovibrio marinus</i> (ma'ri.nus. L. adj. <i>marinus</i> marine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative curved or vibrioid-like rods, 4.8x0.9 μm with pointed or rounded ends.</s><s>Cells are motile by tumbling movement with flagella located on the concave side of cells.</s><s>Long helical filamentous cells up to 70 μmin length were observed at earlier stages of growth (22-36 h).</s><s>Multiple cross-septa formed by regular, deep, cytoplasmic membrane invaginations are typical for cells of all growth phases.</s><s>Growth occurred at temperatures between 15 and 40 °C (optimum 28 °C) and at pH values between 5.5 and 8.0 (optimum 6.5-7.0).</s><s>Obligately anaerobic and slightly halophilic.</s><s>Requires NaCl at 0.5-5% (optimum 2%), but no growth occurs at 10% NaCl.</s><s>Ferments proteins, peptides, amino acids and some organic acids.</s><s>Able to ferment glutamate, histidine, cysteine and threonine.</s><s>Can use lysine, serine and valine in the presence of elemental sulfur or thiosulfate only.</s><s>Also ferments yeast and meat extracts, peptone, tryptone, casein hydrolysate, citrate, pyruvate and 2-oxoglutarate in both the presence and absence of sulfur or thiosulfate.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth.</s><s>Elemental sulfur and thiosulfate, but not sulfate or sulfite, are reduced to sulfide in the presence of fermentable substrates.</s><s>The presence of sulfur or thiosulfate increases the cell yield and the growth rate.</s><s>Cytochromes were not found.</s><s>Unable to utilize carbohydrates (glucose, sucrose, trehalose, arabinose, ribose, xylose, maltose, lactose, fructose, galactose, mannose), some organic acids (acetate, succinate, lactate, formate, fumarate, propionate, butyrate) or alcohols (ethanol, mannitol, glycerol, propanol) in either the presence or absence of yeast extract and thiosulfate.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, fumarate, nitrate, Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, MnO<sub>2</sub>, DMSO and elemental selenium are not reduced.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 51.8 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from `<i>Thiodendron</i>' bacterial sulfur mats in the littoral zone at Kandalaksha Bay (White Sea, Murmansk region, Russia).</s><s>The type strain is WS100<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the DSMZ as strain DSM 12537<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The type strain can be distinguished from strains SR12<sup>T</sup> and SR15<sup>T</sup> by DNA-DNA homology levels.</s></p></content></protolog>