<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1435_nm.1288" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1288" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1288" rank="species">Rhizobium huakuii</organism><reference id="rid.1435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>Y.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium huakuii sp. nov., isolated from the root nodules of Astragalus sinicus.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>275</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-275</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium huakuii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium huakuii</i> (hua.ku'i.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>huakuii</i>, in honor of the Chinese professor of soil microbiology Huakui Chen, who studied rhizobia isolated from <i>Astragalus sinicus</i> for nearly 50 years)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods (0.5 to 0.9 by 1.2 to 3.0 μm).</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Aerobic, possessing a respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Cells usually contain granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, semitranslucent, raised, and mucilaginous; they are usually 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 5 or 6 days on YMA.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, utilizing a wide range of carbohydrates, organic acids, and amino acids as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, fumarate, glucose, lactose, malate, maltose, raffinose, rhamnose, sodium lactate, sodium oxalate, succinate, and sucrose are utilized.</s><s>Alanine, ammonium tartrate, asparagine, caffine, cellulose, cysteine, dulcitol, ferulic acid, fucose, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid, inositol, melibiose, pyrocatechol, salicytol, sodium acetate, sodium benzonate, sodium citrate, sodium formate, sodium hippurate, sodium salicylate, sorbose, starch, and vanillic acid are not utilized.</s><s>Produces an acid reaction which is indicated by brommethyl blue in mineral salts medium containing mannitol.</s><s>Ammonium nitrate, urea, and many amino acids, including arginine, citrulline, lysine, methionine, ornithine monohydrochloride, threonine, tryptophan, and tyrosine, are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>DL-Leucine, D-methionine, and valine are not utilized.</s><s>Peptone is poorly utilized.</s><s>Some strains require thiamine, nicotinamide, and riboflavin for growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 25 to 30°C; most strains grow at 37°C but not at 39°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.0 to 9.5; the optimum pH is 6 to 8.</s><s>Methyl blue is reduced.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Produces a serum zone in litmus milk.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 to 64 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Rhizobium huakuii</i> is strain 103 (= CCBAU 2609), which is the center strain of this species group.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, it uses galactose, L-glutamate, D-mannose, sodium gluconate, sodium pyruvate, sorbitol, and trehalose as sole carbon sources and DL-asparagine and DL-serine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>It requires nicotinamide and riboflavin for growth and grows on YMA containing 1% NaCl.</s><s>It has been deposited in the Culture Collection of Beijing Agricultural University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</s></p></content></protolog>