<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11938_nm.20033" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20033" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20033" rank="species">Anaerococcus murdochii</organism><reference id="rid.11938"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Peptoniphilus gorbachii sp. nov., Peptoniphilus olsenii sp. nov., and Anaerococcus murdochii sp. nov. Isolated from Clinical Specimens of Human Origin</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>45</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1746</fpage><lpage>1752</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.00213-07</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17428937</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anaerococcus murdochii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anaerococcus murdochii</em> (<em>murdochii</em>, to honor D. A. Murdoch, who has contributed a great deal to our knowledge of anaerobic cocci).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccus shaped and gram positive.</s><s>Typical cells are ≥0.7 μm.</s><s>Colonies on brucella blood agar plates at 5 days are gray, flat or low convex, entire, circular, often matt, 1 to 2 mm in diameter with whiter centers.</s><s>They are obligately anaerobic; spot indole negative; and catalase, coagulase, urease, and nitrate negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>In peptone-yeast extract broth and peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth, major amounts of butyric acid and acetic acid are produced by all isolates.</s><s>By the Rapid ID 32A test, all isolates produce similar profiles.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase (strong or weak), histidine arylamidase (strong or weak), leucine arylamidase, and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>β-Glucosidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, and serine arylamidase results are variable.</s><s>Mannose is fermented, but not raffinose, when tested by the Rapid ID 32A system.</s><s>All the other tests are negative.</s><s>The strains are sensitive to vancomycin (5 μg) and resistant to colistin sulfate (10 μg); three strains are sensitive and two strains are resistant to kanamycin (1,000-μg) identification disks.</s><s>Agar dilution tests show that one strain is resistant to clindamycin (MIC, ≥64 μg/ml), and three strains show intermediate susceptibility or resistance to penicillin (MIC, ≥1 μg/ml).</s><s>All the others are susceptible to ampicillin-sulbactam (MIC, ≤0.25 μg/ml), cefazolin (MIC, ≤2 μg/ml), cefoxitin (MIC, ≤0.5 μg/ml), clindamycin (MIC, ≤1 μg/ml), imipenem (MIC, ≤0.062 μg/ml), metronidazole (MIC, ≤4 μg/ml), and vancomycin (MIC, ≤1 μg/ml).</s><s>The isolates are from human clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain is WAL 17230<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 53340<sup>T</sup> = ATCC BAA-1385<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>