<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4188_nm.7552" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7552" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7552" rank="species">Nocardiopsis trehalosi</organism><reference id="rid.4188"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taran</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis tropica sp. nov., Nocardiopsis trehalosi sp. nov., nom. rev. and Nocardiopsis dassonvillei subsp. albirubida subsp. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826789</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis trehalosi</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis trehalosi</i> (tre.ha.lo'si. M.L. adj. <i>trehalosi</i> referring to 3-trehalosamine, an aminoglycoside antibiotic that is produced by the type strain of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, oxidase- and catalase-positive nocardioform actinomycete.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white to cream or yellowish grey.</s><s>The colour of the substrate mycelium ranges from pale olive-brownish to pale orange-yellow.Alight yellow-brownish or light orange-yellow soluble pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>No melanin is observed on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP 6).</s><s>Aerial hyphae are zig-zag or twisted-ribbonlike at the beginning of sporulation; spores are irregularly sized (mostly elongated) and have a smooth surface.</s><s>Long branched substrate hyphae fragment into non-motile elements.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, L-rhamnose and D-xylose are used for growth as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, melibiose, D-sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose and D-xylose, but not from adonitol, D-galactose, <i>i</i>-inositol, melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbose or sucrose.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, lactate, malate, malonate, pyruvate, propionate, sebacate, succinate and tartrate are utilized ; no alkaline reaction occurs with aconitate, benzoate, salicylate and oxalate.</s><s>Casein, calcium oxalate crystals, hypoxanthine, xanthine, Tween 80 and urea are decomposed, but not tyrosine, Tween 40, Tween 60 and Tween 85.</s><s>Decomposition of aesculin is variable.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites.</s><s>The strain is resistant to 50 mg lysozyme ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Growth occurs on media supplemented with 5% (w/v) NaCl, 2.5% (v/v) methanol and 3% (v/v) ethanol, but no growth occurs at 10% (w/v) NaCl and 0.5% (v/v) butanol.</s><s>Growth temperature ranges between 18 and 45 °C; no growth occurs at 10 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth is at 28-37 °C.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>, H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Cell wall teichoic acid of poly(glycerol phosphate) with β-glucosyl residues.</s><s>Produces 3-trehalosamine.</s><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-942<sup>T</sup> (NRRL 12026<sup>T</sup>=JCM 3357<sup>T</sup>=IFO 14201<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The description above is based on the data of Dolak et al. (1980, 1981) and our study.</s></p></content></protolog>