<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12568_nm.21813" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21813" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21813" rank="species">Streptomyces samsunensis</organism><reference id="rid.12568"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sazak</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sahin</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Güven</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Isik</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces samsunensis sp. nov., a member of the Streptomyces violaceusniger clade isolated from the rhizosphere of Robinia pseudoacacia</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1309</fpage><lpage>1314</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021329-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656824</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces samsunensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces samsunensis</em> (sam.sun.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>samsunensis</em> from Samsun, Turkey, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore chains are spirals; the spore surface is rugose.</s><s>Grows well on modified Bennett’s, glucose-yeast extract-malt extract, glycerol-asparagine, inorganic salts-starch, tyrosine, yeast extract-malt extract, oatmeal and peptone-yeast extract-iron agars.</s><s>On oatmeal agar, the aerial spore mass colour is grey, becoming black and moist when mature, the substrate mycelium is greyish yellow and diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on either peptone-yeast extract-iron or tyrosine agars.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 37 °C, but not at 4 or 45 °C, and from pH 5.0 to 10.0, but not at pH 4.0 or 11.0.</s><s>Degrades arbutin, casein, starch, and Tweens 20 and 80, but not adenine, aesculin, chitin, DNA, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine, RNA, xanthine or xylan.</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, (−)-d-fructose, (+)-d-galactose, (+)-d-mannose, melezitose, trehalose, dextrin, maltose, d-mannitol, (+)-l-arabinose, (+)-l-rhamnose, l-glutamate and melibiose as sole carbon sources, but not adonitol, (+)-d-arabinose, (−)-d-sorbitol, inulin, (−)-l-sorbose, sucrose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, raffinose, sucrose, salicin, sodium propionate, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>Utilizes glycine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and l-isoleucine as sole nitrogen sources but not l-cysteine, l-methionine, l-valine, dl-phenylalanine or l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Sensitive to streptomycin sulphate (32 µg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Antimicrobial activity is shown against <em>Aspergillus niger</em> (isolated strain), <em>Bacillus licheniformis</em> NRRL B-1001, <em>Bacillus subtilis</em> NRRL B-209, <em>Candida albicans</em> ATCC 10231, <em>Listeria monocytogenes</em> (medical isolate), <em>Micrococcus luteus</em> NRRL B-287<sup>T</sup>, <em>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</em> NRRL B-2679, <em>Staphylococcus aureus</em> ATCC 25923 and <em>Streptomyces murinus</em> ISP 5091, but not against <em>Aspergillus flavus</em> NRRL 1957, <em>Escherichia coli</em> ATCC 25922, <em>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</em> ATCC 9763 or <em>Proteus vulgaris</em> NRRL B-123.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Tables 1 and 2.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids in whole-organism methanolysates are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is M1463<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 42010<sup>T</sup> = NRRL B-24803<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the rhizosphere of <em>Robinia pseudoacacia</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.8 mol%.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and hence serves as the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>