<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.54_nm.3355" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3355" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3355" rank="species">Yersinia bercovieri</organism><reference id="rid.54"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wauters</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Yersinia mollaretii sp. nov. and Yersinia bercovieri sp. nov., formerly called Yersinia enterocolitica biogroups 3A and 3B.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>424</fpage><lpage>429</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-424</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Yersinia bercovieri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Yersinia bercovieri</i> (ber. co. vi. e' ri. M. L. gen. n. <i>bercovieri</i>, in honor of Hervé Bercovier, who first described biogroups 3A and 3B and has made outstanding contributions to the taxonomy and ecology of yersiniae [see references 3-8, 10, and 19])</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Yersinia bercovieri</i> was formerly called <i>Y. enterocolitica</i> biogroup 3B (4) and was later transferred to biogroup 6 (21).</s><s>Cells are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, fermentative rods that are motile by peritrichous flagella at 25°C but not at 36°C.</s><s>The species conforms to the definitions of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (9) and the genus <i>Yersinia</i>(6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grow on nutrient, tryptic soy, and MacConkey agar media.</s><s>Whitish, opaque colonies about 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter with smooth, entire edges are formed on nutrient agar after 24 h at 25 or 36°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Good growth in 1 day in tryptic soy, nutrient, and brain heart infusion broth media incubated at 25 or 36°C.</s><s>More metabolically active at 25°C than at 36°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive reactions at 25°C in tests for methyl red, urea hydrolysis, L-ornithine decarboxylase, esculin hydrolysis (often delayed), acid production from mucate, tetrathionate reduction, Jordan tartrate, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, acetate utilization, nitrate reduction (nitratase B in all of the strains tested), pyrazinamidase, proline peptidase, and acid production from D-glucose, L-arabinose, cellobiose, L-fucose, D-galactose, glycerol (may be delayed), maltose, D-mannose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production, the Voges-Proskauer reaction, Simmons citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production on Kligler iron agar and peptone iron agar, phenylalanine deaminase, L-lysine decarboxylase, L-arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis, growth in KCN broth, malonate utilization, Tween 8Q esterase, deoxyribonuclease, pigment production, and acid production from adonitol, D-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, i- or my<i>o</i>-inositol, lactose, a-CH2-Dglucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, and L-sorbose.</s><s>Acid production from salicin is delayed positive in most strains.</s><s>A few strains produce small amounts of gas from D-glucose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50 mol%. <i>Y. bercovieri</i> strains have been isolated from human stool specimens, animals, raw vegetables, soil, and water.</s><s>There is no evidence of pathogenicity for humans.</s><s>The type strain of Y. bercovieri is strain WAIP 208 (= CDC 2475-87 = CNY 7506 = ATCC 43970).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 50 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This strain was isolated from a human stool specimen in France.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are given in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>