<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5951_nm.8837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8837" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8837" rank="species">Sejongia antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.5951"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>H.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sejongia antarctica gen. nov., sp. nov. and Sejongia jeonii sp. nov., isolated from the Antarctic</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>409</fpage><lpage>416</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63273-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653910</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sejongia antarctica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sejongia antarctica</em> (ant.arc′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>antarctica</em> named after Antarctica, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are approximately 1·0–3·1×0·4–0·5 μm.</s><s>Grows at 4–28 °C with notional optimum of 18·9 °C.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Decomposes casein and gelatin, but not agar, alginate, CM-cellulose, chitin, elastin or pectin.</s><s>Decomposes l-tyrosine weakly.</s><s>Positive reactions for lecithinase and Tween esterase are delayed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive and lipase (C14), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are negative in API ZYM kits.</s><s>Cannot assimilate any of the compounds contained in API 20NE kits as a sole carbon source.</s><s>Does not produce acid aerobically from d-raffinose or d-salicin.</s><s>Produces acid fermentatively from d-glucose, d-maltose, starch and glycogen, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose (bovine origin), d-melibiose, d-sucrose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate in the API 50 CH kit.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Fatty acid profile is given in Table 2.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 34 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AT1013<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 14040<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12225<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12381<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a soil sample of penguin habitats near the King Sejong Station on King George Island, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>