<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3151_nm.7539" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7539" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7539" rank="species">Nocardiopsis exhalans</organism><reference id="rid.3151"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peltola</surname><given-names>J.S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersson</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Auling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation of toxigenic Nocardiopsis strains from indoor environments and description of two new Nocardiopsis Species, N. exhalans sp. nov. and N. umidischolae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>67</volume><fpage>4293</fpage><lpage>4304</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/AEM.67.9.4293-4304.2001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11526036</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis exhalans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis exhalans</i> (ex.ha'lans. L. partic. adj. <i>exhalans</i>, emitting odors, fumes, toxins, etc.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The vegetative hyphae are yellowish and penetrate agar.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are white, slightly spiral shaped, and 0.5 μm in diameter and fragment to form rod-shaped, nonmotile spores.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Catalase positive and aerobic.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10, 28, and 37°C; no growth at 50°C.</s><s>Assimilates arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, gluconate, glucose, mannose, maltose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, mannitol, putrescine, acetate, cis-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, suberate, L-alanine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, 4-hydroxybenzoate, and phenylacetate, but not N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, arbutin, galactose, melibiose, salicin, adonitol, inositol, maltitol, sorbitol, propionate, adipate, itaconate, lactate, malate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, β-alanine, aspartate, histidine, leucine, ornithine, tryptophan, or 3-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase and α-glucosidase are produced.</s><s>The fatty acid profile includes straight-chain saturated and unsaturated fatty acids, branchedchain fatty acids of the iso and anteiso types, and 10-methyl branched-chain fatty acids.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones were MK-10 (H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10 (H<sub>8</sub>), and relatively high concentrations of MK-10 (H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9 (H<sub>6</sub>), and MK-9 (H<sub>8</sub>) were found.</s><s>Mesodiaminopimelic acid was the diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern was composed of the diagnostic phosphatidylcholine, and phosphatidylinositol, phosphotidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the indoor air of the basement of a water-damaged building of which the occupants suffered from nonspecific health symptoms.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis exhalans</i> is strain ES10.1 (5DSM 44407 = NRRL B-24123).</s></p></content></protolog>