<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9472_nm.14613" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14613" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14613" rank="species">Virgibacillus arcticus</organism><reference id="rid.9472"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Niederberger</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steven</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Charvet</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whyte</surname><given-names>L.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus arcticus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, endospore-forming bacterium from permafrost in the Canadian high Arctic</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2219</fpage><lpage>2225</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002931-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605723</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus arcticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus arcticus</em> (arc′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>arcticus</em> northern, Arctic, the place of origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, motile rods (0.5–0.8×2–5 μm) occurring as single, paired or rarely as short chains of cells.</s><s>Colonies are 2 mm in diameter after 1 week of incubation on ¼ HM at room temperature.</s><s>Forms elliptical endospores, located centrally or subterminally.</s><s>Capable of anaerobic growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–30 °C, but no growth is observed at −5 or 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs from 0 to 20 % NaCl (optimum, 5 % NaCl); no growth occurs at 25 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows between pH 4.4 and 9.1 (optimum, about pH 7.0).</s><s>Growth occurs on d-glucose and sucrose, but not on d-lactose, cellobiose, melibiose or trehalose as sole carbon source.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for gelatinase and nitrate reduction, but negative for ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, amygdalin or l-arabinose; acid is produced weakly from d-glucose, d-mannitol and melibiose.</s><s>In API Staph tests, acid is produced from trehalose, d-mannitol, xylitol and melibiose; acid is produced weakly from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose and lactose.</s><s>Negative for production of alkaline phosphatase and acetyl-methyl-carbinol, and acid production from raffinose, xylose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside.</s><s>Negative for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, rifampicin, erythromycin and streptomycin.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;1 %) of the type strain are iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The peptidoglycan and respiratory quinone types are A1<em>α</em> and MK-7, respectively.</s><s>Major polar lipids comprise diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and two unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Hal 1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19574<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14839<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a permafrost core of 9 m depth collected near Eureka, Ellesmere Island, in the Canadian high Arctic.</s></p></content></protolog>