<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12718_nm.22485" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22485" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22485" rank="species">Shewanella indica</organism><reference id="rid.12718"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pandey</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patole</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shouche</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella indica sp. nov., isolated from sediment of the Arabian Sea</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2058</fpage><lpage>2064</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026310-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851908</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella indica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella</em><em /> <em>indica</em> (in′di.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>indica</em> of India, Indian).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On marine agar, aerobically grown colonies after 48 h at 37 °C are pale brown, circular, low convex with entire margins and butterous consistency, translucent and approximately 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum (Fig. 2), rod-shaped (0.5–0.7×1.5–2.0 µm), Gram-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 2 %), at pH 6.5–10 (optimum, pH 7.5) and at 10–45 °C (optimum, 37 °C).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite, which is not further reduced.</s><s>Negative for glucose, sucrose and lactose fermentation.</s><s>Shows β-haemolysis.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, chitin, gelatin, Tween 80 and urea.</s><s>Produces H<sub>2</sub>S but not acetoin or indole and utilizes citrate and malonate.</s><s>Negative for phenylalanine deaminase production and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions.</s><s>Produces acid from mannose, but not from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, dulcitol, fructose, galactose, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>With lactate as the substrate, sulfur, TMAO, DMSO, nitrate, nitrite and thiosulfate are reduced, but ferric citrate, manganese dioxide, sulfite and dichromate are not.</s><s>In the GN VITEK-2 gallery, positive for Ala-Phe-Pro-arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, glutamyl arylamidase pNA, γ-glutamyl transferase, tyrosine arylamidase, urease, l-lactate alkalinization, succinate alkalinization, phosphatase, glycine arylamidase and Glu-Gly-Arg-arylamidase.</s><s>The remaining reactions of the GN VITEK-2 gallery are negative (Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>The following carbon substrates are oxidized (positive in the Biolog GN2 system): Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, α-d-glucose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, d,l-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine and putrescine.</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not oxidized (Supplementary Table S2).</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated) ofloxacin (5), sparfloxacin (5), aztreonam (30), azithromycin (15), erythromycin (15), penicillin (10 U), ciprofloxacin (5), clarithromycin (15), cefadroxil (30), ampicillin (10), cefaclor (30), augmentin (30), cefotaxime (30), cefoperazone (75), co-trimoxazole (25), amikacin (30), streptomycin (25), chloramphenicol (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), ceftriaxone (30), cefalexin (30), netillin (30), gatifloxacin (30), cefoxitin (30), carbenicillin (100) and clindamycin (2), but resistant to vancomycin (30), doxycycline hydrochloride (30), cefuroxime (30), teicoplanin (30), metronidazole (5) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>) (Supplementary Table S4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KJW27<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23171<sup>T</sup>  = BCC 41031<sup>T</sup>  = NCIM 5388<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the sediments collected in the western coastal region of India (Karwar district, Karnataka).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>