<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2989_nm.6490" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6490" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6490" rank="species">Rhodococcus maris</organism><reference id="rid.2989"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nesterenko</surname><given-names>O.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogina</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasumova</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kvasnikov</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Batrakov</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus luteus nom. nov. and Rhodococcus maris nom. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-1</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus maris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cell morphology of group II bacteria. After 16 to 18 h of incubation on NA, GA, and WA slants, the cells were short ovoids (0.6 to 1.0 μm by 1.0 to 2.0 μm) arranged in an angular fashion.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Time-lapse microscopy revealed (Fig. 2) that the coccoid cells (0.8 μm in length) elongated to 2.0 μm within 6 h of cultivation.</s><s>The rods then divided by snapping, and V forms were produced.</s><s>The angles between the attached daughter cells became smaller, and the cells were then arranged in parallel.</s><s>After several divisions of the rods, microcolonies were produced.</s><s>Growth and division of cells occurred at the edges of the colonies, but at the centers of the microcolonies, the cells did not elongate; with each new division, the cells became shorter and eventually transformed into coccoid forms.</s><s>After 36 to 48 h, the microcolonies consisted of short, straight rods and coccoid forms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group II organisms were gram-positive, were not acid-fast, were nonmotile, and did not form endospores.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics of group II organisms.</s><s>Growth on NA, GA, and WA slants was moderate or poor, butyrous, and orange.</s><s>Colonies on the surface of NA were raised, butyrous, glistening, and circular with an entire edge.</s><s>Nutrient broth became turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and chemotaxonomic characteristics.</s><s>The results of the physiological tests are listed in Tables 7-9.</s><s>Growth occurred in the aerobic and anaerobic tubes of Hugh and Leifson medium, but as a rule, the indicator was not changed to the acid color.</s><s>Catalase was produced.</s><s>Casein, cellulose, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, and xanthine were not attacked.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, indole, <i>p</i>-nitrophenoloxidase, phosphatase, and H<sub>2</sub>S were not produced.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40, 60, and 80 were hydrolyzed.</s><s>No growth occurred with either acetamide or benzamide (84% of the strains were negative) as the sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>γ-Aminobutyrate, benzoate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, α-ketoglutarate, lactate, oxalate, and tartrate were not utilized.</s><s>Acetate, butyrate, fumarate, malate, pyruvate, and succinate were utilized.</s><s>Acid was produced from fructose, glucose, and glycerol.</s><s>No acid was produced from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose , dulcitol, galactose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose (84% of the strains were negative), or xylose.</s><s>Growth occurred in the presence of 5 and 7% NaCl and of C<sub>6</sub>, C<sub>7</sub>, C<sub>8</sub>, (83% of the strains were positive), C<sub>9</sub> to C<sub>17</sub>, C<sub>19</sub>, and C<sub>23</sub> <i>n</i>-alkanes.</s><s>No growth occurred with methane or ethane.</s><s>No growth occurred at 45°C.</s><s>Nitrate was reduced to nitrite.</s><s>There was no change in litmus milk.</s><s>The liquefaction of gelatin, the production of NH<sub>3</sub> from peptone, the decomposition of urea, the utilization of citrate, and the production of acid from mannose were quite variable within the group (Table 9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains contained <i>meso</i>-DAP, arabinose, and galactose in their whole-cell hydrolysates and had a lipid LCN-A chromatographically similar to that of <i>R. erythropolis</i> NCIB 8863.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of strain 195 was 73.2 mol% by thermal denaturation.</s><s>The main fatty acids of stationary-phase cells of this strain were (percentage of total detected): C<sub>16:1</sub> (12%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (17%), C<sub>17:1</sub> (16.5%), C<sub>17:0</sub> (10%), C<sub>18:1</sub> (14.5%), and 10CH<sub>3</sub>C<sub>18</sub> (9.2%).</s><s>Strain 195 possessed MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) as the major isoprenolog, with smaller quantities of MK-6 and traces of MK-8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of the following characteristics, group II bacteria may be classified in the genus of <i>Rhodococcus</i> in the family <i>Nocardiaceae</i> (9,11,13): gram-positive, nonmotile, pleomorphic, do not form endospores, produce soft colonies aerial mycelium, and possess a cell wall of chemotype IV, a lipid LCN-A of the <i>R. erythropolis</i> NCIB 8863 type, a guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of 73.2 mol%, fatty acids containing a high proportion of tuberculostearic acid, straight-chain, and unsaturated acids, and a menaquinone, MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), as the major isoprenolog.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A comparison of group II properties with those of the type or reference strains of 10 established <i>Rhodococcus</i> species (Table 6) indicates that the members of group II also belong to a distinct species of <i>Rhodococcus</i>.</s><s>With respect to the name of this species, the following must be taken into consideration.</s><s>On the basis of morphological, cultural, and physiological properties, the isolates of group II may be identified as members of "<i>B. maris</i>" (Harrison 1929) Breed 1953 (synonym: "<i>Flavobacterium maris</i>" Harrison 1929) (8, 20).</s><s>The strains closely resemble "<i>B. maris</i>" AUCNM B-464 (Tables 6-9), which has a lipid LCN-A similar to that of <i>R. erythropolis</i> NCIB 8863 and a cell wall of chemotype IV; the same wall chemotype was found (44) in another strain of "<i>B. maris</i>", viz., AJ 1480 (=IFM S-30).</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is obvious that at present the genus <i>Brevibacterium</i> is a heterogeneous taxon.</s><s>Some of its members have cell walls of chemotype IV and produce glutamic acid; they were thus named <i>C. glutamicum</i> and were considered to be members of the genus <i>Corynebacterium</i> sensu stricto (1).</s><s>Many other species with ornithine or lysine in the cell wall were transferred from <i>Brevibacterium</i> to either the genus <i>Curtobacterium</i> or the genus <i>Arthrobacter</i> (44).</s><s>The chemotaxonomic properties mentioned above indicate that "<i>B. maris</i>' cannot be classified as a member of the genus <i>Arthrobacter</i> as suggested by Rogosa and Keddie (33).</s><s>Gordon (15) has pointed out that strains with the properties of "'<i>M.' rhodochrous</i>" may previously have been identified as members of the genus <i>Brevibacterium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>According to Yamada and Komagata (44), only strains of <i>B. finens</i> containing <i>meso</i>-DAP in their cell walls can be considered bona fide members of <i>Brevibacterium</i>.</s><s>Subsequently, other authors have stated that <i>B. linens</i> contains ribose but not arabinose or mycolic acids in its cell wall (12, 23, 32, 35).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Our data indicate that "<i>B . maris</i>" corresponds to the isolates of our group II and that these organisms should be classified as a species of the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i>, for which we propose the name <i>Rhodococcus maris</i>.</s><s>As with "<i>M. luteum</i>", the name "<i>Brevibacterium maris</i>" was not included on the Approved Lists (37).</s><s>By reason of the same arguments give above for "<i>M . luteum</i>", the name <i>R. maris</i> should be regarded as a new name.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain IMV 195 (= AUCNM A-593) is the type strain of <i>R. maris</i>.</s><s>A description of this strain is presented in Table 6. (It should be noted that a type or neotype strain was never officially established for "<i>B . maris</i>")</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tests useful for differentiating <i>R. maris</i> and <i>R. luteus</i> from each other and from the type or reference strains of 10 established <i>Rhodococcus</i> species (11, 34) are given in Table 10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In contrast to the rhodococci studied by Gordon (15), <i>R. maris</i> did not oxidize glucose in Hugh and Leifson medium.</s><s>The morphological cycle of <i>R. maris</i> is characterized by a rapid changing of very short rods into coccoid forms without the formation of primary mycelium.</s></p></content></protolog>