<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4429_nm.3948" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3948" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3948" rank="species">Clostridium hungatei</organism><reference id="rid.4429"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Monserrate</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leschine</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium hungatei sp. nov., a mesophilic, N(2)-fixing cellulolytic bacterium isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>123</fpage><lpage>132</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium hungatei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium hungatei</i> (hun.gat'e.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>hungatei</i> of Hungate, named after R. E. Hungate who pioneered the study of the ecology of cellulolytic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, subpolarly flagellated, slightly curved rod (0.5x2.0-6.0 μm) which form round terminal spores (0.8-1.0 μm) when grown in agar medium (medium DNFcb).</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and have a multilayered cell wall.</s><s>Surface colonies (in medium DNFcb­N containing 1.5 g agar per 100 ml medium) are smooth, slightly raised, circular, unpigmented, with butyrous texture and measure 1-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is between 30 and 40 °C, both under N<sub>2</sub>-fixing conditions and in the presence of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl.</s><s>Maximum growth temperature is 45 °C; no growth is observed at either 50 or 15 °C.</s><s>The optimum initial pH for growth in medium DNFcb is 7.2.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic, cellulolytic, N<sub>2</sub>-fixing, utilizes carbohydrates as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Fermentable compounds include cellulose, cellobiose, cellotriose, cellotetraose, cellopentaose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-xylose, xylan and gentiobiose.</s><s>Strain B3B also ferments L-arabinose.</s><s>The following substrates are not fermented: D-ribose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, glycerol, starch, pectin, polygalacturonic acids and Bacto-tryptone (Difco).</s><s>Exogenous vitamins or fatty acids are not required for growth.</s><s>Products of cellulose fermentation are H<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, acetate, ethanol, lactate and formate.</s><s>Cells produce an extracellular cellulase system that yields a large 650000 M<sub>r</sub> protein peak (A<sub>280</sub>) upon fractionation by Sephacryl S-300 gel filtration.</s><s>Grows in the presence of rifampin, streptomycin, penicillin, erythromycin and vancomycin.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by tetracycline, ampicillin, kanamycin, neomycin or chloramphenicol.</s><s>Isolated from moist soil rich in decaying plant material.</s><s>Strains AD<sup>T</sup> and B3B are phylogenetically closely related, based on 16S rRNA sequence analysis (99.5% sequence similarity).</s><s>The DNA G+­C content of is 40 mol%(strain AD<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Type strain is strain AD<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700212<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>