<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7102_nm.2317" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2317" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2317" rank="species">Hydrogenovibrio marinus</organism><reference id="rid.7102"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishihara</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Igarashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kodama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenovibrio marinus gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine obligately chemolithoautotrophic hydrogen-oxidizing bacterium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>130</fpage><lpage>133</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-130</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hydrogenovibrio</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hydrogenovibrio</i> (Hy.dro.ge.no.vib'ri.o. Gr. n. <i>hydro</i>, water; Gr. n. <i>genus</i>, offspring; M.L. masc. n. <i>hydrogenum</i>, hydrogen, that which produces water; M.L. masc. n. <i>Vibrio</i>, a generic name; M. L. masc. n. <i>Hydrogenovibrio</i>, hydrogen vibrio)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of <i>Hydrogenovibrio marinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Hydrogenovibrio marinus</i> (ma.ri'nus.</s><s>L. adj. <i>marinus</i>, marine, of the sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are comma-shaped rods (0.2 to 0.5 by 1 to 2 μm) that occur singly.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Nonsporulating.</s><s>Motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Respiratory metabolism; molecular oxygen is used as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Obligately chemolithoautotrophic, using molecular hydrogen or reduced sulfur compounds, such as elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, and tetrathionate, as electron donors and carbon dioxide as the carbon source.</s><s>Hydrogenase is membrane bound and does not reduce pyridine nucleotides.</s><s>Type b, c, and u cytochromes have been found.</s><s>Carbon dioxide is fixed via the Calvin-Benson cycle.</s><s>Ammonium ions and urea are utilized as sole nitrogen sources, but nitrate ions, nitrite ions, and gaseous nitrogen are not.</s><s>Nitrite inhibits growth.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 37°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is around 6.5.</s><s>Halophilic, with an optimum NaCl concentration for growth of around 0.5 M.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44.1 mol% (as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight-chain saturated C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>18:0</sub> acids and a straight-chain unsaturated C<sub>16:1</sub> acid are the major components of the cellular fatty acids.</s><s>Ubiquinone-8 is the major component of the quinone system.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from seawater from the Shonan Coast, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain MH-110 (= JCM 7688).</s></p></content></protolog>