<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8253_nm.13680" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13680" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13680" rank="species">Weissella ghanensis</organism><reference id="rid.8253"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Bruyne</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Camu</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vuyst</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Weissella ghanensis sp. nov., isolated from a Ghanaian cocoa fermentation.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2721</fpage><lpage>2725</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65853-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060047</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Weissella ghanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Weissella ghanensis</em> (gha.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>ghanensis</em> pertaining to Ghana).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>They do not form spores.</s><s>Gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Cells are small rods (1.0 μm wide and 2.0–4.0 μm long) and appear singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies are beige, opaque, smooth, circular or irregular with low convex elevation and entire margins and are 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth is obtained at 15–37 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed in MRS broth supplemented with 5 % NaCl.</s><s>For strain 215<sup>T</sup>, lactic acid (d/l, 90 : 10), acetic acid, ethanol and gas formation are detected after growth on glucose, indicating the heterofermentative nature of this strain.</s><s>Strain 194B produces different end metabolites.</s><s>Both lactic acid and acetic acid are detected as end products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Mainly d-lactate (d/l, 95 : 5) is produced and no gas production is observed.</s><s>Strain 215<sup>T</sup> and strain 194B both produce slime from sucrose and are able to hydrolyse arginine.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose and gentiobiose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, galactose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Strain 215<sup>T</sup> produces acid from sucrose; strain 194B does not produce acid from sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 215<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24286<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19935<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Ghanaian cocoa bean heaps undergoing fermentation.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.0 mol%.</s><s>The two available strains (215<sup>T</sup> and 194B) both originated from the same cocoa bean heap undergoing fermentation in New Tafo, Ghana.</s><s>However, Camu <em>et al.</em> (2007) detected this organism in five out of seven spontaneous heap fermentations of cocoa beans studied, indicating that this species is common in Ghanaian cocoa bean heaps that are undergoing fermentation.</s></p></content></protolog>