<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7487_nm.6290" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6290" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6290" rank="species">Gordonia alkanivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7487"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kummer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordonia alkanivorans sp. nov., isolated from tar-contaminated soil</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1513</fpage><lpage>1522</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1513</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555331</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordonia alkanivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gordonia alkanivorans</i> (al.ka.ni'vo.rans. M.L. n. <i>alkanum</i> saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to eat; L. adj. <i>alkanivorans</i> alkane-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, regular rod-shaped cells (0.5-0.9 x 1.0-2.3 μm) occurring singly, in pairs, small clusters, in V-shape arrangement or in short chains.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Mycelium absent.</s><s>Rod-coccus growth cycle.</s><s>Colonies orange to orange-red.</s><s>Colony morphology either convex and smooth or rough and flat with irregular margins.</s><s>When grown on hexadecane or hexadecene as sole carbon source the orange colour fades.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Acid production observed from fructose, glycerol, D-mannitol, saccharose and D-sorbitol, but not from Dglucose.</s><s>The alkali salts acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, succinate, propionate and pyruvate were used for growth, but lactate, oxalate and tartrate were not utilized.</s><s>Nitrogenous compounds like ammonia, nitrate and urea were utilized.</s><s>Tween 80 and potato starch were hydrolysed.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, adenine, gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, tyrosine and xanthine were not decomposed.</s><s>Formation of H<sub>2</sub>S was positive, whereas production of indole, the Voges-Proskauer test and the methyl red test were negative.</s><s>Susceptible to the antibiotics ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), nitrofuran (100 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and sulfonamide (250 μg), but weakly susceptible to erythromycin (15 μg), oxacillin (5 μg), penicillin G (10 IU), polymycin B (300 IU).</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin (2 μg).</s><s>The following carbon substrates were not utilized: glycogen, D-arabitol, maltose, D-xylose, α-ketoglutaric acid and L-alanine, but α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, dextrin, D-mannose, D-trehalose, turanose, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, N-acetyl-L-glutamic acid, Tween 40 and 80, D-fructose, α-D-glucose, D-psicose, saccharose, methyl pyruvate and pyruvic acid were utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains nzeso-A<sub>2</sub>pm as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The predominant isoprenologue is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>); minor amounts of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Contains major amounts of straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated fatty acids and tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids with less than 60 carbon atoms are present.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 68 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from contaminated soil sampled from the area of a former tar factory in Rositz (Germany).</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0136<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44369<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>