<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12454_nm.21282" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21282" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21282" rank="species">Nonomuraea endophytica</organism><reference id="rid.12454"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonomuraea endophytica sp. nov., an endophytic actinomycete isolated from Artemisia annua L.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>757</fpage><lpage>761</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022558-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20435751</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nonomuraea endophytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nonomuraea endophytica</em> (en.do.phy′ti.ca. Gr. pref. <em>endo</em> within; Gr. <em>phyton</em> plant; L. fem. suff. -<em>ica</em> adjectival suffix used with the sense of belonging to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>endophytica</em> within plant, endophytic, pertaining to the isolation of the type strain from plant tissues).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-stain-positive, aerobic, non-motile actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelia; soluble pigments are produced on most test media.</s><s>The aerial mycelium develops masses of long, straight spore chains, each containing more than 20 non-motile spores, which show a warty ornamentation.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–37 °C, with optimal growth at 20–28 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is pH 6.0–9.0, with optimal growth at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, milk coagulation, milk peptonization and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, gelatin liquefaction, hydrolysis of urea, cellulose and starch and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed, but Tweens 40 and 80 are not.</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, ribose, d-sorbitol and sucrose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>l-Arabinose, dulcitol, glycerol, d-mannose, sodium acetate and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-hydroxyproline, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine and l-valine can be used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Hypoxanthine and tyrosine are decomposed, but not xanthine.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Cell hydrolysates contain galactose, glucose, mannose, ribose and madurose.</s><s>Polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxyphosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total) are 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 65601<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AA 209037<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 45385<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a surface-sterilized sample of <em>Artemisia annua</em> L. collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>