<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3173_nm.3504" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3504" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3504" rank="species">Desulfovibrio sulfodismutans</organism><reference id="rid.3173"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bak</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemolithotrophic growth of Desulfovibrio sulfodismutans sp. nov. by disproportionation of inorganic compounds.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>147</volume><fpage>184</fpage><lpage>189</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00415282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfovibrio sulfodismutans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfovibrio sulfodismutans</i> (Sul. fo. dis' mu. tans. L.n. <i>sulfur</i> sulfur; L. pref <i>dis</i> apart; L. part. adj. <i>mutans</i> that which changes; M.L. part. adj. <i>sulfodismutans</i> dismutating sulfur compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile, curved rods, sometimes sigrnoid or spirilloid, 0.75 x 2.5-3.5 μm.</s><s>No spore formation.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Thiosulfate, sulfite, or dithionite are utilized as energy sources and disproportionated to sulfate and sulfide.</s><s>Acetate and bicarbonate are required as carbon sources.</s><s>Lactate, ethanol, propanol or butanol serve as substrates for dissimilatory sulfate reduction and are incompletely oxidized.</s><s>Not utilized as electron donors are: Formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, fumarate, succinate, malate, pyruvate, choline, fructose, and benzoate.</s><s>Elemental sulfur, nitrate furmarate, and malate are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Growth requires mineral medium (1 g NaCl and 0.4g MgCl<sub>2</sub>⋄6H<sub>2</sub>O per l) and sulfide or dithionite as reducing agents.</s><s>Pantothenate and biotin are required as growth factors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selective enrichment culture is possible with sulfite (5 mmol/l), acetate (1 mmol/l), and bicarbonate from anoxic freshwater sediments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 6.8-8.2, optimum 7.3.</s><s>Temperature range: 15 - 45°C, optimum at 35°C.</s><s>Cells contain cytochromes and desulfoviridin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 64.1 mol% G + C (CsCl-gradientultracentrifugation, Flossdorf 1983).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats: Anaerobic mud of freshwater, brackish water or marine environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ThAc01, DSM 3696, deposited in: Deutsche Sammlung yon Mikroorganismen, Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>