<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4555_nm.10751" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10751" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10751" rank="species">Gracilibacillus boraciitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.4555"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ahmed</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujiwara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus boraciitolerans sp. nov., a highly boron-tolerant and moderately halotolerant bacterium isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>796</fpage><lpage>802</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64284-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392209</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilibacillus boraciitolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gracilibacillus boraciitolerans</em> (bo.ra′ci.i.to′le.rans. N.L. n. <em>boracium</em> boron; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>boraciitolerans</em> boron-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile using a long monotrichous flagellum.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods, 2.0–4.5 μm in length, 0.3–0.9 μm in diameter, occurring singly, occasionally in pairs; filamentous cells also occur.</s><s>Spherical endospores are produced in a non-swollen or slightly swollen sporangium in a terminal or subterminal position.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire margins, spreading but slightly convex, translucent and viscous in texture, 2–3 mm in diameter after 4 days growth on BUG agar medium (pH 7.5) at 30 °C.</s><s>Younger colonies are dirty white, but become pink and then red in a few to several days.</s><s>The pink or red pigment may diffuse into the agar medium after several days.</s><s>Colonies are mostly light pink at high salt concentrations.</s><s>Grows optimally at 25–28 °C; the temperature range for growth is 16–37 °C; no growth occurs at ≥45 °C and little growth at 16 °C after several days.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.5–8.5, with a range of pH 6.0–10.0.</s><s>The type strain can tolerate 0–450 mM boron, but grows optimally in the absence of boron.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is 0–11 % (w/v), indicating that the type strain is moderately halotolerant; it can grow on MA, TSA and NA (with or without boron or NaCl).</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, Voges–Proskauer and <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside (ONPG) tests are positive, whereas tests for production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase, utilization of citrate and hydrolysis of gelatin and urea are negative (API 20E).</s><s>Can produce acid from l-arabinose, d-ribose, glucose, d-mannose, aesculin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose and d-trehalose; weakly positive for acid production from d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-fructose, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol (API 50CHB).</s><s>Can oxidize 3-methyl glucose, amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, d-xylose, gentiobiose, glycerol, lactulose, l-arabinose, maltose, maltotriose, palatinose, salicin, sucrose, turanose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, dl-lactic acid, d-glucuronic acid, gluconic acid, pyruvic acid and <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid (Biolog).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are: anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (45.7 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (18.2 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (16.9 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (3.2 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (5.3 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.9 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.9 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1.0 %) and traces (less than 1 %) of some other fatty acids.</s><s>The cell wall contains peptidoglycan with <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic amino acid, representing cell-wall peptidoglycan type A1<em>γ</em>.</s><s>The dominant respiratory lipoquinone system is MK-7.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>In addition, moderate to minor amounts of an unknown aminolipid and three polar lipids are detected.</s><s>Strong enzyme activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, whereas weak enzyme activity is observed for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, esterase (C8), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, amoxicillin and metronidazol (ATB-VET Strip).</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 35.8 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain T-16X<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17256<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15263<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1190<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from soil naturally containing boron minerals from the Hisarcik area in the Kutahya Province of Turkey, is the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>