<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1803_nm.2225" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2225" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2225" rank="species">Xanthomonas oryzae</organism><reference id="rid.1803"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van den Mooter</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vauterin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mew</surname><given-names>T.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of the causal agents of bacterial blight (Xanthomonas campestris pv. oryzae) and bacterial leaf streak (Xanthomonas campestris pv. oryzicola) of rice as pathovars of Xanthomonas oryzae, (ex Ishiyama 1922) sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>309</fpage><lpage>311</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i> (Ishiyama 1922) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i> (o.ry'zae. Gr. n. <i>oryza</i>, rice; M. L. gen. n. <i>oryzae</i>, pertaining to rice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>X. oryzae</i> is the same as the description of the genus.</s><s>The phenotypic characteristics described below are based on the data of Vera Cruz et al. (15) and Van den Mooter (Ph.D. thesis, Rijksuniversiteit, Ghent, Belgium, 1984).</s><s>Cells are straight rods, 0.4 to 0.8 by 1.5 to 2.9 μm.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs, or sometimes in chains.</s><s>Filaments may occur.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Catalase present.</s><s>Indole formation, 2-ketogluconate formation, urease, egg yolk hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, and oxidase are all negative.</s><s>Carbon sources are used oxidatively and never fermentatively.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed after 7 days.</s><s>Growth occurs on D-xylose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, sodium fumarate, sodium L-lactate, sodium  L-malate, sodium oxaloacetate, and sodium succinate, but not on L-arabinose, D-ribose, L-rhamnose, lactose, raffinose, inulin, methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, ethanediol, mesoinositol, sorbitol, dulcitol, adenine, guanine, cytosine, thymine, sodium-potassium tartrate, sodium glyoxylate, 2-ketogluconic acid, tannic acid, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid, hydroquinone, phloroglucinol, resorcinol, amygdalin, arbutin, or esculin.</s><s>Acid is formed from D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, cellobiose, and trehalose but not from D-ribose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, dulcitol, adonitol, maltose, lactose, or inulin.</s><s>Litmus milk is never acidified.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 35°C or in the presence of 3% NaCl.</s><s>Weak growth occurs at 32 and 10°C.</s><s>Esculin, Tween 40, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is formed.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in media containing 0.001% (w/vol) tetracycline hydrochloride, 0.005% chloramphenicol, 0.001% novobiocin, or 0.001% doxycycline, but not in media containing 0.001% trimethoprim or 0.005% metronidazole.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. oryzae</i> can be differentiated phenotypically from <i>X. campestris</i> by the following two features, for which <i>X. oryzae</i> is negative and <i>X. campestris</i> is positive: lecithinase activity and growth on sodium-propionate as a carbon source.</s><s>The most reliable way to differentiate <i>X. oryzae</i> from other <i>Xanthomonas</i> species is by sodium dodecyl sulfatepolyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of whole-cell proteins (8), fatty acid profiles (1 3), and specific monoclonal antibodies (1) or by DNA-DNA hybridization.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine values range from 64.6 to 65 mol%.</s><s>The neotype strain is strain PDDCC 3125(= NCCPPB 3002 = Dye YK9 = Rao X08 = LMG 5047).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>X. oryzae</i> contains the causal agents of bacterial blight and leaf streak of rice.</s><s>The two groups constitute a single DNA cluster and species in which no other <i>X. campestris</i> pathovar of grasses or cereals belongs (Table 1).</s><s>A DNA-DNA binding value of 86% is too high to create a subspecies for each group.</s><s>Nevertheless, the two pathovars are phytopathologically and phenotypically so clearly different that we propose to keep them as separate pathovars within <i>X. oryzae</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s><s>We propose the two pathovars described below.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i> pv. <i>oryzae</i> (Ishiyama 1922) comb. nov. causes leaf blight or kresek symptoms on rice (11).</s><s>Bacterial blight occurs in Asia, the Americas, Africa, and Australia and in tropical and temperate climates.</s><s>The pathovar reference strain is strain PDDCC 3125 (=NCPPB 3002=Dye YK9=Rao X08=LMG 5047).</s><s>Currently six pathogenic races are identified in the Philippines on the basis of differential cultivars (9, 10), but many more are suspected.</s><s>No correlation was found between phenotype or protein electrophoretic fingerprinting on the one hand and the pathogenic races on the other hand (15).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i> pv. <i>oryzicola</i> (Fang, Ren, Chen, Chu, Faan, and Wu 1957) comb. nov. causes bacterial leaf streak symptoms on rice.</s><s>It is widely distributed in tropical Asia.</s><s>The pathovar reference strain is strain PDDCC 5743 (=NCPPB 1585=ICPB X0111=Hayward B2115=LMG 797).</s><s>No pathogenic races have been distinguished.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiation between <i>X. oryzae</i> pv. <i>oryzae</i> and <i>X. oryzae</i> pv. <i>oryzicola</i> is possible by (i) the symptoms caused in rice (11), (ii) a few phenotypic features (15), (iii) polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis protein fingerprints (8, 15), (iv) fatty acid profiles (13), and (v) pathovar-specific monoclonal antibodies (1).</s></p></content></protolog>