<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12470_nm.21300" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21300" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21300" rank="species">Lactobacillus kimchicus</organism><reference id="rid.12470"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Z.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivasan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.-B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus kimchicus sp. nov., a β-glucosidase-producing bacterium isolated from kimchi</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>894</fpage><lpage>897</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017418-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lactobacillus kimchicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lactobacillus kimchicus</em> (kim.chi′cus. N.L. n. <em>kimchium</em> kimchi; L. masc. suff. -<em>icus</em> suffix used with the sense of pertaining to; N.L. masc. adj. <em>kimchicus</em> pertaining to kimchi, isolated from kimchi).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-reaction-positive, non-spore-forming and non-motile bacteria.</s><s>Cells are slender rods, 0.3–0.8×1.0–2.0 µm when grown on MRS agar at 37 °C, and occur singly, in pairs or, occasionally, in short chains.</s><s>After 2 days on MRS agar, colonies are white, round to convex and smooth with entire edges, approximately 0.8–1.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-negative.</s><s>Oxidizes glucose to d-lactic acid, but not l-lactic acid.</s><s>Grows well under both aerobic and strictly anaerobic conditions on liquid and solid MRS medium.</s><s>Grows at 15 and 45 °C (optimum 37 °C), but not at 4 or 50 °C, at pH 6.0–7.0, but not at pH 5.0 or 9.0, and with 8 % (w/v) NaCl, but not with 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces β<em>-</em>glucosidase based on aesculin hydrolysis on MRS agar.</s><s>Produces acid from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, arbutin, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, glucose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, ribose and d-xylose, but not from d-adonitol (ribitol), amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol (galactitol), erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl α-d-mannoside, methyl β-d-xyloside, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>The major polar lipid is phosphatidylethanolamine and minor amounts of phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol are found.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 39.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DCY51<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 12976<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 15530<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from kimchi collected in Gyeonggi province in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>