<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9931_nm.14902" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14902" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14902" rank="species">Virgibacillus salinus</organism><reference id="rid.9931"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carrasco</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus salinus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium from sediment of a saline lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3068</fpage><lpage>3073</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009530-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643886</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus salinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus salinus</em> (sa.li′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>salinus</em> of or belonging to salt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, 0.9×1.5–6.0 μm, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are motile.</s><s>Spherical to ellipsoidal endospores are produced at subterminal or terminal positions in swollen sporangia after 4 days cultivation on Mn-medium at 28 °C.</s><s>Colonies are circular, opaque, entire, 1 mm in diameter and cream-pigmented on HM medium supplemented with 10 % salts after 24 h cultivation at 37 °C.</s><s>Moderately halophilic; is able to grow over a wide range of salt concentrations (3–20 %, w/v), with optimal growth at 10 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Grows at 15–40 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 7.5).</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, d-fructose, galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose, but not from glycerol or d-mannitol.</s><s>Casein, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed, but Tween 80 and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, Simmons citrate, Voges–Proskauer, phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-lactose, maltose, sucrose, d-xylose, ethanol, d-mannitol, xylitol, citrate, formate and propionate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: starch, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-glucose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, trehalose, butanol, dulcitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, propanol, d-sorbitol, methanol, acetate, benzoate, fumarate, succinate and valerate.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-arginine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-threonine and tryptophan.</s><s>The following compounds are not used: l-cysteine, phenylalanine, glutamic acid and l-ornithine.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), bacitracin (10 U), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg) and novobiocin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), neomycin (10 μg), penicillin (10 U) and rifampicin (30 μg).</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A1<em>γ</em>, with <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone, with MK-6, MK-5 and an unidentified respiratory quinone present in minor amounts.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>; iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> are present as minor components.</s><s>Polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, a glycolipid and two unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.8 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The description of this species is based upon study of a single strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XH-22<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7562<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7439<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21756<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of a salt lake near Xilinhot in Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p></content></protolog>