<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2295_nm.9718" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9718" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9718" rank="species">Nitrincola lacisaponensis</organism><reference id="rid.2295"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dimitriu</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shukla</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Conradt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maglia</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peyton</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pinkart</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mormile</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nitrincola lacisaponensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel alkaliphilic bacterium isolated from an alkaline, saline lake.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2273</fpage><lpage>2278</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63647-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280482</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nitrincola lacisaponensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nitrincola lacisaponensis</em> (la.ci.sa.po.nen′sis. L. n. <em>lacus</em> lake; L. n. <em>sapo -onis</em> soap; N.L. masc. adj. <em>lacisaponensis</em> pertaining to Soap Lake).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short, motile rods, occurring singly or in pairs (1·3–1·5 μm in length and 0·5 μm in width).</s><s>When grown on alkaline nutrient agar, colonies are 3–4 mm in diameter, whitish-beige-coloured, entire, smooth and convex.</s><s>Obligate alkaliphile.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are produced.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase are not produced; nor are H<sub>2</sub>S, acetoin or indole.</s><s>Urea, gelatin, DNA and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>No visible or fluorescent pigments are formed during incubation on solid King's media B or A, respectively.</s><s>Strain 4CA<sup>T</sup> can grow with O<sub>2</sub> or  as electron acceptors in the presence of acetate, but not with , ,  or .</s><s>Carbon-source utilization is restricted to a limited range of organic acids, including dl-lactate, acetate, pyruvate, malate, fumarate and succinate.</s><s>Glycine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, sarcosine, l-threonine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-methionine, mannitol, d-mannose, d-arabinose, sucrose, d-xylose, glucose, d-galactose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-ribose, ethanol, adonitol, glycerol, dulcitol, sorbitol, propanol, lactose, glucuronate, saccharate, hippurate, vanillate, coumarate and benzoate are not utilized.</s><s>Cells are resistant to erythromycin, bacitracin, novobiocin, polymyxin B, neomycin, gentamicin, streptomycin, carbenicillin, rifampicin and tetracycline, and are susceptible to nalidixic acid, chloramphenicol, ampicillin and penicillin.</s><s>In minimal medium (SBM) containing acetate, the conditions for growth are pH 7·5–11·0 and up to 1·3 M NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at pH 9·0 and at 0·8 M NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 47·4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from decayed wood collected at Soap Lake, a saline, alkaline environment.</s><s>The type strain is 4CA<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-920<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16316<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>