<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7059_nm.5727" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5727" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5727" rank="species">Conexibacter woesei</organism><reference id="rid.7059"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Monciardini</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cavaletti</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Donadio</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Conexibacter woesei gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel representative of a deep evolutionary line of descent within the class Actinobacteria</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>569</fpage><lpage>576</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02400-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710628</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Conexibacter woesei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Conexibacter woesei</em> (woe′se.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>woesei</em> of Woese, named to honour Carl R. Woese, for his pioneering work on the use of 16S rRNA in phylogenetic analysis).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties described for the genus, colonies on Todd–Hewitt agar are smooth, mucoid to sticky and of white to cream colour.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed, urea is not decomposed.</s><s>NaCl is not tolerated at concentrations of 2 % (w/v) or above.</s><s>The type strain is able to utilize the following substrates: glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, pyruvic acid (Biolog GP microplate), methylpyruvate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid and <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid (Biolog GN microplate).</s><s>The type strain shows the following enzyme activities: esterase for 2-naphthyl caprylate and 2-naphthyl butyrate, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM test).</s><s>The following tests of the Biolog substrate panels, API 20 NE gallery and API ZYM enzyme assay are negative: mannan, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetylmannosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, lactulose, maltotriose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stacchyose, d-tagatose, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, methyl succinate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, caprate, adipate, phenylacetate, degradation of tryptophan, fermentation of glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, alkaline phosphatase, lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Good growth occurs at pH 7–7·5 and at 28–37 °C.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to amikacin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 IU) and teicoplanin (30 μg) and only weakly susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Cells are resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), aztreonam (100 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), methicillin (5 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), oxacillin (1 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), trimethoprim (5 μg) and tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics are as given in the genus description.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 71 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: temperate forest soil.</s><s>The type strain is ID131577<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14684<sup>T</sup> =JCM 11494<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>