<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2484_nm.9494" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9494" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9494" rank="species">Nocardioides oleivorans</organism><reference id="rid.2484"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schippers</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardioides oleivorans sp. nov., a novel crude-oil-degrading bacterium</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1501</fpage><lpage>1504</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63500-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014472</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardioides oleivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardioides oleivorans</em> [o.le.i.vor′ans. L. n. <em>oleum</em> oil; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <em>oleivorans</em> capable of utilizing oil (hydrocarbons)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligate aerobic, Gram-positive, non-endospore-forming, non-motile, irregular rods about 0·3 μm wide and up to 1·1 μm long.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, translucent and orange-pigmented with a maximum colony diameter of 2 mm after 2 weeks.</s><s>Growth occurs at 30 °C and with 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Crude oil is used as substrate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, rhamnose, sucrose, adonitol, inositol, xylose or sorbitol.</s><s>Utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sucrose, d-trehalose, d-mannitol, acetate, propionate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-proline, putrescine, phenylacetate and l-ornithine is observed.</s><s>l-Arabinose, <em>α</em>-d-galacturonate, glycogen, d-ribose, salicin, l-xylose, adonitol, i-inositol, sorbitol, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, citrate, suberate, l-alanine, l-hydroxyproline, l-serine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrolysis of <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-maltoside, bis-pNP phosphate, benzolphosphonacid pNP-ester, pNP phosphocholine, 2-desoxythymidine 5′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pNA, l-leucine pna and l-lysine pNA is detected. pNP <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactosaminide, pNP <em>α</em>-l-arabinopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-cellobioside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>β</em>-d-lactoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, glycine pNA, l-proline pna and l-valine pNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The strain contains ll-diaminopimelic acid in its cell wall and possesses a3<em>γ</em>-type peptidoglycan (ll-diaminopimelic acid–Gly).</s><s>The cellular fatty acids comprise saturated, unsaturated, iso-, anteiso- and 10-methyl-branched types and hydroxy fatty acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and 10-methyl fatty acids.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain BAS3<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16090<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 14004<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a crude oil sample from the oilfield Oerrel of the Gifhorn Trough, North-West Germany (Bosecker <em>et al.</em>, 1991).</s></p></content></protolog>