<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6100_nm.10242" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10242" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10242" rank="species">Shimia marina</organism><reference id="rid.6100"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shimia marina gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel bacterium of the Roseobacter clade isolated from biofilm in a coastal fish farm</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1869</fpage><lpage>1873</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64235-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902023</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shimia marina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shimia marina</em> (ma.ri′na. L. fem. adj. <em>marina</em> of or belonging to the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.3–0.6 μm wide and 0.8–3.6 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by several monopolar flagella.</s><s>On MA medium, colonies are circular, entire, convex, opaque and colourless or beige.</s><s>Grows at 15–35 °C (optimum 30–35 °C) and at pH 6–10.</s><s>Growth occurs at sea-salt concentrations of 3–7 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth without sea salts in the medium.</s><s>Amylase, gelatinase, nitrate reductase, DNase and Tween 80 hydrolysis activities are present.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, nitrate reductase, indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase and urease activities are not detected.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase activities are present and esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and acid phosphatase activities are weakly present, whereas lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 11-methyl 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 16 : 0, 18 : 0, 18 : 3<em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (6,9,12) and 2-OH 16 : 0.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetone, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, citrate, ethanol, glycine, glycogen, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, pyruvate, d-raffinose, succinate, tartrate and urea.</s><s>No growth occurs on acetamide, l-ascorbate, benzoate, acetate, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-fructose, formic acid, glycerol, inulin, 2-propanol, l-arabinose, l-aspartate, l-arginine, l-glutamate, l-asparagine, l-proline, d-mannitol, maleic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-rhamnose, salicylate, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, thiamine or d-trehalose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CL-TA03<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42117<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13038<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a biofilm in a coastal fish farm in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>