<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1513_nm.1069" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1069" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1069" rank="species">Hyphomonas oceanitis</organism><reference id="rid.1513"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiner</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devine</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Powell</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dagasan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hyphomonas oceanitis sp. nov., Hyphomonas hirschiana sp.nov., and Hyphomonas jannaschiana sp.nov.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>237</fpage><lpage>243</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hyphomonas oceanitis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyphomonas oceanitis</i> (o. cean. i' tis. N.L. fem.n. <i>oceanitis</i> daughter of the ocean)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are round to oval and ca. 0.9 μm in diameter and usually have one hypha which is up to three times the length of the mother cell (Fig. 1).</s><s>Under favorable growth conditions, a small proportion of cells produce two hyphae, one at each of the poles.</s><s>Both hyphae are capable of producing buds concurrently.</s><s>Buds (daughter cells) are pear shaped and become larger and rounder when they are mature (mother cells) and producing buds.</s><s>Intercalary buds (i.e., two or more daughter cells remaining attached to the distal pole[s] of the stalk[s] of the mother cell) are common.</s><s>Buds are motile until the hyphae form.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>No endospores.</s><s>Aerobic or microaerophilic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On agar, the colonies are colorless, raised, semitranslucent or opaque, and, after 3 days, up to 1.5 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In liquid media, growth produces uniform turbidity without a pellicle or sediment.</s><s>The best growth occurs in media containing sea salts.</s><s>Does not grow on the mineral salts medium used for <i>Hyphomicrobium vulgare</i>.</s><s>A mixture of L-glutamic acid, L-aspartic acid, L-serine, and L-methionine is required for growth.</s><s>Requires biotin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for optimum growth is 20 to 30°C.</s><s>The NaCl concentration for optimum growth is 1.0 to 7.5%.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.6.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Sheep erythrocytes are not hemolyzed.</s><s>Pigment is not formed.</s><s>Under optimal conditions in marine broth, growth is slower than the growth of other species of <i>Hyphomonas</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to NP-40 (0.01%) and Tween 80 (0.1 to 1.0%).</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin, penicillin, ampicillin, and streptomycin.</s><s>Requires 6 to 8 min of treatment with a Brownwill Biosonic IV sonicator (low probe at full power) to produce 99% lysis of cells.</s><s>Other nutritional and biochemical characteristics are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Hyphomonas oceanitis</i> has marginal antigenic relatedness to <i>Hyphomonas polymorpha</i>, <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i>, <i>Hyphomonas hirschiana</i>, and <i>Hyphomonas jannaschiana</i> (Table 3).</s><s>The levels of genetic relatedness to <i>Hyphomonas polymorpha</i> and <i>Hyphomonas neptunium</i>, as determined by DNA homology studies (in solution with endonuclease treatment) (Gebers et al., in press), are 6 and 3%, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the Baltic Sea in 1979 by H.</s><s>Schlesner.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain SCH89 (= IFAM 1325 = ATCC 33879).</s></p></content></protolog>