<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4660_nm.5779" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5779" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5779" rank="species">Actinomyces denticolens</organism><reference id="rid.4660"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dent</surname><given-names>V.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>R.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces denticolens Dent &#x0026; Williams sp. nov: a new species from the dental plaque of cattle</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>183</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6725156</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces denticolens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces denticolens</i> (L.n. <i>dens</i>, <i>dentis</i> tooth; L. adj. <i>suff</i> colens from L.v. <i>colo</i> dwell; L. adj. <i>dentirolens</i> tooth dweller)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology Gram positive, non-spore forming, non-motile rods (0.7 μm x 5 μm).</s><s>Colonies on horse blood agar slightly pink when grown anaerobically, but white if grown aerobically.</s><s>Colonies circular, entire and convex, smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological properties Facultatively anaerobic, stimulated by carbon dioxide; catalase negative; reduces nitrate but not nitrite, hydrolyses aesculin; not haemolytic.</s><s>Ferment glucose, lactose, maltose, raffinose, salicin, sucrose; most strains ferment inositol, inulin and ribose, and some ferment amygdalin, cellobiose, glycerol, mannose, melezitose and rhamnose weakly.</s><s>Arabinose, sorbitol, trehalose and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Fermentation of mannitol is variable.</s><s>Cell suspensions show activities of leucine amino-peptidase, phosphoamidase, β-galactosidase and α-glucosidase; most strains also show acid phosphatase, 1-galactosidase and β-glucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemical composition Peptidoglycan contains glutamate, alanine, ornithine, lysine, glucosamine and muramic acid in the proportions 2:2:1:1:1:1.</s><s>The only detectable carbohydrate in purified cell walls is rhamnose.</s><s>DNA base composition 65.9-67.7 moles % G + C.</s><s>Pattern of polypeptides on SDS-PAGE is unique and allows the taxon to be distinguished from <i>A. naeslundii</i>.</s><s>Isolated from the dental plaque of cattle.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is Sh8/4303 (NCTC 11490).</s></p></content></protolog>