<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11922_nm.20017" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20017" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20017" rank="species">Chryseobacterium arthrosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.11922"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sridhar</surname><given-names>K.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium arthrosphaerae sp. nov., isolated from the faeces of pill millipede Arthrosphaera magna Attems from India</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1765</fpage><lpage>1769</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016840-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749032</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium arthrosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium arthrosphaerae</em> (ar.thro.spha.e′rae. N.L. gen. n. <em>arthrosphaerae</em> of <em>Arthrosphaera</em>, the genus name of the pill millipede <em>Arthrosphaera magna</em> from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, approximately 1 μm wide and 2 μm long.</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-positive and catalase-positive.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h on nutrient agar, brain heart infusion agar and tryptic soy agar (all Oxoid) at 11–36 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar (Oxoid) at 28 °C.</s><s>The type strain is unable to grow at 4 °C and 45 °C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies become mucoid and cannot be identified as single entities after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The yellow pigment is non-diffusible and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Weakly produces acid from d-glucose, maltose and d-mannitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Urease activity, indole production and hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine are positive; hydrogen sulphide production and activity of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG) are negative.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, trehalose, acetate, propionate, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-fructose, d-mannitol, maltitol, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phenyl phosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl choline, 2-deoxythymidine 2′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate <em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline <em>p</em>-nitroanilide are hydrolysed.</s><s><em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;15 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, an unknown fatty acid with an equivalent chain-length of 13.566 and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-VM-7<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 57618<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7645<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the faeces of the pill millipede <em>Arthrosphaera magna</em> Attems collected in India.</s></p></content></protolog>