<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3627_nm.8364" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8364" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8364" rank="species">Fusobacterium polysaccharolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.3627"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium polysaccharolyticum sp.nov., a gram-negative rod from the rumen that produces butyrate and ferments cellulose and starch.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>116</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>163</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7365452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium polysaccharolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The new isolates resemble <i>B. fibrisolvens</i> and the bacterium described by Leatherwood &#x0026; Sharma (1972) in that they are all Gram-negative, anaerobic, non-sporulating rods from the rumen that produce butyric acid and therefore appear to be physiologically similar. They resemble <i>Butyrivibrio</i> in G+C content and differ from it in morphology and type of flagellation (compare Figs 2 to 4 with Figs 5 to 7). They differ morphologically from the bacterium isolated by Leatherwood &#x0026; Sharma (1972) in that the latter possessed no flagella? occurred in long twisted chains and had a G + C content of 36.3 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>According to Bergey's Manual of Determinative Bacteriology (Buchanan &#x0026; Gibbons, 1974), the new isolates would fall in the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i> (Knorr) in that they are motile with peritrichous flagella, Gram-negative anaerobes which produce butyric acid from carbohydrate and have a pH optimum close to 7.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA in most species of fusobacteria examined ranges from 26 to 34 mol % but one species, <i>F. symbiosum</i>, was found to have a G+C mol % of 48 (Buchanan &#x0026; Gibbons, 1974).</s><s>The G+C mol % of the new bacterium would not exclude it from the genus <i>Fusobacterium</i>; however, the novel isolates differ from all the species described under this genus.</s><s>An appropriate specific epithet for the new bacterium would be polysaccharolyticurn in view of its assumed function in the rumen, i.e. that of degrading polymerized carbohydrates such as cellulose, xylan (hemicellulose) and starch.</s><s>Isolate B is the type strain and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (accession number ATCC 33142).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The occurrence of <i>F. polysaccharolyticum</i> in the rumens of sheep fed supplemented maize stover diets was not merely sporadic as bacteria of this type were found in the rumens of two sheep, when fed different levels of grain on different occasions.</s><s>Isolates were obtained from random roll-bottles used when making counts of cellulolytic bacteria and it is possible that a search for this organism may have revealed a more general occurrence in the rumen ingesta of different sheep.</s><s>The dilutions of ingesta in medium from which the organisms were isolated indicate that they occurred at levels of at least 10<sup>6</sup> per g ingesta</s></p></content></protolog>