<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2441_nm.11321" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11321" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11321" rank="species">Chryseobacterium luteum</organism><reference id="rid.2441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium luteum sp. nov., associated with the phyllosphere of grasses</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1881</fpage><lpage>1885</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65104-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684275</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium luteum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium luteum</em> (lu′te.um. L. neut. adj. <em>luteum</em> orange-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, non-motile single rods.</s><s>Gram-negative with classical Gram-staining but produces a false Gram-positive reaction with the fast KOH test.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>On nutrient agar, produces orange colonies that are smooth with regular margins.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 21 °C.</s><s>At 4 °C, slow growth can be observed, but known isolates are unable to grow at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows on nutrient and trypticase soy agars but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase activity is absent.</s><s>Gelatin, starch and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein is strain-dependent.</s><s>Chitin, urea and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>d-Glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid are not assimilated in API 20NE test strips.</s><s>With API 50 CH strips, acid is produced oxidatively from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, glycogen and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, d- or l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-lactose (bovine origin), d-melibiose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from starch is strain-dependent.</s><s>With API ZYM strips, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present.</s><s>Esterase (C4), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Cystine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activities are strain-dependent.</s><s>The fatty acids largely comprise iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (37.7 %±2.8), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω9c</em> (17.9 %±2.0), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (16.8 %±0.6), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (8.0 %±1.2) and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (4.7 %±0.9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P 456/04<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18605<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23785<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses in Paulinenaue, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>