<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6410_nm.7465" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7465" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7465" rank="species">Microbispora karnatakensis</organism><reference id="rid.6410"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rao</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabhu</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sridhar</surname><given-names>B.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venkateswarlu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Actor</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two new species of Microbispora from Indian soils: Microbispora karnatakensis sp. nov. and Microbispora indica sp. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>181</fpage><lpage>185</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbispora karnatakensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Morphology. Substrate and aerial mycelia are produced. Spores arranged in pairs are formed on the branches of main hyphae on aerial mycelium only. Spores are round to oval, measuring 1.2 to 1.8 μm in diameter. Basal spore is attached to mycelium with a stalk. Spore surface is :smooth. Mycelium does not fragment into coccoid or bacillary structures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Color of colony.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white on oat agar and starch agar containing yeast extract, light gray on potato-dextrose agar, pale pink in yeast-malt extract agar, and pale yellowish-pink on glycerol glucose agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Color of reverse side of colony.</s><s>The reverse side is white to gray in oatmeal agar and yeast-malt extract agar and pale yellowish-pink on glycerol glucose agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Color in medium.</s><s>The color in medium is deep orange-yellow to deep orange in oat agar, pale orange-yellow on starch agar with yeast extract, brilliant yellow on glycerol asparagine agar with yeast extract, vivid orange on potato-dextrose agar, and brilliant orange-yellow on glycerol-glucose agar.</s><s>Melanoid pigment is not produced in peptone yeast iron agar, tyrosine agar, or tryptone yeast broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological properties.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed, gelatin is liquefied, and milk is peptonized.</s><s>Carbon sources such as D-(+)-glucose, L-(+)-rhamnose, and <i>meso</i>-inositol are utilized for growth, but not glycerol and L-(+)-arabinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall composition. <i>meso</i>Diaminopimelic acid, madurose, and galactose are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SKF-1-58261 (ATCC 35927), isolated from soil in Karnataka State, India.</s><s>This strain is mesophilic.</s></p></content></protolog>