<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8_nm.8360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8360" rank="subspecies">Fusobacterium necrophorum funduliforme</organism><reference id="rid.8"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shinjo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujisawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of two subspecies of Fusobacterium necrophorum, (Flügge) Moore and Holdeman: Fusobacterium necrophorum subsp. necrophorum subsp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Flugge 1886), and Fusobacterium necrophorum subsp. funduliforme (ex Hallé 1898).</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>395</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-395</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1883714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium necrophorum funduliforme</i> subsp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium necrophorum</i> subsp. <i>funduliforme</i> (fun.du.li.for’me. L. n. <i>fundula</i>, sausage; L. n. <i>forma</i>, shape; M. L. neut. adj. <i>funduliforme</i>, sausage shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown in BTY broth are 0.4 to 0.8 by 1 to 8 μm.</s><s>Shorter cells (1 to 4 μm) are predominant.</s><s>Surface colonies on GAM agar are about 1 mm in diameter, circular with entire margins, grayish, translucent, and raised with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Moderate to abundant growth occurs in BTY broth with the production of sediment and no turbidity.</s><s>Strain Fn524<sup>T</sup> is positive for gelatin liquefaction, but negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>The type strain ferments glucose weakly.</s><s>Hemagglutination of chicken erythrocytes is negative as determined by the glass slide method, and the hemagglutination titer in test tubes is less than 1:2.</s><s>Injection of mice intraperitoneally or intraportally with strains of this subspecies is not lethal; a few focal abscesses are formed in the livers (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 27 to 31 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. necrophorum</i> subsp. <i>fundulgorme</i> subsp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Hallé 1898), is strain Fn524 (= JCM 3724).</s></p></content></protolog>