<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2456_nm.8722" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8722" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8722" rank="species">Mycobacterium psychrotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.2456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Trujillo</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium psychrotolerans sp. nov., isolated from pond water near a uranium mine</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1459</fpage><lpage>1463</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02938-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388695</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium psychrotolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium psychrotolerans</em> (psy.chro.tol′er.ans. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; L. pres. part. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>psychrotolerans</em> cold-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, acid-fast, non-spore-forming, non-motile short rods.</s><s>Smooth, entire, bright orange, scotochromogenic colonies appear after 2 days in GYEA, Bennett's and nutrient agars.</s><s>Growth on Löwenstein–Jensen agar is moderate; no growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C and tolerates 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Shows a positive reaction for nitrate reduction, acid phosphatase, 2-naphthyl-butyrate (esterase), 2-naphthyl-caprylate (lipase), 2-naphthyl-myristate, cysteine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, arginine dehydrolase, trypsin, phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase; urea reaction is weak.</s><s>Negative for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Adonitol, aesculin, erythritol, d-fructose, gluconate, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, inositol, malate, mannitol, d-mannose, sucrose, sorbitol, trehalose and d-xylose are used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not use amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fucose, l-fucose, galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, d-turanose, l-xylose or methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, cefuroxime, cloxacillin, erythromycin, penicillin and polymyxin.</s><s>Sensitive to ciprofloxacin, gentamicin, neomycin and oxytetracycline.</s><s>TLC of mycolic acid methanolysates reveals <em>α</em>-mycolates, keto-mycolates and <em>ω</em>-carboxymycolates plus 2-eicosanol (wax-ester mycolates).</s><s>The mycolic acid HPLC elution profile is unique and can be used for differentiation from the closely related species <em>Mycobacterium aichiense</em>, <em>Mycobacterium gilvum</em>, <em>M. chlorophenolicum</em>, <em>M. parafortuitum</em>, <em>M. sphagni</em> and other mycobacteria.</s><s>The G+C composition of the DNA of the type strain is 64 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WA101<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44697<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21953<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a pond in Salamanca, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>