<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7230_nm.3060" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3060" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3060" rank="species">Aeromonas popoffii</organism><reference id="rid.7230"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altwegg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lamb</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lüthy-Hottenstein</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas popoffii sp. nov., a mesophilic bacterium isolated from drinking water production plants and reservoirs.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1165</fpage><lpage>1171</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1165</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336924</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aeromonas popoffii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aeromonas popoffii</i> (po.pof'fi.i. M. L. gen. n. <i>popoffii</i>, of Popoff)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose the name <i>Aeromonas popoffii</i> for the first seven strains in Table 1.</s><s>The species is named after Michel Y.</s><s>Popoff, a French microbiologist who has greatly contributed to our current knowledge of the phenotypic and genotypic relationships among the mesophilic members of the genus <i>Aeromonas</i> (53-55).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All seven strains of <i>A. popoffii</i> (Table 1) display the following characteristics typical for the genus Aeromonas: gram-negative straight motile rods, chemoorganotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism, cytochrome oxidase and catalase positive, reduction of nitrate to nitrite without the production of gas, and resistance to vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 24 h at 28°C on TSA medium, but all strains also grow at 37°C in broth.</s><s>No brown water-soluble pigment is produced on TSA medium.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from D-glucose and glycerol.</s><s>Growth occurs in KCN broth but not in the presence of 3,6,8, and 10% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, DNase, indole (except strains LMG 17541<sup>T</sup> and LMG 17546), and Voges-Proskauer positive.</s><s>No production of urease, tryptophan deaminase, ornithine and lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Production of H<sub>2</sub> by four of the seven strains.</s><s>Alkalinization of citrate (except strains LMG 17544 and LMG 17546) and malonate (except strain LMG 17544).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are used by all seven <i>A. popoffii</i> strains as the sole carbon and energy source: N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-alanine (except strain LMG 17547), L-aspartate, citrate (except strains LMG 17543 and LMG 17544), D-fructose (except strains LMG 17541<sup>T</sup> and LMG 17545), fumarate, D-galactose, D-gluconate, D-glucose, L-glutamate, L-glutamine, glycerol, L-histidine, DL-lactate (except strain LMG 17546), L-malate, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-maltose, putrescine, pyruvate, D-ribose, succinate, L-serine, D-trehalose, and L-tyrosine.</s><s>None of the strains use acetate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adipate, adonitol, β-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, arbutin, L-arginine (except strains LMG 17544 and LMG 17546), azelate, D-cellobiose, citrullin, dulcitol, ethanol, erythritol, D-glucuronate, glutarate, glycine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, DL-3-hydroxybutyratein, ositol, itaconate, lactose (except strain LMG 17542), L-leucine, maltitol, α-D-melibiose, mesaconate, L-ornithine, oxoglutarate, phenylacetate, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, propionate, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, suberate, D-sucrose, L-tryptophan, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is uniformly produced from D-galactose, D-maltose (except strain LMG 17546), D-mannitol, D-mannose, methyl-Dglucoside, and D-trehalose but not from adonitol, D-arabitol, D-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, lactose, α-D-melibiose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, D-sucrose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>A. popoffii</i> strains hydrolyze the following substrates: L-alanine- pNA, casein, 2-deoxythymidine-5'-pNP-phosphate gelatin, lecithin, bis-pNP-phosphate, <i>ortho</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, pNP-phenylphosphonate, pNP-phosphoryl choline, L-proline-pNA, starch, and Tween 80.</s><s>None of the strains are able to hydrolyze chitin, esculin, L-glutamatey-𝛾-carboxy-pNA, pNP-α-D-glucopyranoside, pNP-β-D-glucuronide, and pNP-β-D-xyloside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>A. popoffii</i> strains listed in Table 1 are resistant to amoxicillin, ampicillin, clarithromycin, oxacillin, penicillin G, teicoplanin, and vancomycin but are sensitive to amikacin, cefotaxim, ceftazidim, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, mezlocillin, netilmicin, piperacillin, spectinomycin, tetracycline, tobramycin, and trimethoprim according to the interpretive standards provided by the National Committee for Clinical Laboratory Standards (48, 49).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content ranges from 57.7 to 59.6 mol% (Table 2).</s><s>D-xylose.</s><s>Isolated from drinking water production plants and reservoirs (Table 1).</s><s>One isolate (strain LMG 17544) displayed weak hemolytic activity after 7 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LMG 17541; it has been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, Universiteit Gent, Ghent, Belgium.</s><s>The G+C content of this strain is 57.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>