<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.300_nm.470" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.470" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.470" rank="species">Fervidobacterium gondwanense</organism><reference id="rid.300"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Andrews</surname><given-names>K.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fervidobacterium gondwanense sp. nov., a new thermophilic anaerobic bacterium isolated from nonvolcanically heated geothermal waters of the Great Artesian Basin of Australia.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>265</fpage><lpage>269</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573506</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fervidobacterium gondwanense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fervidobacterium gondwanense</i> (Gond.wa.nen'se. M.L. neut. adj. <i>gondwanense</i>, pertaining to the large land mass known as Gondwana, which included Australia, Africa, India, and South America before they separated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight motile rods that are 0.5 to 0.6 by 4 to 40 μm and occur singly, in pairs, or in chains.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Cells produce terminal spheroid structures which are protuberances of the outer cell wall.</s><s>Rotund bodies are formed rarely.</s><s>No spores are produced.</s><s>Creamish brown colonies that are 1 mm in diameter develop in TYEG medium containing 2.5% agar after 48 h of incubation at 65°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic, strictly anaerobic bacterium which grows at temperatures of &#x003E;45°C or &#x003C;80°C and at pH 6.0 to 8.0.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 65 to 68°C, and the optimum pH is 7.0.</s><s>Utilizes glucose, mannose, maltose, starch, amylopectin, cellobiose, carboxymethyl cellulose, lactose, dextrin, fructose, xylose, galactose, and pyruvate but not cellulose, Casamino Acids, gelatin, sorbose, ribose, raffinose, arabinose, dextran, xylan, or chitin.</s><s>Produces acetate, ethanol, lactate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub> during glucose fermentation.</s><s>Reduces sulfur but not thiosulfate, sulfite, or sulfate.</s><s>A member of the domain <i>Bacteria</i>.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by streptomycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, phosphomycin, tetracycline, vancomycin, chloramphenicol, and rifampin, partially inhibited by sodium azide and neomycin, and not inhibited by D-cycloserine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetically related to members of the order <i>Thermotogales</i>, particularly <i>F. nodosum</i> Rt17-B1<sub>T</sub> and <i>F. islandicum</i> H21<sub>T</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from nonvolcanic geothermal waters of the Great Artesian Basin, an aquifer in Australia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain AB39 (= Australian Collection of Microorganisms strain ACM 5017).</s></p></content></protolog>