<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12734_nm.22507" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22507" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22507" rank="species">Candidimonas humi</organism><reference id="rid.12734"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Figueira</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Brandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Candidimonas nitroreducens gen. nov., sp. nov. and Candidimonas humi sp. nov., isolated from sewage sludge compost</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2238</fpage><lpage>2246</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021188-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952543</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Candidimonas humi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Candidimonas humi</em> (hu′mi. L. n. <em>humus</em> earth, soil and, in earth sciences or agriculture, humus; L. gen. n. <em>humi</em> of the soil, of the humus).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, circular (~1 mm diameter), convex and rough on PCA after 48 h incubation.</s><s>Cells are coccobacilli (0.50±0.09 µm).</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C, at pH 5–8 and in the presence of up to 3 % (w/v) NaCl [optima about 30 °C, pH 7 and 1 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Unable to grow under anaerobiosis or to reduce nitrate.</s><s>Simmons citrate is not utilized.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Produces acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-chymotrypsin, but not arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, gelatinase, urease, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase or α-fucosidase.</s><s>The following sole carbon sources are assimilated: adipate, citrate, phenyl acetate, itaconic acid, sodium acetate, lactic acid, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, propionic acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and 3-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>The carbon sources d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, malate, potassium gluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, suberic acid, sodium malonate, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, capric acid, l-histidine, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline are not assimilated.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are those listed in the genus description and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH or both).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SC-092<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 55807<sup>T</sup> = LMG 24813<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sewage sludge compost.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>