<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7020_nm.2878" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2878" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2878" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.7020"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhukova</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas agarivorans sp. nov., a novel marine agarolytic bacterium.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>125</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02234-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656163</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoalteromonas agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoalteromonas agarivorans</em> (a.gar.i.vor′ans. N.L. n. <em>agarum</em> agar-agar, algal polysaccharide; L. v. <em>vorare</em> to devour, to digest; N.L. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, rod-shaped cells, 0·8–0·9 μm in diameter and 2·5–3·8 μm long, motile by a single, polar, unsheathed flagellum.</s><s>Cells with two to four polar flagella are observed.</s><s>Does not form endospores.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph.</s><s>Grows at 7–35 °C, with optimal growth at 20–28 °C; no growth at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>Non-pigmented, whitish or pale yellowish S- and R-colonies, depressed into the agar.</s><s>Positive for lipase, caseinase, DNase, gelatinase and β-galactosidase.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from sucrose, maltose and melibiose.</s><s>ONPG test is positive.</s><s>As determined by using the Biolog identification system, Tweens 80 and 40, cyclodextran, dextran and glycogen are utilized; acetic and succinic acids are weakly utilized.</s><s>In addition to metabolic properties used in the differentiation of the species from other <em>Pseudoalteromonas</em> strains indicated in Table 1, negative for the utilization of l-arabinose and gluconate (according to API 20NE), negative for urease, indole production and aesculin hydrolysis and shows no acid formation from l-arabinose, lactose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-xylose, rhamnose or glycerol.</s><s>d-Glucose utilization is weak or slow in the API test and negative in the Biolog GN identification system.</s><s>As determined by the Biolog GN panel, does not utilize cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, gluconate, <em>m</em>-inositol, erythritol, adonitol, methylpyruvate, mono-methylsuccinate, β-hydroxybutyric acid, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, l-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, l-alanine, l-proline, l-threonine, d-glucuronic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, hydroxy-l-proline, acetate, dl-lactate, l-leucine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin (15 μg), benzylpenicillin (10 U), oxacillin (20 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and O/129 (150 μg).</s><s>Major fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid (16 : 0) and hexadecenoic acid (16 : 1ω7<em>c</em>).</s><s>Dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol; bis-phosphatidic acid and diphosphatidylglycerol are minor components.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 42·2–43·8 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s><s>The strains were isolated from sea water deep in the Pacific Ocean and from the marine ascidians <em>Halocynthia aurantium</em>, <em>Polysyncraton</em> sp. and <em>Clarelina molucensis</em>.</s><s>The type strain is strain KMM 255<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14585<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>