<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7283_nm.1104" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1104" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1104" rank="species">Paracoccus marcusii</organism><reference id="rid.7283"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harker</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirschberg</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus marcusii sp. nov., an orange gram-negative coccus.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>543</fpage><lpage>548</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-543</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731296</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paracoccus marcusii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paracoccus marcusii</i> (mar.cus'i.i. N.L. adj. <i>marcusii</i> referring to the late Menashe Marcus, an Israeli geneticist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cocci to short rods, 1-2 by 1.0-1.5 μm in size, growing in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on agar are flat, smooth and bright orange, due to the accumulation of carotenoids, including astaxanthin.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows aerobically on a wide range of carbon sources (including glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, arabinose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, gentiobiose, gluconic acid, glucuronic acid, galacturonic acid, glycerol, erythritol, mannitol, sorbitol, xylitol, inositol, adonitol, arabitol, propionic acid, <i>cis</i>-aconitic acid, citric acid, lactic acid, malonic acid, succinic acid, formic acid, malic acid and alanine).</s><s>Many other substances (including fucose, rhamnose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, N-acetylglucosamine, Nacetylgalactosamine, α-glycerolphosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, methanol, 2,3-butanediol, trimethylamine, Tween 40, Tween 80, acetic acid, asparagine, aspartate, glutamate, histidine, leucine, ornithine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, inosine, uridine and thymidine) are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is not used as electron acceptor.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 66 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The type strain is strain MH1<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated as a contaminant on a nutrient agar plate; this strain has been deposited in DSMZ as strain DSM 11574<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>