<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2566_nm.8038" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8038" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8038" rank="species">Dysgonomonas mossii</organism><reference id="rid.2566"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inganäs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weyant</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dysgonomonas mossii sp. nov., from human sources</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>197</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12353872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dysgonomonas mossii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dysgonomonas mossii</i> (N. L. gen. n. <i>mossii</i>, of Moss, to honour Claude Wayne Moss, a contemporary American microbiologist, in recognition of his contributions to microbial taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of non-motile, Gram-negative coccobacilli to short rods.</s><s>After 48 hours of incubation anaerobically at 37 °C on blood agar, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, non-adherent, entire, grey-white, smooth and non-haemolytic, and produce a slightly aromatic odour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25°C, but not at 42°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur on MacConkey agar.</s><s>The organism grows on nutrient agar around X and XV discs, suggesting a growth factor dependency for haem.</s><s>Catalaseand oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrate.</s><s>Indole is produced but acetoin is not.</s><s>Resistant to Ox bile.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are hydrolysed but gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>Glucose is fermented with production of acid but no gas.</s><s>Using traditional methods acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, inositol (weak reaction), lactose, mannitol (weak reaction), maltose, L-rhamnose (weak reaction), salicin, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>Employing the API rapid ID 32A system acid is produced from mannose but D-raffinose may or may not be fermented.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase 6-phosphate (weak reaction), α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, α-mannosidase (weak reaction) and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Arginine dehydrolase, arginine arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>α-Arabinosidase may or may not be produced.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical sources.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 43457<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107079<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G + C content of the type strain is 38.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>