<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2499_nm.11433" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11433" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11433" rank="species">Rubritalea tangerina</organism><reference id="rid.2499"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rubritalea spongiae sp. nov. and Rubritalea tangerina sp. nov., two carotenoid- and squalene-producing marine bacteria of the family Verrucomicrobiaceae within the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia', isolated from marine animals.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2337</fpage><lpage>2343</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65243-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911307</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rubritalea tangerina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rubritalea tangerina</em> (tan′ge.ri.na. N.L. fem. adj. <em>tangerina</em> tangerine, referring to the reddish-orange colour of colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, facultatively anaerobic and coccoid (0.5–0.8 μm in diameter) or rod-shaped (0.5–0.8×1.0–1.5 μm).</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/2 strength R2A agar with 75 % artificial seawater are circular, convex and reddish orange in colour.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C, with optimum growth at 30–37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.5–8.5.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth, but can tolerate up to 9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-negative but oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are positive, but <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>l-Fucose, d-mannose, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, succinic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are oxidized, but cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, furanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate are not oxidized.</s><s>Major respiratory menaquinones are MK-8 and MK-9.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains muramic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (35.5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2.9 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (4.7 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.4 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (12.2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (12.7 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (23.1 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.1 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (1.5 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2.4 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 50.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM27-005<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08282<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12907<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the visceral specimen of an unidentified sea hare.</s></p></content></protolog>