<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12626_nm.22161" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22161" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22161" rank="species">Methylopila jiangsuensis</organism><reference id="rid.12626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hang</surname><given-names>B.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.-P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylopila jiangsuensis sp. nov., an aerobic, facultatively methylotrophic bacterium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1561</fpage><lpage>1566</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020925-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656805</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylopila jiangsuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylopila jiangsuensis</em> (jiang.su.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>jiangsuensis</em> pertaining to Jiangsu, the province where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-sporulating, short rods (0.8–1.2×1.6–2.0 µm) with rounded ends, motile by lateral flagella, that multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Granules of PHB are observed in cells.</s><s>Colonies on medium K with methanol (0.5 %, v/v) are white, semi-transparent, convex and circular with entire edges.</s><s>Grows well in complex media such as LB medium or trypticase soy medium and in medium K with methanol, methylamine, formate, glycerol, d-sorbitol, maltose, sucrose, d-fructose, succinate, malate, l-arabinose or pyruvate as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Additional growth factors are not required.</s><s>Growth is not observed with methane, dichloromethane, citrate, butanol, ethanol or H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin and resistant to ampicillin, streptomycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Growth is observed at 10–37 °C (optimum, 30 °C), pH 5.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.5–7.5) and 0–2.5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0.5 %).</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests and tests for production of ammonia and H<sub>2</sub>S are negative.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reduction, activities of urease, oxidase and catalase and hydrolysis of starch and casein milk are positive.</s><s>Produces indole from l-tryptophan on medium K with methanol as the sole carbon and energy source and under ammonium limitation.</s><s>Hydrolysis of cellulose, gelatin and aesculin sesquihydrate is not observed.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>C<sub>1</sub> compounds are assimilated via the isocitrate lyase-negative serine pathway.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JZL-4<sup>T</sup> ( = ACCC 05406<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22718<sup>T</sup>  = VKM B-2555<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge in a synthetic pyrethroid-manufacturing wastewater treatment facility in Yangzhou city, Jiangsu Province, PR China.</s></p></content></protolog>