<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4523_nm.7556" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7556" rank="genus">Streptomonospora</organism><reference id="rid.4523"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomonospora alba sp. nov., a novel halophilic actinomycete, and emended description of the genus Streptomonospora Cui et al. 2001</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1421</fpage><lpage>1425</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130027</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Streptomonospora</em> Cui <em>et al.</em> 2001</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomonospora</em> (Strep′to.mo.no.spo′ra. Gr. adj. <em>streptos</em> pliant, bent; Gr. adj. <em>monos</em> single, solitary; Gr. fem. n. <em>spora</em> a seed, spore; N.L. fem. n. <em>Streptomonospora</em> indicating that this organism forms two type of single spore, with wrinkled surfaces, on aerial mycelium and substrate mycelium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic organisms with branching hyphae.</s><s>Non-fragmenting substrate mycelium present.</s><s>The aerial mycelium, at maturity, forms short chains of non-motile spores; spores in short chains are oval- to rod-shaped with wrinkled surfaces.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is extensively branched with non-fragmenting hyphae.</s><s>Single, non-motile, oval to round spores are borne on sporophores or dichotomously branched sporophores of substrate hyphae.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Cell walls contain galactose or galactose plus arabinose.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is complex, consisting of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine and phosphatidylinositol; diphosphatidylglycerol, methylphosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylserine may occur.</s><s>The menaquinone composition may depend on the growth medium and consists mainly of menaquinones with nine or ten isoprenoid chains and a varying degree of hydrogenation: i.e. a combination of one or more representative(s) of the series [MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>), (H4), (H<sub>6</sub>), (H<sub>8</sub>)] plus [MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), (H<sub>4</sub>), (H<sub>6</sub>), (H<sub>8</sub>)].</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 69 to 71 mol% G+C (HPLC).</s><s>Phylogenetically, a neighbour of <em>Nocardiopsis</em>, <em>Thermobifida</em> and <em>Actinomadura</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Streptomonospora salina</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>