<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8508_nm.13426" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13426" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13426" rank="species">Methylobacterium phyllosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.8508"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sa</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium phyllosphaerae sp. nov., a pink-pigmented, facultative methylotroph from the phyllosphere of rice</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>22</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001693-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126717</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium phyllosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium phyllosphaerae</em> (phyl.lo.sphae′rae. N.L. n. <em>phyllosphaera</em> phyllosphere; N.L. gen. n. <em>phyllosphaerae</em> of the phyllosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-endospore-forming, strictly aerobic, motile rods (0.63–0.64×1.8–2.7 μm) occurring singly, in pairs or in rosettes.</s><s>Colonies are pink to red, convex, translucent with regular edges, slow-growing and 0.2–0.8 mm in diameter after 96 h at 28 °C on AMS.</s><s>Grows on NA, R2A, peptone-yeast extract-glucose, succinate, glycerol-peptone and plate count agar media.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of ≥2.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C (optimal temperature 28 °C) and pH 5.0–9.0 (optimal pH 6.8).</s><s>The pink pigment is water-insoluble and has absorption maxima at 233, 359, 505 and 545 nm in chloroform/methanol (1 : 1).</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, arginine dihydrolase and urease tests are positive.</s><s>Pectinase, cellulase, protease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are absent.</s><s>Tests for nitrate reduction, glucose fermentation, indole production and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, glycerol tributyrate, casein and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>d-Glucose, fucose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, fructose, l-glutamate, citrate, sebacate, acetate, ethanol, methylamine and methanol are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, potassium nitrate, sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride, l-alanine, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, urea, methylamine, trimethylamine, 1-aminocyclopropane 1-carboxylate and potassium thiocyanate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>The type strain is highly resistant (up to 500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) to ampicillin, carbenicillin, nalidixic acid and chloramphenicol, but sensitive (lowest concentration) to kanamycin (15 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), gentamicin (200 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), spectinomycin (200 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and tetracycline (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): Tween 80, l-arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized in API 20NE and API 32GN tests: d-glucose, l-arabinose, potassium gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, itaconic acid, sodium malonate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline.</s><s>In API ZYM assays, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids identified in the type strain are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CBMB27<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24361<sup>T</sup> =KACC 11716<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19779<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the leaf surface of rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L.</s><s>‘Dong-Jin’).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>