<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5327_nm.10323" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10323" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10323" rank="species">Nocardia lijiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.5327"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia lijiangensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete strain isolated from soil in China.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>308</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.11.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16337766</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia lijiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s><em>N. lijiangensis</em> (li.jiang.en'sis.</s><s>N.L.adj. lijiangensis pertaining to the city in Yunnan Province in the south of China where the sample was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive and slightly acid-alcohol-fast.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white to pale-yellow.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melicitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, sorbinose, sucrose, xylose, adonitol, glycerol, inositol, dulcitol, xylitol, salicin, oxalate (weak) and dextrin are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but not rhamnose, trehalose, arabitol, sorbitol, acetate, citrate, malonate, tartrate.</s><s>Acid is not formed from these carbon sources tested. l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-cysteine (weak), l-histidine, l-proline, l-tyrosine and l-valine are used as sole nitrogen sources, but not acetamide, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-hydroxyproline, l-lysine, l-methionine, phenylalanine, l-threonine and l-tryptophane.</s><s>Amygdalin, chitin, hypoxanthine, keratin, urea and xanthine are hydrolysed, Tweens 20 and Tweens 80 are degraded, but not aesculin, adenine, allantoin, cellulose, DNA, glucosamine and starch.</s><s>Tests for gelatin, melanin production, milk coagulation and peptonization, nitrate reduction and H<sub>2</sub>S production are negative, but resistance to KCN is positive.</s><s>Growth between 28 and 37 °C, from pH 7 to pH 9 and in the presence of phenol at 0.1%, but not in the presence of sodium chloride.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme, ciprofloxacin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin (weak), oleandomycin (weak), penicillin G, polymyxin B and vancomycin (weak), but sensitive to amikacin, aureomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin sulfate, netilmicin, streptomycin, terramycin, tetracycline and tobramycin.</s><s>The cell wall of strain YIM 33378<sup>T</sup> contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Whole-cell sugars are galactose and arabinose.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub><em>ω</em>-cycl) is the major menaquinone and minor amount of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) is also present.</s><s>The phospholipids are diphosphatidyl glycerol, phosphatidyl ethanolamine, phosphatidyl inositol and phosphatidyl inositol mannosides.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are: ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, 5.0%; i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, 2.4%; i-2OH-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, 6.2%; C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, 26.1%; ai-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, 2.3%; cis6,9- C<sub>18 : 2</sub>, 8.9%; cis9-C<sub>18: 1</sub>, 12.5%; C<sub>18: 0</sub>, 16.8%; 10-methyl C<sub>18: 0</sub>, 11.0%; cis6,9-C<sub>20 : 2</sub>, 2.3%.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA was 65.4 mol%.</s><s>It was isolated from soil in Lijiang, Yunnan Province, China.</s><s>The type strain is strain YIM 33378<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 204005<sup>T</sup>= KCTC 19028<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>