<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1331_nm.4425" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4425" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4425" rank="species">Selenomonas dianae</organism><reference id="rid.1331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas noxia sp. nov., Selenomonas flueggei sp. nov., Selenomonas infelix sp. nov., Selenomonas dianae sp. nov., and Selenomonas artemidis sp. nov., from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>280</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas dianae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenomonas dianae</i> (di.a'nae L. gen. n. <i>dianae</i> of Diana, goddess of the moon [referring to the crescent shape of the cells]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, motile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods.</s><s>Cells are curved, crescent shaped, and 1.1 pm in diameter by 3.2 to 11.6 μm long.</s><s>With Leifson flagellum stain, cells appear to have one or more central-to-polar flagella arising from the concave side.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On rabbit blood agar plates incubated anaerobically for 48 h, colonies are minute, circular, entire, low convex to flat and slightly spreading, transparent, shiny, smooth, and gray-white.</s><s>Strains produce good growth in PY broth and excellent growth with clear broth and granular-to-flaky sediment in PYG broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>Growth at 30 and 45°C is poor to moderate, and there is little if any growth at 25°C.</s><s>No ammonia is detected in PY or PYG broth cultures, but moderate amounts are detected in chopped meat cultures.</s><s>Neutral red is reduced.</s><s>In glucose agar deep cultures, resazurin is not reduced and little or no gas is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation acids of the type strain, in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture, are 1.6 of acetic, 3.3 of propionic, 1.9 of pyruvic, and 5.4 of lactic in PYG cultures; 0.5 of acetic and 0.9 of propionic in PY cultures; and 1.0 of acetic, 3.1 of propionic, 2.2 of pyruvic, and 0.6 of lactic in PYG-fumarate cultures.</s><s>Neither pyruvate nor lactate is used; threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>A trace amount of hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas of PYG cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The PAGE patterns of soluble proteins are shown in Fig. 4.</s><s>Cellular components of the species are given in Table 5.</s><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 53 mol%.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the three other strains tested are 57 to 59 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 43527, isolated from the supragingival flora coronal to an affected site in a person with juvenile (localized) periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species is isolated from the gingival sulcus of persons with moderate periodontitis and from the supragingival flora coronal to the sites affected with moderate and juvenile periodontitis and has been referred to as <i>Selenomonas</i> D-10 (in part) as a species that is negatively correlated with gingivitis and that does not increase in numbers in diseased sites as compared with healthy sites.</s></p></content></protolog>