<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6425_nm.1413" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1413" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1413" rank="subspecies">Liberibacter africanus capensis</organism><reference id="rid.6425"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Garnier</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jagoueix-Eveillard</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cronje</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Le Roux</surname><given-names>H.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genomic characterization of a liberibacter present in an ornamental rutaceous tree, Calodendrum capense, in the Western Cape Province of South Africa. Proposal of 'Candidatus Liberibacter africanus subsp. capensis'.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2119</fpage><lpage>2125</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155987</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of 'Candidatus <i>Liberibacter africanus</i> subsp. <i>capensis</i>' sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>PCR experiments with primers CAL1/J5 on DNA extracted from several HLB-affected citrus trees grown in the Western Cape area of South Africa and in particular from the orchard adjacent to the infected <i>C. capense</i> tree were negative (results not shown). This should be further documented, but suggests that: (i) the <i>C. capense</i> liberibacter is not (yet ?) present in citrus ; (ii) it is closely associated with the ornamental rutaceous tree ; and (iii) it does not seem to be involved in the HLB outbreak in the Western Cape. The PCR method with primers CAL1/J5 can now also be used to determine whether the citrus psyllid <i>T. erytreae</i> is infected with the <i>C. capense</i> liberibacter and whether transmission to citrus is possible. Because of the genomic and serological properties of the liberibacter from <i>C. capense</i>, it is proposed that this bacterium be assigned a subspecies status with the following designation: `Candidatus <i>Liberibacter africanus</i> subsp. <i>capensis</i>' [(α-<i>Proteobacteria</i>) NC; G-F; NAS (GenBank accession no. AF137368), oligonucleotide sequence complementary to unique region of the ribosomal protein operon 5'-GATTCGTAGAGGTGTTTTTTGAGG-3', S (<i>Calodendrum capense</i>, phloem); M].</s></p></content></protolog>