<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1342_nm.4476" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4476" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4476" rank="species">Anaerobaculum mobile</organism><reference id="rid.1342"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Menes</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muxí</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerobaculum mobile sp. nov., a novel anaerobic, moderately thermophilic, peptide-fermenting bacterium that uses crotonate as an electron acceptor, and emended description of the genus Anaerobaculum.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>164</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837298</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerobaculum mobile</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerobaculum mobile</i> (mo'bi.le. L. masc. adj. <i>mobile</i> motile).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 0.5-1.0x2.0-4.0 μm, motile by means of a single flagellum inserted in the lateral region of the cell body, occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic and chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>No spores observed.</s><s>Moderately thermophilic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 35-65°C, with an optimum between 55 and 60°C, and at pH 5.4-8.7, with an optimum between 6.6 and 7.3.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration is 0.08 g l<sup>-1</sup> (in media with no added NaCl), but growth occurs up to 15 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Ferments malate, tartrate, pyruvate, glycerol, starch, glucose, fructose, gluconate, Casamino acids, tryptone and yeast extract.</s><s>Carbohydrates and organic acids are converted to acetate, hydrogen and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Oxidizes leucine to isovalerate with crotonate as electron acceptor, but not in coculture with a methanogenic partner.</s><s>Thiosulfate, sulfur and cystine are reduced to sulfide.</s><s>Crotonate is reduced to butyrate.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, fumarate, acetate and nitrate are not reduced.</s><s>No growth occurs on citrate, 2-oxoglutarate, glutamate, mannose, pectin, lactose, xylose, galactose, maltose, sucrose, rhamnose, raffinose, malonate, lactate, succinate, xylan, dextrin, inulin, melibiose, adonitol, cellobiose, arabinose, polygalacturonate, cellulose, gelatin, butyrate or oleate.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content is 51.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is NGA<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13181<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-54<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the sludge of an anaerobic lagoon treating wool-scouring wastewater from Uruguay.</s></p></content></protolog>