<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6148_nm.9638" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9638" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9638" rank="species">Roseivirga echinicomitans</organism><reference id="rid.6148"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseivirga echinicomitans sp. nov., a novel marine bacterium isolated from the sea urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius, and emended description of the genus Roseivirga</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1797</fpage><lpage>1800</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63621-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166668</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseivirga echinicomitans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseivirga echinicomitans</em> [e.chi.ni.co′mi.tans. L. n. <em>echinus</em> -<em>i</em> sea urchin; L. pres. part. c<em>omitans</em> (from L. v. <em>comito</em>) accompanying; N.L. part. adj. <em>echinicomitans</em> accompanying a sea urchin].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells range from 0·3 to 0·5 μm in width and 2·1 to 3·2 μm in length.</s><s>Gliding motility not observed.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular, shiny with entire edges and pink-pigmented.</s><s>Growth is observed at 4–31 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 21–23 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 1–8 % NaCl. <em>β</em>-Galactosidase-positive.</s><s>Decomposes aesculin, gelatin and Tween 40.</s><s>Does not degrade agar, casein, starch, DNA, Tweens 20 or 80, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Does not form acid from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, l-raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-sucrose, dl-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, citrate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Does not utilize l-arabinose, d-lactose, d-mannose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, malonate or citrate.</s><s>Positive results for citrate utilization, acid formation from amygdalin, assimilation of glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose and adipate and activity of esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and alkaline and acid phosphatases are obtained with API 20E, API 20NE and API ZYM kits.</s><s>According to Microlog GN2 (Biolog), utilizes d-galacturonic acid, glycerol, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate, inosine, thymidine, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-galactose, d-sorbitol, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid and 2,3-butanediol and does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Results are negative for H<sub>2</sub>S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) production.</s><s>Fatty acids accounting for more than 1·0 % are i13 : 0 (2·9 %), i14 : 0 (1·9 %), i15 : 1 (20·2 %), a15 : 1 (2·4 %), i15 : 0 (20·2 %), a15 : 0 (13·1 %), i16 : 1 (2 %), i16 : 0 (1·8 %), i15 : 0 3-OH (4·1 %), i17 : 0 (1 %), 17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1·1 %), i16 : 0 3-OH (4·2 %), i17 : 0 3-OH (12·1 %), 17 : 0 2-OH (2 %) and summed feature 3 (1 %), comprising 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7 and/or i15 : 0 2-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 41·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 6058<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12370<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22587<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the sea urchin <em>Strongylocentrotus intermedius</em> collected in Troitsa Bay, Gulf of Peter the Great, East Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>