<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1321_nm.7953" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7953" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7953" rank="species">Bacteroides gingivalis</organism><reference id="rid.1321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coykendall</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaczmarek</surname><given-names>F.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Slots</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genetic heterogeneity in Bacteroides asaccharolyticus (Holdeman and Moore 1980) Finegold and Barnes 1977 (Approved Lists, 1980) and proposal of Bacteroides gingivalis sp. nov. and Bacteroides macacae (Slots and Genco) comb. nov.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>559</fpage><lpage>564</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides gingivalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides gingivalis</i> (L.n. <i>gingiva</i> gum; L. gen. n. <i>gingiualis</i> of the gums)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods which occur as coccobacilli or as long rods (0.5 by 1.0 to 2.0 μm).</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>On blood agar containing hemin and menadione, cells form small (1 to 2-mm), convex colonies which become brownish and then black in 7 to 10 days, although the pigment rate can vary among strains.</s><s>Sugars are not fermented.</s><s>Cultures do not reduce nitrate, hydrolyze esculin, or produce catalase.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>The end products of metabolism are <i>n</i>-butyric, isobutyric, propionic, <i>iso</i>-valeric, and acetic acids, succinic acid is either not produced or is produced in small quantities.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 46.5 to 48.4 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Strain Slots 2561 is designated as the type strain.</s><s>It was isolated by Slots from a human gingival sulcus.</s><s>Its description conforms to that of the species, and it has a DNA base content of 47.1 mol% G+C.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection.</s><s>Its accession number is ATCC 33277.</s></p></content></protolog>