<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6278_nm.7691" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7691" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7691" rank="species">Bifidobacterium gallicum</organism><reference id="rid.6278"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lauer</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium gallicum sp. nov. isolated from human feces.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>100</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-100</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium gallicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium gallicum</i>(gal'limm. N.L. adj. <i>gallicus</i>, of or belonging to the Gauls, although ethnic relationships to the French remain speculative)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Short rods with rounded ends, generally 0.7 to 0.9 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm, mostly arranged in pairs or short chains when grown in liquid culture.</s><s>Irregular elongations and swellings occur in cells obtained from colony growth.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Not flagellated.</s><s>Slimy, capsule-like material is excreted in complex media containing meat extract, bacteriological peptone, salts, and fermentable carbohydrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are whitish, opaque, round, and entire and have a soft consistency.</s><s>A weak odor of acetic acid is produced in fresh cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main fermentation product is acetic acid, and its concentration is about 15 times that of L-(+)-lactic acid; in addition, variable amounts of ethanol (and certainly formic acid) are formed.</s><s>No D-(-)-lactic acid or gas is produced.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Obligatory saccharoclastic via the characteristic bifidoshunt.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37 to 39°C; no growth occurs below 30°C or at 45°C and above.</s><s>Growth occurs in the range of pH 5.0 to 8.0; optimum growth occurs at pH 6.0 to 7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are fermented: L-(+)-arabhose, D-(+)-xylose, D-(-)-ribose, D-glucose, D-galactose, D-fructose, sucrose, maltose, dextrin, starch, and glycogen.</s><s>Salicin is slowly fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are not fermented: D-gluconate, D-(-)-arabinose, L-(-)-xylose, D-(+)-mannose, L-(-)-sorbose, lactose, cellobiose, melibiose, trehalose, raffinose, melezitose, raffinose, D-(-)-mannitol, D-(-)-sorbitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, glycerol, and L-(+)-rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Litmus milk is not changed.</s><s>Arginine is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S, lipase, gelatinase, urease, and catalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzyme activities are present in cell-free extracts: fructose-6-phosphate and xylulose-5-phosphate phosphoketolases; L-(+)-lactate dehydrogenase (NAD dependent and allosterically regulated by fructose 1,6-diphosphate); and transaldolase.</s><s>There is no fructose-1,6-diphosphate aldolase activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Relative electrophoretic mobilities are as follows: lactate dehydrogenase (R<sub>LDH</sub>), 1.10 relative to rabbit-iso-I lactate dehydrogenase of muscle; transaldolase (R<sub>TA</sub>), 1.65 relative to type X transaldolase of yeast.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type of peptidoglycan is L-Lys-L-Ala-L-Ser (A3α), with some lysine replaced by ornithine to a variable degree.</s><s>The cell wall polysaccharide comprises a galactan polymer of unknown structure; minor amounts of rhamnose may be found in addition to galactose after growth on less complex media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The levels of DNA-DNA relatedness to other bifidobacteria range from 8 to 25%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: not known.</s><s>Only one strain has been isolated from human feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 20093 (= P6).</s></p></content></protolog>