<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1324_nm.4237" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4237" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4237" rank="species">Eubacterium brachy</organism><reference id="rid.1324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burmeister</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Descriptions of Eubacterium timidum sp. nov., Eubacterium brachy sp. nov., and Eubacterium nodatum sp. nov. isolated from human periodontitis.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-1-163</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium brachy</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium brachy</i> (bra'chy. M.L. neut. adj. <i>brachy</i> from Gk. <i>brachy</i> short [referring to the length of the cells]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species are obligately anaerobic, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, short, gram-positive rods that occur predominantly in long chains.</s><s>Cells from PY or PY-glucose broth cultures were 0.4 to 0.8 by 1 to 3 μm.</s><s>Although some cells in a chain might be coccoid, definite rods could be seen upon close examination of the smears.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days in roll tubes, colonies of all strains were 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, lenticular to trifoliate, and transparent to opaque.</s><s>After incubation for 2 days, surface colonies on supplemented BHIA streak tubes were less than 0.5 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, white, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Surface colonies on chopped meat broth agar were similar to those on BHIA but were larger (1.0 mm in diameter).</s><s>Surface growth was obtained more reliably on chopped meat broth agar than on BHIA tubes or anaerobic BAP.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Broth cultures of all strains had a small amount of fine, granular to smooth sediment, often without turbidity.</s><s>Broth cultures often required incubation for 2 to 3 days to attain maximum growth, which at best was 2+, as graded on a scale of negative to 4+.</s><s>Growth of all strains was slightly inhibited by 20% oxgall but was neither inhibited nor stimulated by the addition of 0.02% Tween 80, 5% rumen fluid, or 10% serum with cocarboxylase.</s><s>The temperature for optimum growth was 37°C; most strains did not grow at 30 or 45°C.</s><s>Growth occurred only in the anaerobic portion of agar deep cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because growth was so slight in all media tested, we were unable to obtain enough cells to extract DNA for a determination of the G+C content.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and fermentation products.</s><s>In addition to the characteristics presented in Table 2, growth was not inhibited by 0.05% SPS.</s><s>No strain grew on anaerobically incubated tyrosine plates.</s><s>A small amount of gas was produced in agar deep cultures that had reasonably good growth.</s><s>The type strain and five other strains tested (each isolated from a different person) did not grow in 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>The one strain (of five tested) that grew on anaerobically incubated BAP or egg yolk agar plates did not produce detectable hemolysis; no lecithinase or lipase activity was noted.</s><s>Neutral red was sometimes reduced, apparently depending upon the amount of growth (because most strains grew as fine granules, it was difficult to obtain a uniform inoculum in each tube of substrate).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Major products from broth cultures (PY broth or PY broth plus any of several carbohydrates) of all strains after incubation for to 4 to 5 days averaged (in milliequivalents per 100 ml): isocaproate, 0.5; isovalerate, 0.3; and isobutyrate, 0.3.</s><s>Acetate (0.1 meq/100 ml), formate (0.15 meq/100 ml), and succinate (0.15 meq/100 ml) were also often detected.</s><s>Headspace gas of 5-day-old broth cultures contained 2 to 3% hydrogen.</s><s>Neither lactate nor pyruvate was used.</s><s>Ammonia was produced in PY broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of 30 strains tested, 23 produced sufficient growth in supplemented brain heart infusion broth for reliable interpretation of susceptibility tests.</s><s>All 23 strains were susceptible to test levels of chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin G, and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is VPI D6B-23 (=ATCC 33089), which was isolated from a subgingival area which exhibited periodontitis.</s><s>Because of the fermentation products and the occurrence of short cells in chains, this species resembled <i>P. anaerobius.</i> It initially appeared different from <i>P. anaerobius</i> because it did not grow as well in the usual media and definite rods could be seen in Gram stains.</s><s>The inability of <i>E. brachy</i> to grow on the Schaedler agar-tyrosine plates and its ability to grow in the presence of 0.05% SPS were additional confirmation that this species was different from <i>P. anaerobius</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. brachy</i> was detected in 35% of the subgingival samples and constituted 3 to 30% of the cultivable flora in those specimens from which it was isolated.</s><s>One strain was isolated from 1 of the 16 supragingival samples examined.</s><s>No strains were isolated from the subgingival area adjacent to this sample.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We have received for identification one strain of <i>E . brachy</i> (sent to us by Leona Stringer, Anaheim Memorial Hospital, Anaheim, Calif.) which was isolated, along with <i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i>, from a lung abscess specimen collected by needle aspiration.</s></p></content></protolog>