<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2200_nm.8135" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8135" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8135" rank="species">Capnocytophaga canimorsus</organism><reference id="rid.2200"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Capnocytophaga canimorsus sp. nov. (formerly CDC group DF-2), a cause of septicemia following dog bite, and C. cynodegmi sp. nov., a cause of localized wound infection following dog bite</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>231</fpage><lpage>235</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2915017</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Capnocytophaga canimorsus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Capnocytophaga canimorsus</i> (ca.ni.mor'sus. L. <i>canis</i>, dog; L. <i>morsus</i>; a bite, biting; N.L. gen. n. <i>canimorsus</i> of a dog bite)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are thin, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods 1 to 3 μm long.</s><s>In preparations for blood agar, longer rods, filaments (often curved), spindle-shaped cells, and coccoid forms are also present.</s><s>Flagella are not present; gliding motility as seen by bright-field microscopy.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar at 18 to 24 h are less than 0.5 mm in diameter and may be either convex or flat.</s><s>Flat colonies usually are irregular in shape.</s><s>Some convex colonies have a very narrow, flat edge.</s><s>After incubation for 48 h, colonies are 1 to 3.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>The surface is raised or slightly uneven, and there may or may not be a flat, spreading edge.</s><s>No hemolysis occurs on rabbit blood agar, but confluent growth is seen at 24 h, and colonies at 48 h frequently appear to be light purple.</s><s>The cell mass, when removed from the plate on a loop, however, is light yellow.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>No growth or a neutral reaction on triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Microaerophilic, grow best on heart infusion agar supplemented with 5% rabbit or sheep blood incubated at 35 to 37°C in the presence of C02 (candle extinction jar).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive reactions in tests for oxidase (some strains are weakly positive), catalase, arginine dihydrolase, o-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, and alkaline phosphatase (13).</s><s>Acid production from D-glucose, lactose, and maltose and in most strains from dextrin, D-galactose, glycogen, D-mannose, and starch.</s><s>Variable reactions (10 to 75% positive) in tests for nitrite reduction, esculin hydrolysis, and acid production from cellobiose and fructose.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production, growth on citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production (13), urease, nitrate reduction, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, gelatin hydrolysis, gas production from D-glucose, and acid production from adonitol (13), L-arabinose (13), dulcitol (13), <i>meso</i>-inositol (13), inulin, D-mannitol, melibiose, raftinose, L-rhamnose (13), salicin (13), sorbitol (13), L-sorbose (13), sucrose, trehalose (13), and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Butler et al. reported that DF-2 is susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, penicillin, and tetracycline; resistant to colistin, gentamicin, and kanamycin; and variably resistant to trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole (3).</s><s>In contrast, Verghese et al. (14) recently tested nine strains and found them to be susceptible to trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole and aminoglycosides; colistin was not tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of DNAs from the type strain and three other strains were 36 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human blood, cerebrospinal fluid, and wounds and from the mouths of healthy dogs.</s><s>Pathogenic for humans, causing septicemia, especially in individuals predisposed by splenectomy or alcoholism.</s><s>The route of infection is through the skin after a bite or scratch from a dog or, rarely, a cat or other animal.</s><s>The route of infection was unknown in 20% of the cases reviewed by Hicklin et al. (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 7120 (=ATCC 35979), which was isolated in Upland, Calif., from the blood of a 17-year-old</s></p><p class="description"><s>male in 1961 (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical tests to differentiate <i>C. canimorsus</i> from other <i>Capnocytophaga</i> species are shown in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>