<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7508_nm.896" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.896" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.896" rank="species">Acidiphilium organovorum</organism><reference id="rid.7508"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lobos</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chisolm</surname><given-names>T.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bopp</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidiphilium organovorum sp. nov., an acidophilic heterotroph isolated from a Thiobacillus ferrooxidans culture.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>139</fpage><lpage>144</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-139</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidiphilium organovorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidiphilium organovorum</i> (or.ga.no'vor.um. N. L. n. <i>organum</i> organic, compound; L. v. <i>voro</i> eat, consume; N. L. adj. <i>organovorum</i> organisms which use organic compounds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, aerobic, mesophilic bacilli or coccobacilli (0.6 by 0.8 to 1.0 μm).</s><s>Motile, heterotrophic, obligately acidophilic.</s><s>A variety of organic compounds support growth as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>These include simple sugars, sugar alcohols, carboxylic acids, and amino acids.</s><s>No growth occurs on lactose, maltose, cellobiose, or any form of reduced sulfur or iron.</s><s>Acetic acid and pyruvic acid completely inhibit cell growth at concentrations of 0.01 and 0.1%, respectively.</s><s>Increased growth occurs at glucose concentrations (0.5 to 2.0%) higher than those previously used for culturing other <i>Acidiphilium</i> species (5) .</s><s>Nutritional supplements of yeast extract and trace amounts of FeSO<sub>4</sub> enhance growth.</s><s>Cell doubling times of 2.5 h and cell densities of ≥2 x 10<sup>10</sup> cells per ml are obtained in basal salts-glucose medium supplemented with yeast extract and FeSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>For growth on solid medium, low amounts (0.5 to 0.8%) of high-purity agarose must be used.</s><s>White, glossy colonies ≥2 mm in diameter form in 3 to 4 days.</s><s>This bacterium gives positive catalase and negative oxidase reactions.</s><s>No endospores are formed, and cells die rapidly at temperatures of ≥50°C.</s><s>Susceptible to the antibiotics tetracycline, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, and rifampin.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64 mol%.</s><s>Of the bacteria tested, DNA homology studies indicate that <i>A. organovorum</i> is most closely related to <i>A. cryptum</i>.</s><s>The type strain of <i>A. organovorum</i> is strain ATCC 43141.</s></p></content></protolog>