<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6338_nm.413" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.413" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.413" rank="species">Geoglobus ahangari</organism><reference id="rid.6338"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kashefi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tor</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gaw Van Praagh</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reysenbach</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lovley</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Geoglobus ahangari gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel hyperthermophilic archaeon capable of oxidizing organic acids and growing autotrophically on hydrogen with Fe(III) serving as the sole electron acceptor.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>719</fpage><lpage>728</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01953-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054231</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Geoglobus ahangari</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Geoglobus ahangari</i> (a.han.ga'ri. N.L. n. <i>ahangari</i> from Farsi masc. n. <i>ahangar</i> a blacksmith or a smith who works with iron, named after Kaveh Ahangar, the mythical Persian hero who was also a blacksmith by trade; arbitrary name referring to the ability to use Fe(III) as an electron acceptor)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain was enriched from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent (chimney) sample from Guaymas Basin, Gulf of California (at a depth of 2000 m) with pyruvate as the electron donor and poorly crystalline Fe(III) oxide as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Grows by oxidizing H<sub>2</sub>, acetate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, formate, malate, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, yeast extract, peptone, isoleucine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, arginine, L-cysteine, serine, glutamine, asparagine, propionate, butyrate, valerate, palmitate or stearate coupled to the reduction of Fe(III).</s><s>Only poorly crystalline Fe(III) oxide and Fe(III) citrate are used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Other electron acceptors such as S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup>, SO<sub>4</sub><sup>2-</sup>, SO<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup>, S<sup>0</sup>, NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup>, O<sub>2</sub>, Mn(IV), AQDS, malate and fumarate are not utilized as electron acceptors (Table 1).</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 65 and 90 °C (optimum temperature, approximately 88 °C), in the presence of NaCl concentrations of 9.0-38.0 g l<sup>-1</sup> (optimum 19 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>) and at near-neutral pH (pH 6.8-7.0).</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, phosphomycin, rifampicin and trimethoprim, but resistant to cycloheximide, kanamycin, neomycin sulfate, novobiocin, puromycin, streptomycin and vancomycin hydrochloride.</s><s>The type strain is strain 234<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-425<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The 16S rDNA sequence has been deposited in GenBank under accession number AF220165.</s></p></content></protolog>