<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.547_nm.8101" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8101" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8101" rank="species">Flavobacterium micromati</organism><reference id="rid.547"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandecandelaere</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium degerlachei sp. nov., Flavobacterium frigoris sp. nov. and Flavobacterium micromati sp. nov., novel psychrophilic bacteria isolated from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>85</fpage><lpage>92</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02857-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742463</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium micromati</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium micromati</em> (mi.cro.mat′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>micromati</em> referring to the MICROMAT project).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (&#x003C;1×3–4 μm); gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5–20 °C, very weak growth is observed at 25 °C and no growth occurs at 30 °C.</s><s>Orange–red, convex, translucent colonies with entire margins and a diameter of 1–3 mm are formed on R2A plates after 6 days incubation.</s><s>Colonies on Anacker &#x0026; Ordal's agar are flat, round with entire margins and 0·5–1·0 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on trypticase soy agar (weak), nutrient agar and marine agar (weak).</s><s>Colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Aesculin is degraded.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Growth on carbohydrates (API 20NE) is not observed and acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive for all strains.</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, casein, CM-cellulose, DNA, gelatin, tyrosine, starch and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed and no flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>No production of brown diffusible pigment occurs on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains shows activity for the enzymes arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl <em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Medium enzymic activity is observed for esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) and strong activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Cells contain the fatty acids C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (which comprises iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> or both) as the main constituents.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–2 % NaCl, but not in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 33·1–34·4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21919<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108161<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from Lake Grace in the Vestfold Hills and Lake Fryxell in the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>