<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7434_nm.8158" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8158" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8158" rank="species">Coenonia anatina</organism><reference id="rid.7434"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryll</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Köhler</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Coenonia anatina gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel bacterium associated with respiratory disease in ducks and geese.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>867</fpage><lpage>874</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-867</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319512</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Coenonia anatina</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Coenonia anatina</i> (a.na.ti'na. L. adj. <i>anatinus</i> of a duck)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>In 16-h-old cultures on blood agar, the mean cell size is 0.2-0.4 μm in width and 1-25-23 μm in length.</s><s>Some cells are spherically swollen, spindle or lemon-shaped and arranged in short chains.</s><s>Strains produce flat-convex, circular and non-pigmented to whitish colonies with entire edges and a smooth surface on blood agar.</s><s>The strains do not require special growth factors and grow on conventional media.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 37°C in a microaerobic and CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere.</s><s>Growth is weak in anaerobic conditions and absent in aerobic conditions.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar or on Simmons citrate agar.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>All strains produce catalase and oxidase activity.</s><s>Hyaluronidase and chondroitin sulfatase activity is present.</s><s>No urease, gelatinase, arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase or ornithine or lysine decarboxylase activity.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Production of acetylmethylcarbinol but not indole.</s><s>Methyl red reaction is negative.</s><s>No utilization of citrate.</s><s>No alkali from malonate.</s><s>Acid production in BSS medium from D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose, D-mannose, lactose, D-galactose, N-acetyl glucosamine, lactulose and dextrin but not from trehalose, adonitol, L-arabinose, dulcitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, saccharose, salicin, sorbose or D-xylose.</s><s>Using the API ZYM microtest system, activities of alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, leucine, valine and cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase and trypsin are detected; activity of lipase C 14, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase are not detected.</s><s>Using the API ID 32 E microtest system, acidification of glucose and activities of α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, amaltosidase, lipase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and L-aspartic acid arylamidase are detected; activities of arginine dihydrolase, ornithine and lysine decarboxylase, urease and β-glucuronidase, indole production and acidification of L-arabitol, galacturonate, 5-ketoghconate, mannitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, trehalose, rhamnose, inositol, maltose, adonitol, palatinose, saccharose, cellobiose and sorbitol are not detected.</s><s>The major fatty acid components of all strains examined are 13:0 iso (about 34%), 14:0 (about 3%), 15:0 iso (about 41%), 15:0 anteiso (about 3%), 15:0 iso 3-OH (about 6.5%), 16:0 3-OH (about 4 %) and 17:0 iso 3-OH (about 6.5%).</s><s>Strains have been isolated as pure cultures under microaerobic conditions from samples of the respiratory tract (lungs, airsac fibrin, pericard) and brain of ducks and geese, always associated with signs similar to those of <i>R. anatipestifer</i>-associated exudative septicaemia.</s><s>In the northern part of Germany, <i>Coenonia anatina</i> strains were recovered from over 30% of the cases of septicaemia-related losses in commercial duck flocks in the period 1994-1995.</s><s>Vaccination with an inactivated whole culture of <i>Coenonia anatina</i> strains induced protection of ducklings against <i>Coenonia anatina</i>-associated disease.</s><s>These data suggest its pathogenic role.</s><s>The DNA G + C content of representative strains varied between 35 and 36 mol%.</s><s>All <i>Coenonia anatina</i> strains listed in Table 1 have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG bacteria collection (URL http ://www. belspo.be/bccm/lmg.htm).</s><s>The type strain is LMG 14382<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from a Pekin duck in Germany.</s><s>Its DNA G + C content is 35 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>