<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.703_nm.3886" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3886" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3886" rank="species">Clostridium aerotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van der Toorn</surname><given-names>J.J.T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium aerotolerans sp. nov., a xylanolytic bacterium from corn stover and from the rumina of sheep fed corn stover.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>102</fpage><lpage>105</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-2-102</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium aerotolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium aerotolerans</i> (ae.ro.to'le.rans Gr. masc. n. <i>aer</i>, air, gas; L. v. <i>tolerare</i>, to endure, to put up with; L. neut. part. adj. <i>aerotolerans</i>, air-enduring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grow under strictly anaerobic conditions and also in agar or liquid medium free of added reducing agent.</s><s>They also grow in a shallow layer of liquid medium (5 ml in 50-ml Erlenmeyer flasks loosely covered with sterile caps) free of added reducing agent but exposed to air.</s><s>In this medium growth is observed within 7 or 8 h after inoculation and can be seen as a turbid layer on the bottom of the flasks where the medium is reduced with respect to resazurin.</s><s>About 15 min after gentle shaking of the flasks to suspend the bacteria, the resazurin is almost completely reduced.</s><s>On standing, the upper layer of medium again becomes at least partly oxidized with respect to resazurin, and after incubation for a further period of 16 to 17 h, growth appears as a dense layer on the bottom of the flasks with only the uppermost layer of medium showing some color due to oxidized resazurin.</s><s>At this stage vigorous shaking is required to dislodge the bacteria from the bottom of the flask where most growth has occurred.</s><s>Incubation in a shaking water bath of inoculated medium prepared in the same way does not produce any growth, and the medium is not reduced with respect to resazurin even after 3 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from 16-h cultures on agar slopes containing either cellobiose or xylan are gram negative.</s><s>Very little, if any, stain is adsorbed if crystal violet is the only stain used, Vegetative cells are straight rods often with somewhat pointed ends (Fig. 1A and B).</s><s>They usually occur singly.</s><s>Their width varies from 0.4 to 0.6 μm, and their length is about 1.5 to 3.0 μm and sometimes more.</s><s>Cells are motile by peritrichous flagella (Fig. 1B).</s><s>Spores stain green with malachite green.</s><s>They are terminal and distend the cells where they are formed (Fig. 1C).</s><s>They are slightly oval and measure about 0.6 by 0.8 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation for 3 days on films of glucose (0.5%) agar medium in roll bottles, surface colonies are round with smooth or almost smooth edges.</s><s>They are convex and appear translucent at the edges to semitranslucent and light brown at the center.</s><s>Colonies are up to 2.5 mm wide.</s><s>Submerged colonies are lens shaped and appear brown when viewed from the side.</s><s>Surface colonies in xylan (3%) agar medium in roll bottles appear similar to those that develop on glucose medium and are surrounded by a clear zone (1 to 3 cm in diameter) due to the dissolution of xylan.</s><s>In addition, there are large spreading colonies with lobate edges and thin translucent growth.</s><s>Dissolution of xylan extends to several millimeters beyond the outer periphery of these colonies.</s><s>Submerged, lens-shaped colonies give rise to clearing zones of 1 cm or more in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The four strains are saccharoclastic and show little, if any, growth in media containing peptone and yeast extract but without added carbohydrate.</s><s>Peptone and yeast extract can replace rumen fluid in medium containing carbohydrate.</s><s>Media containing rumen fluid as the sole source of growth factors support moderate growth.</s><s>For two strains tested (X8A62 and X2) absorbance at 578 nm (1-cm path length) of medium containing clarified rumen fluid and cellobiose increases by about 0.3 U in 16 h.</s><s>If this medium is supplemented with peptone (10 g/liter), the absorbance increases to about 0.6 U over the same period.</s><s>If the medium is further supplemented with yeast extract (5 g/liter), the absorbance reached after 16 h is about 0.9 U.</s><s>The last value is also obtained when the medium is enriched with only the yeast extract (without the peptone).</s><s>Incubation for longer periods does not yield appreciably higher absorbance readings.</s><s>A medium containing (apart from minerals and Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>) only glucose (5 g/liter), yeast extract (5 g/liter), cysteine hydrochloride.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>O (0.125 g/liter), and Na<sub>2</sub>S⋄9H<sub>2</sub>O (0.125 g/liter) gives a maximum absorbance of about 1.8 U.</s><s>This medium was used to assess the approximate optimum growth temperature of strain X8A62.</s><s>The maximum absorbance (between 1.4 and 1.8 U) is attained after about 24 h at 38T, 30 h at 30°C, and 60 h at 22°C.</s><s>After 60 h at 15°C, absorbance is about 0.1 U.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A wide range of carbohydrate energy sources is fermented (Table 1) with the final pH not falling below 5.2.</s><s>Xylan is fermented to formic, acetic, and lactic acids, ethanol, hydrogen, and carbon dioxide (Table 2).</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the four strains liquefies gelatin or digests casein, and no H<sub>2</sub> S is formed from peptone or from sulfate reduction.</s><s>Neither indole nor α-methylindole is produced.</s><s>There is no indication that the bacteria possess urease, catalase, or enzymes for reducing nitrate.</s><s>Some lipase activity was exhibited by all four strains.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is about 40 mol% for all four strains.</s><s>All nine values fell between 39 and 41 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is X8A62 (ATCC 43524), isolated from the rumen of a sheep.</s></p></content></protolog>