<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1426_nm.3888" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3888" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3888" rank="species">Clostridium aldrichii</organism><reference id="rid.1426"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chynoweth</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium aldrichii sp. nov., a cellulolytic mesophile inhabiting a wood-fermenting anaerobic digester.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>268</fpage><lpage>272</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-268</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397194</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium aldrichii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium aldrichii</i> (Al. dri´chi.i, N.L. gen. n., of Aldrich, named for Henry C. Aldrich, a professor of the University of Florida, Gainesville, for his contributions to ultrastructural research on the strictly anaerobic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are easily decolorized in Gram stains, but KOH and LANA tests are negative.</s><s>Cell wall structure is that of gram-positive bacterium (Fig. 1A).</s><s>Cells are 0.5 to 1.0 μm by 3 to 5 μm, straight or slightly curved with rounded ends (Fig. 2).</s><s>Pleomorphism is evident, with some cells up to 8 to 12 μm in length; occasionally, some cells are swollen at both attached ends of paired cells.</s><s>Cells are arranged mostly in pairs but some are single, or in short chains (Fig. 2).</s><s>Round particles are sometimes seen between two connected cells (Fig. 1B and 2A).</s><s>Young cells of strain P-1 are motile, with a bundle of flagella at one end of the cell (Fig. 3).</s><s>Oblong spores occur subterminally and are formed after 2 weeks in a medium containing salts, trace vitamins, and cellobiose as the only carbon source at 35°C.</s><s>Mature spores are 0.5 to 1.0 μm by 1 to 2 μm (Fig. 2B).</s><s>Spores are viable after being heated at 80°C for 10 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphologically identical colonies appear in CAM 4 to 6 days after transfer of strain P-1 from medium to medium and within 24 h in the medium with cellobiose as the substrate.</s><s>The surface colonies are round, smooth, entire, soft, jellylike, semitransparent or greyish white, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Clear zones caused by cellulolytic activity around colonies are usually 4 to 6 mm in diameter, and the widths of the clear zones from the edge of the colonies are 2 to 3 mm.</s><s>In roll tubes, surface colonies often flow down along the agar surface to form elongated colonies; the clear zones subsequently appear around the elongated growth.</s><s>Subsurface colonies are irregular in shape, with many platelike structures in different dimensions; they are greyish white and more opaque than surface colonies (Fig. 4).</s><s>This distinctive colony morphology and associated clear zone facilitate recognition of colonies of strain P-1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain P-1 is a strict anaerobe.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 35°C, with a range between 20 and 45°C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 7, and the range is 6.2 to 7.8.</s><s>P-1 does not require rumen fluid, digester sludge, Trypticase, yeast extract, and added trace vitamins for growth but grows more slowly without these additions.</s><s>Cellulose, xylan, and cellobiose serve as growth substrates, and esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, erythritol, fructose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquified, and milk is not clotted.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>The isolate does not reduce nitrate to nitrite, and the lecithinase A test is negative.</s><s>The fermentation products from cellobiose are acetic, propionic, isobutyric, butyric, isovaleric, lactic, and succinic acids, hydrogen, and carbon dioxide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The G+C content of strain P-1 DNA is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>C. aldrichii</i> is strain P-1 (= OGI 112, = ATCC 49358 [OGI, Collection of Methanogenic Archaeobacteria of Oregon Graduate Institute of Science and Technology]).</s><s>It was isolated in 1986 from a 3-month-old, mesophilic, poplar wood-fed continuously stirred anaerobic digester.</s><s>It has been considered a predominant cellulolytic bacterium, since it inhabited (at 10<sup>6</sup> to 10<sup>7</sup>) this digester for at least 2 years.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enumeration of strain P-1.</s><s>Cellulolytic activities in CSM (digestion of the immersed part of the filter paper strip; Fig. 5) and CAM (colonies with clear zones; Fig. 4) correspondingly appear in the same or nearly the same dilution in isolations, and the highest dilutions showing positive cellulolytic activity fall in the range of 10<sup>-6</sup> to 10<sup>-7</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>Clostridium aldrichii</i> P-1 is considered a new species on the basis of the following evidence.</s><s>Most mesophilic, cellulolytic <i>Clostridium</i> species which have been reported (10-12, 14, 15, 18, 19) grow and produce acids in glucose; strain P-1 does not produce acids from glucose.</s><s>No immunological cross-reactions were observed between the polyclonal antibody of <i>C. aldrichii</i> P-1 and 14 other known bacterial species (including 11 cellutololytic species) by using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay technique (an immunological study of <i>C. aldrichii</i> P-1 will be reported elsewhere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only one reported cellulolytic, mesophilic <i>Clostridium</i> species, <i>Clostridium</i> polysaccharolyticurn (20, 21), does not produce acids from glucose.</s><s>The important characteristics of the two species are compared in Table 1.</s><s>Although the DNA base ratios are similar, the arrangement of the flagella, acid production from different carbohydrates, and the differences in fermentation products from cellobiose are the primary bases for separating them into different species.</s></p></content></protolog>