<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8033_nm.996" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.996" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.996" rank="species">Ehrlichia muris</organism><reference id="rid.8033"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rikihisa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mott</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuerst</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suto</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ehrlichia muris sp. nov., identified on the basis of 16S rRNA base sequences and serological, morphological, and biological characteristics.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>250</fpage><lpage>254</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-250</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537059</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ehrlichia muris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ehrlichia muris</i> (mu’ris. L. gen. n. <i>muris</i>, of a mouse; the species was first isolated from a mouse)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, pleomorphic cocci and vary in size, ranging from 0.4 to 1.5 μm long and from 0.2 to 1.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>This organism can establish infections in mice when it is injected intraperitoneally and can cause severe clinical signs in laboratory mice, including splenomegaly and lymphadenopathy.</s><s>Inclusion bodies are observed only in the cytoplasm of spleen and peritoneal macrophages of infected mice on smears stained by the Giemsa method.</s><s>As determined by electron microscopy, small pleomorphic cocci within membrane-lined vacuoles occur in the cytoplasm of macrophages, and each organism is surrounded by a distinct cytoplasmic membrane and a rippled outer membrane without a distinct peptidoglycan layer.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. muris</i> grows in dog macrophage cell line DH82 in minimum essential medium containing 10% fetal bovine serum and 2 mM L-glutamine in a 5% C0<sub>2</sub>-air atmosphere at 37°C.</s><s>No growth occurs in the yolk sacs of chicken embryos.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tetracyclines effectively prevent infection of mice, but penicillin and sulfonamides do not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>E. muris</i> is strain AS145. <i>E. muris</i> has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as VR- 1411.</s></p></content></protolog>