<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1934_nm.8773" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8773" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8773" rank="species">Phenylobacterium lituiforme</organism><reference id="rid.1934"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kanso</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenylobacterium lituiforme sp. nov., a moderately thermophilic bacterium from a subsurface aquifer, and emended description of the genus Phenylobacterium</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2141</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63138-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545448</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Phenylobacterium lituiforme</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Phenylobacterium lituiforme</em> (li.tu.i.for′me. L. masc. n. <em>lituus</em> curved rod of the augurs; L. neut. adj. suffix -<em>forme</em> having the form of; N.L. neut. adj. <em>lituiforme</em> formed like a curved rod).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain FaiI3<sup>T</sup> is a facultative anaerobe isolated from water collected from a free-flowing bore well, tapping the underground water of the Great Artesian Basin of Australia.</s><s>Yellow to pale-yellow colonies (0·5–2 mm) develop on RouF's agar plates after 48 h at 41 °C.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, with an entire edge and smooth surface, are sticky in texture, fairly easily emulsified and odour is present.</s><s>The cells are non-spore-forming straight to slightly curved rods (0·5 by 1–3 μm), motile with a single polar flagellum, occur mainly singly, some in pairs and short chains.</s><s>Cells often tend to clump in liquid medium to form rosettes.</s><s>The cells stain Gram-negative and electron micrographs of thin sections reveal a multi-layered complex Gram-negative cell wall.</s><s>Sheaths and prosthecae are not produced.</s><s>Strain FaiI3<sup>T</sup> grows optimally at 40–41 °C and growth is observed at 45 °C but not at 50 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–9 and optimal growth occurs between pH 6 and 6·5.</s><s>Strain FaiI3<sup>T</sup> is very sensitive to NaCl and growth is inhibited by 0·5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Strain FaiI3<sup>T</sup> grows best with yeast extract as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Peptone, yeast extract, acetate, pyruvate, xylose, sucrose, glucose, glycerol, succinate, butyrate, lactate, citrate, fumarate, l-phenylalanine, cellobiose and gelatin support growth but maltose, fructose, glycine, ethanol, benzoate and oxalate do not.</s><s>Tyrosine is produced from l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Strain FaiI3<sup>T</sup> is catalase-positive, oxidase-negative and does not hydrolyse starch.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by neomycin, tetracycline, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, ampicillin, vancomycin and spectinomycin.</s><s>The G+C content is 66·5±0·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is FaiI3<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-294<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14363<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>