<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8481_nm.13551" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13551" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13551" rank="species">Pseudomonas tuomuerensis</organism><reference id="rid.8481"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas tuomuerensis sp. nov., isolated from a bird's nest</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>139</fpage><lpage>143</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000547-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126738</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas tuomuerensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas tuomuerensis</em> (tuo.mu.er.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>tuomuerensis</em> pertaining to the region of Tuomuer Peak of Tianshan Mountain, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic and motile with polar multitrichous flagella, sometimes twisted into a fascicle or bundle, in a 24 h culture (Supplementary Fig. S2).</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, round, translucent, waved on the edge and 3.0–6.0 mm in diameter after 72 h incubation on nutrient agar plates.</s><s>Does not produce fluorescent pigments.</s><s>No acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–42 °C; no growth at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Grows on medium containing 0–6.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Tests for oxidase, catalase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and phenylalanine deaminase activities are positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tweens 20, 60 and 80 but not gelatin, starch or casein.</s><s>Negative for production of hydrogen sulfide, poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and indole; positive for nitrate reduction.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Uses the following as carbon sources: Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d- and l-lactic acid and succinic acid.</s><s>Does not utilize the following as carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- or l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- or l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Does not form acids from mannose, ribose, glycerol, mannitol, inulin, sorbitol, galactose, cellobiose, rhamnose, salicin, glucose, arabinose, xylose, melibiose, adonitol, fructose, lactose, inositol, raffinose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, maltose, sorbose, trehalose, dulcitol, i-erythritol or amygdalin.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-9.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 60.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 78-123<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.1365<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14085<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of a bird's nest situated on the bank of Qiongtailan River in the region of Tuomuer Peak of Tianshan Mountain in the Xin-jiang Uygur Autonomous Region in north-western China.</s></p></content></protolog>