<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9105_nm.14297" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14297" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14297" rank="species">Sphingomonas japonica</organism><reference id="rid.9105"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas japonica sp. nov., isolated from the marine crustacean Paralithodes camtschatica.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1179</fpage><lpage>1182</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003285-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406815</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas japonica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas japonica</em> (ja.po′ni.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>japonica</em> Japanese, pertaining to the Sea of Japan, the place from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile rods (0.6–0.8 μm wide and 1.5–1.8 μm long).</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are 1–2 mm in diameter, yellow–orange pigmented, smooth, shiny and transparent, with regular edges.</s><s>No production of diffusible pigments is observed.</s><s>Growth temperature optimum is 25–28 °C; no growth occurs at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are positive and <em>β</em>-galactosidase is weakly positive in API 20NE tests.</s><s>Positive for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Indole, urease and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed slowly over 4–5 days in both routine and API 20NE tests.</s><s>Hydrolysis of Tween 80 is positive.</s><s>Casein, starch and chitin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, sucrose, trehalose, melibiose, lactose, d-xylose, mannitol or glycerol.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>API 20NE test results are negative for glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease and mannitol assimilation.</s><s>API ID 32GN test results are negative for assimilation of itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, propionic acid, capric acid, trisodium citrate, l-alanine, l-proline, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, d-mannitol, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, inositol, l-arabinose, l-serine, valeric acid, l-histidine and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>API ZYM test results are positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, weakly positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and <em>α</em>-glucosidase and negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Polar lipids include phosphatidylcholine, sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown lipid.</s><s>Contains C<sub>18 : 1</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> as major fatty acids and 2-OH C<sub>14 : 0</sub> as the major 2-hydroxy fatty acid; minor fatty acid components are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub> and C<sub>19 : 1</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KC7<sup>T</sup> (=KMM 3038<sup>T</sup> =NRIC 0738<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15438<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a specimen of the crab <em>Paralithodes camtschatica</em> collected from Peter the Great Bay, Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>