<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6809_nm.5618" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5618" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5618" rank="subspecies">Streptococcus constellatus constellatus</organism><reference id="rid.6809"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>L.M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A study of small-colony, beta-haemolytic, Lancefield group C streptococci within the anginosus group: description of Streptococcus constellatus subsp. pharyngis subsp. nov., associated with the human throat and pharyngitis.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1443</fpage><lpage>1449</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1443</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555325</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>constellatus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>constellatus</i> is based on the previously reported characteristics of 50 clinical and reference strains of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> (emend.) (Whiley &#x0026; Beighton, 1991). This subspecies is the type subspecies of <i>S. constellatus</i> and contains the type strain according to Rules 40a and 40b of the Bacteriological Code (Lapage et al., 1992). Small (0.5-1.0 μm in diameter), Gram-positive, nonsporing, non-motile cocci in short chains. Catalase-negative. Colonies on blood agar are 0.5-2.0 mm in diameter, white or translucent, and convex with entire margins ; some strains produce colonies that are 0.5-1.0 mm in diameter, white and matte. Growth is reduced under aerobic conditions and is frequently enhanced by the addition of CO<sub>2</sub>. Some strains require anaerobic conditions for growth. Acetoin is produced. Arginine and aesculin are hydrolysed, but urea is not. Hippurate is not split. Alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase are produced. Most strains produce α-glucosidase but very few produce β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase. β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, β-D-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, glucuronidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase and sialidase are not produced. Acid is produced from glucose and frequently from salicin and trehalose. Lactose fermentation and amygdalin fermentation are variable characteristics of this species. A few strains produce acid from cellobiose, melibiose and raffinose. Arabinose, glycerol, inulin and sorbitol are not fermented. Few strains produce hydrogen peroxide. Most strains produce hyaluronidase. Strains are frequently β-haemolytic and belong to Lancefield group F or are nonhaemolytic (α and γ) and serologically ungroupable. A few strains react with Lancefield group A, C and G antisera. The habitats are oral cavities and upper respiratory tracts. Strains are isolated from human purulent infections including appendicitis. The DNA G + C content is 37-38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Streptococcus constellatus</i> subsp. <i>constellatus</i> is NCDO 2226<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 11325<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 27823<sup>T</sup>), which was the type strain of <i>S. constellatus</i> (Whiley &#x0026; Beighton, 1991).</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies described above, is serologically upgroupable against Lancefield grouping antisera, is non-haemolytic, produces hyaluronidase and α-glucosidase, and does not produce β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, β-D-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase or sialidase.</s><s>Lactose is fermented but amygdalin is not.</s></p></content></protolog>