<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6844_nm.2311" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2311" rank="family">Piscirickettsiaceae</organism><reference id="rid.6844"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dumler</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbet</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bekker</surname><given-names>C.P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dasch</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palmer</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ray</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rikihisa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rurangirwa</surname><given-names>F.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of genera in the families Rickettsiaceae and Anaplasmataceae in the order Rickettsiales: unification of some species of Ehrlichia with Anaplasma, Cowdria with Ehrlichia and Ehrlichia with Neorickettsia, descriptions of six new species combinations and designation of Ehrlichia equi and 'HGE agent' as subjective synonyms of Ehrlichia phagocytophila.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2145</fpage><lpage>2165</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Rickettsiaceae</i> (Pinkerton 1936) Weiss and Moulder 1984</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>It is proposed that the genera <i>Ehrlichia</i>, <i>Cowdria</i>, <i>Neorickettsia</i> and <i>Wolbachia</i> be transferred from the family <i>Rickettsiaceae</i> to the family <i>Anaplasmataceae</i>, a change that results in the elimination of all tribes within the family <i>Rickettsiaceae</i>. It is also proposed that the genera <i>Haemobartonella</i> and <i>Eperythrozoon</i> should be transferred from the family <i>Anaplasmataceae</i> to the order <i>Mycoplasmatales</i> and that <i>Coxiella</i>, <i>Rickettsiella</i>, Francisella (<i>Wolbachia</i>) persica and Wolbachia melophagi (Weisburg et al., 1989;Roux et al., 1997) should be removed from the family <i>Rickettsiaceae</i>. This proposal also requires emendation of the description of the family <i>Rickettsiaceae</i> to specify that organisms infect host cells within the cytoplasm or nucleus and are not bounded by a vacuole. The family <i>Rickettsiaceae</i> includes only the genera <i>Rickettsia</i> and <i>Orientia</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>