<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9704_nm.14853" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14853" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14853" rank="species">Marinomonas arenicola</organism><reference id="rid.9704"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinomonas arenicola sp. nov., isolated from marine sediment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2834</fpage><lpage>2838</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011304-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628606</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinomonas arenicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinomonas arenicola</em> (a.re.ni′co.la. L. n. <em>arena</em> sand; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>arenicola</em> a sand-dweller).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, motile rods (approx. 2 μm long).</s><s>Colonies are non-pigmented, semi-transparent, shiny and smooth with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–37 °C (optimum 25–28 °C) but not at temperatures above 38 °C.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Growth is observed with 0.5–10 % (w/v) NaCl but not with 12 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–9.5 (optimum pH 6.5–8.0).</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, Tween 80, starch, chitin and DNA and production of H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>On medium containing l-tyrosine, does not produce melanin-like pigments or clearance zones.</s><s>Acid is formed from d-xylose, but not from d-glucose, d-mannitol, sucrose, lactose, maltose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity (<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis) and negative for reduction of nitrate, production of indole, urease and arginine dihydrolase, acidification of glucose, hydrolysis of gelatin and aesculin and assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannitol, maltose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>According to API 50CH tests, utilizes potassium 5-ketogluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate weakly, but does not utilize glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, l- or d-arabitol or gluconate.</s><s>According to the API ID 32GN tests, does not assimilate itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, propionic acid, capric acid, trisodium citrate, l-alanine, l-proline, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 3- or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, glycogen, d-mannitol, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, inositol, l-arabinose, l-serine, valeric acid or l-histidine.</s><s>Contains C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> as the predominant fatty acids.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, vancomycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, ofloxacin, polymyxin, rifampicin, streptomycin, erythromycin, tetracycline, cephazolin and cephalexin.</s><s>Resistant to nalidixic acid, lincomycin, oxacillin and oleandomycin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3893<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0752<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15737<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sandy sample from the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>