<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1196_nm.889" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.889" rank="genus">Acidiphilium</organism><reference id="rid.1196"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidiphilium cryptum gen. nov., sp. nov., heterotrophic bacterium from acidic mineral environments.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>327</fpage><lpage>332</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-327</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidiphilium </i>, gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(A.ci.di.phi'li.um. M.L. noun <i>acidum</i> an acid; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. neut. n. <i>Acidiphilium</i> acid lover)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, mesophilic, aerobic, rod-shaped bacteria.</s><s>Motile and nonmotile strains occur; motile cells have one polar flagellum or two lateral flagella.</s><s>Growth occurs in lean organic media between pH 1.9 and 5.9 but not at pH 6.1.</s><s>In basal salts medium containing glucose, 0.01% Trypticase soy stimulates growth, whereas 0.05% Trypticase soy inhibits growth.</s><s>Sodium acetate at a concentration of 0.01% is strongly inhibitory.</s><s>In defined media (basal salts medium containing a variety of organic compounds), growth is sparse.</s><s>Although enrichment with 0.01% Trypticase soy enhances growth, yields of more than 2 x 10<sup>8</sup> cells per ml seldom encountered.</s><s>On agar media at 35°C, colonies 0.2 to 0.5 mm in diameter form after 1 week.</s><s>Growth is slow at temperatures below 20°C, fastest between 35 and 41°C, and absent at 47°C.</s><s>Endospores are not formed and cells die rapidly at 67°C.</s><s>These bacteria are catalase positive, but the oxidase reaction is very weak or absent.</s><s>Cells in basal salts liquid medium containing glucose measure 0.3 to 0.4 by 0.6 to 0.8 μm, but cell size and shape are influenced by the kind and concentration of organic substrate and by physical conditions, such as pH.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA varies between 68 and 70 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>A. cryptum</i> sp. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>