<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7468_nm.6466" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6466" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6466" rank="species">Nocardia uniformis</organism><reference id="rid.7468"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Isik</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia uniformis nom. rev.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1227</fpage><lpage>1230</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1227</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425784</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia uniformis</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia uniformis</i> (u.ni.for'mis. L. masc. adj. <i>uniformis</i> having only one form, uniform)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data derived from earlier studies (Marton &#x0026; Szabo, 1959; Goodfellow, 1971).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, acid-alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycete which forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium which fragments in situ into rod-shaped to coccoid elements (0.7-1.1 x 1.1 x 4.0 μm).</s><s>A yellowish-orange substrate mycelium carries whitish, sparse to abundant, aerial hyphae.</s><s>Colony elevation is convex to irregular and colony margins are filamentous.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>DNA, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, RNA, starch, testosterone, Tweens 20 and 80, L-tyrosine, uric acid and xanthine are degraded, but not adenine, casein, cellulose, chitin, gelatin, keratin or xylan.</s><s>Aesculin, allantoin, arbutin and urea are hydrolysed, nitrate is reduced but activity is not shown against hippurate.</s><s>The organism is oxidase-negative, does not produce <i>m</i>-or <i>p</i>-nitrophenoloxidases and is resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>2-Naphthyl caprylate, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 8.5), 2-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, 2-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, naphthol AS-BI phosphate, 2-naphthyl α-D-glucopyranoside and 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside are cleaved but 2-naphthyl myristate, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 5.4), L-valyl-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl α-L-fucopyranoside, 2-naphthyl β-D-galactopyranoside, 1-naphthyl N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide and naphthol AS-BI β-Dglucuronide are not.</s><s>Acid is formed from arbutin, D(-)fructose, D(+)glucose, glycerol and <i>meso</i>-inositol but not from adonitol, amygdalin, D(+) or L(-)arabinose, D(+)cellobiose, dulcitol, ethanol, D(+)galactose, glycogen, inulin, L(+)lactose, D(+)melezitose, D(+)raffinose, α-L-rhamnose, salicin, D(+)sorbitol, D(+)sucrose or D(+)xylose.</s><s>D(+)Glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D(+)mannitol, D(+)-mannose, paraffin, sebacic acid, sodium acetate, sodium <i>n</i>-butyrate, sodium fumarate, sodium hydrogen malate, sodium propionate, sodium pyruvate, sodium succinate and testosterone are used as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth but not adonitol, amygdalin, D(+) or L(-)arabinose, D(+)arabitol, arbutin, D(+)cellobiose, dulcitol, D(-)fucose, D(+)galactose, glycogen, inulin, L(+)lactose, D(+)maltose, D(+)mannitol, α-Dmelibiose, D(+)melezitose, D(+)raffinose, α-L-rhamnose, D(-)ribose, salicin, D(+)sorbitol, D(+)sucrose, D(+)trehalose, D(+)turanose, D(+)xylose, xylitol, D-α-alanine, betaine-HCl, benzamide, <i>m</i>- or β-hydroxybenzoic acid, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzaldehyde, DL-norleucine, D-mandelic acid, pimelic acid, L-proline, protocatechuic acid, sodium acetate, sodium adipate, sodium benzoate, sodium azelate, sodium citrate, sodium gluconate, sodium hippurate, sodium lactate, sodium malonate, sodium <i>n</i>-octoate, sodium oleate, sodium oxalate, sodium tartrate, sodium valerate, L-threonine, L-tryptophan or L-tyrosine.</s><s>The organism grows from 14 to 40°C , from pH 6.0 to 10 and in the presence of crystal violet (0.00001% w/v), phenyl ethanol (0.1%, v/v), potassium tellurite (0.01%, w/v) and sodium azide (0.0001% w/v) but not at 10°C, pH 5.0 or in the presence of crystal violet (0.001 %, w/v), sodium azide (0.0002%, w/v), sodium chloride (10%, w/v), tetrazolium (0.1%, w/v) or thallous acetate (0.01%, w/v).</s><s>The organism was isolated from a degraded solonchaksolonetz soil collected from the Hortobagy steppe in eastern Hungary.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and hence serves as the type strain description.</s><s>The type strain is JCM 3224<sup>T</sup> (=CBS 224.60<sup>T</sup>=DSM 43136<sup>T</sup>=IFO 13702<sup>T</sup>=NCIB 963<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Marton &#x0026; Szabo (1959) considered the most characteristic features of <i>Nocardia uniformis</i> to be its uniform appearance on a variety of media and its limited carbon utilization pattern.</s></p></content></protolog>