<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11902_nm.19988" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19988" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19988" rank="species">Hafnia paralvei</organism><reference id="rid.11902"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abbott</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janda</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hafnia paralvei sp. nov., formerly known as Hafnia alvei hybridization group 2</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1725</fpage><lpage>1728</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018606-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19734282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hafnia paralvei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hafnia paralvei</em> [par.al′ve.i. Gr. prep. <em>para</em> (also shortened to <em>par</em>) besides; L. gen. n. <em>alvei</em> of a beehive and also a bacterial epithet; N.L. gen. n. <em>paralvei</em> organism similar to <em>H. alvei</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on data reported previously by Farmer (2003), Janda <em>et al.</em> (2005), Okada &#x0026; Gordon (2003) and data from this study.</s><s>Except where mentioned otherwise, the phenotypic profile of the type strain corresponds to the species description.</s><s>Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, non-spore-forming, peritrichously flagellated rods.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 24 h at 28–37 °C on nutrient agar and various other non-selective nutrient-rich media.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, non-pigmented, produces nitrate reductase and positive for the enterobacterial common antigen.</s><s>Positive for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Negative for production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, lipase, DNase and degradation of gelatin, mucin and polypectate.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose, l-arabinose, trehalose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-xylose and glycerol, but not from adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabitol, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, melibiose, d-sorbitol, sucrose or methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside.</s><s>Most strains (including the type strain) are positive for the Voges–Proskauer reaction, motility, acid production from d-arabinose and hydrolysis of <em>p-</em>nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-galactoside.</s><s>Strains are negative for either malonate utilization (including the type strain) or <em>β</em>-glucosidase or both.</s><s>Together with <em>H. alvei</em>, the novel species can be distinguished from other enterobacteria based on lysis by the <em>Hafnia</em>-specific phage 1672 after overnight incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Results for tests proposed to discriminate between <em>H. alvei</em> and <em>H. paralvei</em> are listed in Table 1.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from human clinical specimens, mammals, reptiles and freshwater fish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 29927<sup>T</sup> (=CDC 4510-73<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24706<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a human clinical specimen.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 49.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>