<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3616_nm.10235" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10235" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10235" rank="species">Neisseria zoodegmatis</organism><reference id="rid.3616"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bercovier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Centers for Disease Control Group Eugonic Fermenter (EF)-4a and EF-4b as Neisseria animaloris sp. nov. and Neisseria zoodegmatis sp. nov., respectively.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1801</fpage><lpage>1805</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64142-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902011</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Neisseria zoodegmatis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Neisseria zoodegmatis</em> (zoo.deg′ma.tis. Gr. n. <em>zoon</em> an animal; Gr. n. <em>degma</em> a bite; N.L. gen. n. <em>zoodegmatis</em> of an animal's bite).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, convex, entire, opaque, shiny, smooth and haemolytic.</s><s>All 15 strains studied by Holmes <em>et al.</em> (1990) are positive for catalase production, cytochrome oxidase production, growth at 37 °C, growth at room temperature (18–22 °C) and growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Most strains are positive for (exceptions in parentheses) acid production (in peptone water medium) from glucose (C5663, CL 149/79), fermentation in the Hugh and Leifson O-F test (negative: LMG 23014, A8412, B2939, D3138), gelatinase production (plate method; LMG 23012<sup>T</sup>, B2939, C5663, D7300, E764, E928, CL 149/79), nitrate reduction (B2939) and utilization of citrate (Christensen's medium; C3248, C5663, D3138, D7300, E928, CL 392/80).</s><s>All strains are negative for acid production (in peptone water medium) from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>All strains are negative for acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer test; incubation at 37 °C for 2 days and incubation at room temperature for 5 days), arginine dihydrolase production, casein digestion, gluconate oxidation, <em>β</em>-galactosidase production (ONPG test), gas production from glucose in peptone water medium, gelatinase production (stab method), H<sub>2</sub>S production (by lead acetate paper and triple-sugar iron agar methods), indole production, KCN tolerance, lysine decarboxylase production, malonate utilization, methyl red test (both incubation at 37 °C for 2 days and incubation at room temperature for 5 days), motility (hanging drop preparation at 37 °C and room temperature), ornithine decarboxylase production, phenylalanine deamination, pigment production, production of extracellular DNase, reduction of 0.4 % (w/v) selenite, urease production and utilization of citrate (Simmons' medium).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of <em>N. zoodegmatis</em> strains is around 50 mol% (Rossau <em>et al.</em>, 1989); the DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.5 mol% (Rossau <em>et al.</em>, 1989).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 23012<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 12230<sup>T</sup>=CL 194/78<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 29859<sup>T</sup>=CDC D5986<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a dog-bite wound in Hawaii, USA.</s><s>Strains LMG 23013 (=NCTC 12229) and LMG 23014 (=NCTC 12231) are reference strains.</s></p></content></protolog>