<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.178_nm.9131" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9131" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7096" rank="species">Chainia kunmingensis</organism><reference id="rid.178"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chainia kunmingensis, a new actinomycete species found in soil.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>164</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-2-164</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chainia kunmingensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chainia kunmingensis</i> sp. nov. (kun. ming. en’sis. M.L. adj. <i>kunmingensis</i> pertaining to Kunming, a province of South China)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small sclerotia (5 to 25 μm) formed in and on the surface of agar media.</s><s>Coiled chains of conidia also occasionally formed in the aerial hyphae.</s><s>Colonies usually yellowish tan to dark orangish yellow, depending on the medium, with or without yellowish white aerial mycelium.</s><s>Soluble pigments little to none.</s><s>Type I cell wall and type PII phospholipid pattern.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 71.3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Cultures hydrolyze adenine, casein, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine, starch, and esculin but not gelatin and urea.</s><s>Phosphatase and nitrate reductase are produced.</s><s>Acetate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, succinate, citrate, mucate, oxalate, and propionate are utilized but benzoate and tartrate are not.</s><s>Acid is formed from arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, and β-methyl- D-xyloside.</s><s>Acid is not formed from adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, or sorbitol.</s><s>Lysozyme-sensitive.</s><s>Grows well at 10 and 37°C; no growth observed at 42°C.</s><s>Arabinose, fructose, glucose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, and xylose are utilized; sucrose and inositol are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 80-3024 (= ATCC 35682).</s></p></content></protolog>