<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3755_nm.10973" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10973" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10973" rank="species">Pseudomonas knackmussii</organism><reference id="rid.3755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stolz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas knackmussii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>572</fpage><lpage>576</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64761-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329787</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas knackmussii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas knackmussii</em> (knack.muss′i.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>knackmussii</em> of Knackmuss, in honour of Hans-Joachim Knackmuss, who initiated the biochemical studies about the degradation of chlorinated aromatics and other xenobiotic compounds by strain B13<sup>T</sup> and various other micro-organisms).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, polarly flagellated, motile short rods.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>On solid 3-chlorobenzoate-mineral agar the strain forms round, smooth, colourless, opaque colonies of 1–2 mm diameter when grown at 28 °C for 3 days.</s><s>Growth is observed at 20–41 °C but not at 4 °C.</s><s>Good growth is found at pH 6.0 and 8.3; there is no growth at pH 5 or pH 9.</s><s>No fluorescent or phenazine pigments are formed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced under aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>No liquefaction of gelatin, degradation of starch or cellulose, or formation of ethanol from acetate is detected.</s><s>The strain is positive for: acid formation from d-glucose; utilization of d-gluconate, d-glucose, d-fructose, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, pyruvate, 2-oxoglutarate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, 4-hydroxybenzoate, phenylacetate and putrescine; hydrolysis of bis-<em>p</em>NP phosphate, <em>p</em>NP phosphorylcholine, l-alanine <em>p</em>NA, l-glutamate-3-carboxy <em>p</em>na and l-proline <em>p</em>NA (<em>p</em>NP, <em>para</em>-nitrophenyl; <em>p</em>NA, <em>para</em>-nitroanilide).</s><s>Acids are not produced from sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, d-galactose, <em>trans</em>-aconitate or mesaconate.</s><s>The following glycosides are not hydrolysed: <em>p</em>NP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>NP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, <em>p</em>NP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>NP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and <em>p</em>np <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, propionate and l-tryptophan are not utilized.</s><s>The quinone system consists predominantly of ubiquinone Q-9.</s><s>Putrescine and spermidine are the major polyamines.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol, moderate amounts of four unknown phospholipids, an unknown aminolipid and two unknown polar lipids, and minor to trace amounts of one phospholipid and five unknown polar lipids.</s><s>Two highly hydrophobic lipids are also detectable.</s><s>Fatty acid composition is as follows: C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (36.6 %), summed feature 3 (24.8 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (19.4 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4.0 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (3.7 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH (3.5 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.5 %) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (2.7 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B13<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 6978<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23759<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sewage treatment plant in Göttingen (Germany) after continuous enrichment with 3-chlorobenzoate.</s></p></content></protolog>