<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1986_nm.11126" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11126" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11126" rank="species">Vibrio comitans</organism><reference id="rid.1986"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niwa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aono</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio comitans sp. nov., Vibrio rarus sp. nov. and Vibrio inusitatus sp. nov., from the gut of the abalones Haliotis discus discus, H. gigantea, H. madaka and H. rufescens</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>916</fpage><lpage>922</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64789-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473233</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio comitans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio comitans</em> (co′mi.tans. L. part. adj. <em>comitans</em> accompanying).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile and non-flagellated.</s><s>Cells in ZoBell 2216E broth are rod-shaped, with rounded ends (0.5–1.0×1.2–2.0 μm).</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solidified medium or in liquid medium.</s><s>Colonies on ZoBell 2216E agar are beige, circular, smooth and convex with an entire edge.</s><s>Sodium ions are essential for growth.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph that grows at 4–30 °C.</s><s>No growth above 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on thiosulfate/citrate/bile salts/sucrose (TCBS) agar (green colonies).</s><s>Positive for acid production from d-glucose, d-mannitol and maltose, nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of alginate, oxidase, catalase and assimilation of d-gluconate, d-galactose, cellobiose, d-glucuronate, pyruvate, l-glutamate, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, fumarate and succinate.</s><s>The following tests are negative: gas production from glucose, acetoin production, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, indole production, luminescence, pigmentation, requirement for organic growth factors, <em>β</em>-galactosidase test, hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, chitin, Tween 80 and agar, acid production from l-arabinose, inositol, l-rhamnose, sucrose and d-sorbitol and assimilation of d-mannose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, 2-oxoglutarate, melibiose, lactose, trehalose, putrescine, acetate, l-tyrosine, propionate, l-proline, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, dl-malate and aconitate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45.0–48.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GHG2-1<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23416<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102076<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain and five reference strains [GHD1-9 (=LMG 23413=NBRC 102078), GHG2-4 (=LMG 23417=NBRC 102077), NHG1-3 (=LMG 23421=NBRC 102080), NHG1-11 (=LMG 23422=NBRC 102079) and NHM1-4 (=LMG 23425=NBRC 102081)] were isolated from the guts of wild-caught abalone (<em>H. discus discus</em>, <em>H. gigantea</em> and <em>H. madaka</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>