<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7189_nm.6661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6661" rank="species">Hongia koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.7189"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hongia gen. nov., a new genus of the order Actinomycetales.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>191</fpage><lpage>199</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826804</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hongia koreensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hongia koreensis</i> (ko.re.en'sis. M.L. adj. <i>koreensis</i> pertaining to Korea, the location of the soil sample from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The aerial mycelium is white and fragments into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is creamy and fragments into short or elongated rod-shaped elements.</s><s>The substrate hyphal swellings and budding are formed on oatmeal agar.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H#S is produced.</s><s>Utilizes D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, inulin, D-lactose, D-lyxose, D-mannose, D-melezitose, melibiose, methyl a-D-glucoside, methyl a-dmannoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, D-mannitol, sodium acetate, trans-aconitate, sodium citrate, sodium fumarate, a-ketoglutarate, sodium lactate, sodium malate, sodium malonate, sodium oxalate, sodium propionate, sodium pyruvate and sodium succinate as carbon sources.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, starch, arbutin and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Pectin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Xanthine, hypoxanthine, DL-tyrosine and sodium hippurate are decomposed but adenine is not decomposed.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-raffinose.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, inulin, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-melezitose, melibiose, methyl a-D-glucoside, methyl a-D-mannoside, L-rhamnose, L-ribose, salicin, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, 2, 3-butanediol, meso-erythritol, glycerol, meso-inositol, D-mannitol or 1, 2-propanediol.</s><s>Tolerant to lysozyme, 0.1% phenol, 0.01% potassium tellurite, 0.00005% crystal violet and 0.001% brilliant green, but not to 3% (w/v) sodium chloride, 0.01% sodium azide, 0.3% phenylethanol or 0.01% thallous acetate.</s><s>Susceptible to 40 g cephaloridine ml<sup>-1</sup> and 20 g neomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, but resistant to 4 g tetracycline ml<sup>-1</sup>, 4 g rifampin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 20 g streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 160 g oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 4 g vancomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid, alanine, glycine and glutamic acid (approx. 1:2:1:1).</s><s>The acyl type is acetyl.</s><s>Mannose, glucose, galactose and ribose are present as cell wall sugars.</s><s>The diagnostic polar lipid is phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 12-methyltetradecanoic acid and 14-methylpentadecanoic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71.3 mol%.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Hongia koreensis</i> is strain LM 161<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 50530<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The only known isolation site is a golD-mine cave in Kongju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>