<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9161_nm.14358" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14358" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14358" rank="species">Marispirillum indicum</organism><reference id="rid.9161"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marispirillum indicum gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a deep-sea environment.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1278</fpage><lpage>1281</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003889-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502301</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marispirillum indicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marispirillum indicum</em> (in.di′cum. L. neut. adj. <em>indicum</em> Indian, referring to the Indian Ocean, where the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 1.9–2.7 μm long and 0.6–0.7 μm wide and motile, by means of 1–3 flagella (one flagellum at each pole).</s><s>Positive for denitrification, lipase (Tween 80), amylase, urease, gelatinase, arginine dihydrolase and indole production.</s><s>On 216L agar plates, colonies are smooth, grey and yellowish with regular edges, 1–2 mm in diameter and slightly raised in the centre after 72 h incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing with NaCl at 0.5–12 % (optimally at 2–8 %).</s><s>Grows at 10–41 °C (optimally at 25–37 °C), but not at 4 or 45 °C, within 7 days.</s><s>Unable to ferment glucose.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (Oxoid) (μg per disc): carbenicillin (100), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), minocycline (30), neomycin (10), norfloxacin (10), ofloxacin (5), rifampicin (5), ceftriaxone (30), streptomycin (10) and doxycycline (30).</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): ampicillin (10), cefalexin (30), cefazolin (30), cefoperazone (30), cefradin (30), clindamycin (2), co-trimoxazole (25), furazolidone (15), lincomycin (2), metronidazole (5), oxacillin (1), penicillin G (10), piperacillin (100), polymyxin B (30 U), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>In the API ZYM test, positive for  alkaline phosphatase and leucine aminopeptidase, weakly positive for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphoamidase and negative for acid phosphatase, cystine aminopeptidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin, valine aminopeptidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>In the API 20NE test, positive for utilization of potassium gluconate and malic acid, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the Biolog GN2 system (96 substrates), positive for l-alaninamide, l-alanine, bromosuccinic acid, dl-lactic acid, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-psicose, glycogen, l-glutamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-threonine, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, Tween 40, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B142<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 208225<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24627<sup>T</sup>=MCCC 1A01235<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from deep-water samples from the Indian Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>