<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6665_nm.8776" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8776" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8776" rank="species">Photobacterium lipolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.6665"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium lipolyticum sp. nov., a bacterium with lipolytic activity isolated from the Yellow Sea in Korea</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>335</fpage><lpage>339</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63215-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653897</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Photobacterium lipolyticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Photobacterium lipolyticum</em> (li.po.ly′ti.cum. Gr. n. <em>lipos</em> fat; Gr. adj. <em>lytikos</em> dissolving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>lipolyticum</em> dissolving fat or lipid).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are pleomorphic.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, glistening, low-convex, cream-coloured and 1·5–2·0 mm in diameter after 2 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 25 and 28 °C; growth occurs at 4 and 34 °C but not at 35 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth pH is between 7·0 and 8·0; growth is observed at pH 5·0 but not at pH 4·5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 1–2 % NaCl; no growth occurs without NaCl or in the presence of more than 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA and MA with nitrate.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein is weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Malate and succinate are utilized for growth.</s><s>d-Xylose, benzoate, butyrate, citrate, glutamate, lactate, formate, ethanol and methanol are not utilized for growth.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, d-glucose, d-fructose, maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, d-galactose, lactose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose or l-rhamnose.</s><s>The predominant respiratory lipoquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 47 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M37<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 10562BP<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16190<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an intertidal sediment from the Yellow Sea of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>