<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1421_nm.10253" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10253" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10253" rank="species">Hoeflea alexandrii</organism><reference id="rid.1421"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palacios</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reguera</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marín</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hoeflea alexandrii sp. nov., isolated from the toxic dinoflagellate Alexandrium minutum AL1V</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1991</fpage><lpage>1995</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64238-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902042</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hoeflea alexandrii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hoeflea alexandrii</em> (a.lex.an′dri.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>alexandrii</em> of <em>Alexandrium</em>, the genus name of the dinoflagellate <em>Alexandrium minutum</em>, the source of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, about 2.5×0.8 μm in size and motile by single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 are circular, around 1–2 mm in diameter and pigmented light brown after 2 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.</s><s>The temperature and pH ranges for growth are 10–42 °C and pH 6–9, respectively.</s><s>Shows no specific ionic requirement, growing with salts in the range 0–11.8 % (optimally between 0 and 6.8 %).</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or nitrogen.</s><s>The following API 20NE tests give positive results: hydrolysis of aesculin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity (PNPG).</s><s>The following API 20NE tests give negative results: nitrate reduction, indole production, acids from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, hydrolysis of gelatin and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-maltose, gluconate, caproate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM): alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzyme activities (API ZYM): lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Ferments the following substrates (API 50 CH): glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, sucrose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Does not ferment erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, xylitol, d-tagatose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Growth on artificial seawater with phosphate and traces of minerals and vitamins, supplemented with glycerol or glucose as sole carbon source, is weak.</s><s>Organic acids do not support growth.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (25 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg) and trimethoprim (5 μg); sensitive to cephalothin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), streptomycin (15 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>Fatty acids detected in strain AM1V30<sup>T</sup> include (in order of abundance): 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (83.1 %), 16 : 0 (7.7 %), 11-methyl 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (3.6 %), summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 : 0 iso 2-OH; 2.3 %), 18 : 0 (1.4 %) and minor amounts of other fatty acids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AM1V30<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5682<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16655<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a culture of the toxin-producing marine dinoflagellate <em>Alexandrium minutum</em> AL1V (Instituto Español de Oceanografia, Vigo, Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>