<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5822_nm.10051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10051" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10051" rank="species">Pseudoxanthomonas kalamensis</organism><reference id="rid.5822"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoxanthomonas kalamensis sp. nov., a novel gammaproteobacterium isolated from Johnston Atoll, North Pacific Ocean</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1103</fpage><lpage>1107</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63556-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627662</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoxanthomonas kalamensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoxanthomonas kalamensis</em> (ka.lam.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>kalamensis</em> of Kalama Island, referring to the Hawaiian name for Johnston Atoll, where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Yellow colonies form on heterotrophic media after 4–5 days (e.g. TSA, MA).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, single, straight rods 1.0–1.25 μm in length and 0.5 μm in width.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Mesophilic, with an optimum temperature range of 30–37 °C.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG hydrolysis) and positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis).</s><s>The spectra of substrates utilized is presented in Table 1.</s><s>Additionally, strain JA40<sup>T</sup> oxidizes diverse carbon sources available in Biolog GN and GP, namely <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, mannan, Tween 80, amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, salicin, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, succinamic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and d-lactic acid methyl ester.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64 mol%.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are 15 : 0 iso, 17 : 1 iso <em>cis</em>7 and 11 : 0 iso 3-OH.</s><s>Nitrite is reduced, with the production of nitrous oxide as a main product; nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA40<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1031<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108476<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil contaminated with polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons and polychlorinated biphenyls collected from Johnston Atoll in the North Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>