<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2731_nm.7596" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7596" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7596" rank="species">Actinomadura hibisca</organism><reference id="rid.2731"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tomita</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nishio</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saitoh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohkuma</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Konishi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pradimicins A, B and C: new antifungal antibiotics. I. Taxonomy, production, isolation and physico-chemical properties.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>755</fpage><lpage>762</lpage><source id="175">The Journal of Antibiotics</source><abbrev>J Antibiot (Tokyo)</abbrev><issn>0021-8820</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2387769</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomadura hibisca</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomadura hibisca</i> (Origin: hi-bisika, L.n.; Gr <i>hibiskos</i> rose mallow, a plant with reddish flower reffering to the red diffusible pigments)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is No. P157-2 (ATCC 53447).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxonomy of the Producing Strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>The producing organisms, strain PI57-2 and strain Q278-4 were isolated from soil samples collected in the Fiji Islands and Andhra Pradesh State, India, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological Characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both strains form white aerial mycelium and non-fragmentary substrate mycelium.</s><s>Long straight spore-chains (10 to 50 spores per chain) are formed on all parts of the aerial mycelium.</s><s>The spores are oblong in shape, 0.4 to 0.6 by 0.7 to 1.5 μm in size, non-flagellate, and have smooth surface (Fig. 1).</s><s>A fused coil of spore chain is occasionally formed intercalary or at the tip of long chains, which is observed by photomicroscopy as a small globose body (1.5 to 4 μCultural and Physiological</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>White aerial mycelium-is formed on some media such as yeast extract - malt extract agar (ISP medium No. 2) (Fig. 3).</s><s>A reddish pigment, which is recognized as pradimicins, is produced abundantly in ISP media No. 2 and 6, but slightly in ISP media No. 3, 4 and 5, and a brown melanoid pigment only</s></p><p class="description"><s>in ISP medium No. 7.</s><s>The growth temperature range is 18 to 40°C for strain PI57-2 and 16 to 43°C for strain Q278-4.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance for growth is seen at 3% (w/v) but not at 6% (w/v).</s><s>The cultural characteristics of strains PI57-2 and Q278-4 are shown in Table 1 , and the physiological characteristics examined by the methods of Gordon et al.) are given in Table 2.m in diameter) (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemotaxonomical Studies</s></p><p class="description"><s>The whole-cell hydrolysate contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glucose and a small amount of</s></p><p class="description"><s>madurose, hence the cell wall is type III and the whole cell-sugar is Pattern B.</s><s>The phospholipids contain phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol but lack nitrogenous phospholipids, hence belong to type P-I.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>Glycolate test is negative.</s><s>Mycolate is absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxonomic Position</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on the major characteristics of strains PI57-2 and Q278-4, both strains were placed in the genus <i>Actinomadura</i>.</s><s>Many strains of <i>Actinomadura</i> produce reddish pigments such as those identified as prodigiosins or anthracyclines, while these two strains produce three new red pigments, pradimicins A, B and C having benzo[a]naphthaeenequinone as aglycone.</s></p></content></protolog>