<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12786_nm.22573" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22573" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22573" rank="species">Schleiferia thermophila</organism><reference id="rid.12786"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Schleiferia thermophila gen. nov., sp. nov., a slightly thermophilic bacterium of the phylum ‘Bacteroidetes’ and the proposal of Schleiferiaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2450</fpage><lpage>2455</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028852-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21097639</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Schleiferia thermophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Schleiferia thermophila</em> (ther.mo′phi.la. Gr. adj. <em>thermos</em> hot; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>thermophila</em> heat-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics reported for the genus, forms very short rod-shaped cells, 0.5 to 1.5 µm in length and 0.5 to 0.7 µm in width, without motility.</s><s>Colonies on Degryse medium 162 are orange-pigmented and irregular.</s><s>Growth occurs between 30 and 60 °C.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is about 50 °C; growth does not occur at 25 or 62.5 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between 7.5 and 8.5; growth does not occur at pH 6.0 or pH 10.0.</s><s>Grows in media with up to 3 % salt; however, optimum growth occurs in medium without added NaCl.</s><s>Yeast extract and vitamin B12 are required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrogen.</s><s>The polar lipid profile is composed of one aminophospholipid, two aminolipids and three unidentified lipids.</s><s>Gelatin, casein and hippurate are degraded; starch, aesculin, arbutin and xylan are not degraded.</s><s>DNase-positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive in the API ZYM system; other activities are negative.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, d-arabinose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, acetate, succinate, fumarate, aspartate, glutamate, proline, l-glutamine, l-arginine, l-ornithine and threonine are assimilated.</s><s>l-Rhamnose, l-fucose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, raffinose, melezitose, glycerol, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, erythritol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, α-ketoglutarate, pyruvate, malate, citrate, benzoate, formate, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-serine, valine, l-phenylalanine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine and methionine are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following carbohydrates using API 50 CH: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, starch, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The DNA of the type strain has a G+C content of 42.8±0.1 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TU-20<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 21410<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24594<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hot spring at Furnas on the Island of São Miguel in the Azores.</s></p></content></protolog>