<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1794_nm.2120" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2120" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2120" rank="species">Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus</organism><reference id="rid.1794"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bryantseva</surname><given-names>I.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new alkaliphilic purple sulfur bacterium with bacteriochlorophyll b.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2157</fpage><lpage>2163</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155992</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus</i> (lim.nae'us. Gr. fem. n. <i>limne</i> lake, pond, swamp; Gr. adj. <i>limnaios</i> pertaining to, living in lakes, swamps;N.L. masc. adj. <i>limnaeus</i> living in lakes and swamps)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical or oval in shape, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are cocci of 1.3-1.8 μm diameter, usually non-motile and surrounded by a thin capsule.</s><s>Occasionally cells with a single flagellum are observed.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes of tubular type form by invagination of the cell membrane and fill most of cytoplasm.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is yellowish to orange-brown.</s><s>The absorption spectrum of intact cells exhibits maxima at 410, 462, 492, 530 and 1030 nm with shoulders at 602 and 835 nm.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <i>b</i> and carotenoids of similar absorption properties as tetrahydrospirilloxanthin.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic growth occurs in light with hydrogen sulfide and elemental sulfur as electron donors.</s><s>Thiosulfate is not used for phototrophic growth.</s><s>During growth with sulfide as electron donor, globules of elemental sulfur are accumulated inside the cells.</s><s>The final oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and sodium bicarbonate, acetate, yeast extract, malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate and fumarate are used as organic substrates for phototrophic growth.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Mesophilic, obligate alkaliphilic bacterium with optimum growth at pH 8.8-9.5 (range pH 8-10) and 20-25 °C.</s><s>Development is dependent on sodium salts in low concentrations and good growth occurs over a broad range of salt concentrations without exhibiting a strong optimum, up to 6% NaCl (in the presence of 0.5%sodium carbonates) and up to 8.5% sodium carbonates (in the presence of 0.05% NaCl).</s><s>Habitat is the surface of sediments rich in organic matter and microbial mats of soda lakes containing hydrogen sul®de and exposed to light.</s><s>The DNA G­+C content of the type strain is 64.0-64.5 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s><s>The type strain, A26<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited at the American Type Culture Collection, Manassas, VA, USA, as ATCC BAA32<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>