<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.23_nm.3393" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3393" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3393" rank="species">Pasteurella trehalosi</organism><reference id="rid.23"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stevens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus rossii sp. nov., Actinobacillus seminis sp. nov., nom. rev., Pasteurella bettii sp. nov., Pasteurella lymphangitidis sp. nov., Pasteurella mairi sp. nov., and Pasteurella trehalosi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella trehalosi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella trehalosi</i> (tre. hal.os'i. M.L. gen. n. <i>trehalosi</i>, pertaining to trehalosum [trehalose])</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. haemolytica</i> group T, which was distinguished by Smith (40, 41) from <i>P. haemolytica</i> sensu stricto (which is group A, to which type strain NCTC 9380 of <i>P. haemolytica</i> belongs); phenon 9 of Sneath and Stevens (46); <i>P. haemolytica</i> T of Kilian and Frederiksen (21); <i>P. haemolytica</i> biovar T of Carter (11).</s><s>Cells are small nonmotile rods and coccobacilli.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic and facultatively anaerobic, mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on sheep blood agar are round, greyish, semitransparent, and about 2.5 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C; they usually have a pronounced zone of hemolysis (often double) and occasionally produce some greening of the erythrocytes.</s><s>Notable for giving a weak or negative reaction for catalase and a negative reaction for urease, in producing acid from sorbitol and trehalose but not from galactoce, and for often showing delayed fermentation in Hugh-Leifson (17) medium (46).</s><s>This organism is distinguished from <i>P. haemolytica</i> sensu stricto by fermenting trehalose but not L-(+)-arabhose and usually not galactose or D-(+)-xylose and by being relatively more resistant to penicillin (2, 11).</s><s>Other properties are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Associated with septicemia in older lambs, unlike <i>P. haemolytica</i> sensu stricto, which is associated with pneumonia in cattle and sheep and septicemia in newborn lambs (11, 40, 41).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism is phenotypically similar to <i>P. haemolytica</i>, <i>P. pneumotropica</i>, <i>Pasteurella gallinarum</i>, and <i>P. multocida</i> (46) and shows low DNA-DNA pairing values (15 to 35%) to <i>P. haemolytica</i>, <i>P. gallinarum</i>, <i>P. ureae</i>, and <i>P. multocida</i> (3, 28, 35).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. trehalosi</i> exhibits a level of pairing of about 62% to <i>Pasteurella testudinis</i> (26, 28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of one strain of biovar T, serovar 3/T15 (9), strain NCTC 10624, is 42.6 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method) (26, 28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 10370 (= S11O = ATCC 29703 = A92 = serovar 3/T15) (9, 46).</s><s>In our hands this strain was positive for the tests marked d in Table 1, except that inositol was acidified late.</s></p></content></protolog>