<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10099_nm.15055" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15055" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15055" rank="species">Mangrovibacter plantisponsor</organism><reference id="rid.10099"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rameshkumar</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nair</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mangrovibacter plantisponsor gen. nov., sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium isolated from a mangrove-associated wild rice (Porteresia coarctata Tateoka)</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>179</fpage><lpage>186</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008292-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648330</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mangrovibacter plantisponsor</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mangrovibacter plantisponsor</em> (plan.ti.spon′sor. L. fem. n. <em>planta</em> plant; L. masc. n. <em>sponsor</em> sponsor, guarantor; N.L. masc. n. <em>plantisponsor</em> sponsor of plants, referring to the potentially plant-beneficial properties of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on TSA (HiMedia) are circular, smooth, creamy white and 1–2 mm in diameter within 2 days at 28 °C; swarming is not detected.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C, optimally at 28–30 °C, but not at 5 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–8 % NaCl; no growth at 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and citrate utilization.</s><s>Negative reactions for urease, lysine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, hydrogen sulphide production, denitrification and hydrolysis of Tween 80, DNA, starch, casein and gelatin.</s><s>Produces acid from sucrose, raffinose, cellobiose, arabinose, sorbitol, glycerol, ribose, d-xylose, sucrose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, gentiobiose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabinose, gluconate and 6-ketogluconate.</s><s>Delayed acid production (48 h) in API CH50 test strips for salicin and amygdalin.</s><s>Negative for acid production from erythritol, d-arabinose, 5-ketogluconate, adonitol, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, lactose, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose and l-arabitol.</s><s>Utilizes gluconate, 5-ketogluconate and malate as carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize phenylacetate, caprate or adipate (API 20NE).</s><s>Other characteristics are as described for the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSSRF40<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24236<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19579<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mangrove-associated wild rice (<em>Porteresia coarctata</em> Tateoka) in Pichavaram, Tamil Nadu, India.</s></p></content></protolog>