<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2776_nm.8813" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8813" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8813" rank="species">Rhodopirellula baltica</organism><reference id="rid.2776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schlesner</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rensmann</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gade</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rabus</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfeiffer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic heterogeneity within the Planctomycetales as derived by DNA-DNA hybridization, description of Rhodopirellula baltica gen. nov., sp. nov., transfer of Pirellula marina to the genus Blastopirellula gen. nov. as Blastopirellula marina comb. nov. and emended description of the genus Pirellula.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1567</fpage><lpage>1580</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63113-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388712</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodopirellula baltica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodopirellula baltica</em> (bal′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>baltica</em> pertaining to the Baltic Sea, the place of isolation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 1·0–2·5×1·2–2·3 μm in size.</s><s>A single flagellum is subpolarly inserted at the proximal pole.</s><s>Colonies are round, smooth and pink to red in colour.</s><s>Growth is optimal between 28 and 30 °C.</s><s>Growth is not observed above 32 °C.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> and sea water are required for growth.</s><s>The bacterium is strictly aerobic.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Nitrate cannot serve as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized are as follows: cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, lyxose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, aesculin, amygdalin, gluconate, glucuronate, salicin and chondroitin sulfate.</s><s>Carbon sources not utilized are as follows: fucose, sorbose, methylamine, methylsulfonate, methanol, ethanol, erythritol, adonitol, arabitol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, adipate, benzoate, caproate, citrate, formate, fumarate, glutarate, lactate, malate, 2-oxoglutarate, phthalate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, tartrate, alanine, arginine, asparagine, aspartate, cysteine, cystine, glutamine, glutamate, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, norleucine, ornithine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine, valine, urea, indole, inulin and pectin.</s><s>Peptone, Casamino acids, yeast extract, gelatin, ammonium, nitrate and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine are each utilized as a nitrogen source, but neither nicotinate nor urea is utilized.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but alginate, casein, cellulose, chitin and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>No haemolytic activity is found with horse, calf or sheep blood.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase activities are observed, but urease activity is not observed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S, but not acetoin or indole, is produced.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to tetracycline, but resistant to streptomycin, ampicillin and penicillin.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 53–57 mol% (55 mol% for the type strain).</s><s>The chemical composition is identical to that in the genus description.</s><s>The main habitat is brackish water of Kiel Fjord (Baltic Sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SH 1<sup>T</sup> (=IFAM 1310<sup>T</sup>=DSM 10527<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13988<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>