<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5718_nm.5852" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5852" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5852" rank="species">Arthrobacter flavus</organism><reference id="rid.5718"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aggarwal</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter flavus sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from a pond in McMurdo Dry Valley, Antarctica</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1553</fpage><lpage>1561</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939663</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter flavus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter flavus</i> (fla'vus. L. adj. flavus yellow, the colour of a pigment that the bacterium produces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, non-motile, non-fermentative and exhibit a rod-coccus growth cycle.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract medium are yellow, round, smooth, convex and 0.5-2 mm in diameter.</s><s>The pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits fine structure in its absorption spectrum with absorption maxima at 410, 440 and 470 nm.</s><s>Pigment production is not dependent on growth conditions or media composition.</s><s>No growth factors are required.</s><s>Grows between 5 and 30 °C, at pH 6-9 and tolerates up to 11.5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 25°C and pH 7.</s><s>Positive for catalase, lipase, gelatinase and β-galactosidase but negative for oxidase, urease, phosphatase, indole production, nitrate reduction and levan formation.</s><s>Unable to utilize a number of carbon compounds, such as sucrose, rhamnose, cellulose, arabinose, mellibiose, cellobiose, galactose, sucrose, fructose, mannose, trehalose, xylose, mannitol, raffinose, glycerol, ribose, lactose, lactic acid, adonitol, maltose, glucose, glucosamine, sorbitol, melezitol, bhydroxy butyric acid, dulcitol, dextrose, polyethylene glycol, glycine, lysine, Na-citrate, Na-acetate, Nasuccinate, cellulose, inulin, <i>meso</i>-inositol, glutamic acid, l-alanine, phenylalanine, methionine, glutamine, arginine, serine, potassium hydrogen phosphate, myristic acid, ammonium formate, creatine, methanol, tyrosine, sodium pyruvate, glycogen, erythritol, tryptophan, ethanol and sodium thioglycolate.</s><s>Able to utilize sorbitol as the only source of carbon.</s><s>Unable to oxidize or ferment glucose, galactose, sucrose, thioglycolate or mannose but able to acidify sucrose and hydrolyse aesculin but not starch or cellulose.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is Lys-Thr-Ala3 (the A3α variant) and the major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The cell wall sugars are galactose, glucose and ribose.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>15:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, C<sub>17:0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>18:0</sub>, C<sub>18:0</sub> and C<sub>20:0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64±2 mol%.</s><s>Closely related phylogenetically to group I <i>Arthrobacter</i> species and exhibits maximum similarity to <i>A. agilis</i> (97.31%), as determined by 16S rDNA analysis.</s><s>Sensitive to all antibiotics tested: carbenicillin (50 μg), tobramycin (15 μg), chlortetracycline (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), nitrofurantoin (300 μg), penicillin (10 μg), bacitracin (10 μg), nitrofurazone (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), furazolidone (50 μg), colistin (10 μg), furoxone (100 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nystatin (100 μg), co-trimoxazole (25 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), amoxycillin (100 μg), trimethoprim (5 μg) and erythromycin (15 μg).</s><s>Isolated from a cyanobacterial mat sample from McMurdo Dry Valley, Antarctica.</s><s>The type strain is CMS 19Y<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 3476<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>