<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10569_nm.17812" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17812" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17812" rank="species">Salinicoccus carnicancri</organism><reference id="rid.10569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>K.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus carnicancri sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a Korean fermented seafood</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>653</fpage><lpage>658</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012047-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656926</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus carnicancri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus carnicancri</em> (car.ni.can′cri. L. n. <em>caro</em> <em>carnis</em> flesh; L. n. <em>cancer</em> -<em>cri</em> a crab; N.L. gen. n. <em>carnicancri</em> of the flesh of a crab).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, non-sporulating, Gram-stain-positive cocci with a diameter of 1.0–2.5 μm, and exist singly or as pairs, tetrads or clumps.</s><s>Colonies are ivory-coloured, circular and measure 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 3 days culture on MA supplemented with 10 % NaCl at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–20 % (w/v) NaCl, at temperatures ranging from 4–45 °C, and in the pH range 6.0–11.0.</s><s>Optimal growth at 30–37 °C, pH 7.0–8.0 and with a NaCl concentration of 12 %.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Casein and tyrosine hydrolysis occurs, but DNA, starch, Tween 80 and cellulose hydrolysis does not.</s><s>Possesses alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities (API ZYM).</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not observed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following substrates of Biolog GP2 plates can be utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, arbutin, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, l-serine and glycerol.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major cellular polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The major amino acid constituents of the cell-wall hydrolysate are glycine and lysine, and the major menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Crm<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13301<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15796<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s></p></content></protolog>