<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6145_nm.9575" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9575" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9575" rank="species">Virgibacillus dokdonensis</organism><reference id="rid.6145"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus dokdonensis sp. nov., isolated from a Korean island, Dokdo, located at the edge of the East Sea in Korea</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1833</fpage><lpage>1837</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63613-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166674</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus dokdonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus dokdonensis</em> (dok.do.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>dokdonensis</em> of Dokdo, a Korean island located at the edge of the East Sea in Korea from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·6–0·8×2·5–5·0 μm, Gram-variable and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Terminal or subterminal ellipsoidal or spherical endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are irregular, flat, translucent, milky white in colour and 3–5 mm in diameter after 2 days of incubation at 37 °C on MA supplemented with 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C; growth occurs at 15 and 50 °C, but not at 10 or 55 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7·0–8·0; growth occurs at pH 5·5, but not at pH 5·0.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 4–5 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs without NaCl and in the presence of 23 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of &#x003E;24 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA and MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, xanthines and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are absent.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are present, but lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-cellobiose, lactose, maltose, d-ribose, sucrose, <em>myo</em>-inositol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose or d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: d-cellobiose, d-mannose, maltose, acetate, citrate, pyruvate and salicin.</s><s>d-Galactose, d-trehalose, benzoate, succinate, l-malate, formate and l-glutamate are not utilized.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (34·4 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (19·4 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (15·4 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (12·3 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 36·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSW-10<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 3933<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16826<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Dokdo, an island located at the edge of the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>