<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2472_nm.11389" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11389" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11389" rank="species">Enterococcus camelliae</organism><reference id="rid.2472"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sukontasing</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moonmangmee</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus camelliae sp. nov., isolated from fermented tea leaves in Thailand.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2151</fpage><lpage>2154</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65109-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766890</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterococcus camelliae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterococcus camelliae</em> [ca.mel′li.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>camelliae</em> of <em>Camellia</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from fermented tea leaves (<em>Camellia sinensis</em>)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming, spherical or ovoid, 0.5–1 μm in diameter and arranged in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Colonies on GYP agar plates are circular, raised or low-convex with entire margins, and non-pigmented.</s><s>Small, red colonies appear on Slanetz–Bartley agar.</s><s>No growth is observed on kanamycin aesculin azide agar.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin but weak reactions for starch hydrolysis and blood haemolysis.</s><s>Negative for catalase, hydrolysis of arginine and gelatin, reduction of nitrate and production of gas from glucose, gluconate and citrate.</s><s>Utilizes glucose fermentatively.</s><s>No acidification, coagulation, reduction or liquefaction in litmus milk.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–9.6, at 15–45 °C and in 2–6 % NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-cellobiose, aesculin, d-mannose, maltose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, trehalose, sucrose and salicin, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, d-galactose, d-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-amygdalin, arbutin, lactose, inulin, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-sorbitol, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate or 2- or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Riboflavin, niacin and calcium pantothenate are required for growth.</s><s>DMK-7 is the major menaquinone.</s><s>C<sub>16 : 1</sub> is the dominant component of the fatty acid profile.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FP15-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13133<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 101868<sup>T</sup> =NRIC 0105<sup>T</sup> =TISTR 932<sup>T</sup> =PCU 277<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from fermented tea leaves (‘miang’) produced in Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>