<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6130_nm.9323" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9323" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9323" rank="species">Arthrobacter stackebrandtii</organism><reference id="rid.6130"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tvrzová</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Páčová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomic study of strain CCM 2783 resulting in the description of Arthrobacter stackebrandtii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>805</fpage><lpage>808</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63428-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774666</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter stackebrandtii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter stackebrandtii</em> (sta.cke.brand′ti.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>stackebrandtii</em> of/from Stackebrandt, named in honour of Erko Stackebrandt for his pioneering contributions to our insight into the phylogenetic structure of the suborder <em>Micrococcineae</em> and of the genus <em>Arthrobacter</em> in particular).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular club-shaped rods showing a rod–coccus cycle, 0·6–1×1–3 μm, occurring in pairs as typical V-forms.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-motile and non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs over a pH range 5·7–9·1 and in the presence of 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Positive for catalase, urease and pyrazinamidase.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and pyrrolidonyl arylamidase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Nitrite is not reduced; Tween 80 and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid production is negative from glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose and glycogen.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized (Biolog system): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tween 40, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, <em>β</em>-ketovaleric acid, methyl pyruvate, pyruvic acid, l-asparagine, glycerol, adenosine, inosine, thymidine and uridine.</s><s>Negative reactions (Biolog) were observed with <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>meso</em>-inositol, d-melezitose, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-rhamnose, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, xylitol, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglutamic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-glycerophosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCM 2783<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16005<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from poultry litter.</s></p></content></protolog>