<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7092_nm.4878" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4878" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4878" rank="species">Bacillus barbaricus</organism><reference id="rid.7092"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Täubel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buczolits</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lubitz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus barbaricus sp. nov., isolated from an experimental wall painting.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>725</fpage><lpage>730</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02304-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807193</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus barbaricus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus barbaricus</em> (bar.ba′ri.cus. L. adj. <em>barbaricus</em> strange, foreign, referring to the strange behaviour towards growth at different pH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile rods that produce subterminal, oval endospores in a swollen sporangium.</s><s>Cells are 0·5 μm wide and 4–5 μm long.</s><s>Colonies are brownish, opaque, circular, flat and 3–7 mm in diameter when grown on PYES agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase- and urease-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Alkalitolerant.</s><s>Good growth occurs at temperatures ranging from 18 to 37 °C.</s><s>No growth at 4 or 47 °C or in the presence of 5 or 10 % NaCl, and only weak growth in 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, maltose, trehalose, starch and glycogen.</s><s>Acid production is variable from d-fructose (V2-BIII-A2<sup>T</sup> is weakly positive), galactose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, lactose, sucrose and d-turanose (V2-BIII-A2<sup>T</sup> is negative).</s><s>No acid is produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>The cell-wall diamino acid is diaminopimelic acid and MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The polar lipid profile is composed of the major compounds phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol and minor amounts of an unknown phospholipid, an unknown aminophospholipid, an unknown aminolipid and one unknown polar lipid.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of the predominant compounds ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>; i-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are present in moderate amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, V2-BIII-A2<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 4982<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14730<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an experimental wall painting exposed in the Virgilkapelle in Vienna, Austria.</s></p></content></protolog>