<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6293_nm.5371" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5371" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5371" rank="species">Lactobacillus gallinarum</organism><reference id="rid.6293"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fujisawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yaeshima</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of the Lactobacillus acidophilus group, with recognition of Lactobacillus gallinarum sp. nov. and Lactobacillus johnsonii sp. nov. and synonymy of Lactobacillus acidophilus group A3 (Johnson et al. 1980) with the type strain of Lactobacillus amylovorus (Nakamura 1981).</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>487</fpage><lpage>491</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-487</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503977</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus gallinarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus gallinarum</i> (gallin.ar'um. L. gen. pl. <i>gallinarum</i> of hens)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, gram-positive, non-sporeforming rods that produce DL-lactic acid as a major fermentation product from glucose.</s><s>Cells of the strains from BL agar plate cultures are short to long rods (0.5 to 1.5 μm in width and 1.5 to 10.0 μm in length) and occur singly, in pairs, and sometimes in short chains.</s><s>Surface colonies on BL agar plates are 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, circular to slightly irregular, entire, grayish brown to reddish brown, and rough.</s><s>Grown at 15°C.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Acid is produced without gas formation from glucose, mannose, maltose, galactose, sucrose, fructose, cellobiose, melibiose, raffinose, dextrin, esculin, salicin, and amygdalin.</s><s>No acid formation from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, ribose, trehalose, melezitose, mannitol, and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid production from lactose and starch is variable.</s><s>Strains are tolerant to 4.0% NaCl.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35.9 to 37.2 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from chicken intestine.</s><s>Type strain is ATCC 33199.</s></p></content></protolog>