<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2425_nm.6331" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6331" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6331" rank="species">Mycobacterium celatum</organism><reference id="rid.2425"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Connor</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yakrus</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smithwick</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plikaytis</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woodley</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilburn</surname><given-names>J.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vadney</surname><given-names>F.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium celatum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>539</fpage><lpage>548</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-539</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8102246</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium celatum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium celatum</i> (ce.la' tum. L. neut. part. adj. <i>celutum</i>, hidden or concealed, referring to the concealed nature of these organisms among the recognized <i>Mycobacterium</i> species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid-alcohol fast, slender, and predominantly rod-shaped, with occasional coccoidal forms (0.25 to 0.5 by 0.5 to 13.0 μm).</s><s>Does not form cords or branches.</s><s>Eugonic growth on L-J medium occurs at 33, 37, and 42°C in 3 to 5 weeks.</s><s>Dysgonic growth occurs at 27, 30, and especially 45°C.</s><s>Comparable results are found on 7H10 agar medium at these temperatures, but growth is visible in 1 week.</s><s>Older colonies are polymorphic, usually smooth, dome shaped, and nonpigmented or pale yellow or infrequently, flat and transparent.</s><s>Cultures are nonphotochromogenic.</s><s>All strains produce less than 45 mm of foam in the semiquantitative catalase test and are negative in tests for niacin production, nitrate reduction, Tween opacity, iron uptake, and enzymatic hydrolysis of urea and Tween.</s><s>They do not grow on L-J medium containing 5% sodium chloride or on MacConkey agar without crystal violet, but are resistant to thiophen-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide.</s><s>All strains are positive in 3- and 14-day arylsulfatase, heat-stable catalase, pyrazinamidase, and tellurite reduction tests.</s><s>Strains are completely or partially resistant to most antituberculosis drugs tested but are susceptible to a high concentration of streptomycin (10.0 μg/ml) and capreomycin. <i>M. celutum</i> produces α-, keto-, and dicarboxylic mycolic acids, as well as a secondary alcohol chemically released from dicarboxylic mycolate during saponification.</s><s>Evaluation of the 16s rRNA sequence data confirms the phylogenetic position of <i>M. celatum</i> among the slowly growing <i>Mycobacterium</i> species.</s><s>Type strain CDC 89-0899, which is representative of type 1 (ET 1 and RFLP pattern A), was isolated from sputum produced by a 74-year-old human female; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51131.</s><s>An additional strain, CDC 89-0444, which is representative of type 2 (ET 2 and RFLP pattern B), was isolated from a bronchial wash specimen from a 47-year-old human male; this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51130.</s></p></content></protolog>