<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2752_nm.9769" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9769" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3398" rank="species">Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</organism><reference id="rid.2752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nørskov-Lauritsen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans, Haemophilus aphrophilus, Haemophilus paraphrophilus and Haemophilus segnis as Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans gen. nov., comb. nov., Aggregatibacter aphrophilus comb. nov. and Aggregatibacter segnis comb. nov., and emended description of Aggregatibacter aphrophilus to include V factor-dependent and V factor-independent isolates.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64207-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</em> (Klinger 1912) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</em> [ac.ti.no.my.ce.tem.co′mi.tans. Gr. n. <em>actis</em> a ray; N.L. n. <em>myces</em> from Gr. n. <em>mukes</em> a fungus; N.L. n. <em>actinomyces</em> ray fungus; L. part. adj. <em>comitans</em> accompanying; N.L. part. adj. <em>actinomycetemcomitans</em> (sic) accompanying an actinomycete].</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans</em> (Klinger 1912) Topley and Wilson 1929.</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Other synonym: <em>Haemophilus actinomycetemcomitans</em> (Klinger 1912) Potts <em>et al.</em> 1985.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Small rods which may appear as cocci in broth or actinomycotic lesions.</s><s>They may occur singly, in pairs or in small clumps.</s><s>Grows poorly in ambient air, but well in 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Colonies on chocolate agar are small, with a diameter of ≤0.5 mm after 24 h, but may exceed 1–2 mm after 48 h.</s><s>On primary isolation, the colonies are rough-textured and adherent and have an internal, opaque pattern described as star-like or like ‘crossed cigars’.</s><s>The rough phenotype is related to fimbriation and to the production of hexoseamine-containing exopolysaccharide.</s><s>Cells from rough colonies grow in broth as granular, autoaggregated cells that adhere to the glass and leave a clear broth.</s><s>Successive rounds of subculturing <em>in vitro</em> on solid media can result in transformation into a smooth, non-adherent colony type that exhibits planktonic growth in broth and reduced ability to colonize the mouth of experimental animals.</s><s>X and V factors are not required.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, maltose and mannose, whereas arabinose, cellobiose, galactose, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, trehalose, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol and sucrose are not fermented.</s><s>Variable fermentation is observed with mannitol and xylose.</s><s>Catalase-positive; ONPG is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Secretes a leukotoxin of the highly conserved repeat toxin (RTX) family.</s><s>Six serotypes a–f have been described.</s><s>Key tests for discrimination between <em>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</em> and V factor-independent strains of <em>Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</em> are catalase and ONPG, plus fermentation of lactose, sucrose and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Indigenous to man, with primary habitat on dental surfaces.</s><s>A particular clone of serotype b with enhanced leukotoxic activity is predominantly associated with cases of localized aggressive periodontitis. <em>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</em> has regularly been isolated together with <em>Actinomyces</em> species from human actinomycosis.</s><s>It is sometimes found in other pathological processes such as endocarditis, brain abscess and urinary tract infections.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42.7 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCTC 9710<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 33384<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 13227<sup>T</sup>=CIP 52.106<sup>T</sup>=DSM 8324<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is M75039.</s></p></content></protolog>