<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2799_nm.3085" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3085" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3085" rank="species">Anaerobiospirillum thomasii</organism><reference id="rid.2799"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Malnick</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerobiospirillum thomasii sp. nov., an anaerobic spiral bacterium isolated from the feces of cats and dogs and from diarrheal feces of humans, and emendation of the genus Anaerobiospirillum.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>384</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103625</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerobiospirillum thomasii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerobiospirillum thomasii</i> (thom'as.i.i. N. L. gen. n. <i>thomasii</i>, of Thomas, named after M. E. M. Thomas [Public Health Laboratory Service, 1947 to 19841, whose interest in and enthusiasm for uncommon medical bacterial infections led to the initiation of this study)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative helical rods (0.5 to 0.7 by 5 to 32 μm).</s><s>Flagella are arranged in bipolar tufts.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 33 and 43°C; the optimal temperature is 37°C.</s><s>Flat colonies with even, sometimes spreading edges are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 24 to 48 h on horse blood agar.</s><s>Hemolysis does not occur.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Carbohydrate metabolism is fermentative.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, galactose, glucose, and maltose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from cellobiose, fructose, inulin, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>The following tests are negative: catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction, and hydrolysis of esculin, hippurate, and urea.</s><s>The enzymes detected with an API ZYM kit are leucine arylamidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>The enzymes not detected with an API ZYM kit include acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C-4), esterase-lipase (C-8), lipase (C-14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphohydrolase, α-D-galactosidase, β-D-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The major products of glucose metabolism are succinic acid and acetic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39 to 42 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from cat and dog feces and as a pathogen in human diarrheal feces.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 12467.</s></p></content></protolog>