<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3598_nm.4325" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4325" rank="genus">Desulfosporosinus</organism><reference id="rid.3598"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüler</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Desulfotomaculum auripigmentum as Desulfosporosinus auripigmenti corrig., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1439</fpage><lpage>1443</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02526-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Desulfosporosinus</em> (Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em> 1997, Robertson <em>et al.</em> 2001, emend.)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Desulfosporosinus</em> [De.sul.fo.spo.ro.si′nus. L. pref. <em>de</em> from; L. n. <em>sulfur</em> sulfur; M.L. n. <em>spora</em> spore; L. n. <em>sinus</em> bend; N.L. masc. n. <em>Desulfosporosinus</em> a spore-forming curved (organism) that reduces sulfur compounds].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods that have a multi-layered cell wall structure.</s><s>Endospores present, oval and subterminal to (almost) terminal, causing the cells to swell slightly.</s><s>Non-motile or motile with lateral or peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>If determined, desulfoviridin and cytochrome <em>c</em><sub>3</sub> absent and bisulfite reductase P<sub>582</sub> present.</s><s>Sulfate and thiosulfate are reduced to sulfide in the presence of lactate but not in the presence of acetate or fructose.</s><s>Incomplete oxidation of organic compounds to acetate.</s><s>Acetate is the fermentation end-product; capable of homoacetogenic growth.</s><s>Grows autotrophically with hydrogen plus sulfate.</s><s>ll-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid of peptidoglycan.</s><s>Contains menaquinone with a side-chain with seven isoprene units (MK-7 type).</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are even-numbered, saturated and unsaturated fatty acids; significant amounts of 1,1-dimethylacetals have been found in <em>Desulfosporosinus auripigmenti</em>; traces of iso- and anteiso-branched-chain fatty acids and cyclopropane fatty acids may occur.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41·6–45·9 mol%.</s><s>Phylogenetically, a member of the <em>Clostridium</em>–<em>Bacillus</em> subphylum of Gram-positive bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <em>Desulfosporosinus orientis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>