<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8422_nm.13555" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13555" rank="species">Pseudoxanthomonas sacheonensis</organism><reference id="rid.8422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoxanthomonas sacheonensis sp. nov., isolated from BTEX-contaminated soil in Korea, transfer of Stenotrophomonas dokdonensis Yoon et al. 2006 to the genus Pseudoxanthomonas as Pseudoxanthomonas dokdonensis comb. nov. and emended description of the genus Pseudoxanthomonas</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2235</fpage><lpage>2240</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65678-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoxanthomonas sacheonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoxanthomonas sacheonensis</em> (sa.che.on.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>sacheonensis</em> pertaining to Sacheon, Korea, the location of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are yellow, opaque, circular and convex with entire margins after 3 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-negative, short, non-motile rods, 0.3–0.5 μm wide and 0.8–1.6 μm long.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–30 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, urea, tyrosine, casein and gelatin, but not Tweens 20 or 80 or starch.</s><s>Produces acids from raffinose, lactose, l-arabinose, melibiose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, arbutin and salicin, but not from <em>myo</em>-inositol or d-galactose.</s><s>Positive for glucose fermentation, but negative for indole production and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose, but negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but not <em>α</em>-galactosidase or <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Weak activities are observed for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Contains large amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol and a small amount of an unknown amino-group-containing polar lipid.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.5 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BD-c54<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22080<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19373<sup>T</sup>), isolated from BTEX-contaminated soil in Sacheon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>