<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.280_nm.3966" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3966" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3966" rank="species">Clostridium litorale</organism><reference id="rid.280"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fendrich</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hippe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschalk</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium halophilium sp. nov. and Clostridium litorale sp. nov., an obligate halophilic and a marine species degrading betaine in the Stickland reaction.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>154</volume><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>132</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00423321</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium litorale</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium litorale</i> (li.to.ra'le. L. adj. n. <i>litorale</i>, at the beach or coast, referring to the source of samples, the seashore of northern Germany, from which the species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, 1.0 - 1.5 μm x 2.0 x 8.0 μm in size, with rounded ends; motile; ovoid spores (1.5 x 2.0 μm) formed subterminally in old cultures, preferentially on agar medium or in litmus milk; gram-reaction negative, also in young cultures; gram-positive cell wall.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph , and no carbohydrates are fermented.</s><s>Betaine is reductively cleaved as oxidant in the Stickland reaction into trimethylamine and acetate with hydrogen, glycine, L-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-valine or L-phenylalanine.</s><s>Sarcosine is fermented with L-alanine as electron donor and utilizes glycine and L-serine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In complex standard media acetate and butyrate are the major fermentation products.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced and growth is stimulated by Tween 80.</s><s>Gas, indole, ammonia or hydrogen are not produced.</s><s>It is positive for esculin hydrolysis, reduction of neutral red and resazurin and catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Lipase, lecithinase or urease is not produced.</s><s>Meat and milk are not digested and gelatine and starch not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate, sulfate, thiosulfate or sulfite are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No complex nutrients required</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range. 13°C-38.5°C; optimum growth at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH Range. 6.5-8.4; optimum growth at 7.3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>NaCl.</s><s>Optimum at 1.0%, growth completely inhibited by 6.0% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 26.1% G + C (thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitats.</s><s>Anoxic marine mesophilic sediments from the North Sea, Germany.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Strain W6, DSM 5388, deposited in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig, FRG.</s></p></content></protolog>