<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2957_nm.6276" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6276" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6276" rank="species">Corynebacterium ulcerans</organism><reference id="rid.2957"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Corynebacterium diphtheriae and related taxa, with recognition of Corynebacterium ulcerans sp. nov. nom. rev.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>126</volume><fpage>271</fpage><lpage>276</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0378-1097(95)00022-W</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7729671</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium ulcerans</i> sp. nov. nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium ulcerans</i> (ul'ce.rans. L. part adj. <i>ulcerans</i> making sore, causing to ulcerate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The salient characteristics of this species, based on previous data [1,2,4,5,18] and our observations, are as follows: Bacteria are nonmotile pleomorphic rods, arranged in palisades or V-shaped forms.</s><s>They are Gram-positive, non-spore forming and contain metachromatic granules.</s><s>They are non-acid fast, and no rod-coccus cycle is present.</s><s>They are catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>They are facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies (1 to 2 mm in diameter) on 5% sheep blood agar are grey-white and exhibit a light hemolysis, a dry aspect and a waxy consistency.</s><s>They are circular, slightly convex with an entire margin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, glycogen, maltose, fructose and ribose but not from lactose, sucrose, D-xylose, and trehalose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from mannitol.</s><s>Starch, DNA and urea are degraded but not tyrosine.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolyzed at 25°C and at 37°C for some strains.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The methyl red test is positive and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Growth is visible in 6.5% NaCl for some strains.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Alcaline phosphatase and alpha-glucosidase are produced but not pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>As sole carbon sources, cells utilize glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose and malate.</s><s>Utilization of mannitol and gluconate occurs variably.</s><s>Acetate, lactate, propionate, caprate, adipate and phenyl-acetate are not utilized.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose and mycolic acids of short chain lengths (C<sub>26</sub> to C<sub>36</sub>). <i>C. ulcerans</i> strains can be isolated from animal and human infections.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CCUG 2708 = National Collection of Types Cultures NCTC 7910.</s><s>It was isolated from a human throat.</s><s>This strain has all of the above properties.</s><s>Mannitol is utilized but not gluconate and acid is produced from mannitol.</s><s>Growth in 6.5% NaCl is visible.</s><s>The mol% G + C content of DNA is 53.</s></p></content></protolog>