<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8823_nm.13771" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13771" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13771" rank="species">Saxeibacter lacteus</organism><reference id="rid.8823"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yun</surname><given-names>Y.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saxeibacter lacteus gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from rock.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>906</fpage><lpage>909</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65558-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398192</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saxeibacter lacteus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saxeibacter lacteus</em> (lac.te′us. L. masc. adj. <em>lacteus</em> milk-coloured, milky).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are cream-coloured, circular, smooth and convex, reaching 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>The morphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>The temperature and pH ranges for growth are 4–37 °C and pH 5.1–9.1.</s><s>No growth occurs at 0 or 42 °C, at pH 4.1 or above pH 10.1.</s><s>Grows at NaCl concentrations up to 3 %; does not grow in the presence of 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of DNA; negative for hydrolysis of chitin, CM-cellulose and elastin.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The following tests in the API 20E system are negative: H<sub>2</sub>S production, utilization of citrate, indole production and Voges–Proskauer reaction, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and gelatinase.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, tests for leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are positive.</s><s>Weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8) and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>l-Arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol and methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but benzoate, cellobiose, citrate, dextran, d-dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, formate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-sorbose, dl-tartrate, trehalose and d-xylitol are not used.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-galactose.</s><s>Other physiological properties are given in Table 1.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (25.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (19.6 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (15.7 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (15.0 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 74.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DLS-10<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19285<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19367<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a rock sample collected from the peak of Darangshi Oreum (a small mountain, 300 m above sea level) in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>