<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4325_nm.5564" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5564" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5564" rank="species">Vagococcus fessus</organism><reference id="rid.4325"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohlén</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grainger</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vagococcus fessus sp. nov., isolated from a seal and a harbour porpoise.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1151</fpage><lpage>1154</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843057</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vagococcus fessus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vagococcus fessus</i> (fes.sus. L. adj. <i>fessus</i> weary, pertaining to the general biochemical unreactivity of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci that occur as single cells, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Cells are elongated in the direction of the chain.</s><s>α-Haemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Using API systems, acid may or may not be produced from cyclodextrin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, melezitose, pullulan, D-raffinose, D-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Activities for chymotrypsin, esterase C4 (weak), ester lipase C8 (weak), phosphoamidase (weak), pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and leucine arylamidase are detected.</s><s>Activity may or may not be detected for alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase and glycyl tryptophan arylamidase.</s><s>No activity for alanyl phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-galacturonidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, lipase C14, trypsin, urease or valine arylamidase is detected.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content is 40.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 41755<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from a dead seal.</s><s>A second strain was recovered from multiple organs from a dead harbour porpoise.</s><s>Pathological significance is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>