<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12416_nm.21246" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21246" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21246" rank="species">Agarivorans gilvus</organism><reference id="rid.12416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Z.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>G.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rooney</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miao</surname><given-names>T.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Q.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agarivorans gilvus sp. nov. isolated from seaweed</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>493</fpage><lpage>496</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019810-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20363930</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agarivorans gilvus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agarivorans gilvus</em> (gil′vus. L. masc. adj. <em>gilvus</em> pale yellow, referring to the pale yellow pigmentation of the bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped, motile by single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow, smooth and 2.5–3.5 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation at 28 °C on MA.</s><s>Strictly aerobic and agar-hydrolysing; shallow craters with a clear zone (6–8 mm in diameter) are observed surrounding the colonies due to agar hydrolysis.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.5–9.5, optimum at pH 8.4–8.6.</s><s>Cells grow in the presence of 0.5–5 % (w/v) NaCl and at 10–45 °C.</s><s>Prolific growth occurs at 28–32 °C in media containing 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs without NaCl.</s><s>Cells are oxidase, catalase, ONPG and Voges–Proskauer positive.</s><s>No citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, arginine dihydrolase or indole production.</s><s>Aesculin and starch are hydrolysed, but urea and gelatin are not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acidic phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not produced.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-mannose, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, lactose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acids are produced from amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin ferric citrate, salicoside, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose.</s><s>Resistant to sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), clindamycin (30 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), acetylspiramycin (30 μg), tobramycin (30 μg) and midecamycin (30 μg), but sensitive to nalidixic acid (30 μg), gentamicin (120 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg) and streptomycin (25 μg).</s><s>Major whole-cell fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH/iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (Supplementary Table S1 available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is WH0801<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-59247<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.10131<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the surface of seaweed collected in the shallow coastal region of Weihai, China.</s></p></content></protolog>