<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2837_nm.998" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.998" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.998" rank="species">Ehrlichia risticii</organism><reference id="rid.2837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holland</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burgdorfer</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kakoma</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ehrlichia risticii sp. nov.: etiological agent of equine monocytic ehrlichiosis (synonym, Potomac horse fever).</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>524</fpage><lpage>526</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-524</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ehrlichia risticii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ehrlichia risticii</i> (ris. ti. ci' i. N.L. gen. n. <i>risticii</i> in honor of Miodrag Ristic for his many valuable contributions to the field of rickettsiae and rickettsial diseases)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Ehrlichia risticii</i> possesses all of the general phenotypic characteristics common to other members of the genus <i>Ehrlichia</i> (3, 5, 9, 11).</s><s>The organisms are pleomorphic, appearing as round, oval, or elongated sausage-like structures surrounded by a double plasma membrane and a highly rippled cell wall.</s><s>Their internal components are highly electron dense and are presumed to consist of deoxyribonucleic acid and ribosomes (3, 10).</s><s>The sizes of individual cells are intermediate between the sizes of <i>E. canis</i> and <i>E. sennetsu</i> cells, ranging from 0.4 to 0.75 μm wide and from 0.5 to 1.2 μm long (3, 10, 11).</s><s>The organisms are contained within a cytoplasmic vacuolar membrane and may occur singly or multiply as inclusion bodies (3, 10).</s><s>Division occurs by binary fission (Fig. 1).</s><s>The organisms are gram negative and stain bluish purple with Wright Giemsa stain.</s><s>They cannot be propagated in cell-free media.</s><s>In vitro cultivation has been established in primary equine and canine monocyte cultures (3) and with murine macrophage cell lines P388D1 and MDH-SP in medium 199 (GIBCO Laboratories) or RPMI 1640 medium (GIBCO; Quality Biological, Inc.) supplemented with 20% fetal bovine serum.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 37 to 38°C under normal atmospheric conditions (3), but the organism may also be cultured in an humidified atmosphere of 5% CO<sub>2</sub> in air.</s><s>It can be successfully stored at -100°C as a suspension of infected host cells in tissue culture medium containing 8 to 10% dimethyl sulfoxide.</s><s>The organism requires L-glutamine for growth and is severely inhibited by low concentrations of antibiotics, such as tetracycline, penicillin, streptomycin, and gentamicin.</s><s>As has been reported for <i>E. sennetsu</i> (7), mice are susceptible to infection by <i>E. risticii</i> when they are infected intraperitoneally with the blood or buffy coat from an acutely infected horse or with cultured organisms (Jenny, personal communication; A.</s><s>I.</s><s>Cole and M.</s><s>Khondowe, unpublished data; G.</s><s>S.</s><s>Miranpuri and W.</s><s>Burgdorfer, unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The susceptibility of other mammalian species and the mechanisms by which this organism is transmitted in nature are not known.</s><s>A blood-sucking arthropod, such as ticks, is strongly suspected in transmission of the disease since experimental infections have only been produced thus far by blood transfusion or intravenous inoculation of cultured organisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Within the genus <i>Ehrlichia</i>, <i>E. risticii</i> is more closely related to <i>E. sennetsu</i> and <i>E. canis</i>, which are also monocytic parasites, than to <i>E. equi</i> and, presumably, <i>Ehrlichia phagocytophila</i>, which multiply in granulocytes (11).</s><s>The guanosine-plus-cytosine contents of the major species of <i>Ehrlichia</i> are currently being investigated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>E. risticii</i> has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC VR-986; this strain is the first isolate of <i>E. risticii</i> (= strain HRC-IL) and is described in this paper and elsewhere (3, 5).</s></p></content></protolog>