<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7254_nm.7525" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7525" rank="family">Nocardiopsaceae</organism><reference id="rid.7254"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Thermomonospora and Microtetraspora</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>411</fpage><lpage>422</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-411</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the family <i>Nocardiopsaceae</i> (Rainey et a/. 1996)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Since phylogenetic evidence alone has been used previously to allocate phenotypically diverse genera of actinomycetes into one family (16,46), it is appropriate to transfer <i>Thermobifida</i> into the family <i>Nocardiopsaceae</i> on the same basis. <i>Nocardiopsis</i> and <i>Thermobifida</i> are morphologically and chemotaxonomically different. However, the 16s rRNA sequence-based phylogenetic analysis showed that they formed a distinct clade in the suborder <i>Streptosporangineae</i> (52). The description below is based on the descriptions from previous investigations (4, 19, 31, 46).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genus <i>Nocardiopsis</i> describes aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-fast organisms that form fragmenting and branched substrate mycelium 05-0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Fragmentation into coccoid and bacillary elements may occur.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is well developed and abundant; hyphae are long, branched, straight flexuous or irregularly zagged.</s><s>Hyphae may fragment completely into spores of various length.</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Members of genus <i>Thermobifida</i> form single, heat-sensitive, non-motile spores on dichotomously branched sporophores resulting in spore clusters on aerial hyphae.</s><s>Spores may also be produced on substrate mycelium.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is composed of extensively branched non-fragmenting hyphae.</s><s>Spores are oval to round and 0.5-2 μm in diameter.</s><s>Wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-DAP with no diagnostic sugars.</s><s>Mycolic acid is absent.</s><s>Phospholipid types, menaquinone profiles and fatty acid types are heterogeneous.</s><s>Phospholipid pattern type III (PC, μmE, GL), menaquinone pattern type 4c [MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), -10(H<sub>4</sub>), -10(H<sub>6</sub>)] and fatty acid pattern type 3d are found in members of Nocardiopsis, but Thermobijida species contain phospholipid pattern type I1 (PE, μmE, GL), menaquinone pattern type 4d [MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), -10(H<sub>8</sub>), -11(H<sub>6</sub>)] and fatty acid pattern type 3e.</s><s>Growth temperature is mesophilic, except for Therrnobijida which can grow in the temperature range 35-60 °C.</s><s>G + C content is 64-69 mol % (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) in strains of <i>Nocardiopsis</i>.</s><s>Type genus is <i>Nocardiopsis</i> Meyer 1976 (31).</s></p></content></protolog>