<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4076_nm.4840" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4840" rank="genus">Asteroleplasma</organism><reference id="rid.4076"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freundt</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for an amended classification of anaerobic mollicutes.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>78</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-1-78</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Asteroleplasma</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Asteroleplasma</i> (A.ste.rol.e.plas'ma. Gr. pref. <i>a</i> not; <i>sterol</i> derived from Gr. adj. <i>stereos</i> solid, plus Lat. n. <i>oleum</i> oil, ending of cholesterol, ergosterol, etc., and used as a separate word to denote a class of solid monohydroxy alcohols; <i>e</i> combining vowel; Gr. neut. n. <i>plasma</i> something formed or molded, a form; M.L. neut. n. <i>Asteroleplasma</i> name intended to indicate that sterol is not required for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Among the anaerobic mycoplasmas, the group represented by strains 161, 162, and 163 differs from members of the genus <i>Anaeroplasma</i> in not requiring sterol for growth (16,17, 24).</s><s>The significance of this group and the need for clarification of their taxonomic status within the <i>Mollicutes</i> is further emphasized by the recent finding that sterol-nonrequiring organisms compose a large proportion of the anaerobic mollicute population of the rumen in cattle and sheep (14, 18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains 161,162, and 163 form a homogeneous and distinct serological group, tentatively referred to as serovar 4 (16, 17).</s><s>The distinctiveness of the group was further confirmed and strengthened by the study of Stephens et al. (24) who obtained less than 5% DNA-DNA homology between these strains and all other anaerobic mycoplasmas tested, as opposed to about 80% homology among the three strains themselves.</s><s>Furthermore, there was no significant hybridization (&#x003C;5%) between a [<sup>3</sup>H]DNA probe prepared from strain 161 and unlabeled DNA from each of the nine established <i>Acholeplasma</i> species.</s><s>Moreover, determination of the G + C ratio was considerably higher for strains 161 and 162 (40.2 and 40.3%, respectively) than for <i>A. abactoclasticum</i> (6-1<sup>T</sup>), <i>A. bactoclasticum</i> (JR<sup>T</sup>), <i>A. varium</i> (A-2<sup>T</sup>), and <i>A. intermedium</i> (7LA<sup>T</sup>), viz. 40.2 and 40.3% versus 29.3, 33.7, 33.4, and 32.5%, respectively (24).</s><s>The genome size of strain 161 was about 1,000 megadaltons; this is similar to the genome size of other anaerobic mycoplasmas (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Collectively, the nutritional, antigenic, and genomic characteristics of strains 161, 162, and 163 clearly indicate their unique taxonomic status as compared with anaerobic mycoplasmas of the genus <i>Anaeroplasma</i> and with sterol-nonrequiring facultatively anaerobic mollicutes of the family <i>Acholeplasmataceae</i>.</s><s>In accordance with the opinion previously expressed by Stephens et al. (24), these organisms should belong to a new genus, for which we propose the name <i>Asteroleplasma</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three related strains examined most thoroughly, strains 161, 162, and 163, are placed in a single species, <i>Asteroleplasma anaerobium</i>.</s><s>Strain 161 (ATCC 27880) is designated as the type strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>