<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8217_nm.13296" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13296" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13296" rank="species">Deinococcus aquatilis</organism><reference id="rid.8217"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deinococcus aquatilis sp. nov., isolated from water.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2803</fpage><lpage>2806</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001206-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060062</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Deinococcus aquatilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Deinococcus aquatilis</em> (a.qua.ti′lis. L. masc. adj. <em>aquatilis</em> living in water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Aerobic and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Good growth after 48 h on R2A agar, nutrient agar and tryptic soy agar at 15–36 °C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, pale pinkish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges, becoming mucoid.</s><s>Unable to grow at 5 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–11.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>.</s><s>MK-8 is the predominant lipoquinone.</s><s>Presents a complex polar lipid profile, consisting of different unidentified glycolipids and polar lipids, two unknown phospholipids and three unknown phosphoglycolipids, among them a predominant phosphoglycolipid with a migration on TLC similar to that of 2′-<em>O</em>-(1,2-diacyl-<em>sn</em>-glycero-3-phospho)-3′-<em>O</em>-(<em>α</em>-galactosyl)-<em>N</em>-d-glyceroyl alkylamine, which has been identified in <em>Deinococcus radiodurans</em>.</s><s>The polyamine pattern consists of the predominant component spermidine and traces of spermine, putrescine and 1,3-diaminopropane.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources (positive after prolonged incubation for 14 days according to the method of Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991): d-glucose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose and acetate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: d-gluconate, propionate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, suberate, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>bis-<em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) phosphate, bis-pNP phenylphosphonate and bis-pNP phosphorylcholine are hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-aniline <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA and l-proline pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 53370<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7524<sup>T</sup>), isolated from water.</s></p></content></protolog>