<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.694_nm.527" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.527" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.527" rank="species">Thermus ruber</organism><reference id="rid.694"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Loginova</surname><given-names>L.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Egorova</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Golovacheva</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seregina</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermus ruber sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>498</fpage><lpage>499</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-498</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermus ruber</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermus ruber</i> (ru'ber. M.L. adj. <i>ruber</i> red)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative nonmotile rods that are 3 to 6 by 0.5 to 0.8 μm, have rounded lends, and are nonsporeforming.</s><s>In potato-peptone-yeast extract broth incubated at 60°C with shaking (260 rpm), filamentous forms (20 to 40 μm in length) are observed along with shorter rods after a few hours.</s><s>No filamentous forms are seen after 16 h of incubation.</s><s>Obligately thermophilic.</s><s>On potato-peptone-yeast extract medium, the temperature range for growth is 35 to 40°C (minimal) to 70°C (maximal), and the optimum temperature is 60°C (the generation time is then 60 min).</s><s>A bright red intracellular carotenoid pigment is produced, which resembles retro-dehydro-γ-carotene (neo A, neo B) in spectral properties (5, 8).</s><s>The absorption spectra of acetone, methanol-acetone (1:1), and hexane extracts show three maxima at 455, 483, and 513 nm.</s><s>One strain (strain INMI-a) contains a bright yellow pigment (12) resembling neurosporaxanthine in its spectral properties (4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs in minimal medium supplemented with 0.15% (wt/vol) peptone as an N source, 0.05% (wt/vol) yeast extract, and one of the following carbon sources at a concentration of 0.25% (wt/vol): D-glucose, sucrose, maltose, D-galactose, D-mannose, rhamnose, D-cellobiose, glycerol, D-mannitol, acetate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, or DL-malate (sodiuim salts) (10, 11).</s><s>No growth occurs if the concentration of D-glucose in the medium is raised to 0.5% (wt/vol).</s><s>Only moderate growth occurs when ammonium phosphate (0.1%, wt/vol) is substituted for peptone as the N source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs in control medium without a carbon source.</s><s>No growth occurs on minimal medium supplemented with 0.25% (wt/vol) D-glucose, 0.05% (wt/vol) yeast extract and one of the following nitrogen sources at a concentration of 0.1% (wt/vol): L-alanine, glycine, L-asparagine, L-tyrosine, L-glutamate, ammonium sulfate, nitrate, or urea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are not reduced; milk is not peptonized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are as follows (expressed as percentages of the total fatty acids): isopentadecanoic acid, 30.6%; isoheptadecanoic acid, 15.8%; anteisopentadecanoic acid, 8.3%; and anteisoheptadecanoic acid, 7.3% (2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 66 mol% (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: hot springs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is All-Union Collection of Microorganisms strain 1258 (= Loginova strain 21) (10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics listed above for the species.</s><s>A bright red intracellular carotenoid pigment is produced.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a hot spring (70 to 93°C, pH 6.5 to 7.3) in the Kamchatka Peninsula.</s><s>The original culture was at 60°C.</s></p></content></protolog>