<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5752_nm.2046" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2046" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2046" rank="species">Propionivibrio limicola</organism><reference id="rid.5752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brune</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionivibrio limicola sp. nov., a fermentative bacterium specialized in the degradation of hydroaromatic compounds, reclassification of Propionibacter pelophilus as Propionivibrio pelophilus comb. nov. and amended description of the genus Propionivibrio.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>441</fpage><lpage>444</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02082-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931155</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionivibrio limicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionivibrio limicola</i> (li.mi'co.la. L. n. <i>limus</i> mud; L. v. <i>colere</i> to inhabit; N.L. adj. <i>limicola</i> living in mud)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, slender rods, 0.6-0.7 μm wide and 1.5-2.5 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile (polar monotrichously flagellated), Gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-negative, superoxide-dismutase-positive.</s><s>No spores are formed.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, fermentative metabolism; external electron acceptors are not used.</s><s>Contains no cytochromes.</s><s>Quinic acid and shikimic acid are the only substrates, which are fermented to acetate, propionate and CO<sub>2</sub> as the only products.</s><s>No growth with sugars (cellobiose, fructose, glucose, erythrose, lactose, ribose, xylose), alcohols (<i>meso</i>-erythritol, ethanol, glycerol, mannitol), carboxylic acids (citrate, crotonate, fumarate, glycolate, 2-hydroxybutyrate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 4-hydroxybutyrate, lactate, malate, 2-oxobutyrate, pyruvate, sorbate, tartrate), amino acids (alanine, aspartate, glycine, threonine) or aromatic compounds (gallate, phloroglucinol, protocatechuate, resorcinol, 3,4,5- trimethoxybenzoate, 3,4,5-trimethoxycinnamate).</s><s>External electron acceptors (amorphous ferric iron, nitrate, oxygen, sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate) are not used.</s><s>Aerotolerant; growth occurs in non-reduced media when incubated under air without agitation.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.0-8.0, with an optimum around pH 7.0-7.5.</s><s>Temperature optimum is 37 °C; no growth at 45 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth in freshwater medium (identical growth rates with quinic acid and shikimic acid: μ=0.22 h<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Growth is inhibited completely in brackish medium with 10 g NaCl and 1.0 g MgCl<sub>2</sub> l<sup>-1</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 61.6±0.2 mol% G­+C.</s><s>Habitat: anoxic freshwater sediment.</s><s>Type strain: GolChi1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 6832<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-290<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>