<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5964_nm.4528" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4528" rank="genus">Coprothermobacter</organism><reference id="rid.5964"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of the type species of the genus Thermobacteroides to the genus Thermoanaerobacter as Thermoanaerobacter acetoethylicus (Ben-Bassat and Zeikus 1981) comb.nov., description of Coprothermobacter gen. nov., and reclassification of Thermobacteroides proteolyticus as Coprothermobacter proteolyticus (Ollivier et al. 1985)</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>857</fpage><lpage>859</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-857</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Coprothermobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Coprothermobacter</i> (co'pro.ther'mo.bac'ter, Gr. fem. n. <i>kopros</i> manure; Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i> warm; Gr. hyp. mas. n. <i>bakter</i> rod; N.L. mas. n. <i>Coprothermobacter</i>, because it is a thermophilic rod-shaped bacterium isolated from cattle manure)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular characteristics have been adopted from the descriptions of Ollivier et al. (7) for <i>Thermobacteroides proteolyticus</i>.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonmotile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophs which metabolize peptone and are proteolytic.</s><s>Glucose and lactose are fermented; other carbohydrates are used poorly unless yeast extract and either rumen fluid or Trypticase peptone are added.</s><s>The principal fermentation end products are acetic acid, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub> or acetic acid and ethanol.</s><s>Thermophilic temperature range for growth, with optimum of 65°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45 mol%.</s><s>The type species <i>C. proteolyticus</i>, represents a novel line of descent within the radiation of deep-branching phyla of the domain Bacteria.</s></p></content></protolog>