<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5626_nm.4010" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4010" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4010" rank="species">Clostridium saccharobutylicum</organism><reference id="rid.5626"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Keis</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shaheen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of Clostridium acetobutylicum and Clostridium beijerinckii, and descriptions of Clostridium saccharoperbutylacetonicum sp. nov. and Clostridium saccharobutylicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760952</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium saccharobutylicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium saccharobutylicum</i> (sac.cha.ro.bu.ty'li. cum. Gr. n. <i>saccharon</i> sugar juice ; N.L. n. <i>butylum</i> butanol; N.L. neut. adj. <i>saccharobutylicum</i> denoting the production of butanol from sugar)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The industrial strains belonging to this species were originally isolated and patented by the Commercial Solvents Corporation under the name `<i>Clostridium saccharo-butyl-acetonicum-liquefaciens</i> (Jones &#x0026; Keis, 1995).</s><s>The US patents describing this saccharolytic,solvent-producing Clostridium species were filed by Arzberger (1938) and Carnarius &#x0026; McCutchan (1938).</s><s>These industrial strains subsequently became designated as <i>C. acetobutylicum</i>.</s><s>As the original name never gained widespread usage, we propose the less cumbersome name <i>Clostridium saccharobutylicum</i> for this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in most broth cultures consist of straight, short and long rods with rounded ends, with a mean size of 1.4 μmx6.3 μm and lengths ranging from 3.8 μm to 10 μm (Long, 1984).</s><s>Rods may occur singly or in pairs and short chains, and are motile by means of peritrichous flagella; they are initially phase-dark and Gram-positive, becoming Gram-negative in older cultures (Jones et al., 1982).</s><s>Towards the end of exponential growth, the rod-shaped cells typically begin to accumulate granulose, assume a swollen cigar-shaped clostridial form, and produce extracellular slime or capsules (Jones et al., 1982).</s><s>These morphological changes are typically associated with the metabolic shift from acid production to solvent production.</s><s>Endospores are oval, measuring 1.1- 1.8 μm x 1.7-3.9 μm, terminal or subterminal with up to 15% being bipolar (Long, 1984).</s><s>Colonies on CBM agar are 2-3 mm in diameter, domed, creamy yellow, have smooth surfaces and have circular}irregular margins.</s><s>The species is mesophilic: the optimum growth for solvent production is between 30°C and 34°C and the optimum pH ranges between 6.2 and 7.0.</s><s>All of the strains tested are catalase-negative and susceptible to rifampicin (10 ng).</s><s>Urease and indole are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>All strains ferment arabinose, xylose, glucose, mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, saccharose, inositol, melibiose, methyl-glucopyranoside, raffinose, salicin, trehalose, turanose, amygdalin, starch, glycogen and dextrin.</s><s>Weak fermentation was observed with ribose, and no fermentation was seen with glycerol, dulcitol, sorbitol, melezitose, rhamnose or pectin.</s><s>Variable results were obtained with the sugars D- and L-arabitol, mannitol and inulin.</s><s>Curd formation in milk occurs within the first 24 h, but no riboflavin is produced (Johnson et al., 1997).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA has not been determined but DNA sequencing data indicate that it is likely to fall in the range 28-32 mol%.</s><s>Fermentation products include acetic and butyric acids, acetone, butanol, ethanol, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>These industrial strains were used in the applied fermentation process for the production of the solvents acetone, butanol and ethanol from a variety of sugar- and starch-based substrates.</s><s>Commercial production of solvents commonly used various types of molasses mash supplemented with nitrogen in the form of ammonium salts and organic nitrogen.</s><s>Typically, industrial fermentations utilized molasses containing 6-7.5% fermentable sugars at temperatures of 29- 33°C, for 29-33 h, giving a final pH of 5.2-6.4, solvent yields of 27-33% and solvent concentrations of 17-20 g l<sup>-1</sup>, (maximum 21 g l<sup>-1</sup>) ; the proportion of butanol ranged from 55% to 74%.</s><s>Corn mash typically required longer fermentation times and produced significantly lower yields and concentrations of solvents.</s><s>More detailed information on solvent ratios, concentrations and yields for both sugar-based and starch-based substrates with various strains belonging to this species is available in a recent publication by Shaheen et al. (2000).</s><s>The type strain is NCP 262<sup>T</sup>, which has been lodged with the DSMZ and the American Type Culture Collection under accession numbers DSM 13864<sup>T</sup> and ATCC BAA-117<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>