<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6739_nm.2858" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2858" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2858" rank="species">Marinobacter lipolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6739"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martín</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mellado</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter lipolyticus sp. nov., a novel moderate halophile with lipolytic activity.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1383</fpage><lpage>1387</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02528-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130022</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter lipolyticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter lipolyticus</em> (li.po.ly′ti.cus. Gr. n. <em>lipos</em> fat; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus</em> from Gr. adj. <em>lytikos</em> dissolving; N.L. adj. <em>lipolyticus</em> fat-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells that are 0·3–0·5×2·5–3·5 μm in size and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on SW-7·5 medium are circular, convex, slightly elevated, 2–3 mm in diameter and cream-pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1–15 % (w/v) total salt; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 7·5 % (w/v) total salt.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Grows occurs at 15–40 °C (optimal temperature, 37 °C) and at pH 5·0–10·0 (optimal pH, 7·5).</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose and d-mannitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, d-lactose or d-melibiose.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed, but DNA, gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Indole, methyl red, phosphatase, Voges–Proskauer, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-trehalose, methyl pyruvate, d-gluconic acid, inosine and thymidine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, m-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57·0 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SM19<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15157<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13907<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107627<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7048<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Habitat: saline soil.</s></p></content></protolog>