<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4527_nm.10797" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10797" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10797" rank="species">Labrys neptuniae</organism><reference id="rid.4527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elliott</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>James</surname><given-names>E.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sprent</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Labrys neptuniae sp. nov., isolated from root nodules of the aquatic legume Neptunia oleracea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>577</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64553-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329788</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Labrys neptuniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Labrys neptuniae</em> (nep.tu′ni.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>neptuniae</em> of <em>Neptunia</em>, named because the type strain was isolated from <em>Neptunia oleracea</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming, capsulated, rod-shaped and multiply by budding.</s><s>They are 0.7–0.9 μm in diameter and 1.2–1.5 μm in length.</s><s>Growth is evident at temperatures between 15 and 35 °C and at pH 4.0–10.0; optimum growth is displayed at 28–30 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>The following characters (API 20NE) are positive for the type strain: nitrate reduction, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate and malate.</s><s>Negative results are displayed for oxidase, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis and assimilation of maltose, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Positive results (API ZYM) are seen for activities of alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative results are obtained for C8 lipase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (positive result with the Biolog GN2 system): glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, <em>i</em>-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactate, malonic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The type strain can not oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, sucrose, turanose, citrate, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, phenylethylamine or 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>The type strain is resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, penicillin G and rifampicin and sensitive to gentamicin, kanamycin, novobiocin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acid components are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 16 : 0 and 19 : 0 cyclo.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.7 (±1.7) mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Liujia-146<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17578<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23578<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from root nodules of <em>Neptunia oleracea</em>, an aquatic legume, growing in a freshwater pond located in Tainan County in southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>