<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12410_nm.21238" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21238" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21238" rank="species">Paenibacillus rigui</organism><reference id="rid.12410"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choe</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus rigui sp. nov., isolated from a freshwater wetland</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>534</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021485-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382792</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus rigui</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus rigui</em> (ri′gu.i. L. gen. n. <em>rigui</em> of a well-watered place, referring to where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of strain WPCB173<sup>T</sup> are Gram-reaction-variable, motile, rod-shaped, 0.4–0.6×2–5 μm and occur singularly or in chains.</s><s>Produces ellipsoidal endospores that lie in the subterminal position and usually cause the sporangia to swell.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA plates for 2 days at 30 °C are circular, ∼1 mm in diameter, opaque, cream, convex and have entire margins.</s><s>Does not grow under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Grows at 15–37 °C (optimum 30 °C), pH 5–8 (optimum pH 6–7) and in up to 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Starch and Tween 20 are hydrolysed but carboxymethyl cellulose, casein, DNA, egg yolk, gelatin, Tween 80, l-tyrosine and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, positive for nitrate reduction, fermentation of d-glucose, aesculin hydrolysis (<em>β</em>-glucosidase), <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and malic acid, but negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis and urease activities and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and leucine arylamidase activities are present and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are weakly active.</s><s>In the Biolog GP2 Microplate (Biolog) system, the following substrates are assimilated: dextrin, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, melibiose, palatinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, monomethyl succinate and pyruvic acid; the following substrates are weakly assimilated: glycogen, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-xylose, acetic acid and methyl pyruvate; other substrates are not assimilated.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (<em>μ</em>g per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin (10 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), streptomycin (10) tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>The diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WPCB173<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13282<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16352<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from freshwater collected from the Woopo wetland, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>