<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1762_nm.9557" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9557" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9557" rank="species">Prevotella marshii</organism><reference id="rid.1762"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutcliffe</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella marshii sp. nov. and Prevotella baroniae sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1551</fpage><lpage>1555</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63634-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella marshii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella marshii</em> (mar′shi.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>marshii</em> of Marsh, named in honour of British microbiologist Philip Marsh, for his contributions to oral microbiology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on five strains isolated from the human oral cavity.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, Gram-negative bacilli (0·4×0·9–3 μm) occurring singly and in pairs with an occasional elongated cell up to 6 μm long.</s><s>After 5 days incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 1·8–3·5 mm in diameter, circular and entire, convex, watery, opaque and grey to off-white/grey to greenish grey.</s><s>Areas of heavier growth at the end of the streak lines on FAA are cream in colour.</s><s>Viewed under a plate microscope the colonies have a striated appearance with concentric rings of varying opacity and iridescent hues of pink, green and yellow.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces moderate turbidity that is markedly enhanced by the addition of glucose, fructose or maltose.</s><s>Cells are saccharolytic and ferment glucose and maltose strongly and fructose and mannose weakly and variably.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose are not fermented.</s><s>Major amounts of acetic acid and succinic acid and moderate amounts of propionic acid are produced as end-products of metabolism in PYG broth.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed; aesculin, arginine and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The Rapid ID 32A profile is 0400 4442 0 <sup>0</sup>/<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The fatty acid profile predominantly comprises anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 51 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the human oral cavity in subjects with endodontic and periodontal infections and from subgingival dental plaque in healthy subjects.</s><s>The type strain is E9.34<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16973<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 50419<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>