<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.2740" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2740" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2740" rank="species">Rhizobacter dauci</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Rhizobacter dauci</em> Goto and Kuwata 1988</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The emended description is based on the original description of Goto &#x0026; Kuwata (1988) supplemented with our own data.</s><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.9–1.3×2.1–2.5 μm, with rounded ends.</s><s>Usually, a small number of cells in a population are motile with polar flagella or lateral flagella or both.</s><s>Pseudo-oligotrophic.</s><s>Forms tough, white, plicated colonies on potato-peptone-glucose agar plates, but yellowish-white colonies on diluted yeast extract-peptone-glucose agar plates.</s><s>Forms copious flocs consisting of globular cell aggregates in liquid media.</s><s>Aerobic with respiratory metabolism of glucose.</s><s>Positive for production of urease, lipase (Tween 80), lecithinase, H<sub>2</sub>S formation from cysteine, nitrate reduction (negative according to API 20NE), the <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>O</em>-d-galactopyranoside test, hydrolysis of aesculin, pit formation on pectate gels at pH 7.0, susceptibility to 10 μg of the vibriostatic agent O/129 phosphate (Sigma) and growth inhibition by KCN.</s><s>Weakly positive in gelatin liquefaction tests.</s><s>Negative for denitrification, the gluconate test, the methyl red test, casein hydrolysis and production of arginine dihydrolase, nitrogenase, acetoin, indole, fluorescent pigment and 3-ketolactose.</s><s>Maximum NaCl tolerance is 0.7 %.</s><s>Does not require growth factors.</s><s>Can utilize as sole carbon sources l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-sorbitol, glycogen, starch, dextrin, monomethyl succinate, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, adonitol, salicin, galacturonate and <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid.</s><s>Cannot utilize as carbon sources trehalose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, erythritol, acetate, citrate, dl-lactate, malonate or benzoate.</s><s>Additional reactions are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile of the type strain is listed in Supplementary Table S1.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66.9–70.6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>Occurs in soil.</s><s>Plant pathogen causing galls on carrot roots in nature.</s><s>The tobacco hypersensitivity reaction is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain H6<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 43778<sup>T</sup> =DSM 11587<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>