<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1462_nm.2777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2777" rank="species">Acinetobacter radioresistens</organism><reference id="rid.1462"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ino</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iizuka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acinetobacter radioresistens sp. nov. isolated from cotton and soil.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>209</fpage><lpage>211</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-2-209</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acinetobacter radioresistens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acinetobacter radioresistens</i> (ra.di.o.re.sis'tens. L. n. <i>radius</i> ray, beam; L. part. adj. <i>resistens</i> resisting; M.L. part. adj. <i>radioresistens</i> ray resisting, because of high resistance to gamma-ray irradiation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods 0.6 to 0.7 by 0.8 to 1.0 μm.</s><s>Pleomorphic.</s><s>A plump form is 0.8 to 0.9 by 1.2 to 1.8 μm; elongate cells (15 μm or more long) occur in young cultures; and coccoid cells (0.6 to 0.9 μm in diameter) occur in old cultures.</s><s>The cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Nonsporeforming, noncapsulated, nonmotile, non-acid fast, gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, entire, convex, glistening, opaque, and yellowish white to pale yellow.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A pellicle is formed on the surface of nutrient broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite in succinate-nitrate medium but not in Casitonenitrate medium.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxydase, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, and urease are not produced.</s><s>Hemolysis on sheep blood agar is negative.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium containing 5% NaCl.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 27 to 31°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 42°C.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-glUCOSe, D-fructose, D-mannose , L-rhamnose, D-glucosamine, D-cellobiose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, and raffinose are not oxidized and not assimilated.</s><s>Acetate, fumarate, DL-lactate, L-malate, malonate, succinate, hexadecane, heptadecane, octadecane, eicosane, ethanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, L-alanine, L-glutamate, L-leucine, and L-proline are assimilated.</s><s>Citrate, gluconate, decane, nonadecane, methanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, isopropanol, ethanolamine, <i>p</i>-alanine, DL-phenylalanine, L-histidine, L-isoleucine , DL-norleucine, DL-serine, L-threonine, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, and sorbitol are not assimilated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Highly resistant to gamma-ray irradiation (D<sub>10</sub> value, 125 to 220 krads under air equilibrium in 0.067 M phosphate buffer).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to benzylpenicillin (100 IU).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base compositions range from 44.1 to 44.8 mol% guanine plus cytosine (as determined by the thermal melting temperature of the DNA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are the even-numbered straight-chain acids C<sub>18:1</sub>, C<sub>16:1</sub>, and C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ubiquinone system is Q-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain FO-1 (= IAM 13186), which was isolated from cotton.</s><s>Two strains, G82012 (= IAM 13187) and G82076 (= IAM 13188), were isolated from soils.</s></p></content></protolog>