<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3885_nm.9740" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9740" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9740" rank="species">Palleronia marisminoris</organism><reference id="rid.3885"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Cánovas</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Palleronia marisminoris gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium belonging to the 'Alphaproteobacteria', isolated from a saline soil.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2525</fpage><lpage>2530</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63906-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280521</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Palleronia marisminoris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Palleronia marisminoris</em> (ma′ris.min.or.is. L. sb. n. gen. <em>maris</em> of the sea; L. adj. n. gen. <em>minoris</em> smaller; L. adj. <em>marisminoris</em> of the smaller sea, i.e. from el Mar Menor, a shallow area of sea highly sheltered from the Mediterranean sea on the south-eastern coast of Spain, from whence the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the traits reported for the genus, the species grows on MY solid medium in the form of circular, convex, pink, mucoid colonies.</s><s>In liquid medium its growth pattern is uniform.</s><s>The cells are encapsulated.</s><s>It is moderately halophilic, capable of growing in salt concentrations (mixture of sea salts) from 0·5 to 15 % w/v.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 5 % w/v sea salt.</s><s>It cannot grow with NaCl as the sole salt.</s><s>Minimum salt requirements are 0·66 M Na<sup>+</sup>, 0·1 M Mg<sup>2+</sup> and 0·01 M K<sup>+</sup>.</s><s>It grows within the temperature range of 20 to 37 °C and at pH values of between 5 and 10.</s><s>It produces H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Selenite reduction and phosphatase tests are positive.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed.</s><s>It does not produce acids from the following sugars and related compounds: adonitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose and d-trehalose.</s><s>ONPG is positive.</s><s>O/F, indole, methyl-red, Voges–Proskauer and gluconate oxidation are negative.</s><s>Phenylalanine deaminase is not produced.</s><s>Urea, tyrosine, Tween 80, starch, aesculin, gelatin, DNA, lecithin and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Growth on either MacConkey or cetrimide agar is inviable.</s><s>Blood is not lysed.</s><s>Neither nitrate nor nitrite is reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are not acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, glucose, galactose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-salicin, trehalose, acetate, citrate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, lactate, malonate, propionate, succinate, adonitol, ethanol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol and sorbose.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, l-cysteine, d-histidine, isoleucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>It is susceptible to (μg) amoxicillin (25), ampicillin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefotaxime (30), cefoxitin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), streptomycin (10), nitrofurantoin (300), rifampicin (30) and tobramycin (10) and is resistant to nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300) sulfonamide (250) and trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1·25/23·7).</s><s>The major fatty acids are: 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (68·9 %), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (12·8 %), 3-hydroxy 10 : 0 (5 %), 16 : 0 (4·2 %), 18 : 0 (3·4 %).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 64·2 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain B33<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7066<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22959<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hypersaline soil bordering a solar saltern in Marchamalo (Murcia, south-eastern Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>