<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2757_nm.4409" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4409" rank="species">Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus</organism><reference id="rid.2757"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leuteritz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidel-Rüfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of anaerobic, gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria from breweries: emended description of Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus and description of Pectinatus frisingensis sp. nov., Selenomonas lacticifex sp. nov., Zymophilus raffinosivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., and Zymophilus paucivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-19</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1699594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The emended description below of <i>Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus</i> is based on the descriptions given by Lee et al. (16) and by Moore (personal communication) and our results. Cells are gram-negative, slightly curved rods that are 0.7 to 0.9 μm in diameter and 2 to 30 μm or more long. They occur singly, in pairs, and only rarely in short chains. The occurrence of longer, helical filaments is characteristic for older cells. The cells are usually motile. These organisms are obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming mesophiles. Flagella emanate from only one side of the cell (comblike). They do not produce catalase and cytochromes. Colonies are circular, entire, beige to white, glistening, and opaque. The optimum temperature for growth is 30°C. Glucose is fermented to acetic and propionic acids. In contrasts to the original description given by Lee et al. (16), both Moore (for the type strain) and we (also for other strains) found that xylose and melibiose are fermented, whereas maltose and cellobiose are not. Cadaverine and putrescine are found as characteristic components of the cell wall peptidoglycan type, directly cross-linked <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid. Lipid F is also found as a characteristic cellular compound. The G+C content of the DNA is 38 to 41 mol%. The type strain is strain ATCC 29359 (= DSM 20467). The phenotypic properties of the type strain are shown in Table 1</s></p></content></protolog>