<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3703_nm.10258" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10258" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10258" rank="species">Gillisia myxillae</organism><reference id="rid.3703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>O.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>S.C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plakhotnikova</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobretsov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gillisia myxillae sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from the marine sponge Myxilla incrustans</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1795</fpage><lpage>1799</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64345-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902010</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gillisia myxillae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gillisia myxillae</em> (my.xil′lae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Myxilla</em> systematic name of a genus of sponges; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>myxillae</em> from <em>Myxilla</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the sponge <em>Myxilla incrustans</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (1.3–2.0 μm in length and 0.5 μm in width), strictly aerobic, devoid of gliding and flagellar motility.</s><s>Upon cultivation on marine agar, colonies are yellow in colour, 2–4 mm in diameter, circular and convex with a smooth surface and an entire edge.</s><s>Does not produce flexirubin-type or diffusible pigments.</s><s>MK-6 is the only respiratory quinone.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 5.0 and 10.0 (pH 7.0–9.0 optimum) and between 4.0 and 28.0 °C (12.0–20.0 °C optimum), but not at 36.0 °C or higher.</s><s>Requires NaCl (2.0–10.0 %; 4.0–6.0 % optimum) for growth.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are i15 : 0, a15 : 0, i15 : 1, i16 : 0, i17 : 0 3-OH, 17 : 0 2-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), together representing 69.0 % of the total.</s><s>Susceptible to benzylpenicillin (1.0 μg), chloramphenicol (1.0 μg), ampicillin (1.0 μg) and tetracycline (10.0 μg), but resistant to streptomycin and kanamycin (tested up to 100.0 μg).</s><s>Acetoin, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Casein, starch, and Tweens 20 and 40 are degraded, but agar, Tween 80, chitin and carboxymethylcellulose are not.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, DNase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and tryptophan deaminase activities.</s><s>Negative for gelatinase, urease, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Utilization of glycerol, d-glucose, sucrose, d-mannitol, d-galactose, starch, d-sorbitol, d-arabinose and d-melibiose as sole carbon sources is observed on agar medium supplemented with 4 % (w/v) carbon source and utilization of d-galacturonic acid, l-proline and putrescine is observed in the MicroLog 3 system.</s><s>However, none of the carbon sources included in the API 20NE and 50CH systems are utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-maltose, starch and glycogen in the API 50CH system, but no acid production is observed from the carbon sources in the API 20E system.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UST050418-085<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13546<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-41416<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the surface of the marine sponge <em>Myxilla incrustans</em> at Friday Harbor, San Juan Island, WA, USA.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain UST050418-085<sup>T</sup> is 34.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>