<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.268_nm.4230" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4230" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4230" rank="species">Eubacterium acidaminophilum</organism><reference id="rid.268"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zindel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freudenberg</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rieth</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andreesen</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schnell</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Widdel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium acidaminophilum sp. nov., a versatile amino acid-degrading anaerobe producing or utilizing H2 or formate.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>150</volume><fpage>254</fpage><lpage>266</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00407789</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium acidaminophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium acidaminophilum</i> (a.cid.a.mi.no'phi.lum. M.L.n. <i>acidum</i> acid; M.L.pref. <i>amino</i> amino group containing; M.L. suff. neutr. <i>philum</i> from Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving. <i>Eubacterium acidaminophilum</i> loving amino acids)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells 0.7 to 1.0 x 1.3 to 6 μm, mostly with pointed ends, usually single, sometimes in chains; slow tumbling motility by means of a subpolar to polar flagellum.</s><s>Gram reaction positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fast growth (doubling time about 1 h) occurs by fermentation of glycine to acetate, ammonia and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Glycylglycine, glycylglycylglycine, N-carbamoylglycine, hydantoin, the glycine moiety of hippurate and glutathione, serine and pyruvate are fermented, too.</s><s>Glycine derivatives such as betaine, sarcosine, and creatine serve as substrates only in the presence of an electron donor like formate.</s><s>Pure cultures grow very poorly by fermentation of alanine or aspartate to acetate, ammonia, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Good growth on alanine or aspartate occurs in co-cultures with H<sub>2</sub>-utilizing sulfate-reducing, methanogenic or homoacetogenic bacteria.</s><s>Valine, leucine and malate are also oxidized by the co-cultures or in the presence of an electron-accepting substrate.</s><s>Glutamate, glucose and fructose are not fermented.</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfur and nitrate are not used as electron acceptors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows in defined sulfide-reduced, bicarbonate-buffered media with biotin as a vitamin.</s><s>NaCl concentrations higher than approximately 30 g/1 are inhibitory.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selenite (≥0.1 μM) is required for growth on glycine, betaine, sarcosine or creatine, but not on other substrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range 10- 40 °C, optimum at 32- 36 °C; pH range 6.5-8.5, optimum 7.1-7.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio: 44.0 mol % guanine plus cytosine (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: Black, anaerobic mud.</s><s>Enrichment possible with alanine at low H<sub>2</sub> partial pressure, e.g. in the presence of sulfate and <i>Desulfovibrio vulgaris</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adverse effects on animals and humans are not known; because of the ability of <i>E. acidaminophilum</i> to ferment amino acids and peptides, the possibility of harmful effects cannot be excluded.</s><s>Cautious handling and autoclaving of cultures before disposal is recommended.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: al-2, deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, Federal Republic of Germany, under DSM no. 3953.</s></p></content></protolog>