<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8259_nm.286" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.286" rank="genus">Haloarcula</organism><reference id="rid.8259"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended descriptions of genera of the family Halobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>637</fpage><lpage>642</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008904-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Haloarcula</em> Torreblanca <em>et al.</em> 1986, 573<sup>VP</sup></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloarcula</em> [Ha.lo.ar′cu.la. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> the sea, salt; L. fem. n. <em>arcula</em> small box; N.L. fem. n. <em>Haloarcula</em> salt (-requiring) small box].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Effective publication: Torreblanca, Rodriguez-Valera, Juez, Ventosa, Kamekura &#x0026; Kates 1986, 98.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This emended description is based on the genus description by Torreblanca <em>et al.</em> (1986) and emendations based on Juez <em>et al.</em> (1986), Takashina <em>et al.</em> (1990), Ihara <em>et al.</em> (1997), Oren <em>et al.</em> (1999) and Yang <em>et al.</em> (2007).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short pleomorphic rods, with shapes ranging from almost regular rods to triangular and irregular shapes under optimal growth conditions, 0.2–1×2–5 μm, and stain Gram-negative.</s><s>Most species are motile.</s><s>Colonies are red or pink due to the presence of bacterioruberin carotenoids; retinal pigments may be present as well.</s><s>Pigmentation does not vary with the salt concentration of the medium.</s><s>Cells lyse in distilled water.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Extremely halophilic, with growth occurring in media containing 2–5.2 M NaCl; most strains grow best at 2.5–3.5 M NaCl.</s><s>The optimum magnesium concentration varies between 0.005 and 0.1 M.</s><s>Temperatures between 20 and 55 °C and pH between 6.5 and 9 may support growth.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic; amino acids are not required for growth.</s><s>Grow by aerobic respiration; some grow by anaerobic respiration in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>All species reduce nitrate to nitrite and produce acid from sugars.</s><s>A wide range of substrates can be used as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Most are lipolytic (Tween 40) and produce H<sub>2</sub>S from cysteine.</s><s>The major polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> glycerol diether derivatives of PG, Me-PGP, PGS and TGD-2 (1-<em>O</em>-[<em>β</em>-d-glucose-(1′→6′)-<em>α</em>-d-mannose-(1′→2′)-<em>α</em>-d-glucose]-2,3-di-<em>O</em>-phytanyl-<em>sn</em>-glycerol).</s><s>All species have at least two different copies of the 16S rRNA gene.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is between 60.1 and 65 mol%.</s><s>The DNA may contain a major and a minor component.</s><s>Isolated from solar salterns and salt lakes.</s><s>The type species is <em>Haloarcula vallismortis.</em></s></p></content></protolog>