<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.310_nm.4052" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4052" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4052" rank="species">Clostridium viride</organism><reference id="rid.310"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Buckel</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuhmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eikmanns</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Messner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sleytr</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium viride sp. nov., a strictly anaerobic bacterium using 5-aminovalerate as growth substrate, previously assigned to Clostridium aminovalericum.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>162</volume><fpage>387</fpage><lpage>394</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00282102</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium viride</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium viride</i> (vi'ri.de. L. adj. <i>viridis</i>, <i>e</i> green, greenish; in reference to the green-colored cells and green FAD-containing enzymes of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are gram-positive pointed-ended to oval rods, 0.8 μm wide and 1.2-1.5 μm long, and are motile by two subpolarly inserted flagella.</s><s>The center-to-center spacing of the hexagonally arranged S-layer lattice is 18.5 nm.</s><s>Cell pellets are yellowish-green in color.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is supported by 5-aminovalerate (fermented to acetate, propionate, valerate, and ammonia), 5-hydroxyvalerate (fermented to acetate, propionate, and valerate), and crotonate, vinylacetate, and 4-hydroxybutyrate (fermented to acetate and butyrate).</s><s>No significant hydrogen production occurs on 5-aminovalerate.</s><s>The following substrates do not support growth (D-isomers of sugars and L-isomers of organic and amino acids were tested unless noted otherwise; substrates marked with an asterisk were also tested in the presence of 2 mM acetate): H<sub>2</sub>* (excess), glucose, fructose, galactose, ribose, xylose, arabinose, melibiose, mannose (all 4 mM), cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, lactose (all 2 mM), cellulose, starch, pectin (all at 1 g⋄l<sup>-1</sup>), formate*, pyruvate, lactate, succinate, malate, fumarate, glycerol*, mannitol, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, tartrate, 1,2-propanediol* (all 20 mM), acrylate, citrate (both 10 mM), betaine, alanine, β-alanine, aspartate, norvaline, 2-aminobutyrate, 4-aminobutyrate, 6-aminocaproate, glutamate, isoleucine, arginine, proline, urea, valine (all 20 mM), leucine (15mM), tryptophan (5mM), trypticase, yeast extract, and casamino acids (all 1 g⋄l<sup>-1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate, sulphate, amorphous ferric hydroxide, and fumarate are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Sulphur is reduced to sulphide at the expense of valerate production, but this is neither linked to energy conservation, nor does it stop reductive valerate formation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>5-Aminovalerate is metabolized via 2,4-pentadienoyl-CoA and 2-pentenoyl-CoA by a pathway involving at least two FAD-containing enzymes that form green crystals.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic conditions are required for growth.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Indole is not formed from L-tryptophan.</s><s>Urea, aesculin, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Growth is possible at 40°C but not at 44°C Both yeast extract and L-cysteine are required for growth on 5-aminovalerate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C ratio of the DNA is 41.5 mol%.</s><s>16S rRNA analysis shows that strain T2-7 forms a distinct lineage within a phylogenetically coherent cluster of <i>Clostridium</i> spp. not related to Group I.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is T2-7 (DSM 6836), isolated from anaerobic sewage sludge.</s></p></content></protolog>