<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7164_nm.2052" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2052" rank="genus">Thauera</organism><reference id="rid.7164"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macy</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rech</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Auling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thauera selenatis gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the beta subclass of Proteobacteria with a novel type of anaerobic respiration.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>135</fpage><lpage>142</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-135</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8427805</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Thauera</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thauera</i> (Thau'e-ra. N. L. fem. n. <i>Thauera</i>, in honor of R. Thauer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells are 1.4 μm long by 0.56 μm wide, have rounded ends, and contain poly-β-hydroxybutyrate inclusions.</s><s>Cells are motile, and each cell has a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-8.</s><s>Grows aerobically in defined media containing acetate as the carbon source and electron donor.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions exhibits anaerobic respiration with selenate or nitrate as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to N<sub>2</sub>O.</s><s>Selenate is reduced to selenite.</s><s>Acetate is metabolized to C02.</s><s>Growth is also supported by the carbon and energy sources alanine, arginine, aspartate, benzoate, D-amino-N-butyrate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, isobutyrate, citrate, fructose, glutamate, lactate, lactose, proline, propionate, pyruvate, serine, succinate, and sucrose.</s><s>Less vigorous growth occurs with glucose.</s><s>No growth occurs on nutrient agar (Difco).</s><s>Vitamins are required for growth in defined media.</s><s>Colonies are small, round with entire edges, convex, adherent, and light brown.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25 to 30°C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth with nitrate is pH 8, and the optimal pH for growth with selenate is pH 7.</s><s>Grows autotrophically with hydrogen, carbon dioxide, and air.</s><s>Unable to fix dinitrogen.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is absent.</s><s>The major polyamines are putrescine and 2-hydroxyputrescine.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus is a member of the beta subclass of the Proteobacteria.</s><s>The base composition of the DNA of the type strain of the type species is 66 mol% G+C (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type species is <i>Thauera selenatis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>