<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2869_nm.2305" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2305" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2305" rank="subspecies">Francisella tularensis tularensis</organism><reference id="rid.2869"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Olsufjev</surname><given-names>N.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meshcheryakova</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Subspecific taxonomy of Francisella tularensis McCoy and Chapin 1912</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>872</fpage><lpage>874</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Francisella tularensis</i> subsp. <i>tularensis</i> (McCoy and Chapin) subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The synonyms of <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>tularensis</i> are the nearctic subspecies (8), kind A of Jellison et al. (3), and <i>F. tularensis</i> subsp. <i>nearctica</i> of Olsufjev (6). In changing the rank of this taxon from variety to subspecies (6), Olsufjev substituted the epithet <i>nearctica</i> for the epithet <i>tularensis</i>. However, this substitution infringes upon Rule 40 of the Bacteriological Code; therefore, we rehabilitate the epithet <i>tularensis</i> in this paper.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology and principal characteristics are as described previously for the species (11).</s><s>The strains of this subspecies ferment glycerol, glucose, maltose, and citrulline; they are highly susceptible to erythromycin, as well as to other macrolide antibiotics and lincomycin.</s><s>This subspecies is highly pathogenic for domestic rabbits (subcutaneous infection with a single cell or a few cells is always lethal) and for humans (untreated cases of cutaneous infection have 5 to 6% mortality).</s><s>Cross-immunity studies have demonstrated that animals infected with the holarctic strain are not adequately protected from the nearctic strain (7).</s><s>Gas-liquid chromatography has revealed the presence of fatty acids in moderate quantities (C<sub>14:0</sub>, 6.5 to 7.7%) and the presence of a higher level of C<sub>24:0</sub> acid (12 to 16%) than in the holarctic subspecies (9).</s><s>The antigenic substances contain more hexosamine (6 to 12%) than they do in the holarctic subspecies (5 to 7%) (13).</s><s>The nearctic subspecies is found only in North America (United States, Canada) and is found more often than the holarctic subspecies (biovar I Ery<sup>S</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distribution of this causative agent of tularemia in nature is mainly by <i>Lagomorpha</i> and ticks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. tularensis</i> is strain B-38 (= ATCC 6223), but strain B-38 is completely avirulent.</s><s>Hence, this strain has lost one of the most important properties of the species, and so we propose a type strain for the subspecies, strain Schu. (All type and reference strains mentioned in this paper have been deposited in the live culture museum of the Tularemia Laboratory, Gamaleya Institute of Epidemiology and Microbiology [GIEM], Academy of Medical Sciences, Moscow, Union of Soviet Socialist Republics [USSR].) This strain was isolated in 1941 in the United States by Foshay from humans.</s><s>It is highly virulent and is used in many laboratories throughout the world.</s></p></content></protolog>