<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9922_nm.14889" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14889" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14889" rank="species">Actinocatenispora rupis</organism><reference id="rid.9922"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinocatenispora rupis sp. nov., isolated from cliff soil, and emended description of the genus Actinocatenispora</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3078</fpage><lpage>3082</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012922-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643893</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinocatenispora rupis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinocatenispora rupis</em> (ru′pis. L. gen. n. <em>rupis</em> of a cliff, referring to the site from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-staining-positive, catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium is well developed and pale to strong yellow in colour.</s><s>Spore chains are borne on rudimentary aerial mycelium.</s><s>The spores are smooth-surfaced and cylindrical (0.4–0.5×0.9–1.6 μm).</s><s>Hyphal swellings are observed on the tips of the vegetative mycelium.</s><s>Soluble pigments are not produced on any of the tested media.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25–42 °C (optimum 37 °C) and pH 5.1–12.1 (optimum pH 5.1–9.1).</s><s>Tolerates up to 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Degrades DNA, elastin, aesculin, casein, Tween 80 and chitin, but not cellulose, starch, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea or xanthine.</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, dextran, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, adonitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-sorbitol and citrate as sole carbon sources, but not inulin, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, salicin, l-sorbose, dulcitol, d-xylitol, acetate, benzoate, formate, malate, succinate or tartrate.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Other physiological properties are given in Table 1.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>The whole-cell sugars are glucose, rhamnose, ribose, arabinose and xylose.</s><s>The diagnostic polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> G.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 74.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CS5-AC17<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45178<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24660<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil taken from a cliff on Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>