<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2372_nm.7434" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7434" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7434" rank="species">Streptosporangium carneum</organism><reference id="rid.2372"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptosporangium carneum sp. nov. isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>247</fpage><lpage>253</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptosporangium carneum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptosporangium carneum</i> (car. ne' um. L. adj. <i>carneum</i>, flesh colored, referring to the color of the aerial spore mass)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are nonmotile, filamentous, and differentiated into substrate and aerial hyphae.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are predominantly light yellowish pink, and the vegetative mycelium is orange.</s><s>A light brown soluble pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>Aerial hyphae bear sporangia containing large, oval, nonmotile spores.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, mannose, and trehalose; no acid is produced from adonitol, D- and L-arabinose, cellulose, dextrin, dulcitol, ethanol, erythritol, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, amethyl- D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, xylitol, and D-xylose.</s><s>Assimilates acetate and pyruvate; does not assimilate benzoate, butyrate, citrate, formate, lactate, malate, mucate, oxalate, propionate, succinate, or tartrate.</s><s>Casein, hippurate, testosterone, and tyrosine are hydrolyzed or degraded; adenine, allantoin, calcium malate, elastin, esculin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, urea, and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Catalase, phosphatase, and hydrogen sulfide are produced.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not produced; gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Milk is neither hydrolyzed nor peptonized.</s><s>Unable to survive a temperature of 50°C for 8 h.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2% sodium chloride.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 37°C.</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin, cephalothin, gentamicin, lincomycin, penicillin, streptomycin, tetracycline, and tobramycin.</s><s>Susceptible to neomycin, oleandomycin, rifampin, vancomycin, and lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain A84575 (= NRRL 18437).</s><s>This strain was isolated from soil collected by the Tana River in Nairobi, Kenya.</s></p></content></protolog>