<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9919_nm.14886" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14886" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14886" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora tripterygii</organism><reference id="rid.9919"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora tripterygii sp. nov., an endophytic actinomycete isolated from the stem of Tripterygium hypoglaucum</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3040</fpage><lpage>3044</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011734-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643898</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharopolyspora tripterygii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharopolyspora tripterygii</em> (trip.te.ry′gi.i. N.L. n. <em>Tripterygium</em> a botanical genus name; N.L. gen. n. <em>tripterygii</em> of <em>Tripterygium</em>, the plant genus from which this species was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms extensively branched substrate mycelia and aerial mycelia differentiate into long spore chains.</s><s>Spores are elliptical or short rods (0.5–0.8×1.0–1.5 μm).</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are white, vegetative mycelia are orange–yellow.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is up to 12 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Negative for the production of H<sub>2</sub>S and melanin, for nitrate reduction and for milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Urea and Tweens 20 and 40 are hydrolysed, but Tween 80, cellulose, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-ribose, sodium acetate, trisodium citrate and d-xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin and aesculin.</s><s>Cellobiose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sodium oxalate, d-sorbitol and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>Adenine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-hydroxyproline, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tyrosine and l-valine can be used as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-alanine, glycine or xanthine.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid in the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Arabinose, galactose, glucose and ribose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and one unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 65359<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208062<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45269<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface-sterilized stem sample of <em>Tripterygium hypoglaucum</em> collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 70.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>