<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.664_nm.8718" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8718" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8718" rank="species">Mycobacterium nebraskense</organism><reference id="rid.664"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mohamed</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwen</surname><given-names>P.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tarantolo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinrichs</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium nebraskense sp. nov., a novel slowly growing scotochromogenic species</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2057</fpage><lpage>2060</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63126-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545434</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium nebraskense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium nebraskense</em> (ne.bras.ken′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>nebraskense</em> referring to the State of Nebraska, USA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming rods that stain acid-fast-positive.</s><s>Mature growth is produced in 3 weeks on Middlebrook 7H11 medium and in 4 or more weeks on LJ medium at 25–35 °C, with optimal growth at 30–35 °C and no growth at 42 °C.</s><s>Mature colonies are rough with an elevated centre and produce strong yellow pigmentation in the dark.</s><s>The organism is positive for heat-stable catalase and negative for nitrate reductase, urease activity, niacin accumulation, arylsulfatase activity at 3 days and pyrazinamidase production.</s><s>Less than 45 mm foam is produced in the semi-quantitative catalase test and variable results are indicated for Tween 80 hydrolysis.</s><s>Growth is inhibited on MacConkey agar without crystal violet and by the addition of 5 % NaCl to the culture medium.</s><s>Exhibits a unique mycolic acid profile by HPLC analysis characterized by a widely separated double peak clusters pattern that is typical for genus <em>Mycobacterium</em>.</s><s>Genetically, the organism has unique <em>Mycobacterium</em> sequences for the 16S rRNA gene and ITS1 region targets.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis using 16S rRNA gene sequences shows that <em>M. nebraskense</em> belongs to the slowly growing mycobacteria and is closely related to <em>M. kansasii</em>, <em>M. scrofulaceum</em>, <em>Mycobacterium malmoense</em> and <em>M. avium</em>.</s><s>The sequences of the 16S rRNA gene (AY368456) and the partial ITS1 region (AY368458) of the type strain have been deposited in GenBank.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human sputum in Nebraska, USA.</s><s>The type strain is UNMC-MY1349<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-837<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44803<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>