<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7099_nm.6411" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6411" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6411" rank="species">Mycobacterium tusciae</organism><reference id="rid.7099"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bartoloni</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caroli</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jan</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawlowski</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Emler</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium tusciae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1839</fpage><lpage>1844</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1839</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555367</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium tusciae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium tusciae</i> (tu'sci.ae. L. gen. n. <i>tusciae</i> referring to the Italian region of Tuscany, where all the organisms were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are alcohol-acid-fast and rod-shaped.</s><s>At temperatures between 25 and 32°C, scotochromogenic colonies grow in about 4 weeks on Lowenstein-Jensen medium.</s><s>Growth at 37°C is inconsistent and requires a longer incubation, while no growth occurs at 42°C.</s><s>Colonies are rough and strongly yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Their early microscopic morphology on Middlebrook 7H11 agar is characterized by a very elevated centre surrounded by an uneven flat fringe.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reductase, heat-stable catalase, Tween 80 hydrolysis after 10 d incubation, arylsulfatase after 14 but not after 3 d incubation and urease, but negative for niacin and β-glucosidase. <i>M. tusciae</i> produces less than 45 mm of foam in a semi-quantitative catalase test.</s><s>Growth is inhibited on MacConkey agar and by addition to the culture medium of sodium chloride, <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoate, hydroxylamine, isoniazid or oleate, but not by thiophene-2-carboxylic acid or thiacetazone.</s><s>The strain is susceptible to ciprofloxacin, clarithromycin, rifabutin, rifampicin, sparfloxacin and streptomycin.</s><s>Lipid composition is characterized by the presence of a- and ketomycolates and wax esters.</s><s>The HPLC profile of mycolic acid bromophenacyl esters is unique.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is composed of hexadecanoic acid (30%), hexadecenoic acids (9%), octadecanoic acid (2%)o, ctadecenoic acids (22%) and tuberculostearic acid (10%).</s><s>Two alcohols, C<sub>18:0</sub> (11%) and C<sub>20:0</sub> (8%) are also found.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66.4 mol%.The 16s rDNA sequence demonstrates that strains FI-25796<sup>T</sup>, FI- 24797 and FI-27697 belong to a novel species phylogenetically related to <i>M. aichiense</i> and <i>M. farcinogenes</i>, with characteristics of a fast-growing mycobacterium; the signature sequence within region A is characteristic of <i>M. tusciae</i>, however.</s><s>Strain FI-25796<sup>T</sup> is the type strain of <i>Mycobacterium tusciae</i> and has been deposited in the DSMZ as strain DSM 44338<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>