<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6649_nm.1835" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1835" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1835" rank="species">Xenophilus azovorans</organism><reference id="rid.6649"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Blümel</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stolz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Xenophilus azovorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a soil bacterium that is able to degrade azo dyes of the Orange II type.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1831</fpage><lpage>1837</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594616</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xenophilus azovorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xenophilus azovorans</i> (a.zo.vo'rans. N.L. neut. <i>azo</i> from azo compounds; L. v. <i>vorare</i> to devour; N.L. part. adj. <i>azovorans</i> azo-devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as that given above for the genus.</s><s>On nutrient agar, colonies are circular, opaque, slightly raised and pale-yellowish with entire margins.</s><s>Colonies are often not detectable as single entities because of the production of extracellular slimy substances.</s><s>The type strain grows at 30 °C; no growth is found at 4, 37 or 42 °C.</s><s>L-Alanine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide and 2-deoxythymidine 2'-<i>p</i>-nitrophenylphosphate are hydrolysed.</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucuronide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl α-D-glucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-xylopyranoside, bis-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate, bis-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phenylphosphonate, bis-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphorylcholine, L-aniline <i>p</i>-nitroanilide, c-L-glutamate <i>p</i>-nitroanilide and L-proline <i>p</i>-nitroanilide.</s><s>No acid production can be detected from the following sugars: glucose, lactose, sucrose, D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, D-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl D-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, D-arabitol and D-mannose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon: glycerol, D-fructose, D-mannitol, maltitol, acetate, propionate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dL-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, L-aspartate, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-proline, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and 4-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: N-acetylgalactosamine, N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabinose, L-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, D-maltose, D-mannose, α-D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, putrescine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, mesaconate, L-alanine, β-alanine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-serine and phenylacetate.</s><s>The major non-polar fatty acids are 16:0, summed feature 4 (16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> and iso 15:0 2-OH) and summed feature 7 (18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 18:1<i>ω</i>9<i>t</i> and}or 18:1<i>ω</i>12<i>t</i>).</s><s>In addition, 8:0 3-OH, 10:0 3-OH, 16:0 2-OH, 16:1 2-OH, 18:1 2-OH and 17:0 cyclo are detected in significant amounts.</s><s>The type strain is strain KF46F<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13620<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13707<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain KF46F<sup>T</sup> was isolated from soil after continuous enrichment with 1-(4'-carboxyphenylazo)-2-naphthol.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence has been deposited in the EMBL database under the accession number AF285414.</s></p></content></protolog>