<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6933_nm.1298" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1298" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1298" rank="species">Rhizobium mongolense</organism><reference id="rid.6933"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Berkum</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beyene</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eardly</surname><given-names>B.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium mongolense sp. nov. is one of three rhizobial genotypes identified which nodulate and form nitrogen-fixing symbioses with Medicago ruthenica [(L.) Ledebour]</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>13</fpage><lpage>22</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-13</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542071</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium mongolense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium mongolense</i> (mŏng'ga.len'se. L. adj. <i>mongolense</i> referring to Inner Mongolia, the region in the People's Republic of China from where the bacteria originated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic non-spore-forming rods which are motile by a single polar or sub-polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MAG are circular, elevated, white opaque, appearing in 3-5 d at 30 °C when they are 1-3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Bacteria produce acid on YEM.</s><s>Growth on YEM is inhibited between 0 and 1% NaCl and below pH 4.0.</s><s>Strains are generally resistant to bacitracin, cefuperazone and penicillin G, utilize sodium acetate, fructose, sodium malate and maltose as sole carbon substrates for growth, and utilize arginine and lysine as sole nitrogen substrates for growth.</s><s>Strains were isolated from nodules of <i>Medicago ruthenica</i>, which is native to open hillsides, mixed grass steppes and meadows of <i>Siberia</i>, <i>Mongolia</i> and <i>Manchuria</i>.</s><s>The strains nodulate <i>Medicago ruthenica</i> and <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i>.</s><s>The strains can be distinguished by SSU rRNA gene sequences, by DNA homology and by distinctive multilocus electrophoretic types.</s><s>The type strain is USDA 1844, which has the characteristics given above for the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After this manuscript was accepted for publication we became aware of the proposal for the new species <i>Rhizobium gallicum</i> and <i>Rhizobium giardinii</i> originating from bean nodules growing in French soils (Amarger, N., Macheret, V. &#x0026; Laguerre, G. (1997) <i>Rhizobium gallicum</i> sp. nov. and <i>Rhizobium giardinii</i> sp. nov., from <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> nodules.</s><s>Int J Syst Bacteriol 47, 9961006).</s><s>The SSU rRNA gene sequences of the type strains for <i>R. gullicum</i> and <i>R. mongolense</i> are 99.2% similar.</s></p></content></protolog>