<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5267_nm.3705" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3705" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3705" rank="species">Anaeromyxobacter dehalogenans</organism><reference id="rid.5267"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sanford</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization and description of Anaeromyxobacter dehalogenans gen. nov., sp. nov., an aryl-halorespiring facultative anaerobic myxobacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>68</volume><fpage>893</fpage><lpage>900</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11823233</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaeromyxobacter dehalogenans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaeromyxobacter dehalogenans</i> (de.ha.lo'.ge.nans. N.L. adj. part. <i>dehalogenans</i>, dehalogenating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are narrow rods 4 to 8 μm long and 0.25 μm wide that exhibit gliding motility.</s><s>Terminal ends of cells have pilus structures and form blebs periodically.</s><s>Refractile cysts are visible in older cultures.</s><s>Cells stain gram negative.</s><s>Growth is facultative and occurs only with low concentrations of the following electron acceptors: oxygen, nitrate (reduced to ammonia), fumarate, 2-CPh, 2-bromophenol, and 2,6-DCP.</s><s>2-CPh is the best substrate for halorespiration (doubling time 12 h).</s><s>Acetate, succinate, pyruvate, formate, and H<sub>2</sub> are used as electron donors.</s><s>Cells grow by complete oxidation of organic electron donors to carbon dioxide.</s><s>The best temperature and pH for growth are 30°C and 7.0, respectively.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar medium anaerobically with fumarate are red, raised, and round with a diameter of 1 to 2 mm after 2 weeks of incubation.</s><s>A red pigmentation is produced in fumarate-grown cells.</s><s>The type strain, 2CP-1, was isolated from stream sediment near Lansing, Mich.</s><s>Strains 2CP-1 and 2CP-C have been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection under accession no. ATCC BAA-258 and ATCC BAA-259, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>