<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7511_nm.2401" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2401" rank="family">Methylococcaceae</organism><reference id="rid.7511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the methanotrophs: Description of Methylobacter gen.nov., emendation of Methylococcus, validation of Methylosinus and Methylocystis species, and a proposal that the family Methylococcaceae includes only the Group I Methanotrophs.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>753</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-735</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the family <i>Methylococcaceae</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cell morphology varies from rods to cocci that are 0.5 to 1.5 μm in diameter and 1.0 to 3.0 μm long. Cells usually occur singly or in pairs, occasionally forming chains. Cells do not form rosettes. Gram negative. The majority of the species produce a dormant resting stage that appears as a cyst similar to the cysts which occur in members of the genus <i>Azotobacter</i>. Cysts may be desiccation resistant or sensitive. If the cells are motile, they possess a single polar flagellum. Catalase is produced. Strictly aerobic chemoheterotrophs. Obligate utilizers of C<sub>1</sub> compounds (primarily methane and methanol) for carbon and energy. A few species can utilize methylated amines, formate, or formamide. Compounds with carbon-carbon bonds are not utilized. C<sub>1</sub> compounds are incorporated via the ribulose monophosphate pathway. The tricarboxylic acid pathway is usually incomplete, lacking 2-oxoglutarate dehydrogenase. The dissimilatory methane oxidation pathway is associated with type I intracytoplasmic membranes which appear as stacks of vesicular discs. No growth occurs on complex organic media. No growth factors are required. Nitrogen is fixed by an oxygen-sensitive nitrogenase (not present in <i>Methylobacter</i> strains). Denitrification does not occur. Ammonia is oxidized to nitrite nonspecifically via methane monooxygenase and hydroxylamine cytochrome c oxidoreductase. The G+C content ranges from 49 to 66 mol% (point of temperature inflection, <i>T<sub>t</sub></i>). The enome molecular weight varies from 1.5 x 10<sup>9</sup> to 3.0 x 10<sup>9</sup>. Most fatty acids have a carbon chain length of 16 and are either saturated or monounsaturated; several different 16:1 isomers are present in some species. Ubiquinone 8 or its 18-methylenated version (MQ-8) are the predominant lipoquinones present (12). The member genera include <i>Methylomonas</i>, <i>Methylobacter</i>, and <i>Methylococcus</i>, which form a cluster within the y subdivision of the Proteobacteria and are collectively referred to as the group I methanotrophs. The type genus is the genus <i>Methylococcus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>