<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6232_nm.2982" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2982" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2982" rank="species">Vibrio mediterranei</organism><reference id="rid.6232"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Vibrio mediterranei sp. nov.: a new marine member of the genus Vibrio.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>278</fpage><lpage>281</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-278</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio mediterranei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio mediterranei</i> (me.di.ter.ra'ne.i. L.gen. n.<i> mediterranei</i> of the Mediterranean Sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative rods that are 1 to 2 by 0.5 μm and are motile with a polar flagelum when they are grown on liquid medium (Fig. 1).</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl in the culture medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on marine agar are circular, translucent, and not pigmented and do not swarm.</s><s>The thiosulfate-citrate-bile-sucrose agar colonies are yellow (sucrose positive).</s><s>No growth occurs at 40°C or in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (vibriostatic agent O/129).</s><s>Starch, esculin, DNA, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>No hydrolysis of gelatin, urea, or human blood.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and ornitine decarboxilase negative; lysine decarboxylase and indole positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from D-glucose, D-fructose, D-ribose, maltose, D-mannitol, sucrose, D-mannose, D-galactose, D-cellobiose, D-trehalose, D-sorbitol, and D-raffinose, but not from L-arabinose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-xylose, dulcitol, or L-rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sole carbon and energy sources include sucrose, cellobiose, and putrescine, but not D-gluconate or gammaaminobutyrate.</s><s>Other carbon and energy sources are Lalanine, L-serine, L-asparragine, glycine, L-glutamine, Lproline, L-threonine, L-glutamate, L-aspartate, malate, lactate, D-sorbitol, D-galactose, lactose, myo-inositol, and salicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics which vary among strains are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from marine water, sediments, and plankton of the coastal area of Valencia, Spain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The percentage of G+C content of strain 50<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) is 43 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method), and the G+C content of strain 104 is 42 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 50 (= CECT 621).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genetic relationships between <i>V. mediterranei</i> and some other selected species are shown in Table 3.</s><s>The DNA homology data confirm results obtained by using numerical taxonomy for these strains, which clustered apart from the other wild and type strains of <i>Vibrio</i> species at a similarity level of 86% (10).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. mediterranei</i> is readily distinguished from Vibrio species with similar G+C contents by the arginine dihydrolase, Voges-Proskauer and gelatin tests (Table 4).</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-negative species can be differentiated as indicated in Table 5 .</s></p></content></protolog>