<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1541_nm.7640" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7640" rank="genus">Blastococcus</organism><reference id="rid.1541"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Blastococcus jejuensis sp. nov., an actinomycete from beach sediment, and emended description of the genus Blastococcus Ahrens and Moll 1970</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2391</fpage><lpage>2396</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64268-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012568</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Blastococcus</em> Ahrens and Moll 1970</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description is taken from Ahrens &#x0026; Moll (1970), Urzì <em>et al.</em> (2004) and this study.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid and sugars of peptidoglycan are <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and arabinose and galactose, respectively.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>MK-9 occurs in variable amounts depending on the strain.</s><s>The polar lipid profiles are characterized by the common basis comprising diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>The presence of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine and phosphatidylmethylethanolamine is variable among the species.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids consist of saturated, unsaturated and iso-branched fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNA are in the range 72.3–74 mol%.</s><s>Gram-positive, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and aerobic.</s><s>Some cells may be microaerophilic.</s><s>Cells are coccoid or rod-shaped and reproduce by budding and binary or multiple fission.</s><s>Vibrioid or non-motile cocci occur in pairs or tend to form aggregates, whereas rod-shaped cells occur singly and show motility by means of flagella.</s><s>Bud formation varies according to the species.</s><s>Most strains utilize a broad spectrum of organic compounds.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus belongs to the family <em>Geodermatophilaceae</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Blastococcus aggregatus</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>