<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.14180_nm.7677" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7677" rank="genus">Bifidobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.14180"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Delcenserie</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gavini</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beerens</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tresse</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franssen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daube</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of a new species, Bifidobacterium crudilactis sp. nov., isolated from raw milk and raw milk cheeses</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>30</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>381</fpage><lpage>389</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2007.01.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17321094</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium crudilactis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bifidobacterium crudilactis</em> (cru.di.lac’tis L. adj. crudus, raw, not cooked; L. n. lac lactis, milk; N.L. gen. n. crudilactis, of raw milk)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming bacilli.</s><s>They are irregularly shaped rods, curved, arranged singly, with occasional bifurcations and spatulated extremities, and 0.5×1.5–2.5 μm in size in 24 h TPY cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on TPY agar at 39 °C under anaerobic conditions are cream, circular, and convex with whole edges.</s><s>They reach a diameter of up to 1 mm within 48 h.</s><s>They have a reduced diameter (less than 1 mm) under aerobic conditions within the same time.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature for the ten strains is 39 °C, with a maximum of 45 °C (within 8 days) and a minimum of 5 °C (4 °C for three strains, within 14 days).</s><s>FR62/b/3<sup>T</sup> is able to grow at 4 °C.</s><s>In TPY, the minimum initial pH for growth of FR62/b/3<sup>T</sup> is 4.7 (within 48 h; weak growth at pH 4.4 within 15 days and not at pH 3.8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All ten strains of <em>B. crudilactis</em> (⩾90% of the strains) ferment ribose, galactose, glucose, fructose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, raffinose, and d-turanose.</s><s>None ferment (⩽10% of the strains) glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, <em>β</em>-methyl-xyloside, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosamine, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, starch, glygogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>All strains (⩾90% of the strains) were positive for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, and histidine arylamidase.</s><s>All were negative (⩽10% of the strains) for urease, indole production, nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>α-</em>arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-<em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosaminidase, glutamic decarboxylase acid, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, and glutamyl arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from raw milks and raw milk cheeses.</s><s>The origin of the raw milk contamination was not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean DNA G+C content for ten strains is 55.3 mol% (SD=0.82).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of FR62/b/3<sup>T</sup> is 56.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is FR62/b/3<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23609<sup>T</sup>=CNCM I-3342<sup>T</sup>), isolated from raw cow milk in France.</s></p></content></protolog>