<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8363_nm.13371" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13371" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13371" rank="species">Kineococcus gynurae</organism><reference id="rid.8363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Duangmal</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thamchaipenet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineococcus gynurae sp. nov., isolated from a Thai medicinal plant.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2439</fpage><lpage>2442</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65671-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842871</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kineococcus gynurae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kineococcus gynurae</em> [gy.nu′ra.e. N.L. n. <em>Gynura</em> scientific genus name of a plant; N.L. gen. n. <em>gynurae</em> of <em>Gynura</em>, isolated from <em>Gynura pseudochina</em> (L.) DC. var. <em>hispida</em> Thwaites, a Thai medicinal plant].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative cocci.</s><s>Colonies are circular, rough and deep orange in colour.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction but positive for urease activity.</s><s>Negative for casein but positive for hydrolysis of gelatin.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.0–9.0 with an optimum at pH 6.0–7.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 14–34 °C with an optimum at 25–28 °C.</s><s>In ISP 2 medium, good growth occurs at 1–5 % NaCl, moderate growth at 6 % NaCl and poor growth at 7 % NaCl.</s><s>d-Arabitol, l-arabitol, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, trehalose, turanose and xylitol are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources for growth.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: d-adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, glycogen, glycerol, inositol, inulin, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, potassium gluconate, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, starch, d-tagatose, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine aminopeptidase, trypsin and phosphoamidase are detected with the API ZYM enzyme assay, but not chymotrypsin, cystine aminopeptidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase or valine aminopeptidase.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid of the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Whole-cell sugars contain arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The glycan moiety of the murein is acetylated.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not detected.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (81.42 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (6.34 %).</s><s>Other cellular fatty acids detected as minor components are C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH (3.42 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2.47 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 2-OH (1.46 %) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.3 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KKD096<sup>T</sup> (=TISTR 1856<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24568<sup>T</sup>=BCC 26245<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 103943<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the roots of <em>Gynura pseudochina</em> (L.) DC. var. <em>hispida</em> Thwaites, collected from Bangkok, Thailand.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>