<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1531_nm.2255" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2255" rank="genus">Stenotrophomonas</organism><reference id="rid.1531"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Palleroni</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bradbury</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stenotrophomonas, a new bacterial genus for Xanthomonas maltophilia (Hugh 1980) Swings et al. 1983.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>606</fpage><lpage>609</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-606</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347518</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Stenotrophomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Stenotrophomonas</i> (Ste.no.tro.pho.mo'nas. Gr. adj. <i>stenus</i>, narrow; Gr. n. <i>trophus</i>, one who feeds; Gr. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; M.L. fem. n. <i>Stenotrophomonas</i>, a unit feeding on few substrates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporulating cells, about 0.5 by 1.5 μm, motile with several polar flagella (13).</s><s>They may produce fimbriae (9).</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules are not accumulated, and exogenous polymer is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The colonies are smooth, glistening, with entire margin, white, grayish, or pale yellow.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains require methionine for growth, but this is not a universal property (16).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but it is not used as an N source.</s><s>Denitrification and egg yolk reaction are negative.</s><s>Liquefaction of gelatin and lipolytic reaction (Tween 80 hydrolysis) are positive.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature, 35°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The nutritional spectrum is restricted.</s><s>Of 145 organic compounds tested as the sole sources of carbon and energy, only 23 were used for growth (25).</s><s>These include the disaccharides maltose, lactose, trehalose, and cellobiose and the glucoside salicin.</s><s>Growth on lactose is poor, probably because of the inability to use galactose.</s><s>Few fatty acids and amino acids were used for growth.</s><s>None of the polyalcohols, aromatic compounds, or amines were used (25).</s><s>Freshly isolated strains were found to use hydrocarbons, but the</s></p><p class="description"><s>property was lost after subcultivation in common laboratory media (14, 15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from assorted natural materials, human infections, and clinical materials.</s><s>They are the most frequently isolated pseudomonads, after <i>P. aeruginosa</i>, in the clinical laboratory (11).</s></p></content></protolog>