<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.933_nm.2820" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2820" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2820" rank="species">Alteromonas hanedai</organism><reference id="rid.933"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tebo</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nealson</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Alteromonas hanedai, sp. nov., a nonfermentative luminous species of marine origin.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>311</fpage><lpage>315</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02601812</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas hanedai</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas hanedai</i> (in honor of Yata Haneda, a Japanese biologist who has made numerous contributions to our knowledge o f the biology of bioluminescence)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>All of the 11 strains were motile straight rods (Fig. 1) which when stained for flagella by the Liefson method [6] were found to have a single polar flagellum (Fig. 2).</s><s>An electron microscopic examination of three isolates indicated that the polar flagellum was not surrounded by a sheath (Fig. 3) of the type found in species of <i>Beneckea</i> [1].</s><s>None of the strains accumulated poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product.</s></p><p class="description"><s>General physiological properties.</s><s>All strains were oxidase positive and reduced nitrates to nitrites but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>None were able to grow on a minimal medium containing 0.1% potassium acetate, 0.1% L-glutamate, and 0.1% L-alanine.</s><s>If this medium was supplemented with vitamin-free casein hydrolysate and 50 mg/liter of L-tryptophan, L-methionine, and L-cysteine, 5 of the 11 strains were able to grow.</s><s>All of the strains grew in the minimal medium supplemented with 0.1% yeast extract, while none grew in this medium if the sodium ion in the seawater base was replaced by equimolar amounts of potassium.</s><s>All strains grew at 4 and 20°C none grew at 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ability to ferment D-glucose, D-galactose, and N-acetylglucosamine was tested in two media (F-1 and F-2) which have been previously described [4,6].</s><s>In F-1 medium (which was sealed by means of an agar plug) no visible growth was apparent, the pH after 7 days incubation being either unchanged or decreased by up to 0.25 pH units.</s><s>In F-2 medium (which contained thioglycolate but was not sealed) growth was visible only on the surface but not in the anaerobic portion.</s><s>The pH after 7 days incubation was unchanged or increased by up to 0.3 pH units.</s><s>Three strains were also tested for growth in F-2 medium incubated under an atmosphere of 90% N<sub>2</sub> and 10% CO<sub>2</sub> with no visible growth.</s><s>When tested under similar conditions species of <i>Beneckea</i> and <i>Photobacterium</i> grew well throughout the medium and lowered the pH from 7.5 to a value below 5.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mol% G+C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNAs from strains 281, 282, 283, 284, and 287 was 46.4, 45.4, 44.9, 44.9, and 44.4 mol%, respectively, with a mean value of 45.2 ± 0.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxonomic assignments and nutritional analysis.</s><s>The morphological properties, mol% G+C contents of the DNAs, as well as the requirement of sodium ion for growth indicate that the 11 luminous isolates have properties of the previously described genus <i>Alteromonas</i> [3,6].</s><s>The results of a nutritional screening of these strains indicated considerable phenotypic similarity (Table 1).</s><s>When these data along with those from six previously characterized species of <i>Alteromonas</i> [3,7,17] were subjected to numerical analysis [4], the results presented in Fig. 4 were obtained.</s><s>The luminous isolates were phenotypically similar and distinct from other species of <i>Alteromonas</i>, justifying a new species designation.</s><s>Strain 281 has been designated as the type strain and deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC 33224).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 2 gives the diagnostic properties differentiating <i>A. hanedai</i> from other species of <i>Alteromonas</i>.</s><s>Since there is considerable interest in the ecology of the marine luminous bacteria, it is also useful to differentiate <i>A. hanedai</i> from other luminous species on the basis of traits other than fermentation.</s><s>For this purpose, we have compiled Table 3.</s><s>Since several of the luminous bacteria prefer lower temperatures, it is advisable that in ecological studies the initial incubation be conducted at 15°C.</s><s>The nutritional screening can also be performed at this temperature with most of the tests scored after 3, 5, and 7 days of incubation.</s></p></content></protolog>