<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6697_nm.7541" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7541" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7541" rank="species">Nocardiopsis halophila</organism><reference id="rid.6697"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Al-Tai</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis halophila sp. nov., a new halophilic actinomycete isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>474</fpage><lpage>478</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis halophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis halophila</i> (ha. lo. phi' la. Gr. n. <i>halos</i>, salt; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. fem. adj. <i>halophila</i>, loving salt)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Nocardiopsis halophila</i> is an aerobic, gram-positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile, filamentous actinomycete.</s><s>It forms a long and extensively branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>Fragmentation of the substrate mycelium is rarely observed; its color ranges from creamy yellow to coral red.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is irregularly branched with very long hyphae and zigzag and fragments into elongated spores with smooth surfaces.</s><s>It does not have distinctive pigmentation.</s><s>The cell wall type is type III.</s><s>Sugar pattern C.</s><s>Phospholipid type PIII.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>, H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>No mycolic acids are present.</s><s>Additional physiological characteristics (Tables 3 and 4) include resistance to lysozyme, amoxicillin, clindamycin, bacitracin, cephalexin, and oxacillin and susceptibility to carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and novobiocin.</s><s>Hydrolyzes urea and Tween 80, but does not degrade carboxymethyl cellulose, starch, xanthine, and tyrosine.</s><s>Produces acids from the carbon sources maltose, mannitol, xylose, fructose, arabinose, ribose, inositol, and rhamnose.</s><s>Acids are not produced from glucose, sucrose, galactose, mannose, and raffinose.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30°C.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl concentrations up to 20% (wt/vol).</s><s>Habitat: soil.</s></p></content></protolog>