<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6638_nm.1188" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1188" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1188" rank="species">Sphingomonas pituitosa</organism><reference id="rid.6638"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paukner</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wanner</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lubitz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas pituitosa sp. nov., an exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium that secretes an unusual type of sphingan.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>827</fpage><lpage>841</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411704</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas pituitosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingomonas pituitosa</i> (pi.tu.i.to'sa. L. fem. adj. <i>pituitosa</i> slimy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-sporeforming and motile (each cell has a polar monotrichous flagellum).</s><s>Cells are 0.4-0.75 μm wide and 1.0-3.0 μm long.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Yellow intracellular pigments (carotenoids) are produced; the visible absorption spectrum of the yellow pigment (acetone extract) has two peaks at kmax 452 and 478 nm and a slight in¯exion at 425 nm.</s><s>Poly-fhydroxybutyrate is accumulated.</s><s>Colonies on complex, peptone-containing standard media are deep yellow, circular, entire, convex and smooth.</s><s>Capable of growth at room temperature and at 30 °C but not at 4, 37 or 45 °C.</s><s>Capable of growth on nutrient-reduced media such as Czapek-Dox and R2A.</s><s>No growth on Simmons citrate agar.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for catalase and β-galactosidase.</s><s>No reactions are obtained for oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, urease, nitrate reduction, production of indole, gelatin liquefaction or H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed but starch, casein and DNA are not.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin and tetracycline; resistant to penicillin G, polymyxin B and streptomycin.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated: N-acetyl D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, p-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-maltose, α-D-melibiose, sucrose, salicin, D-trehalose, D-xylose, acetate, fumarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, L-malate, pyruvate, L-alanine and L-proline.</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: D-fructose, gluconate, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, adonitol, i-inositol, maltitol, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, putrescine, propionate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, glutarate, itaconate, DL-lactate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, suberate, β-alanine, L-aspartate, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-serine, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The following compounds are hydrolysed: aesculin, <i>para</i>-nitrophenyl (pNP) β-D-galactopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucuronide, pNP α-D-glucopyranoside, pNP β-D-glucopyranoside, pNP β-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphate, pNP phosphoryl-choline, 2-deoxythymidine-5'-pNP phosphate, L-alanine-<i>para</i>-nitroanilide (pNA) and L-glutamate-γ-3-carboxy-pNA.</s><s>L-Proline-pNA is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Weak production of acid can be observed, after prolonged incubation, from D-glucose, lactose, sucrose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, D-xylose and cellobiose.</s><s>No acids are produced from D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, raffinose, trehalose, methyl α-D-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, D-arabitol or D-mannose.</s><s>Phylogenetically, <i>S. pituitosa</i> clusters with the validly published species of the genus <i>Sphingomonas</i> within the α-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> (Woese, 1987; Stackebrandt et al., 1988).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.5 mol%.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the major respiratory lipoquinone.</s><s><i>sym</i>-Homospermidine is the major component in the polyamine pattern.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown lipid (L1).</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine, as well as several unknown lipids, are present in minor concentrations.</s><s>Sphingoglycolipid is present.</s><s>The predominant non-polar fatty acids are 18:1 and 16:0; the major 2-hydroxy fatty acid is 14:0 2-OH, but minor amounts of 15:0 2-OH are also present.</s><s>Isolated from the water of a eutrophic fountain in Vienna, Austria, in which an algal bloom was observed.</s><s>The type strain is EDIV<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106154<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13101<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>