<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7279_nm.6274" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6274" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6274" rank="species">Corynebacterium thomssenii</organism><reference id="rid.7279"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zimmermann</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuchs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Köchel</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium thomssenii sp. nov., a Corynebacterium with N-acetyl-beta-glucosaminidase activity from human clinical specimens</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>489</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-489</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731289</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium thomssenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium thomssenii</i> (thomsse'.ni.i. M . L. gen. n. <i>thomssenii</i> of Thomssen, to honour Reiner Thomssen, a prominent German virologist and medical microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of biochemical and morphological characteristics is based on the results of the studies of one strain.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, nonspore-forming diphtheroids.</s><s>Colonies of this fastidious slow-growing bacterium are whitish, circular, mucoid and sticky.</s><s>After 24 h incubation on Columbia agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood, the colony diameter is less than 0.5 mm.</s><s>Metabolism is fermentative.</s><s>Catalase is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, sucrose, D-fructose, D-mannose, trehalose and 5-keto-gluconate, but not from mannitol, xylose, glycerol, erythritol, arabinose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-lyxose, L-arabitol, gluconate and 2-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is negative.</s><s>The strain is non-lipophilic, the CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>DNase activity is observed Tyrosine is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Activities of pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are present, whereas lipase, valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>The cell wall contains arabinose and galactose.</s><s><i>meso</i>-Diaminopimelic acid is the cell wall diamino acid.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids (C<sub>32</sub>-C<sub>36</sub>) represent.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids, the predominant unsaturated fatty acid is oleic acid.</s><s>The polar lipids are composed of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) are the predominant menaquinones and small amounts of MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>) are also found.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens with as-yet-unknown pathogenicity.</s><s>Type strain DSM44276 has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures (DSMZ), Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>