<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1437_nm.1807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1807" rank="genus">Hydrogenophaga</organism><reference id="rid.1437"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goor</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jantzen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Auling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hydrogenophaga, a new genus of hydrogen-oxidizing bacteria that includes Hydrogenophaga flava comb. nov. (formerly Pseudomonas flava), Hydrogenophaga palleronii (formerly Pseudomonas palleronii), Hydrogenophaga pseudoflava (formerly Pseudomonas pseudoflava and Pseudomonas "carboxydoflava"), and Hydrogenophaga taeniospiralis (formerly Pseudomonas taeniospiralis).</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>319</fpage><lpage>333</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-319</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hydrogenophaga</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hydrogenophaga</i> (Hy.dro.ge.no´pha.ga. Gr. n. <i>hydoor</i>, water; Gr. n. <i>gennao</i>, to create; M.L. <i>hydrogenum</i>, hydrogen, that which produces water; Gr. v. <i>phagein</i>, to eat; M.L. fem. n. <i>Hydrogenophaga</i>, eater of hydrogen)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods (0.3 to 0.6 by 0.6 to 5.5 μm); they occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of one, rarely two, polar to subpolar flagella.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Catalase variable.</s><s>A nondiffusible yellow pigment is produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic or chemolithoautotrophic, using the oxidation of hydrogen as an energy source.</s><s>Oxidative carbohydrate metabolism with oxygen as a terminal electron acceptor or heterotrophic denitrification of nitrate (by <i>Hydrogenophaga pseudoflava</i> and <i>Hydrogenophaga taeniospiralis</i>).</s><s>Cells grow well on media containing organic acids, amino acids, or peptone, but are less versatile in the use of carbohydrates.</s><s>A cyclopropane-substituted fatty acid (17:cyc) is present; 3-hydroxy-octanoic acid (3-OH-8:O) is present alone or together with 3-hydroxy-decanoic acid (3-OH-10:0). 2-Hydroxy-substituted fatty acids are absent.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is present as the main quinone.</s><s>2-Hydroxyputrescine and putrescine are present in roughly equimolar concentrations either exclusively or as the dominant polyamine compounds.</s><s>The mean G+C content of the DNA ranges from 65 to 69 mol%.</s><s>In DNA:rRNA hybridizations <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i> values of 77.3 to 81.1°C are obtained versus rRNA from <i>Hydrogenophaga pseudoflava</i> GA3<sup>T</sup> or <i>Hydrogenophaga palleronii</i> Stanier 362t1<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The genus <i>Hydrogenophaga</i> belongs to the acidovorans rRNA complex.</s><s>It is equidistantly related to the following other taxa in this complex: the genera <i>Comamonas</i> and <i>Xylophilus</i> and the generically misnamed species [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>facilis</i>, [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>delajeldii</i>, [<i>Pseudomonas</i>] <i>avenue</i>, and [<i>Alcaligenes</i>] <i>paradoxus</i>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Hydrogenophaga flava</i> (Niklewski 1910) comb. nov.</s><s>This species grows slowly and easily loses its chemolithoautotrophic ability (4).</s><s>Because of its high genotypic and protein electrophoretic similarity to the type species, <i>Hydrogenophaga pseudoflava</i> can be used as an alternative reference species for the genus.</s></p></content></protolog>