<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2733_nm.5798" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5798" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5798" rank="species">Actinomyces oricola</organism><reference id="rid.2733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inganäs</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces oricola sp. nov., from a human dental abscess.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1515</fpage><lpage>1518</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02576-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130041</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces oricola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces oricola</em> (o.ri′co.la. L. n. <em>os</em>, <em>oris</em> mouth; L. masc. suffix <em>cola</em> inhabitant of; N.L. masc. n. <em>oricola</em> inhabitant of the mouth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, rod-shaped cells, some of which display branching and filaments may be observed.</s><s>Cells are non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies after 48 h anaerobic incubation on Fastidious Anaerobe Agar with 5 % horse blood are pin-point, breadcrumb-like, white and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic, but grows best under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The end products of glucose metabolism are acetic, lactic and succinic acids.</s><s>Using conventional tests, acid is produced from amygdalin (weak), cellobiose, fructose, glucose, raffinose (weak), salicin, sucrose and trehalose, but not from arabinose or lactose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Lipase, lecithinase and urease are not detected and indole is not produced.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, acid is produced from glucose, but not from d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, d-ribose, sorbitol, tagatose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from maltose, sucrose and raffinose, depending on the test system used.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin and hippurate are not.</s><s>Indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Alanine arylamidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, phenyl alanine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase are detected.</s><s>Activity for alkaline phosphatase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase may or may not be detected, depending on the test system used.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl trypyophane arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, histidine arylamidase, serine arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-negative.</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acids are C16 : 0, C18 : 0 and C18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Isolated from human dental abscess.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>Type strain is R5292<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46090<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107639<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>