<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7107_nm.6769" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6769" rank="genus">Thermobispora</organism><reference id="rid.7107"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A proposal to transfer Microbispora bispora (Lechevalier 1965) to a new genus, Thermobispora gen. nov., as Thermobispora bispora comb. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>933</fpage><lpage>938</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-933</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863419</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermobispora</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermobispora</i> (Ther.mo.bi.spo'ra. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. adj. <i>bis</i>, two; Gr. fem. n. <i>spora</i>, seed; M. L. fem. n. <i>Thermobispora</i>, high temperature two-spored organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains are gram-positive, aerobic, non-acid-fast, thermophilic organisms that produce substrate mycelia with hyphae which are 0.5 to 0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>The aerial mycelia branch monopodially and bear longitudinal pairs of spores which are usually arranged alternately on side branches arising from the main hyphae.</s><s>The smooth-surface spores are oval to spherical and nonmotile.</s><s>Fragmentation of mycelia is not observed on agar or in liquid media.</s><s>Neither sclerotia, sporangia, nor any other special structure is formed.</s><s>The cell wall contains a major amount of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, and the whole-cell hydrolysate contains madurose and galactose.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>0</sub>) is the major menaquinone.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern type is type PIV, and the phospholipids include a small amount of glucosamine-containing phospholipids.</s><s>14-Methylpentadecanoic acid is the major fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 70 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>