<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3416_nm.1051" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1051" rank="genus">Amaricoccus</organism><reference id="rid.3416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maszenan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rees</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McDougall</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amaricoccus gen. nov., a gram-negative coccus occurring in regular packages or tetrads, isolated from activated sludge biomass, and descriptions of Amaricoccus veronensis sp. nov., Amaricoccus tamworthensis sp. nov., Amaricoccus macauensis sp. nov., and Amaricoccus kaplicensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>727</fpage><lpage>734</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-727</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226904</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amaricoccus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amaricoccus</i> (A.ma'ri.coc.cus. Gr. n. <i>amara</i>, sewage duct; Gr. n. <i>coccus</i>, grain; L. n. <i>Amaricoccus</i>, spherical cells from sewage ducts)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large, gram-negative, non-spore-forming cocci (mean cell diameter, 1.3 to 1.8 μm) that are usually arranged in tetrads.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile.</s><s>They do not store polyphosphate granules either in situ or in axenic culture. <i>Amancoccus</i> spp. possess the following enzymes: alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase-lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, and α-glucosidase.</s><s>They lack the enzymes cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, and arginine dihydrolase (at both 24 and 48 h).</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: dextrin, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cellobiose, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, or-D-glucose, <i>m</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-psicose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, DL-lactic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-asparagine, L-glutamic acid, maltotriose, palatinose, D-ribose, salicin, D-tegatose, D-xylose, D-lactic acid methyl ester, L-lactic acid, D-malic acid, L-malic acid, methyl succinate, pyruvic acid, N-acetyl-L-glutamic acid, and adenosine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: α-cyclodextrin, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, i-erythritol, α-D-lactose, lactulose, D-raffinose, D-glucosaminic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, L-alanyl-glycine, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-pyroglutamic acid, uridine, inulin, amygdalin, α-methyl-D-galactoside, β-methyl-D-mannoside, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, and UMP.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 20 and 37°C and at pH values between 5.5 and 9.0.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>The DNA base compositions range from 51 to 63 mol% G+C.</s><s>The natural habitat is activated sludge.</s><s>The type species is <i>Amaricoccus kaplicensis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>