<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5879_nm.5214" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5214" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5214" rank="species">Sporosarcina macmurdoensis</organism><reference id="rid.5879"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sporosarcina macmurdoensis sp. nov., from a cyanobacterial mat sample from a pond in the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1363</fpage><lpage>1367</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02628-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130019</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sporosarcina macmurdoensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sporosarcina macmurdoensis</em> (mac.mur.do.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>macmurdoensis</em> pertaining to the McMurdo Region, Antarctica, where the isolates were collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, flat, irregular, opaque and white with a diameter of 2–3 mm.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, single and non-motile and form subterminal spores.</s><s>Cells can tolerate a maximum of 3 % (w/v) NaCl and grow at pH 6–9 (pH 7 is optimum for growth).</s><s>Psychrophilic; grows at 4–25 °C (optimum growth temperature 18–20 °C).</s><s>Positive for catalase, phosphatase, gelatinase and starch hydrolysis and negative for lipase, urease, oxidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, arginine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, indole production, methyl red test, Voges–Proskauer test, aesculin hydrolysis and nitrate reduction to nitrite.</s><s>Does not produce acid or gas from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, pyruvate, d-raffinose, d-xylose and l-glutamic acid as sole carbon sources, but not acetate, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, cellulose, citrate, dextran, glucose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, fumaric acid, glycerol, inulin, lactic acid, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sorbitol, d-sorbose, sucrose, succinic acid, trehalose, thioglycollate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-aspargine, l-glutamine, l-lysine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan or l-valine.</s><s>Sensitive to amikacin, ampicillin, amoxycillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, cefazoline, cefaperazone, cephotaxime, chloramphenicol, chlorotetracycline, co-trimoxazole, ciprofloxacin, erythromycin, furazolidone, furoxone, gentamicin, kanamycin, lomefloxacin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, nitrofurazone, nitrofurantoin, norfloxacin, novobiocin, nystatin, oxytetracycline, penicillin, polymyxin-B, rifampicin, roxithromycin, streptomycin, tetracycline, tobramycin, trimethoprim and vancomycin, but resistant to cefuroxime, colistin and lincomycin.</s><s>Peptidoglycan type is l-lys–d-Glu of the A4<em>α</em> variant and MK-7 is the major menaquinone.</s><s>When grown in nutrient broth at 22 °C, the fatty acid composition is as follows (proportions of total fatty acids in parentheses): C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0·5 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0·5 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (11·1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1·1 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (4·0 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (37·4 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (1·5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (0·7 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (3·2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (1·1 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (22·6 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (3·0 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (13·0 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain, CMS 21w<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4670<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15428<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107784<sup>T</sup>), is 44 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>