<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1398_nm.2272" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2272" rank="genus">Dichelobacter</organism><reference id="rid.1398"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>La Fontaine</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rood</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Kingella indologenes (Snell and Lapage 1976) to the genus Suttonella gen. nov. as Suttonella indologenes comb. nov.; transfer of Bacteroides nodosus (Beveridge 1941) to the genus Dichelobacter gen. nov. as Dichelobacter nodosus comb. nov.; and assignment of the genera Cardiobacterium, Dichelobacter, and Suttonella to Cardiobacteriaceae fam. nov. in the gamma division of Proteobacteria on the basis of 16S rRNA sequence comparisons.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>426</fpage><lpage>433</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2275858</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dichelobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dichelobacter</i> (Di.che´lo.bac.ter. Gr. adj. <i>Dichelos</i>, cloven hoofed; N. L. n. <i>bacter</i>, a rod; N. L. masc. n. <i>Dichelobacter</i>, cloven-hoofed rod, because this organism is the rod-shaped bacterium that causes footrot in sheep, goats, and cattle)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data published previously by Beveridge (2), Cato et al. (7), Holdeman et al. (14), and Skerman (33).</s><s>Large straight or slightly curved rods that are 1.0 to 1.7 μm in diameter and 3 to 6 μm long and have rounded ends.</s><s>The cells often have terminal swellings, although this feature is less pronounced in subcultured organisms.</s><s>Gram negative, but there is a tendency to resist decolorization.</s><s>Organisms stained with Loeffler methylene blue have prominent polychromic granules toward the poles and at intermediate sites within the cells.</s><s>The cells have large numbers of pili (N-methylphenylalanine-type pilins) which vary in number according to changes in colony morphology.</s><s>Cells exhibit twitching motility, and spreading of colonies occurs.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine, asparagine, serine, and threonine.</s><s>Positive for ornithine decarboxylase phosphatase (weak), H<sub>2</sub>S production, selenite reduction, and proteolytic activity on gelatin, casein, and albumin.</s><s>Negative for acid or gas production from carbohydrates, ammonia production from phenylalanine, cysteine, citrulline, and ornithine, starch hydrolysis, esculin hydrolysis, indole production, nitrate reduction, growth in 0.1% bile, hemolysis, arginine decarboxylase, catalase , oxidase, urease, DNase, coagulase, lipase, lecithinase, and hyaluronidase.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45 mol%.</s><s>The genus contains a single species, <i>Dichelobacter nodosus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>