<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7182_nm.6617" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6617" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6617" rank="species">Propionibacterium cyclohexanicum</organism><reference id="rid.7182"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kusano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Niwa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionibacterium cyclohexanicum sp. nov., a new acid-tolerant ω-cyclohexyl fatty acid-containing propionibacterium isolated from spoiled orange juice.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>825</fpage><lpage>831</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-825</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226913</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionibacterium cyclohexanicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionibacterium cyclohexanicum</i> (cy.clo.hex.a'ni.cum. Gr. n. <i>kyklos</i>, circle; Gr. n. <i>hexa</i>, six; M. L. masc. adj. <i>cyclohexanicum</i>, referring to ω-cyclohexyl fatty acid, the characteristic cellular fatty acid of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, aerotolerant, nonmotile, non-acid-fast, non-spore-forming, pleomorphic rods.</s><s>The cells are 1.5 to 3.0 μm long and 1.1 to 1.6 μm wide.</s><s>Some cells are club shaped or bent.</s><s>Colonies grown anaerobically on the surface of peptone-yeast extract-glucose agar for 3 days are circular, white to creamy, translucent, and 0.2 to 0.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>The catalase, oxidase, and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative, and the methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Urea and esculin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, and indole is not produced.</s><s>Glycerol, L-xylose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, amygdalin, arbutin, esculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, saccharose, trehalose, melezitose, D-turanose, D-fucose, acetic acid, lactic acid, malic acid, citric acid, and succinic acid are assimilated.</s><s>Erythritol, D-arabinose, ribose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methylmannoside, α-methylglucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, inulin, D-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, and 5ketogluconate are not assimilated.</s><s>Lactic acid and propionic acid are the major end products of the glucose fermentation, and acetic acid is also detected.</s><s>Grows at pH 3.2 to 7.5 (optimum pH, 5.5 to 6.5) and at 20 to 40°C (optimum temperature, 35°C).</s><s>The cells are heat resistant and survive at 90°C for 10 min.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>ω-Cyclohexyl undecanoic acid is the main cellular fatty acid.</s><s>The isomer of diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall is <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The N-glycolyl residue is not present.</s><s>The cell wall amino acids are alanine, glutamic acid, and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The whole-cell sugars are galactose, glucose, mannose, ribose, and rhamnose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66.8 mol%.</s><s>The bacterium was isolated from pasteurized orange juice.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TA-12 (=IAM 14535=NRIC 0247).</s></p></content></protolog>