<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8203_nm.14180" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14180" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14180" rank="species">Salinicoccus albus</organism><reference id="rid.8203"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus albus sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium from a salt mine.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>874</fpage><lpage>879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003251-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329623</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus albus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus albus</em> (al′bus. L. masc. adj. <em>albus</em> white, referring to the colony colour).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-positive and are non-motile, non-sporulating, obligately aerobic cocci (0.6–1.1 μm) that occur singly or in pairs, tetrads or clumps.</s><s>Colonies are white, circular, convex, smooth, non-translucent with entire margins, 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation at 25 °C for 3–5 days on MA supplemented with 10.0 % NaCl.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Moderately halophilic and facultatively alkaliphilic, growth occurring with 1.0–30.0 % NaCl (optimum, 10.0 % NaCl) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 8.5).</s><s>NaCl cannot be replaced by MgCl<sub>2</sub> . 6H<sub>2</sub>O or KCl.</s><s>Growth at 5–40 °C, with optimum growth at 25 °C.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 40 and 80, but negative for hydrolysis of casein, DNA, aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20 and 60.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive but the methyl red test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrite is not reduced to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol and d-xylose, but not from d-adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, d-lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-sorbose, sucrose or trehalose.</s><s>Sole carbon and energy sources are l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>The following substances are not used as sole sources of carbon or nitrogen: d-adonitol, dulcitol, d-fucose, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, salicin, adonitol, ethanol, acetate, benzoate, butyrate, citrate, formate, fumarate, d-gluconate, malate, malonate, pyruvate, suberate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, threonine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>With the API 50CH system, the following organic compounds are metabolized: d-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, inositol, d-mannitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, d-sorbitol and d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are oxidized in the Biolog GP system: d-arabitol, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-propionic acid, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>Constitutive expression of acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, catalase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and oxidase, but not <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin, lipase (C14), urease or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Cells are resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg), but susceptible to ampicillin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (20 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The major amino acid constituents of the cell-wall hydrolysate are glycine and lysine.</s><s>MK-6 is the predominant respiratory quinone (69.2 % in the type strain), with MK-7 (30.8 % in the type strain) present in minor amounts.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and one unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 46.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM-Y21<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 207024<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19776<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 13192<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a brine sample collected from the Yipinglang salt mine in Yunnan, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>