<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4454_nm.6144" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6144" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6144" rank="species">Mycetocola tolaasinivorans</organism><reference id="rid.4454"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shida</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shirata</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Mycetocola gen. nov. in the family Microbacteriaceae and three new species, Mycetocola saprophilus sp. nov., Mycetocola tolaasinivorans sp. nov. and Mycetocola lacteus sp. nov., isolated from cultivated mushroom, Pleurotus ostreatus.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>937</fpage><lpage>944</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411718</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycetocola tolaasinivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycetocola tolaasinivorans</i> (to.laa.si.ni.vo'rans. N.L. neut. n. <i>tolaasinum</i> tolaasin, type of toxin produced by <i>Pseudomonas tolaasii</i>; L. part. adj. <i>vorans</i> devouring, decomposing; N.L. part. adj. <i>tolaasinivorans</i> tolaasindecomposing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, obligately aerobic, irregular rods, 0.2-0.4x2.0-3.5 μm, non-sporulating and nonmotile.</s><s>Smooth, yellowish-white colonies are found on PS agar.</s><s>The maximum temperature for growth is 33 °C and the optimal temperature for growth is 25 °C, but no growth at 4 °C in PS broth medium.</s><s>Catalase is produced, but oxidase is not produced.</s><s>The following tests are positive: aesculin hydrolysis, growth in peptone water, acid production from D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, D-ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose, utilization of fumarate, and detoxification of tolaasins produced by <i>Pseudomonas tolaasii</i>.</s><s>The following tests are negative: reduction of nitrate or nitrite, nitrate respiration, liquefaction of gelatin, Voges-Proskauer reaction, methyl red reaction, lecithinase, tyrosinase, urease, hydrolysis of arbutin, arginine, casein and Tween 80, production of diffusible and fluorescent pigment, hydrogen sulfide, indole, 3-ketolactose, 2-ketogluconate and levan from sucrose, growth in Corn's solution, Fermi's solution and Uschinsky's solution, utilization of asparagine as sole source of carbon and nitrogen, maceration of potato tubers, hypersensitive reaction in tobacco leaves, acid production from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-dulcitol, erythritol,<i>m</i>-inositol, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose and starch, and utilization of benzoate, butyrate, citrate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, oxalate, propionate, D- and L-tartarate.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine as a diamino acid and the muramic acid of the cell wall is an acetyl type.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone MK-10 and small amounts of MK-9 and MK-11 are present.</s><s>The G­+C content is 65.1 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>Isolated from cultivated mushroom <i>Pleurotus ostreatus</i>.</s><s>Type strain is CM-05<sup>T</sup> (=IFO 16277<sup>T</sup>=MAFF 211325<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24120<sup>T</sup>=strain 9405<sup>T</sup>, described in Tsukamoto et al., 1998).</s></p></content></protolog>