<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6292_nm.4142" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4142" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4142" rank="species">Johnsonella ignava</organism><reference id="rid.6292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oribaculum catoniae gen. nov., sp. nov.; Catonella morbi gen. nov., sp. nov.; Hallella seregens gen. nov., sp. nov.; Johnsonella ignava gen. nov., sp. nov.; and Dialister pneumosintes gen. nov., comb. nov., nom. rev., Anaerobic gram-negative bacilli from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186083</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Johnsonella ignava</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Johnsonella ignava</i> (ig.na'va. L. fem. adj. <i>ignava</i>, sluggish, because of the inactivity of this organism in vitro)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on studies of the type strain and 10 other strains.</s><s>Cells of the type strain in PYG broth cultures are 0.8 μm wide by 3.7 to 6.4 μm long and occur singly and in pairs.</s><s>Some cells have central swellings.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar plates are minute to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, white to tan, shiny, smooth, and sometimes mottled.</s><s>No hemolysis occurs around colonies grown on rabbit blood agar, and no colonies with a dark pigment are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A small amount of granular, smooth, or stringy sediment, without turbidity, is produced in broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, esculin, fructose, glucose, glycerol, glycogen, gum arabic, inositol, lactose, larch arabinogalactan, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, xylan, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>No hydrogen sulfide is produced in SIM (sulfide-indole motility) medium (BBL Microbiology Systems, Baltimore, Md.).</s><s>No growth occurs in PYG-20% bile broth or in deoxycholate broth.</s><s>Indole, oxidase, DNase, and catalase are not produced, and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Neither lipase nor lecithinase is detected on egg yolk agar (2).</s><s>Resazurin is not reduced, and no gas is produced in PYG agar cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following amounts of fermentation products (in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture; mean ± standard error of the mean) are produced in PYG broth cultures: acetate, 0.7 ± 0.1; and isovalerate, 0.2 ± 0.04.</s><s>Trace amounts of lactate, succinate, butyrate, and isobutyrate are also produced.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 51276 (= VPI D94B-12).</s><s>The reactions of the type strain are the same as those given above for the species.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the gingival crevices of humans with gingivitis and periodontitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular constituents, lack of pigment production, and G+C content help differentiate this species from phenotypically similar anaerobic gram-negative bacilli.</s></p></content></protolog>