<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8355_nm.13607" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13607" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13607" rank="species">Shewanella vesiculosa</organism><reference id="rid.8355"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miñana-Galbis</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manresa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mercadé</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella vesiculosa sp. nov., a psychrotolerant bacterium isolated from an Antarctic coastal area.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>336</fpage><lpage>340</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000737-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196774</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella vesiculosa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella vesiculosa</em> (ve.si.cu.lo′sa. L. fem. adj. <em>vesiculosa</em> full of blisters, vesiculous).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5 μm wide and 1.5–3 μm long), Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>After 48 h incubation at 15 °C on TSA, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, round with regular edges, slightly mucous and slightly brownish.</s><s>The growth temperature ranges from −4 to 30 °C (optimum 15–20 °C), the pH range for growth is 6.0–8.5 (optimum approx. pH 7.5) and sodium ions are not required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % NaCl (w/v); no growth in the presence of &#x003E;7 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin, Tween 80, gelatin, casein and lecithin, but negative for hydrolysis of urea and starch.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Cells are able to grow anaerobically by reducing trimethylamine <em>N</em>-oxide and sodium nitrate with lactate as the electron donor.</s><s>With the API 50 CH test, growth is positive for d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, malate and sucrose.</s><s>The most abundant fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The quinone composition of the type strain is Q-7 (50.5 %), Q-8 (25.3 %), MK-7 (14.4 %) and MMK-7 (9.8 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M7<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24424<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7339<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediments collected from Deception Island (South Shetland Islands, Antarctica).</s></p></content></protolog>