<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1408_nm.3926" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3926" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3926" rank="species">Clostridium disporicum</organism><reference id="rid.1408"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Horn</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium disporicum sp. nov., a saccharolytic species able to form two spores per cell, isolated from rat cecum.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>398</fpage><lpage>401</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-398</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium disporicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium disporicum</i> (di.spor´i.cum. Gr. pref. <i>di</i>, two; Gr. n. <i>sporos</i>, seed; Gr. suffix, <i>ikos</i>, pertaining to; N. L. neut. adj., <i>disporicum</i>, pertaining to [or possessing] two spores)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and 1.5 μm wide by 2.5 to 10 μm long.</s><s>They are obligately anaerobic, gram positive, nonmotile, forming subterminal oval spores, and belong to the genus <i>Clostridium</i>.</s><s>Spores are formed in both ends of some cells.</s><s>Cells containing two spores are present in a lower proportion than cells with only one spore and form approximately 10 to 20% of the total population.</s><s>Examination by electron microscopy showed no evidence of incipient cell division or cross-wall formation in cells with two developing or fully developed spores (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic conditions are required for the growth of DS1<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>No growth occurs in a medium without fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The major products from peptone-yeast broth medium containing glucose (0.5%, wt/vol) are acetic and lactic acid with trace amounts of <i>n</i>-butyric and succinic acids (Table 1).</s><s>Production of short-chain fatty acids is greater in basal SM10 containing glucose (0.5%, wt/vol).</s><s>A small amount of ethanol is also formed in both media.</s><s>Moderate amounts of gas are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbohydrates are used by DS1<sup>T</sup> as carbon sources for growth and acid production: esculin, cellobiose, dulcitol, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Esculin and starch are both hydrolyzed.</s><s>Arabinose , inositol, melezitose, rhamnose, and sorbitol are not utilized.</s><s>DS1<sup>T</sup> does not liquefy gelatin or digest cooked meat or casein in milk.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase, and catalase activities are not present, and indole is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reference strains NCIB 8052<sup>T</sup> and NCIB 9362<sup>T</sup> (Table 1) have a G+C content of 29 mol%.</s><s>Precise determination of the G+C content of DS1<sup>T</sup> (38 to 41 mol%) was made difficult by the general broadness of the peak obtained from density centrifugation.</s><s>Most <i>Clostridium</i> species have a G+C content close to 28 mol% (9); <i>C. oceanicum</i> has a G+C content of 27 to 28 mol%.</s><s>A second smaller group has a G+C content range from 40 to 54 mol% with <i>C. nexile</i> and <i>C. sphenoides</i> having a content close to that of DS1<sup>T</sup> at 40 to 41 and 41 to 42 mol%, respectively.</s><s>In other biochemical characteristics the latter strains have no similarity with DS1<sup>T</sup> (5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>One other <i>Clostridium</i> species, <i>C. oceanicum</i>, has been reported to produce cells containing two spores (20).</s><s>This species, however, unlike DS1<sup>T</sup> hydrolyzes gelatin, a major subdivision in the classification of <i>Clostridium</i> sp. (5).</s><s>Additionally, <i>C. oceanicum</i> does not ferment lactose, maltose, raffinose, starch, or sucrose, as does DS1<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological and biochemical characteristics of strain DS1<sup>T</sup> do not match the characteristics of other species in the genus <i>Clostridium</i> (5); it is therefore proposed to be a new species, <i>Clostridium disporicum</i>.</s><s>The type strain, DS1, has been deposited in the NCIB as no. 12424.</s></p></content></protolog>