<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5562_nm.9836" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9836" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9836" rank="species">Belnapia moabensis</organism><reference id="rid.5562"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagy</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Pichel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Belnapia moabensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an alphaproteobacterium from biological soil crusts in the Colorado Plateau, USA</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>58</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63764-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403866</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Belnapia moabensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Belnapia moabensis</em> (mo.a.ben′sis. N.L. gen. n. <em>moabensis</em> of Moab, UT, USA, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are convex, round and rough.</s><s>It grows from 15 to 30 °C, but not at 37 °C, with an optimum growth temperature of 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–8, with an optimum pH of 7.</s><s>Cannot tolerate NaCl.</s><s>Cells test negative for lipase, phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, DNase, arginine decarboxylase and phenylalanine deaminase activities.</s><s>Negative in methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, indole and Simmons' citrate tests.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, cellulose, aesculin or starch and does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S gas, but reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Cells do not produce acid from d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Ferments l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-maltose and d-xylose but not d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannose or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Utilizes adonitol, d-cellobiose, glucose, dulcitol, fumaric acid, d-glucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, lactic acid, maltose, d-levulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, sucrose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, d-xylose, l-aspargine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-threonine, l-valine, oxalate and phenanthrene as sole carbon sources but not l-arabinose, acetate, citrate, dextran, ethanolamine, d-fructose, fumaric acid, d-galactose, glycerol, d-melibiose, pyruvate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, adenine, cytosine, guanine, thymidine, nicotinic acid, tartaric acid or indole.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to carbencillin (100 μg disc), ceftriaxone (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), erythromycin (2 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin (10 U), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), sulfisoxazole (300 μg) and sulfathiazole (300 μg), but resistant to aztreonam (30 μg), bacitracin (10 U), cephalothin (30 μg), colistin (10 μg), ethanbutol (50 μg), ethionamide (25 μg), nitrofurantoin (150 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), tetracycline (30 μg), trimethoprim (5 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Methanol extracts of the type strain exhibit absorption maxima at 315, 363, 465, 493 and 519 nm.</s><s>Phosphate buffer suspensions (0·1 M, pH 7·4) absorb maximally at 354, 415, 465, 505 and 536 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain CP2C<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1043<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16746<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a BSC in the Colorado Plateau, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>