<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1564_nm.10921" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10921" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10921" rank="species">Paenibacillus sepulcri</organism><reference id="rid.1564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Smerda</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedlácek</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pácová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krejcí</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Havel</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus sepulcri sp. nov., isolated from biodeteriorated mural paintings in the Servilia tomb</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2341</fpage><lpage>2344</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64280-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012558</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus sepulcri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus sepulcri</em> (se.pul′cri. L. gen. neut. n. <em>sepulcri</em> from a tomb, pertaining to the place of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-variable, facultatively anaerobic rods.</s><s>Spores are oval and are positioned subterminally in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Moderately psychrotolerant.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10–30 °C, but no growth occurs at 37 °C; the optimum is 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–8.0; the optimum is between pH 7.2 and 7.4.</s><s>Tolerates up to 2 % NaCl, but not 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, smooth, slightly convex with complete edges and colourless.</s><s>Tests positive for catalase, oxidase, lecithinase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase and tests negative for arginine dihydrolase, DNase, haemolysis and citrate utilization.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and hippurate but not casein, starch, urea, gelatin, Tween 80 or tyrosine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, rhamnose, mannitol, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-turanose, l-fucose and 5-ketogluconate, but not from glycerol, erythritol, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, d-fructose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, inulin, starch, xylitol, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite and is negative for the production of acetoin and indole.</s><s>Hydrolysis of agar is not observed.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Cell-wall analysis reveals <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The natural habitat is unknown.</s><s>The type strain, CCM 7311<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 19508<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from biodeteriorated mural paintings in the Servilia tomb at the Roman necropolis of Carmona in Seville, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>