<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12857_nm.22664" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22664" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22664" rank="species">Tolumonas osonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12857"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Caldwell</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allen T.D.</surname><given-names /></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tolumonas osonensis sp. nov., isolated from anoxic freshwater sediment, and emended description of the genus Tolumonas</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2659</fpage><lpage>2663</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023853-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21148672</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tolumonas osonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tolumonas osonensis</em> (o.so.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>osonensis</em> pertaining to Oso Creek, Corpus Christi, Texas, USA, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, Gram-negative rods (2.4–3.6 µm long and 0.9 µm wide) and are found singly, in pairs or occasionally in short chains.</s><s>Facultative anaerobe.</s><s>Grows at 15–37 °C (optimum, 22 °C) and pH 5.5–8.5 (optimum, pH 7.5).</s><s>Vitamins or yeast extract are not required for growth.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, cellobiose, melezitose, maltose, lactose, galactose, sucrose, ribose, raffinose, melibiose, trehalose, mannose, turanose, glycogen, mannitol, sorbitol, amygdalin, pyruvate, fumarate, salicin, aesculin, inulin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and yeast extract are used as growth substrates.</s><s>Arabinose, xylose, glycerol, starch, inositol, adonitol, malate, glycolate, choline, betaine, trimethylamine, formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, lactate, succinate, methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, n-butanol, peptone, tryptone, Casamino acids, H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> and CO/CO<sub>2</sub> are not utilized.</s><s>Urea is hydrolysed, but cellulose, gelatin, chitin and starch are not.</s><s>Nitrate and sulfate are not reduced.</s><s>End products from glucose are formate, acetate, ethanol and lactate.</s><s>Toluene is not formed from phenylacetate, phenylalanine, phenylsuccinate, phenylbutyrate or phenoxyacetate in the presence of glucose.</s><s>Phenol is not formed from tyrosine or phenoxyacetate.</s><s>Under oxic conditions, catabolizes the following organic substrates when analysed with the 24 h Biolog GN2 MicroPlate: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and turanose.</s><s>Using the API Rapid ID 32A kit, positive reactions are observed for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, arginine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase (weak), alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s><s>Furthermore, mannose and raffinose are fermented.</s><s>Activity is not detected for urease, arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase-6-phosphate, α-arabinosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, α-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>In addition, indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Using the API ZYM kit, positive enzyme activities are high for β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase, moderate for esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, α-galactosidase and α-glucosidase and weak for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> (and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative when grown aerobically.</s><s>The respiratory quinone under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions is menaquinone MK-8.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is OCF 7<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22975<sup>T</sup>  = ATCC BAA-1908<sup>T</sup>), isolated from anoxic sediment of a freshwater creek.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>