<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5918_nm.8699" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8699" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8699" rank="species">Methylobacterium aquaticum</organism><reference id="rid.5918"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium hispanicum sp. nov. and Methylobacterium aquaticum sp. nov., isolated from drinking water</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>281</fpage><lpage>287</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63319-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653888</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium aquaticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium aquaticum</em> (a.qua′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>aquaticum</em> living in water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 1·5–1·7×4·5–8·0 μm, occurring singly, in pairs or in rosettes.</s><s>Cells are motile, non-spore-forming and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are pink to red, convex, not translucent, with regular edges, slow growing and 1–2 mm in diameter after 5 days at 28 °C on PCA.</s><s>Cells do not grow in the presence of 1·0 % NaCl or higher.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C (optimal temperature 28 °C) and at pH 5·0–7·0 (optimal pH 6·0).</s><s>Catalase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Oxidase is negative.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer are negative.</s><s>Starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, aesculin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not form hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Produces acid oxidatively from d-arabinose but not from d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose or maltose.</s><s>Methanol, formate and formaldehyde are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, nitrate, aspartate and glutamate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): Tween 40, Tween 80, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, l-asparagine and l-glutamic acid.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenyl acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Isolated from drinking water.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67·3–67·9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain GR16<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5998<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7218<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16371<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108333<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain GR16<sup>T</sup> is 67·5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>