<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12085_nm.20068" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20068" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20068" rank="species">Meiothermus granaticius</organism><reference id="rid.12085"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Meiothermus granaticius sp. nov., a new slightly thermophilic red-pigmented species from the Azores</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>246</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.04.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20451341</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>M. granaticius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Meiothermus granaticius</em> (gra.na.ti’ci.us. L. masc. adj. granaticius, pertaining to pomegranate and to the ruby red color of the pomegranate grains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms rod-shaped cells of variable length with a minimum length of about 1.5 μm and a maximum of about 10.0 μm and 0.8–1.0 μm in width.</s><s>Gram stain is negative.</s><s>The cells are non-motile and spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on <em>Thermus</em> medium are red-pigmented and 0.5–0.8 mm in diameter after 72 h of growth.</s><s>Large aggregates of cells form during growth in the liquid media examined.</s><s>Growth occurred in the range 30–55 °C.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is between 45 and 50 °C; growth does not occur at 25 or 60 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH is about 7.0–8.0; growth does not occur at pHs 6.0 or 9.5.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is menaquinone 8.</s><s>The major polar lipids are PL-2 and GL-1 variant designated GL-1b.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:0 anteiso, 17:0 iso, 15:0 iso and 17:0 anteiso.</s><s>Aerobic and heterotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and DNAse positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hippurate, arbutin and gelatine are hydrolyzed, but xylan is not.</s><s>Degradation of esculin, starch and casein is weakly positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C 4), esterase lipase (C 8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase test positive in API ZYM; other activities test negative. d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, d-mannitol, myo-inositol, lactate, acetate, succinate, malate, fumarate and l-glutamine are assimilated; l-rhamnose, l-fucose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, d-raffinose, d-melizitose, glycerol, ribitol, xylitol, d-sorbitol, erythritol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, α-ketoglutarate, pyruvate, citrate, benzoate, formate, d-gluconate, d-glucoronate, aspartate, glutamate, l-alanine, l-aspargine, glycine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-proline, l-arginine, l-serine, l-valine, l-phenylalanine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-ornithine, methionine and l-threonine are not assimilated.</s><s>The DNA of strain AF-68<sup>T</sup> has a G + C content of 63.5 ± 0.3 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain AF-68<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 23260<sup>T</sup> = LMG 25524<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from a runoff of the hot spring known as Área da Fonte 1825, Furnas, on the Island of São Miguel in the Azores.</s><s>Strain AF-49 (=DSM 23259 = LMG 25525) is an additional strain of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>