<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12561_nm.5813" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5813" rank="genus">Arcanobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.12561"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siering</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comparative chemotaxonomic and phylogenetic studies on the genus Arcanobacterium Collins et al. 1982 emend. Lehnen et al. 2006: proposal for Trueperella gen. nov. and emended description of the genus Arcanobacterium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1265</fpage><lpage>1274</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020032-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20622055</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Arcanobacterium</em> Collins <em>et al.</em> 1983, emend. Lenen <em>et al.</em> 2006</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arcanobacterium</em> (Ar.ca.no.bac.te′ri.um. L. adj. <em>arcanus</em> secretive; L. neut. n. <em>bakterium</em> a small rod; N. L. neut. n. <em>Arcanobacterium</em> secretive bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data of Collins <em>et al.</em> (1982b), Lehnen <em>et al.</em> (2006) and the present study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On blood agar plates cells are slender, irregular and predominately rod-shaped or arranged at an angle to give V-formations during the first 18 h of growth, becoming granular and segmented, resembling small, irregular cocci over time.</s><s>Both rod-shaped and coccoid cells are Gram-reaction-positive, non-acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth is considerably enhanced in an atmosphere of CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth is sparse on ordinary media but enhanced on blood- or serum-containing media.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Unable to withstand heating at 60 °C for 15 min.</s><s>CAMP-test positive.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the type A5α, variation l-Lys–l-Lys–d-Glu.</s><s>The muramic acid residue of the peptidoglycan is <em>N</em>-acetylated.</s><s>Characteristic whole-cell sugars are rhamnose and glucose.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>Long-chain fatty acids are primarily straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated as well as branched-chain iso-/anteiso-types.</s><s>The phospholipid type is type PI according to Lechevalier <em>et al.</em> (1977), comprising DPG, PG, PI but without PGL.</s><s>The principal menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50–57 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Arcanobacterium haemolyticum.</em></s></p></content></protolog>