<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10109_nm.15068" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15068" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15068" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter rigui</organism><reference id="rid.10109"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter rigui sp. nov., isolated from wetland freshwater, and emended description of the genus Mucilaginibacter</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>134</fpage><lpage>139</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011130-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648338</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter rigui</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter rigui</em> (ri.gu′i. L. gen. n. <em>rigui</em> of a well-watered place).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, non-endospore-forming, non-motile, aerobic rods, 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter and 1.0–1.7 μm long, occurring singly or in pairs (Supplementary Fig. S1 available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>No cyclic cell shape change is noticed during culture.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, convex with entire margins, mucoid, translucent, pale pink and approximately 3.0 mm in diameter after 3 days at 25 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A, MM1, PCA and TSA, but only weak growth occurs on NA.</s><s>Large amounts of extracellular polymeric substances are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–10 (optimum, pH 6–7) and at 4–37 °C (optimum, 25 °C).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 1 % (w/v).</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tween 20, but negative for hydrolysis of alginate, casein, cellulose, chitin, CM-cellulose, pectin, starch, Tween 80, l-tyrosine and xylan.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, lactose, maltose, mannose and sucrose, but not from cellobiose, fructose, glucose, rhamnose, xylan and xylose.</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20E and 20NE systems) for acetoin production, aesculin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetyglucosamine, glucose, mannose and maltose.</s><s>Negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease activities, utilization of citrate, production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction, oxidation of amygdalin, arabinose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol and sucrose, fermentation of glucose, and assimilation of adipate, arabinose, caprate, potassium gluconate, malate, mannitol, phenylacetate and trisodium citrate.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, melibiose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose; acid is not produced from d-adonitol, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d- or l-fucose, gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol or d- or l-xylose.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase activities are present; but <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and trypsin activities are absent.</s><s>Positive for Biolog GN2 MicroPlate substrates <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, dextrin, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β-</em>d-glucoside, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose, but negative for acetic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, adonitol, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, bromosuccinic acid, 2,3-butanediol, d- and l-carnitine, citric acid, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, i-erythritol, formic acid, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, d-glucuronic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycerol, d- and l-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glycogen, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-hydroxyproline, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d- and l-lactic acid, l-leucine, malonic acid, d-mannitol, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, phenylethylamine, l-proline, propionic acid, d-psicose, putrescine, l-pyroglutamic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, quinic acid, l-rhamnose, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, d- and l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, l-threonine, thymidine, Tweens 40 and 80, uridine, urocanic acid and xylitol.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), nalidixic acid (30), rifampicin (5) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), aztreonam (30), cephalothin (30), cefepime (30), cefmetazole (30), cefotaxime (30), ceftazidime (30), ceftriaxone (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), imipenem (10), isepamicin (30), kanamycin (30), lincomycin (2), moxalactam (30), nitrofurantoin (300), oxacillin (1), penicillin (10 IU), piperacillin (100), streptomycin (100), teicoplanin (30), ticarcillin/clavulanic acid (75/10), tobramycin (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;25 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The complete fatty acid composition is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47 mol%.</s><s>The only respiratory quinone detected is menaquinone 7 (MK-7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is WPCB133<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12534<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 101115<sup>T</sup>), isolated from freshwater of Woopo wetland, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>