<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12905_nm.22725" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22725" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22725" rank="species">Vibrio maritimus</organism><reference id="rid.12905"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chimetto</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moreira</surname><given-names>A.P.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brocchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio variabilis sp. nov. and Vibrio maritimus sp. nov., isolated from Palythoa caribaeorum</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3009</fpage><lpage>3015</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026997-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21296931</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio maritimus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio maritimus</em> (ma.ri′ti.mus. L. masc. adj. <em>maritimus</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 1 µm wide and 1.5–4.0 µm long, Gram-negative, motile bacilli.</s><s>Forms translucent, convex, smooth-rounded colonies with entire margins, 1 mm in size and beige in colour after 1 day incubation at 28 °C on TSA.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 37 °C, at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–8.0 % (w/v) and at pH 5–12.</s><s>Weak growth is observed in the presence of 8 % NaCl and at pH 5.</s><s>No growth is observed in 0 or ≥9 % NaCl, at temperatures ≤7 or ≥40 °C, or at pH ≥4.</s><s>Yellow colonies are able to grow on the selective medium TCBS (positive for acid production from sucrose).</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 28–37 °C, in 1.5–6.0 % NaCl and at pH 7–10.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, lipase (C14), indole production, fermentation of glucose, mannitol, sucrose, amygdalin and inositol, nitrate reduction to nitrite, and assimilation of dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, d-glucuronic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, dl-carnitine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Negative for α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer), reduction of nitrate to N<sub>2</sub> gas, fermentation of sorbitol, melibiose, arabinose and rhamnose, and assimilation of α-cyclodextrin, citrate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, l-rhamnose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>Weak reactions are observed for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, valine arylamidase and α-hydroxybutyric acid assimilation.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in small amounts: C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I, an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain-length of 10.928 and/or C<sub>12 : 0</sub> ALDE), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R-40493<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25439<sup>T</sup> = CAIM 1455<sup>T</sup>), isolated from mucus of the zoanthid <em>Palythoa caribaeorum</em> in Portinho Beach, São Sebastião Channel, São Paulo, Brazil.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain R-40493<sup>T</sup> is 46.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>