<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8380_nm.13735" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13735" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13735" rank="species">Leptobacterium flavescens</organism><reference id="rid.8380"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mitra</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haga</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yasumoto-Hirose</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leptobacterium flavescens gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine member of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from marine sponge and seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>212</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004358-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196755</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leptobacterium flavescens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leptobacterium flavescens</em> (fla.ves′cens. L. part. adj. <em>flavescens</em> becoming golden–yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are approximately 0.5–0.6 μm wide and 8.5–9.0 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, flat with entire edges and pale-yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs at 17–30 °C (optimally at 25–30 °C).</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–9 (optimum, around pH 6–7).</s><s>NaCl is required for growth and can be tolerated up to 4 % (w/v).</s><s>In API 20E strips, gelatin and tryptophan are hydrolysed, but tests for the Voges–Proskauer reaction, citrate utilization, urea hydrolysis and the production of ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide and indole give negative results.</s><s>In API 50 CH strips, acid is produced from aesculin-ferric citrate, maltose, 5-ketogluconate and d-arabinose, but not from l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, galactose, glucose, fructose, ribose, mannose, rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, inulin, raffinose, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, glycerol, erythritol, adonitol, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API ZYM strips, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, but esterase, esterase lipase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The major fatty acids are i15 : 0, i15 : 1 and i17 : 0 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YM3-301<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22160<sup>T</sup>=MBIC 06275<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104141<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sponge <em>Clathria</em> (<em>Microciona</em>) <em>eurypa</em> collected at Iwayama Bay on Koror Island, Republic of Palau.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>