<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.750_nm.7529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7529" rank="subspecies">Nocardiopsis dassonvillei prasina</organism><reference id="rid.750"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miyashita</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikami</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arai</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alkalophilic actinomycete, Nocardiopsis dassonvillei subsp. prasina subsp. nov. isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>405</fpage><lpage>409</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-405</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i> subsp. <i>prasina</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i> subsp. <i>prasina</i> (pra.si'na. Gr. adj. <i>prasina</i> leek green, referring to the mature aerial mycelium color)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The presence of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and the absence of diagnostically important sugars in whole-cell hydrolysates, the absence of glycine in the cell walls, a type PIII phospholipid pattern, a menaquinone system composed of MK-10s, the development of aerial mycelia with long spore chains, and fragmentation of substrate mycelia identify strains 153, 161, 164, and 208<sup>T</sup> as members of the genus <i>Nocardiopsis</i> Meyer (16).</s><s>Nocardiopsis syringae (5), <i>Nocardiopsis mutabilis</i> (12), and <i>Nocardiopsis atra</i> (W.</s><s>D .</s><s>Celmer et al., U.</s><s>S. patent 55194C, July 1980) have been reported as new antibiotic producers.</s><s>However, <i>N. atra</i> and <i>N. mutabilis</i> were easily differentiated from our isolates by physiological characteristics (Table 4). <i>N. syringae</i> also differed from our isolates by producing dark brown substrate mycelium on organic media (5).</s><s>Our isolates were closely related to but easily distinguished from <i>N. dassonvillei</i> Meyer 1976.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Therefore, on the basis of the results presented above, we believe that strains 153, 161, 164, and 208<sup>T</sup> should be considered a new subspecies of <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i>, for which we propose the name <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i> subsp. prasina.</s><s>Type strain is strain 208 (=JCM 3336).</s><s>This subspecies is easily differentiated from other strains of <i>N. dassonvillei</i> by its apparently higher optimum pH for growth and by its lack of ability to utilize maltose and rhamnose as sole carbon sources.</s></p></content></protolog>