<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6791_nm.3821" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3821" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3821" rank="species">Arcobacter skirrowii</organism><reference id="rid.6791"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mels</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vlaes</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van den Borre</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomic study of the emended genus Arcobacter with Arcobacter butzleri comb. nov. and Arcobacter skirrowii sp. nov., an aerotolerant bacterium isolated from veterinary specimens.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>344</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-344</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503968</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arcobacter skirrowii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arcobacter skirrowii</i> (ski.ro'wi.i.) N. L. gen. n. <i>skirrowii</i>, of Skirrow, in honor of M. B. Skirrow, a British microbiologist who was the first to describe a simple isolation technique for <i>Campylobacter jejuni</i> obtained from stool specimens, which enabled most routine laboratories to culture the organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 1 to 3 μm long and 0.2 to 0.4 μm wide.</s><s>After 3 days of incubation on blood agar, colonies are 2 to 3 mm in diameter and greyish and have a flat irregular shape on moist media.</s><s>Most characteristics are as given above for the genus.</s><s>Additional characteristics are given below.</s><s>Most strains produce alpha-hemolysis on blood agar.</s><s>Growth occurs on VB medium; no growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 1% oxgall.</s><s>No production of hydrogen sulfide from cysteine.</s><s>Most strains (14 of 18 strains tested) grow in the presence of 1% glycine.</s><s>Most strains (17 of 18 strains tested) do not grow in the presence of 0.04% TTC and 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to nalidixic acid (30-μg discs), and most strains (14 of 18 strains tested) are susceptible to cephalothin (30-μg discs).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition of <i>A. skirrowii</i> is 29 to 30 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 12:0, 14:O 30H, 16:1 cis 9, 16:1 trans 9, 16:0, and 18:1 cis 11.</s><s>Additional fatty acids that are present in smaller quantities are 14:1 cis 7, 14:0, and an unidentified fatty acid with an equivalent chain length of 15.276.</s></p><p class="description"><s>So far, <i>A. skirrowii</i> strains have been isolated mainly from preputial fluids of bulls; the other strains are bovine, porcine, and ovine isolates obtained from aborted fetuses and diarrheic feces.</s><s>The clinical significance of this new species remains to be established.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain LMG 6621 (= Skirrow 449/80 = CCUG 10374), which was isolated from the feces of a lamb with diarrhea.</s><s>Characteristics of the type strain are summarized in Table 4.</s><s>Its G+C content is 29 mol%.</s><s>All of our <i>A. skirrowii</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Ghent, Ghent, Belgium.</s></p></content></protolog>