<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3514_nm.6246" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6246" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6246" rank="species">Corynebacterium mooreparkense</organism><reference id="rid.3514"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brennan</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beresford</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Simpson</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cogan</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium mooreparkense sp. nov. and Corynebacterium casei sp. nov., isolated from the surface of a smear-ripened cheese</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>843</fpage><lpage>852</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411705</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium mooreparkense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium mooreparkense</i> (moore.par.ken'se. N. L. gen. n. <i>mooreparkense</i> of Moorepark, named because the organism was isolated at the Dairy Products Research Centre, Moorepark, Fermoy, County Cork, Ireland)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the biochemical and morphological characteristics was based on results for 10 isolates.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming, partially acid-fast, irregularly shaped rods, 1-3 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies on Funke media are cream, circular, matt, entire and low-concave, 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, ribose, mannose and fructose but not from glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, galactose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Urea and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin, tyrosine and ONPG, and the Christie-Atkins-Munch-Petersen reaction, are negative.</s><s>Esterase, esterase/lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase and tryptophan deaminase activities are present in the organism.</s><s>The isolates do not possess valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase, β-galactosidase, pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, trypsin, naphthol-AS-β1-phosphohydrolase, N-acetylglucosaminidase or α-fucosidase activity.</s><s>All strains produce acetoin from pyruvate and methanethiol from methionine.</s><s>The cell wall of strains of <i>Corynebacterium mooreparkense</i> sp. nov. was found to be type IV, containing <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose and short-chain mycolic acids (C<sub>22</sub> to C<sub>36</sub>).</s><s>The menaquinones in the cell wall are of the MK-9 (H<sub>2</sub>) type.</s><s>Analysis of polar lipid of the cell wall revealed the presence of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylglycerol mannosides.</s><s>The G+C content of the isolates is 60 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMG S-19265<sup>T</sup> (=DPC 5310<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>