<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1815_nm.10841" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10841" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10841" rank="species">Maribius pelagius</organism><reference id="rid.1815"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lanoil</surname><given-names>B.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Maribius salinus gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a solar saltern and Maribius pelagius sp. nov., cultured from the Sargasso Sea, belonging to the Roseobacter clade</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>270</fpage><lpage>275</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64552-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267963</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Maribius pelagius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Maribius pelagius</em> (pe.la′gi.us. L. masc. adj. <em>pelagius</em> of or belonging to the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.8 μm wide and 1.3–2.8 μm long.</s><s>Growth occurs within the temperature range of 10–40 °C (optimum 30–35 °C), at pH values of between 6 and 9 and at sea salt concentrations of 2–15 % (w/v).</s><s>Gives a positive result in tests for amylase, urease, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities, hydrolysis of Tween 80 and aesculin hydrolysis and glucose acidification.</s><s>Negative results in tests for DNase, gelatinase, nitrate reductase, alkaline and acid phosphatases, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and arginine dihydrolase activities and for indole production.</s><s>Several fatty acids, including 18 : 0, 3-OH 10 : 0 and ECL 11.799 are present at &#x003E;1 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on citrate, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-ribose, d-xylose, ethanol, glycerol, l-arginine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and pyruvic acid.</s><s>No growth occurs on d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, formic acid, glycine, l-glutamate, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-rhamnose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sucrose or succinate.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to gentamicin, cephalexin, vancomycin, mitomycin, kanamycin, penicillin, erythromycin, tetracycline, chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, ampicillin and streptomycin, but resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 66.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B5-6<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42336<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14009<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water of the Sargasso Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>