<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8240_nm.14188" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14188" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14188" rank="species">Enterovibrio nigricans</organism><reference id="rid.8240"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Enterovibrio nigricans sp. nov., reclassification of Vibrio calviensis as Enterovibrio calviensis comb. nov. and emended description of the genus Enterovibrio Thompson et al. 2002.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>698</fpage><lpage>704</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001990-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329591</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterovibrio nigricans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterovibrio nigricans</em> (ni′gri.cans. L. part. adj. <em>nigricans</em> blackish).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, motile rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Cells are 1.0–1.5 μm long and 0.4–0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and facultatively anaerobic, able to ferment glucose without gas production under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Some strains reduce nitrate to nitrite, but not to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Able to grow on seawater-based media such as MA, on which some strains produce a black/deep-brown, slightly diffusible pigment.</s><s>Colonies are round, with entire margins and a bright surface.</s><s>They also grow on TSA supplemented with 1 % NaCl.</s><s>They do not swarm or luminesce.</s><s>Growth on TCBS agar is scarce and slow, producing green (non-sucrose-fermenting) colonies.</s><s>Growth is observed at 15–28 °C but not at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth.</s><s>Media containing 0.9–6.0 % total salinity sustain good growth; no growth is observed at 0.4 or 7 % or more salinity.</s><s>In O/F medium, acid is produced under anaerobic conditions from d-mannose, sucrose (weakly) and melibiose (weakly and only strain 8/6b).</s><s>The following carbohydrates are not fermented: d-ribose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, trehalose, l-rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, amygdalin, salicin, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol and <em>myo</em>-inositol.</s><s>Under aerobic conditions, strain 8/6b, but not DAl 1-1-4 or DAl 1-1-5<sup>T</sup>, produces acid from d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, melibiose, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>None of the known strains is able to hydrolyse casein, gelatin, starch, alginate or lecithin.</s><s>Tween 80 and DNA are degraded, the latter weakly.</s><s>Thornley's arginine dihydrolase test is variable.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, indole and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Carbon sources that support growth are d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, d-gluconate and l-glutamate.</s><s>The use of d-ribose, d-fructose, fumarate, acetate, lactate and glycerol is variable among strains.</s><s>No growth is observed on l-arabinose, d-xylose, trehalose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, salicin, amygdalin, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-glycerate, d-saccharate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, pyruvate, propionate, butyrate, citrate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 2-oxoglutarate, succinate, malate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, glycine, l-leucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-tyrosine, l-ornithine, l-citrulline, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-sarcosine or putrescine.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-15 : 0 2-OH (43–50 % in known strains), 16 : 0 (18–19 %) and 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (11–15 %).</s><s>Minor amounts (1–5 %) of the following fatty acids are also detectable: 12 : 0, 12 : 0 3-OH, 14 : 0, 14 : 0 3-OH/iso-16 : 1 I, iso-16 : 0 and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DAl 1-1-5<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7320<sup>T</sup> =CAIM 661<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the head kidney of <em>Sparus aurata</em> cultured on the Spanish Mediterranean coast.</s><s>The type strain produces black pigment, is negative for arginine dihydrolase and positive for nitrate reduction and has a DNA G+C content of 47.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>