<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7118_nm.1754" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1754" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1754" rank="species">Bordetella trematum</organism><reference id="rid.7118"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bordetella trematum sp. nov., isolated from wounds and ear infections in humans, and reassessment of Alcaligenes denitrificans Rüger and Tan 1983.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>849</fpage><lpage>858</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-849</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863408</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bordetella trematum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bordetella trematum</i> (tre.ma'tum. Gr. neut. n. <i>trema</i>, referring to something pierced or penetrated, an aperture, or a gap; N. L. gen. pl. n. <i>trematum</i>, pertaining to penetrated or open things, referring to the presence of these bacteria in wounds and other exposed parts of the human body)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>B. trematum</i> cells are gram-negative, non-spore-forming, capsulated rods that are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Motility does not differ significantly when cells are grown at 25, 30, or 37°C.</s><s>In 16- to 24-h-old cultures on blood agar, the average cell is 0.5 to 0.6 μm wide and 1 to 1.8 μm long; the longest rods are up to 2.4 μm long.</s><s>Strains produce convex, circular, and greyish cream white colonies with entire edges on blood agar.</s><s>The strains do not require special growth factors and grow on conventional media.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited at an incubation temperature of 4TC, but is reduced markedly at 25°C.</s><s>Strains grow microaerobically, but not anaerobically.</s><s>Colonies grown for 16 to 24 h on transparent D.</s><s>S.</s><s>T. agar at 37°C exhibit greenish yellow to yellow-red iridescence in obliquely transmitted light under a stereomicroscope.</s><s>Other biochemical characteristics are described above and in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fatty acid components of all of the strains examined are 12:0 2OH (about 3%), 14:0 2OH (about 5%), 16:0 (about 37%), 17:0 cyclo (about 32%), 16:0 2OH (about 2%), 18:O (about 4%), and summed feature 3 (probably 14:0 3OH) (about 10%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have been isolated from ear infections and wounds of humans, but not from respiratory systems.</s><s>Pathogenic significance is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is between 64 and 65 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is strain LMG 13506, which was isolated from a chronic ear infection in Germany.</s><s>Its G+C content is 65 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>B. trematum</i> strains have been deposited in the Laboratorium Microbiologie Gent Culture Collection.</s></p></content></protolog>