<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1324_nm.4276" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4276" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4276" rank="species">Eubacterium timidum</organism><reference id="rid.1324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burmeister</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Descriptions of Eubacterium timidum sp. nov., Eubacterium brachy sp. nov., and Eubacterium nodatum sp. nov. isolated from human periodontitis.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>163</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-1-163</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium timidum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium timidum</i> (ti'mi.dum. L. neut. adj. <i>timidum</i> fearful, timid [referring to the slight or slow growth in clumps])</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile, gram-positive rods that are regular to slightly diphtheroid in shape.</s><s>Cells from PY-glucose broth cultures were 0.8 to 1.6 by 1.6 to 3.1 μm.</s><s>Cells were often arranged in clumps.</s><s>Cells from actively growing cultures were gram positive; they often stained gram negative from older cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days in roll tubes (either enriched BHIA or chopped meat broth agar), colonies of all strains were 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter, lenticular, and transparent to translucent.</s><s>After incubation for 2 days, surface colonies on BHIA or BHIA blood streak tubes were 0.2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, and transparent to translucent.</s><s>Four of five strains tested did not grow on the surface of anaerobic blood agar plates.</s><s>No hemolysis was produced around colonies on the BAP by the one strain that grew.</s><s>Five of five strains tested grew on the surface of anaerobically incubated egg yolk agar plates, but they did not grow on egg yolk agar plates incubated in an aerobic atmosphere enriched with carbon dioxide to 5%.</s><s>Surface colonies on plates were similar to those in streak tubes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Broth cultures of all strains usually had only a small amount of smooth or slightly granular sediment and no, or only very slight, turbidity.</s><s>Growth of all strains was inhibited by 2% oxgall but was neither inhibited nor enhanced by the addition of 0.02% Tween 80, 5% lumen fluid, or 10% serum with cocarboxylase.</s><s>Growth of all strains occurred only in the anaerobic portion of agar deep cultures.</s><s>The type strain and five other strains tested (each from a different person) grew equally well at 37 and 45°C but did not grow at 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because the strains grew very poorly in all broth media tested, we were unable to obtain enough cells to extract DNA for a determination of the G+C content.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and fermentation products.</s><s>Distinctive characteristics of the species are presented in Table 2.</s><s>No strain produced ammonia from arginine or in PY broth cultures.</s><s>No gas was detected in agar deep cultures.</s><s>Growth of the type strain and five other strains tested was inhibited by 6.5% NaCl but was not inhibited by 0.05% SPS.</s><s>Neither lecithinase nor lipase was produced on egg yolk agar plates by the six strains tested.</s><s>Neutral red was reduced by six strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only trace amounts (0.07 to 0.09 meq/1OO ml) of acetate, formate, or succinate were detected from PY or PY-glucose cultures of all strains after incubation for 2 to 7 days.</s><s>No, or only slight, hydrogen was detected in the headspace gas of all strains.</s><s>Neither pyruvate nor lactate was utilized by the type strain or by five other strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and 29 other strains tested were susceptible to the test levels of chloramphenicol, clindamycin, and erythromycin; two were resistant to 2 U of penicillin G per ml, and eight were resistant to 6 μg of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is VPI D1B-22 (=ATCC 33093), which was isolated from a subgingival area which exhibited periodontitis.</s><s>The inability of <i>E. timidum</i> to use arginine as a substrate and the shape and arrangement of the cells differentiated <i>E. timidum</i> from <i>E. lentum</i>, the species of <i>Eubacterium</i> which it most closely resembles.</s><s>The inability of <i>E. timidum</i> to ferment any of the carbohydrate substrates tested differentiated it from members of the genus <i>Actinomyces</i>, which it resembled somewhat in cellular morphology.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. timidum</i> was detected in 42% of the subgingival samples and constituted 3 to 57% of the cultivable flora in those specimens from which it was isolated.</s><s>It was isolated from 19% of the supragingival samples examined, where it represented 3 to 13% of the flora.</s></p></content></protolog>