<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8460_nm.13443" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13443" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13443" rank="species">Microbulbifer halophilus</organism><reference id="rid.8460"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbulbifer halophilus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium from north-west China.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2036</fpage><lpage>2040</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65519-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768600</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbulbifer halophilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbulbifer halophilus</em> (ha.lo.phi′lus. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>halophilus</em> salt-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative rods, motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish-brown, smooth, opaque and mucoid on modified ISP 5 medium.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing in a wide range (1–20 % w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimal growth at 10 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C and pH 6.0–9.0, with optimal growth at 37 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, starch and Tweens 40 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, l-arabinose, d-fucose, d-glucose, glycogen, d-lactose, maltose, l-rhamnose, turanose, d-tagatose, starch, d-xylose, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not from d-adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, l-fucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, trehalose, xylitol, l-xylose or potassium gluconate.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase tests are positive.</s><s>Lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase tests are negative.</s><s>Q-8 is the predominant lipoquinone, at a peak area ratio of approximately 91.5 %.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 63.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 91118<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 206094<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 12848<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a saline soil sample in Xinjiang province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>