<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1309_nm.5495" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5495" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5495" rank="species">Carnobacterium mobile</organism><reference id="rid.1309"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferusu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Lactobacillus divergens, Lactobacillus piscicola, and some catalase-negative asporogenous, rod-shaped bacteria from poultry in a new genus, Carnobacterium.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>310</fpage><lpage>316</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-310</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Carnobacterium mobile</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Carnobacterium mobile</i> (mo'bi.le. L. neut. adj. <i>mobile</i>, movable or motile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonsporeforming, straight, slender rods which occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are motile.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, shiny, and circular.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0 and 35°C (some strains do not grow at 37°C) but not at 40°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>L-(+)-Lactic acid is produced heterofermentatively.</s><s>Gas production from glucose is observed for most strains in arginine-MRS broth.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, inulin, maltose, D-mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, amidon, amygdalin, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycogen, gluconate, inositol, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-turanose, D-xylose, L-xylose, and xylitol.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from β-gentiobiose, 2-ketogluconate, and D-tagatose.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze esculin and are arginine dihydrolase and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>All strains are lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan desaminase, and urease negative.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced, Voges-Proskauer negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types, with hexadecanoic, hexadecenoic, and 9,lO-octadecenoic acids predominating.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA ranges from 35.5 to 37.2 mol% (midpoint melting temperature [T<sub>m</sub>].</s><s>Isolated from irradiated chicken meat.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCFB 2765T (MT37L).</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to that of  the species, except that growth occurs at 37°C, acid is produced from β-gentiobiose, and acid is not produced from D-tagatose.</s></p></content></protolog>