<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1422_nm.9320" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9320" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9320" rank="species">Paenibacillus phyllosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.1422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus phyllosphaerae sp. nov., a xylanolytic bacterium isolated from the phyllosphere of Phoenix dactylifera</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>743</fpage><lpage>746</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63323-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774655</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus phyllosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus phyllosphaerae</em> (phyl.lo.sphae′rae. Gr. neut. n. <em>phyllon</em> leaf; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> ball, sphere; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>phyllosphaerae</em> of the phyllosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore-forming rods, 0·9–1·6 μm wide, 3·3–4·2 μm long.</s><s>Gram-variable.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in swollen sporangia and they are in subterminal position in cells.</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, chemo-organotrophic and xylanolytic bacterium.</s><s>Colonies on YED medium are circular, flat, whitish-cream, opaque and usually 1–3 mm in diameter within 48 h at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimal growth occurs at 28 °C) and optimal pH for growth is 7.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>The pH in Voges–Proskauer broth is 5·3.</s><s>Could not grow in the presence of 5 % NaCl.</s><s>The major quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The main fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Gas is not produced from d-glucose.</s><s>d-Glucose, glycerol, l-arabinose, d-xylose, galactose, d-fructose, mannitol, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, <em>β</em>-gentobiose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, xylan, carboxymethyl cellulose and gentiobiose are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Assimilation of d-mannose, rhamnose and d-turanose is weakly positive.</s><s>In contrast, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 5-ketogluconate, adipate, caproate, citrate, phenylacetate and malate do not serve as carbon sources for growth.</s><s>Xylanase, cellulase, amylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are produced actively, but caseinase, arginine dihydrolase, indole, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, phenylalanine deaminase, tryptophan deaminase, hydrogen sulfide and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer medium) are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PALXIL04<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22192<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5862<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the phyllosphere of <em>Phoenix dactylifera</em> in Palma de Mallorca (Spain).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50·7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>