<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4564_nm.1679" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1679" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1679" rank="species">Ralstonia metallidurans</organism><reference id="rid.4564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Diels</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergeay</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of metal-resistant bacteria from industrial biotopes as Ralstonia campinensis sp. nov., Ralstonia metallidurans sp. nov. and Ralstonia basilensis Steinle et al. 1998 emend.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1773</fpage><lpage>1782</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ralstonia metallidurans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ralstonia metallidurans</i> (me.tal.li.du'rans. L.n. <i>metallum</i> metal; L. pres. part. <i>durans</i> enduring; N.L. part. adj. <i>metallidurans</i> enduring metal, to indicate that these strains are able to survive high heavy-metal concentrations)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short, motile rods (0.8x1.2-2.2 μm), single, in pairs or in short chains, forming round (sometimes with a slightly scalloped margin), smooth, flat, convex or umbonate and transparent colonies of about 0.5 mm diameter after 24 h of incubation on TSA at 30 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 20, 30 and 37 °C, but no growth detected at 4 or 41 °C.</s><s>An exception is AS2, which does grow at 41 °C.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced (CH34<sup>T</sup> reduces nitrate, but not nitrite ; VA1 and AS2 reduce neither nitrate nor nitrite).</s><s>No indole production from tryptophan.</s><s>No glucose fermentation.</s><s>Enzyme activities detected: alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Enzyme activities not detected: arginine dihydrolase, urease (AS2 and AS168 show a weak reaction after 48 h), α-glucosidase, protease, β-galactosidase, lipase  (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and fucosidase.</s><s>Assimilation of D-gluconate, caprate (except CH34<sup>T</sup>), adipate, L-malate and citrate (except CH34<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Most strains seem to be able to assimilate phenylacetate after 48 h of incubation [exceptions are AB2 and VA2 (weak assimilation even after 48 h) and CH34<sup>T</sup> (no assimilation)].</s><s>No assimilation of dglucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, <i>N</i>-acetyl D-glucosamine or maltose.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content is 63.7-63.9 mol%.</s><s>Major fatty acid components are 14:0 (4.4%), 16:0 (20.9%), 17:0 cyclo (3.2%), 18:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> (19.8%), 16:0 2OH (3.3%), 18:1 2OH (1.4%), summed feature 2 (11.3%) and summed feature 3 (34.2%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CH34<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 1195<sup>T</sup>=DSM 2839<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wastewater from a zinc factory at Liége, Belgium.</s><s>Its DNA G+­C content is 63.7 mol% and its phenotypic characteristics are as described above for the species, unless stated otherwise.</s><s>The accession number of its 16S rRNA gene sequence is Y10824.</s></p></content></protolog>