<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2374_nm.7674" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7674" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7674" rank="species">Glycomyces tenuis</organism><reference id="rid.2374"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taptykova</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Semyonova</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalakoutskii</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glycomyces tenuis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>154</fpage><lpage>157</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Glycomyces tenuis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Glycomyces tenuis</i> (te' nu. is. L. adj. <i>tenuis</i>, thin)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The vegetative hyphae are very thin (diameter, 0.15 to 0.40 μm), long, densely branched, and white or sometimes cream or slightly pink.</s><s>The spores, which are borne singly or in chains, are oval or spherical (0.3 to 0.6 by 0.4 to 0.8 μm) or (rarely) rod shaped (length, 0.3 to 0.7 μm); the spore diameter exceeds the hypha diameter (Fig. 1).</s><s>Aerial mycelium is not formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures grow well on rich organic media.</s><s>When cells are grown on synthetic media, yeast extract or Casamino Acids (0.3%) must be added.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature growth range is 10 to 40°C.</s><s>The cell wall chemotype is chemotype II (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glycine, arabinose, and xylose).</s><s>Glycerolteichoic acid is also present in the cell wall (5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains alanine, glutamic acid, glycine, <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glucosamine, and muramic acid (molar ratio, 1.0:1.1:0.85:1.0:1.07:2.0).</s><s>The glycine is probably combined with glutamic acid and arranged in a tetrapeptide chain, not in an interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The linkage of tetrapeptide chains is directly between the <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid of one chain and the terminal alanine of the other.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is type A1, (15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen-containing phospholipids are absent, although phosphatidylinositol, cardiolipin, and phosphatidylinositolmannoside are present (type PI phospholipid pattern).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The predominant fatty acids include the following saturated branched iso acids (up to 35% of the total fatty acids) and anteiso acids (up to 48% of the total fatty acids): 13-methyltetradecanoic acid (iso-15:O acid), 10.3%; 12-methyl-tetradecanoic acid (anteiso-15:O acid), 19.4%; 14-methyl-pentadecanoic acid (iso-160 acid), 23.1%; and 15-methyl-hexadecanoic (iso-17:0 acid), 24.0%.</s><s>The percentages of all other fatty acids are less than 10% (Table 2).</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are menaquinones with hexahydrogenated isoprenoid chains having 9, 10, and 11 isoprene units [MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-1O(H<sub>6</sub>), and MK-11(H<sub>6</sub>)].</s><s>The relative amounts of menaquinones MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>,H<sub>8</sub>), MK-1O(H<sub>4</sub>,H<sub>8</sub>), and MK-11(H<sub>4</sub>,H<sub>8</sub>) are noteworthy.</s><s>MK-7(H<sub>?</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>?</sub>) are present in trace quantities (the degree of hydrogenation was not determined) (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes arbutin, esculin, hypoxanthine, casein, starch, and hippurate; does not hydrolyze tyrosine or urea.</s><s>Utilizes as carbon sources and produces acid from L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-xylose, lactose, maltose, L-rhamnose, raffinose, sucrose, and D-fructose.</s><s>Does not produce acid from adonitol, D-arabinose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, sorbitol, or sorbose.</s><s>Decarboxylates acetate and lactate.</s><s>Does not utilize aconitate, benzoate, citrate, oxalate, malate, succinate, tartrate, formate, or fumarate; does not utilize alanine, histidine, or leucine as a nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not grow in lysozyme broth.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to 5 μg of oligomycin per ml, 1 μg of novobiocin per ml, and the following antibiotics at concentrations less than 1 μg/ml: carbenicillin, erythromycin, streptomycin, tetracycline, rifampin, and ristomycin.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 10 μg of streptomycin per ml, 5 μg of tobramycin per ml, 10 μg of erythromycin per ml, 1 μg of ristomycin per ml, 10<sup>-4</sup>% crystal violet, 0.01% phenol, 10<sup>-3</sup>% methylene blue, or 0.1% sodium azide.</s><s>No antibiotic activity is observed when the agar block method and test strains of <i>Bacillus mycoides</i>, <i>Escherichia coli</i>, <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i>, <i>Sarcina lutea</i>, and <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i> are used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from an association with <i>Streptomyces galilaeus</i> INA 5888, a soil isolate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>G. tenuis</i> is strain VKM Ac-1250 (=INA n-5888).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>G. tenuis</i> could be differentiated from <i>G. rutgersensis</i> and <i>G. harbinensis</i> by its thin hyphae (diameter 0.15 to 0.40 μm) with spore chains on the substrate mycelium, by its color, by the absence of aerial hyphae, and by its menaquinone composition.</s><s>A number of strain VKM Ac-1250<sup>T</sup> physiological characteristics were compared with those of two other <i>Glycomyces</i> species.</s><s>On the whole, <i>G. tenuis</i> is characterized by a broader spectrum of susceptibility to antibiotics and growth inhibitors compared with the type strains of <i>G. rutgersensis</i> and <i>G. garbinensis</i> and a narrower range of nutritional compounds utilized (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The low level of DNA-DNA relatedness between <i>G. tenuis</i> VKM Ac-1250<sup>T</sup> and <i>Streptomyces galilaeus</i> INA 5888, from which the former organism was isolated, suggests that the presence of spontaneous variants with altered cell wall chemotypes is unlikely.</s><s>Thus, as suggested previously (19), the possibility of perpetuation of two different organisms within a common actinomycete colony deserves the attention of workers interested in variability among actinomycetes.</s></p></content></protolog>