<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.54_nm.3361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3361" rank="species">Yersinia mollaretii</organism><reference id="rid.54"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wauters</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Yersinia mollaretii sp. nov. and Yersinia bercovieri sp. nov., formerly called Yersinia enterocolitica biogroups 3A and 3B.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>424</fpage><lpage>429</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-424</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Yersinia mollaretii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Yersinia mollaretii</i> (mol. la. ret' i. i. M. L. gen. n. <i>mollaretii</i>, in honor of Henri H. Mollaret, head of the National Yersinia Center at the Pasteur Institute in Paris, France, whose many years of valuable studies have greatly increased our knowledge and appreciation of classification and epidemiology in the genus <i>Yersinia</i> [see references 2, 4-6, 8, 10, and 19 for references and citations to his work])</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Yersinia mollaretii</i> was formerly called <i>Y. enterocolitica</i> biogroup 3A (4) and was later transferred to <i>Y. enterocolitica</i> biogroup 6 (21))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, fermentative rods that are motile by peritrichous flagella at 25°C but rarely motile at 36°C.</s><s>The species conforms to the definitions of the 'family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (9) and the genus <i>Yersinia</i> (6).</s><s>All strains grow on nutrient, tryptic soy, and MacConkey agar media.</s><s>Whitish, opaque colonies about 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter with smooth, entire edges are formed on nutrient agar after 24 h at 25 or 36°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Good growth in 1 day in tryptic soy, nutrient, and brain heart infusion broth media incubated at 25 or 36°C.</s><s>More metabolically active at 25°C than at 36°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive reactions at 25°C in tests for methyl red, urea hydrolysis, L-ornithine decarboxylase, acid production from mucate, esculin hydrolysis (delayed in most strains), Jordan tartrate, reduction of nitrates to nitrites (almost always contain nitratase B), <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, acetate utilization (often delayed), pyrazinamidase, proline peptidase, and acid production from fermentation of D-glucose, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, glycerol (may be delayed), maltose, D-mannitOl, D-mannose, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production, the Voges-Proskauer reaction, Simmons citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production on Kligler iron agar and peptone iron agar, phenylalanine deaminase, L-lysine decarboxylase, L-arginine dihydrolase, gelatin hydrolysis, growth in KCN broth, malonate utilization, Tween 80 esterase, deoxyribonuclease, pigment production, and acid production from adonitol, D-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, L-fucose, lactose, melibiose, α-CH<sub>2</sub>-D-glucoside, raffinose, and L-rhamnose.</s><s>Tetrathionate reduction is variable and is often delayed when positive, as are acid production from <i>i</i>- or <i>myo</i>-inositol and salicin.</s><s>A few strains produce small amounts of gas from D-glucose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50 to 51 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Y. mollaretii</i> strains have been isolated from human stool specimens, meat, raw vegetables, soil, and drinking water.</s><s>There is no evidence of pathogenicity for humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Y. mollaretii</i> is strain WAIP 204 (= CDC 2465-87 = CNY 7263 = ATCC 43969).</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 50 mol%.</s><s>It was isolated from soil in the United- States.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are given in Table 3.</s></p></content></protolog>