<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4439_nm.9246" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9246" rank="genus">Thioalkalivibrio</organism><reference id="rid.4439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sorokin</surname><given-names>D.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mityushina</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuenen</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thioalkalimicrobium aerophilum gen. nov., sp. nov. and Thioalkalimicrobium sibericum sp. nov., and Thioalkalivibrio versutus gen. nov., sp. nov., Thioalkalivibrio nitratis sp.nov., novel and Thioalkalivibrio denitrificancs sp. nov., novel obligately alkaliphilic and obligately chemolithoautotrophic sulfur-oxidizing bacteria from soda lakes.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>565</fpage><lpage>580</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321103</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thioalkalivibrio</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thioalkalivibrio</i> (Thi.o.al.kal.i.vi'bri.o. Gr. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; N.L. n. <i>alcali</i> Arabic <i>al</i> the; <i>qaliy</i> soda ash; L. v. <i>vibrio</i> vibrate ; M.L. n. <i>Thioalkalivibrio</i> sulfur alkaline vibrio)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are mostly vibroid, up to spirilla, 0.4-0.6x0.8-3.0 μm, motile with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Gramnegative; cell wall is usually highly rippled.</s><s>Most strains contain multiple carboxysomes in the centre of the cells.</s><s>Some strains are able to deposit globes of elemental sulfur in the periplasmic space.</s><s>Young colonies are bright white from heavy sulfur deposition which is gradually converted to soluble polysulfide-like compounds.</s><s>Matured colonies are usually yellow to orange-brown.</s><s>Obligately autotrophic sulfur-oxidizing bacteria.</s><s>Grows at pH 7.50-10.65 with an optimum at pH 10.0-10.2.</s><s>The maximum specific growth rate with thiosulfate is 0.18 h<sup>-1</sup> ; the maximum molar yield on thiosulfate is 6 g protein mol<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>During growth in batch cultures with thiosulfate at pH 10, elemental sulfur is always produced at the beginning of the exponential phase.</s><s>Oxidizes sulfide, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, sulfite and polythionates with relatively low activities within the pH range 7.0 to 11.0-11.5 (optimum pH 9-10).</s><s>Polysulfide is oxidized completely to sulfate without intermediate sulfur formation.</s><s>All strains express AMP-independent sulfite dehydrogenase.</s><s>Contains cytochromes of <i>c</i> and <i>b</i> types.</s><s>The cytochrome <i>c</i> oxidase activity is relatively high, with moderate sensitivity to cyanide and with spectroscopic properties of cytochrome <i>o</i>.</s><s>Denitrifying strain ALJD<sup>T</sup> contains cytochrome oxidase type <i>aa<sub>3</sub></i>.</s><s>Carbon assimilation is via the Calvin cycle.</s><s>Major ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>All strains are halotolerant and able to grow in presence of up to 1.2-1.5 Mtotal Na<sup>+</sup>.</s><s>Two strains are halophilic and thermotolerant, growing in up to 4 M total Na+ (optimum at 1-2 M) and up to 45-47 °C (optimum at 40 °C).</s><s>Three strains produce membrane-bound yellow carotenoids.</s><s>Four strains reduce nitrate to nitrite under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>One strain is a facultatively anaerobic denitrifier growing best with nitrous oxide as electron acceptor and thiosulfate as electron donor.</s><s>NH<sub>3</sub> (at low concentrations), NO<sup>−</sup><sub>2</sub> and NO<sup>−</sup><sub>3</sub> are used as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Most strains also assimilate nitrogen from thiocyanate.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content is between 61 and 65.6 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>Isolated from soda lakes.</s><s>Member of the γ-<i>Proteobacteria</i> with only a distant relationship to the anaerobic purple sulfur bacteria <i>Ectothiorhodospira</i>.</s><s>Represented by strains with a DNA homology level more than 30% that are assigned to three species-<i>Thioalkalivibrio versutus</i>, <i>Thioalkalivibrio denitrificans</i> and <i>Thioalkalivibrio nitratis</i>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Thioalkalivibrio versutus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>