<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12580_nm.21836" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21836" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21836" rank="species">Pacificibacter maritimus</organism><reference id="rid.12580"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalinovskaya</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pacificibacter maritimus gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from shallow marine sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1375</fpage><lpage>1381</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026047-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601488</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pacificibacter maritimus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pacificibacter maritimus</em> (ma.ri.ti′mus. L. masc. adj. <em>maritimus</em> maritime, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to properties given in the genus description, the species can be characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are rods, 0.4–0.6 µm in diameter and 1.8–2.0 µm in length, which are enlarged at one pole due to the budding process.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are whitish, translucent, smooth, shiny with regular edges and 2–3 mm in diameter on MA.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll α is not produced.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs with 0.5–6.0 % (w/v) NaCl; growth is weak with 6.0 % NaCl and optimal with 2–3 %.</s><s>Grows in/on basal media containing only NaCl in the absence of any other sea salts components (MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub> and MgSO<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 2–36 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C and no growth at 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.5–9.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.5–8.5.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, DNA, chitin and Tween 80.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 40 and 20 and l-tyrosine.</s><s>Weakly positive for hydrolysis of starch.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, produces grey-brownish colonies and forms a clearance zone, but not diffusible brown pigments.</s><s>No acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, d-galactose, lactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, d-ribose, fructose, l-sorbose, raffinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, d-<em>myo</em>-inositol or d-mannitol.</s><s>According to the API 20NE test kit, positive for the PNPG (β-galactosidase) test and aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification under anaerobic conditions, gelatin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease, and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The API 32GN test kit yielded positive results for assimilation of inositol, lactic acid, melibiose and l-proline, but negative results for assimilation of l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, sucrose, maltose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and 4-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s><s>Positive API ZYM test results were obtained for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase; negative results were obtained for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, maltose, cellobiose, l-tyrosine, citrate, acetate, fumarate and malate as carbon and energy sources; weakly utilizes inositol and l-arginine; and does not utilize l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-xylose, sucrose, fructose, raffinose, d-mannitol, glycerol, aminoacetic acid, ornithine, dl-leucine, l-α-alanine, dl-β-phenylalanine, dl-lysine, l-asparagine or l-methionine.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, followed by C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>12 : 1</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>Detailed fatty acid composition and polar lipids are shown in Table 2 and Fig. 3.</s><s>Susceptible to antibiotics (content per disc): ampicillin (10 µg), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), rifampicin (5 µg), streptomycin (30 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), ofloxacin (5 µg), oxacillin (10 µg), neomycin (30 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), oleandomycin (15 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), cephazolin (30 µg), cephalexin (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and chloramphenicol (30 µg).</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin (15 µg) and polymyxin (300 U).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain KMM 9031<sup>T</sup> ( = NRIC 0785<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 17096<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sandy sediment sample collected from the Sea of Japan seashore, Russia.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>