<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5690_nm.3849" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3849" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3849" rank="species">Helicobacter nemestrinae</organism><reference id="rid.5690"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bronsdon</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodwin</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chilvers</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schoenknecht</surname><given-names>F.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter nemestrinae sp. nov., a spiral bacterium found in the stomach of a pigtailed macaque (Macaca nemestrina)</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1995031</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter nemestrinae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter nemestrinae</i> (ne.rnes.tri'nae. N.L. gen. n. <i>nemestrinae</i>, of the macaque species <i>M. nemestrina</i>, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is a gram-negative, helically curved, rod-shaped bacterium (0.2 to 0.3 by 2.0 to 5.0 μm) with smooth walls and rounded ends.</s><s>Exhibits bizarre pleomorphic forms in in vitro culture (Fig. 1).</s><s>Motile by means of multiple sheathed polar flagella with terminal bulbs (Fig. 2).</s><s>Does not swarm.</s><s>Coccoid bodies form in aging cultures.</s><s>Does not have a capsule or form spores.</s><s>Growth on moist enriched blood or chocolate agar produces small, colorless, translucent colonies that are 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter and have irregular edges in 3 to 5 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at 35 and 42°C but not at 25°C in a humid microaerobic atmosphere.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 35°C in a humid atmosphere containing a reduced O<sub>2</sub> concentration (6%) and 6 to 10% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Weak growth occurs in humid air enriched with 10% CO<sub>2</sub> and anaerobically at 35°C.</s><s>No growth occurs in air.</s><s>Grows poorly or not at all in liquids.</s><s>Produces oxidase, catalase, and urease but not DNase.</s><s>Does not metabolize glucose.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or hydrolyze hippurate or esculin.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced on fresh TSI agar.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 1% glycine, 1.5% NaCl, or 1% bile.</s><s>Member of cellular fatty acid GLC group K.</s><s>Isolated from the gastric mucosa of a monkey (<i>M. nemestrina</i>).</s><s>Not associated with clinical disease or pathology of the host.</s><s>The G+C content is 24 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible in vitro to penicillin, ampicillin, erythromycin, gentamicin, cephalothin, cefoperazone, tetracycline, polymyxin, furoxone, rifampin, metronidazole, and chloromycetin.</s><s>Resistant in vitro to nalidixic acid, trimethoprim, sulfamethoxazole, and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When it was first isolated, <i>H. nemestrinae</i> grew poorly in a standard laboratory CO<sub>2</sub> incubator, but after many months of repeated subculturing it did grow weakly under these conditions.</s><s>It grows less luxuriantly under the anaerobic conditions described above.</s><s>The single isolate does not grow in enriched peptone water or enriched brain heart infusion broth.</s><s>Individual cells appear to be morphologically similar to the cells of other <i>Helicobacter</i> species.</s><s>When grown on chocolate agar, the cells are longer and less curved, often folding unevenly (Fig. 1a and b).</s><s>When grown on blood agar, the cells curl into multiple bizarre forms, as well as spirals, and stain more intensely with safranin (Fig. 1c and d).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain T81213-NTB (= ATCC 49396), which was isolated from a captive-born monkey at the Regional Primate Research Center, University of Washington, Seattle.</s></p></content></protolog>