<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10586_nm.17838" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17838" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17838" rank="species">Mesonia phycicola</organism><reference id="rid.10586"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mesonia phycicola sp. nov., isolated from seaweed, and emended description of the genus Mesonia</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>591</fpage><lpage>594</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011338-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654356</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mesonia phycicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mesonia phycicola</em> [phy.ci.co′la. L. n. <em>phycos</em> -<em>i</em> (from Gr. n. <em>phukos</em>) seaweed; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> (from L. masc. n. <em>incola</em>) an inhabitant of a place, a resident; N.L. n. <em>phycicola</em> an inhabitant of seaweed].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, aerobic rods, 0.6–1.6 μm in diameter and 2.1–2.5 μm in length.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Devoid of flagellar and gliding motility.</s><s>On marine agar 2216, colonies are circular, convex with entire edges and yellow in colour.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–30 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C), at pH 6.1–9.1 (optimum, pH 7.1) and in the presence of 1–12 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and DNA are hydrolysed but agar, CM-cellulose, chitin, starch, Tween 40 and Tween 80 are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose or maltose.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, and for arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate are not assimilated (API 20NE).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities are present; esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is menaquinone 6 (MK-6).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 30.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MDSW-25<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22373<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21425<sup>T</sup>), isolated from seaweed collected in the vicinity of Mara Island in Jeju province, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>