<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2639_nm.4788" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4788" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4788" rank="species">Spiroplasma floricola</organism><reference id="rid.2639"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Worley</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spiroplasma floricola, a new species isolated from surfaces of flowers of the Tulip Tree, Liriodendron tulpifera L.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>456</fpage><lpage>464</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-456</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spiroplasma floricola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spiroplasma floricola</i> (L. n. <i>flora</i> flower; L. v. <i>colo</i> dwell M. L. n. <i>floricola</i> flower dweller)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains 23-6 and 27-31 from the surfaces of flowers clearly belong to the genus <i>Spiroplasma</i>, based on morphological, ultrastructural, growth requirement, and other characteristics described previously (9, 10, 17, 18) and evaluated more extensively here.</s><s>We propose that strains 23-6 and 27-31 represent a single new species of <i>Spiroplasma</i>, based on similarities in properties of these two strains and on their distinctness from <i>S. citri</i>, the only <i>Spiroplasma</i> species formally proposed previously (28).</s><s>That certain other strains now in cultivation may represent additional new species is strongly suggested by related work.</s><s>Indeed, during the past several years investigations by several groups of researchers have shown that the cultured spiroplasmas comprise several types distinctly different from one another and from <i>S. citri</i> (1, 4, 9, 10, 12, 19, 22- 24, 34-36, 40).</s><s>Spiroplasmas isolated from flowers have been important elements in some of these investigations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spiroplasmas that occur on surfaces of flowers (presumably in nectar) were first isolated in culture from flowers of <i>L. tulipifera</i> L. (9).</s><s>Shortly thereafter, other isolates were recovered from flowers of <i>Magnolia grandiflora</i> L. (7) and <i>C. haematocephala</i> (22).</s><s>The isolates from tulip tree flowers included strains 23-6, 27-31, SR3, and SR9 (9, 12).</s><s>Two new separate species were thought to be represented among these four strains (9, 10, 12).</s><s>In a scheme for the classification of <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains into serogroups and serological subgroups based on results from tests on membrane antigen reactivity (12), strains 23-6 and 27-31 were serologically indistinguishable and were placed in a single major serogroup (serogroup 11).</s><s>Flower <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains SR3 and SR9 were placed in another group (serogroup III), to which additional strains from flowers and insects have been added more recently (25a, 34, 37).</s><s>The lack of cross-reactions between serogroups II and III and between these groups and a separate group (serogroup I) containing <i>S. citri</i> was believed to be taxonomically significant (12).</s><s>Work by others has further shown the feasibility of serological grouping of <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains (40; J .</s><s>G.</s><s>Tully, D.</s><s>L.</s><s>Williamson, D.</s><s>L.</s><s>Rose, and R.</s><s>F.</s><s>Whitcomb, Abstr.</s><s>Annu.</s><s>Meet.</s><s>Am.</s><s>SOCM. icrobiol. 1979, G8, p. 83).</s><s>For example, it has been shown that <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains OBMG and BNR1, which were isolated by T.</s><s>B.</s><s>Clark from magnolia and tulip tree flowers, respectively, and were found by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis analyses of proteins to be identical to strain 23-6 (M.</s><s>J.</s><s>Daniels, personal communication), are distinct from <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains in other serological groups (17, 40).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results from polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis studies of cellular proteins and DNA homology experiments among <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains agree well with the identifications and grouping based on serological reactions (1,4, 17, 18, 23, 24; M.</s><s>J.</s><s>Daniels, personal communication).</s><s>For example, strains 23-6 and 27-31 have identical cellular protein electrophoretic patterns (see above) but are distinct from <i>S. citri</i> and from <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains belonging to other serogroups (Daniels, personal communication).</s><s>Furthermore, strains 23-6 and 27-31 share close to 100% DNA homology with one another, but DNA homology between these strains and <i>S. citri</i> and other spiroplasmas was estimated at 55% (18). <i>Spiroplasma</i> groups and subgroups with strains separated on the basis of serology had the same identities as the groups and subgroups identified by reciprocal DNA homology studies (18).</s><s>In this work, the guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the strain 23-6 and 27-31 DNAs were found to be close to 25 mol%, a value approximating the value for <i>S. citri</i> DNA (26 mol%) (1, 28) but distinct from the value of 29 mol% reported for the DNAs from the suckling mouse cataract agent (1, 4) and flower <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains SR3 and SR9 (18).</s><s>In a separate study (17), DNAs from strains 23-6, OBMG, and BNR1 were also found to contain about 25 mol% guanine plus cytosine and to share no homology with <i>S. citri</i>.</s><s>The available data are consistent with the conclusion that <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains 23-6 and 27-31 are very similar or identical to one another and are distinct from <i>S. citri</i> and members of other serogroups.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In accordance with criteria proposed by the International Committee on Systematic Bacteriology Subcommittee on the Taxonomy of Mollicutes for separation of species (32), the distinction of strains 23-6 and 27-31 from <i>S. citri</i> by serology, gel electrophoresis of cellular proteins, and DNA homology indicates that strains 23-6 and 27-31 belong to a single new species of <i>Spiroplasma</i>.</s><s>Based on the findings discussed above, we propose that <i>Spiroplasma</i> strains 23-6 and 27-31 be placed in a new species, for which we propose the name <i>Spiroplasma floricola</i> (L. n. <i>flora</i> flower; L. v. <i>colo</i> dwell M.</s><s>L. n. <i>floricola</i> flower dweller).</s><s>Strain 23-6 (=ATCC 29989) is the type strain, This new species occurs in flower nectar and is characterized by motile, helical, wall-less cells 0.15 to 0.2 μm in diameter and 2 to about 5 μm long during log-phase growth in DSM4 broth medium, by inhibition of growth by digitonin, by enhancement of growth by increasing concentrations of cholesterol, and by a DNA base composition of about 25 mol% guanine plus cytosine (Table 7).</s><s>The type strain and strain 27-31 are capable of growth at 22 to 37°C and grow rapidly at 30 to 37°C, yielding turbid cultures in DSM4 broth medium and diffuse, spreading colonies on agar medium.</s><s>These two strains catabolize glucose, fructose, mannose, and arginine but lack phosphatase activity.</s></p></content></protolog>