<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2418_nm.11292" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11292" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11292" rank="species">Rhodovulum visakhapatnamense</organism><reference id="rid.2418"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>C.h.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>C.h.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodovulum visakhapatnamense sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1762</fpage><lpage>1764</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65076-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684252</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodovulum visakhapatnamense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodovulum visakhapatnamense</em> (vi.sa.kha.pat.na.men′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>visakhapatnamense</em> pertaining to Visakhapatnam, the place from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, 0.9 μm wide and 1.2 μm long, non-motile and multiply by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of phototrophic cultures is yellowish-brown, while aerobic cultures are pink.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 467, 520, 590, 802 and 857 nm.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and most probably carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>The type strain is mesophilic (temperature range 20–35 °C, optimum at 28 °C), with a pH optimum at pH 6.0–8.0 (range pH 4.0–9.0).</s><s>Sodium chloride is not required but the type strain tolerates up to 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Photo-organoheterotrophy with various organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>The substrates which are utilized as carbon sources and electron donors under photo-organoheterotrophic conditions include acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, lactate, pyruvate, 2-oxoglutaric acid, malate, succinate, fumarate, glucose, fructose, sucrose, glycerol, glutamate, ascorbate, peptone and Casamino acids.</s><s>Substrates that can not be utilized include formate, benzoate, tartrate, citrate, lactose, mannitol, sorbitol, methanol, ethanol, propanol, thioglycolate, methionine, aspartate and cysteine.</s><s>Sulfate, cysteine, thiosulfate and thioglycolate are utilized as sulfur sources under photoheterotrophic conditions.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, molecular nitrogen, glutamate and glutamine are utilized as nitrogen sources, while nitrate, nitrite, aspartate and urea do not support growth.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth is possible in the presence of thiosulfate as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Biotin, niacin, thiamine and <em>p-</em>aminobenzoic acid are required as growth factors.</s><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 61.2 mol% G+C (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JA181<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13531<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1274<sup>T</sup> =DSM 17937<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine surface and tidal waters exposed to light.</s></p></content></protolog>