<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6292_nm.9182" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9182" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8025" rank="species">Oribaculum catoniae</organism><reference id="rid.6292"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Oribaculum catoniae gen. nov., sp. nov.; Catonella morbi gen. nov., sp. nov.; Hallella seregens gen. nov., sp. nov.; Johnsonella ignava gen. nov., sp. nov.; and Dialister pneumosintes gen. nov., comb. nov., nom. rev., Anaerobic gram-negative bacilli from the human gingival crevice.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>187</fpage><lpage>192</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-187</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186083</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Oribaculum catoniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Oribaculum catoniae</i> (ca.to'ni.ae. L. gen. n. <i>catoniae</i>, of Cato, in honor of Elizabeth P. Cato, a United States microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on studies of the type strain and 84 other strains.</s><s>Cells of the type strain grown in PYG broth are 0.6 μm wide by 0.8 to 1.7 μm long and occur in pairs and short chains.</s><s>Cells grown in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate may be highly vacuolated.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar plates incubated for 2 days are 0.5 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, flat to low convex, and transparent.</s><s>Although most strains are not hemolytic on rabbit blood agar, an occasional strain may be beta-hemolytic.</s><s>No colonies with a dark pigment are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Abundant growth occurs in peptone-yeast extract or PYG broth.</s><s>Broth cultures are turbid with a smooth to fine granular sediment.</s><s>The pH of PYG broth cultures is 5.0 to 5.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following amounts of fermentation acids (in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture; mean ± standard error of the mean) are produced in PYG broth cultures: propionic acid, 2.3 ± 0.2; acetic acid, 0.9 ± 0.06; succinic acid, 0.8 ± 0.1; lactic acid, 0.6 ± 0.1; and isovaleric acid, 0.2 ± 0.02.</s><s>Trace to moderate amounts of formic acid may be produced.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas of PYG broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics of the species are shown in Tables 1 and 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the gingival crevices of humans with gingivitis or periodontitis and from persons with healthy gingiva.</s><s>Type strain: ATCC 51270 (= VPI N3B-3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 49 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>For distinctive characteristics, see the genus description above.</s></p></content></protolog>