<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6493_nm.10172" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10172" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10172" rank="species">Tenacibaculum aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.6493"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tenacibaculum aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat sediment in Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1577</fpage><lpage>1581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64302-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825632</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tenacibaculum aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tenacibaculum aestuarii</em> (aes.tu′a.ri.i. L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of the tidal flat, from where the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, unflagellated and 0.3×2.0–3.5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, pale yellow, irregular with spreading edges and greenish glistening.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA or on MA with nitrate.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 7.5–8.5; weak growth occurs at pH 5.5, but there is no growth at pH 5.0.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of more than 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Tyrosine and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed, but aesculin, urea, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Peptone and tryptone are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose and l-leucine are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-xylose, d-ribose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, melibiose, l-arabinose, d-melezitose, d-glucose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, d-mannose, d-cellobiose, lactose, sucrose, maltose, d-trehalose or d-raffinose.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system (bioMérieux), alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are present, but cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to cephalothin, lincomycin, oleandomycin and carbenicillin, but not to polymyxin B, streptomycin, penicillin G, ampicillin, gentamicin, novobiocin, tetracycline, kanamycin or neomycin.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 33.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SMK-4<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12569<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13491<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from tidal flat sediment at Saemankum, Pyunsan, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>