<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7371_nm.8187" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8187" rank="genus">Riemerella</organism><reference id="rid.7371"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torck</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hinz</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Riemerella columbina sp. nov., a bacterium associated with respiratory disease in pigeons</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>295</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Riemerella</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Riemerella</i> cells are Gram-negative, nonsporulating and nonmotile rods 0.2-0.5 μm wide and 1-2.5 μm long. All strains grow microaerobically and most of them aerobically on blood agar. Some strains grow anaerobically at 37°C. Colonies are smooth, nonpigmented or greyish-white to beige pigmented. Growth on litmus lactose agar is strain-dependent, no growth is obtained on MacConkey's agar. Most strains show a positive Voges-Proskauer reaction. Nitrates are not reduced. Reaction for acid production from glucose is frequently negative in peptone-containing media. Activity of the following enzymes is present: oxidase, catalase, gelatinase, α-glucosidase, α-maltosidase, alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase lipase C8, esterase C4, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase and L-aspartic acid arylamidase. The following reactions are strain-dependent: urease, chymotrypsin, trypsin and arginine dihydrolase activity, indole production, haemolysis on blood, aesculin hydrolysis. Depending on the micro-test kit used, the following enzyme reactions give variable results: β- glucosidase, α-galactosidase and lipase activity (these three reactions were all positive in the API ID32E and negative in the API ZYM system) and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase [negative in API ZYM and API ID32E, positive in LRA-ZYM-OSIDASES (Hinz et al., 1998b); only some representative <i>R. anatipestifer</i> strains were tested using the latter system]. Activity of the following enzymes is absent: chondroitin sulfatase, hyaluronidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, amannosidase, α-fucosidase, trypsin, ornithine and lysine decarboxylase. None of the strains used malonate as a carbon source, or assimilated in the API 20NE system D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, D-gluconate, caprate, adipate, L-malate, citrate or phenyl acetate. No acid production was detected from D- and Larabitol, galacturonate, 5-ketogluconate, phenol red, D-mannitol, maltose, adonitol, palatinose, saccharose, L-arabinose, trehalose, rhamnose, inositol, sorbitol or cellobiose in the API ID32E system. Using the BSS test, however, acidification of the following carbohydrates may be detected: D-glucose, maltose, Dmannose and dextrin, and to a lesser extent D-fructose, L-sorbose and trehalose. No acid was produced from lactose, D-galactose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, lactulose, trehalose, saccharose, D-mannitol, L-arabinose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, D-xylose, dulcitol, salicin or adonitol. The genus is a member of the family <i>Flavobacteriaceae</i>. The closest phylogenetic neighbours are the genera <i>Chryseobacterium</i> and <i>Bergeyella</i>. Menaquinone-6 is the major respiratory quinone detected in the type species. The dominant fatty acids are the branched-chain fatty acids 13:0 iso, 15:0 iso, 15:0 anteiso, 15:0 iso 3-OH and 17:0 iso 3-OH. Isolated mainly from diseased birds, in a few cases from pigs. The illness caused by the organism is a septicaemic disease in ducks, pigeons and other domestic and wild birds. The type species is <i>R. anatipestifer</i>. The DNA G+C composition ranges from 29 to 37 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>