<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2267_nm.7652" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7652" rank="genus">Acidothermus</organism><reference id="rid.2267"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mohagheghi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grohmann</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Himmel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leighton</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Updegraff</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Acidothermus cellulolyticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus of thermophilic, acidophilic, cellulolytic bacteria.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>435</fpage><lpage>443</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-3-435</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidothermus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidothermus</i> (L. adj. <i>acidus</i> acid; Gr. n. <i>thermus</i> heat; M. L. masc. n. <i>Acidothermus</i> acid and heat [loving])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology: slender rods and long, slender filaments, 0.4 by 5 to 20 μm, which have rounded ends.</s><s>Does not form endospores, flagella, or rotund bodies.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Gram variable, but usually stains gram negative.</s><s>Thin sections show no outer cell membranes and thus are distinctly different from the typical gram-negative cell walls of <i>Thermus</i> and <i>Thermomicrobium</i> species.</s><s>The principal constituents of purified cell walls are diaminopimelic acid, glucosamine, muramic acid, serine, and alanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony characteristics: on LPBM mineral salts agar with 0.5 g of yeast extract per liter and 5.0 g of D-glucose or D-cellobiose per liter, creamy white, smooth, circular, entire, 1 to 3 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Liquid cultures: on same medium lacking agar show a moderate uniform turbidity.</s><s>Some strains tend to flocculate and sediment out after 3 to 10 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology: obligate aerobes, prototrophic; grow on several carbohydrates, including D-glucose and D-cellobiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature characteristics: thermophilic, growth range 37 to 70°C.</s><s>pH requirements: acidophilic; pH range for growth, 3.5 to 7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base ratio, 60.7 ± 0.6 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: acidic hot springs at Yellowstone National Park, pH 4 to 5.5, 45 to 65°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>A . cellulolyticus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>