<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7036_nm.1576" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1576" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1576" rank="species">Xanthobacter aminoxidans</organism><reference id="rid.7036"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of 'Blastobacter viscosus' 7d and 'Blastobacter aminooxidans' 14a as Xanthobacter viscosus sp. nov. and Xanthobacter aminoxidans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>179</fpage><lpage>182</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02231-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656170</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Xanthobacter aminoxidans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Xanthobacter aminoxidans</em> (am.in.ox′i.dans. N.L. n. <em>aminum</em> amine; M.L. v. <em>oxido</em> make acid, oxidize; N.L. part. adj. <em>aminoxidans</em> amine-oxidizing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative pleomorphic rods, 0·8–1·0×1·5–3·5 μm, apparently branching to form V-shaped cells.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Reproduction occurs by asymmetric division (budding) of the mother cell to produce a shorter daughter cell.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, round, convex, bright, non-transparent, smooth-surfaced, with an even edge, homogeneous and of slimy consistency.</s><s>In liquid medium with methylated amines or glucose the cells do not produce exopolymer.</s><s>The temperature range is 5–34 °C, optimum 29–32 °C, and the pH range is 6·5–8·5, optimum pH 7·2–7·8.</s><s>Obligately aerobic, but potentially, microaerophilic.</s><s>Catalase-, peroxidase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urease, phenylalanine deaminase and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Indole is formed from l-tryptophan.</s><s>Reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>With glucose medium, acid and gas are not produced.</s><s>Utilizable carbon sources are monomethylamine, dimethylamine or trimethylamine, ethanol, butanol, mannitol, xylose, glucose, raffinose, glyoxylate, fumarate, malate and lactate.</s><s>Utilizable nitrogen sources are ammonium salts, nitrates, peptone, methylated amines and some amino acids.</s><s>Fixes N<sub>2</sub> when grown in nitrogen-deficient media.</s><s>Grow autotrophically in an atmosphere of H<sub>2</sub>+O<sub>2</sub>+CO<sub>2</sub> and on methylamines by the key Calvin-cycle enzymes phosphoribulokinase and ribulosebisphosphate carboxylase.</s><s>Trimethylamine and methylamine are oxidized by the appropriate dehydrogenases and dimethylamine is oxidized by monooxygenase (NADH or NADPH).</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid of peptone-yeast extract-glucose agar-grown cells is C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (76·0 %).</s><s>The major phospholipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69·1 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of strain 14a<sup>T</sup> is AF399969. <em>X. aminoxidans</em> strain 14a<sup>T</sup> was isolated from activated sludge of a sewage-purification system at the Baikal paper mill, Russia.</s><s>The type strain, 14a<sup>T</sup>, is deposited in the All-Russian Collection of Microorganisms as VKM B-2254<sup>T</sup> and the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC BAA-299<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>