<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.98_nm.2733" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2733" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2733" rank="species">Chryseomonas polytricha</organism><reference id="rid.98"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseomonas polytricha gen. nov., sp. nov., a pseudomonas-like organism from human clinical specimens and formerly known as Group Ve-1.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>161</fpage><lpage>165</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-161</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chryseomonas polytricha</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chryseomonas polytricha</i> (po.ly'tri.cha. Gr. adj. <i>polytrichos</i>; N. L. fem. adj. <i>polytricha</i> many-haired, referring to the possession of multiple flagella)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of <i>Chryseomonas polytricha</i> sp. nov. are as follows.</s><s>The cells are strictly aerobic, gram-negative, nonsporeforming, uniformly staining rods with parallel sides and rounded ends.</s><s>They are motile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth, incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C), by means of multitrichous polar flagella (Fig. 1).</s><s>There is growth at 42°C but not at 5°C.</s><s>After growth on nutrient agar for 24 h, colonies are typically circular, low convex, about 1 mm in diameter, smooth (strain CL612/77 produces deep yellow colonies which, after a few days, develop a wrinkled appearance similar to that of certain strains of <i>Pseudomonas stutzeri</i>), shining, entire, and pale to deep yellow.</s><s>Hemolysis was not present after aerobic growth for 24 h on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although most colonies of strain CL612/77 were initially smooth, rough colonies were occasionally also observed, and these produced only rough colonies on subculture.</s><s>Cultures of strain A7701 also caused concern that they might be mixed.</s><s>Two colony types were observed: one was bright yellow and smooth, and the other was smaller, not so brightly pigmented, and had a distinct dimple in the center.</s><s>Both colony types bred true on subculture, and therefore both were tested in parallel in all 129 phenotypic tests.</s><s>There were no significant differences between the two, and therefore there was no evidence to suggest that they were not the same strain.</s><s>The results recorded for this strain are those obtained for the first colony type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A total of 92 characteristics was common to all strains (either all positive or all negative).</s><s>There were 37 characteristics in which one or more of the strains differed (Table 3).</s><s>No strain conformed to the median organism, but the proposed type strain, E2770, was a centrotype strain.</s><s>Strains CL764177, CL612/77, E208, and E3283 were the least typical members of the group; CL764/77 differed from the other eight strains in three biochemical characteristics, whereas CL612/77, E208, and E3283 each differed from the other eight strains in two (but not the same two) biochemical characteristics, All strains had the following characteristics in common: production of catalase but not cytochrome oxidase; oxidative reaction in glucose oxidation-fermentation medium; hydrolysis of tributyrin, Tween 20, and tyrosine, and gelatin by the plate method; no production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar; no reduction of nitrate; no production of indole; no production of hydrogen sulfide (lead acetate paper and triple sugar iron agar methods); growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on MacConkey agar; hydrolysis of esculin but not starch; alkali production on Christensen citrate; utilization of citrate (Simmons medium) and malonate; not fluorescent on King medium B; no oxidation of gluconate; production of arginine dihydrolase but not lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase; no production of 3-ketolactose; no reduction of selenite and no deamination of phenylalanine; production of β-D-galactosidase (o-nitrophenyl- β-D-galactopyranoside test) but not phosphatase; production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from glucose, arabinose, ethanol, fructose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannitol, trehalose, and xylose; no production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from cellobiose, dulcitol, lactose, and raffinose; production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and lactose, and no production of gas from glucose in peptone-water medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains hydrolyzed the following substrates (tests done with API ZYM galleries): N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthyl-amide; 4-methylumbelliferylarabinopyranoside; L-lysyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-alanyl-β-naphthylamide; DL-methionyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide hydrobromide; glycyl-L-phenylalanyl-β- naphthylamide; glycyl-L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide; L-leucyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-glutamine-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; L-seryl-β-naphthylamide; and N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginine-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains hydrolyzed the following substrates (tests done with API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl myristate; L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide; N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside; 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside; naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronic acid; 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside; 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside;</s></p><p class="description"><s>2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-xylopyranoside; p-nitrophenyl-α-D-xylopyranoside; p-nitrophenyl-β-L-fucopyranoside; o-nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide; p-nitrophenyl-lactoside; p-nitrocatechol-sulfate; 4-methyllumbelliferylcellobiopyranoside; ϒ-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide; N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide; S-benzyl-L-cysteyl-β-naphthylamide; N-carbobenzoxy-L-arginine-4-methoxy-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; α-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide; and L-threonyl-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of three phenotypically representative strains of <i>C. polytricha</i> are between 53.9 and 55.6 mol%, with a mean of 54.6 mol% and a standard deviation of ±1.1 mol%; the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 54 mol% (as estimated by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is E2770 (= NCTC 11843).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group Ve strains apparently occur very rarely in clinical material, mainly in wounds or abscesses (17).</s><s>The group Ve-1 reference strain from cerebrospinal fluid included in this study may have been clinically significant, but the details received were insufficient to make a valid judgement.</s><s>Only once has a group Ve-1 strain been reported as a cause of septicemia, and only then in a patient who was severely immunocompromised while under treatment for pancreatitis (1).</s><s>Group Ve strains are, in any case, generally susceptible to several antimicrobial agents (ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, colistin, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, moxalactam, neomycin, polymyxin, streptomycin, and tetracycline [7, 9], as well as several newer cephalosporins [15]) so that treatment should present no special difficulties.</s><s>A combination of amikacin and mezlocillin has proved effective (1).</s><s>The prosthetic valve endocarditis described by O'Leary and Fong (12), however, was fatal to the patient despite earlier treatment for 2 weeks with intravenous netilmicin and cefamandole, antibiotics to which the strain was susceptible.</s><s>Their strain (12) was resistant to ampicillin, cephalothin, and co-trimoxazole. <i>C. polytricha</i> appears to be widely distributed; the nine strains were isolated in Australia, England, and six states in the United States.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The biochemical characteristics of the field and reference strains examined agree with those presented by other authors, except for some minor discrepancies as follows.</s><s>All the strains studied by Gilardi (8) and Gilardi et al. (9) failed to produce deoxyribonuclease, whereas all but one of our group Ve-1 strains were able to produce it.</s><s>Conversely none of our strains hydrolyzed starch, whereas several of the strains tested by Gilardi (8) gave a positive result.</s><s>The G+C content determined for <i>C. polytricha</i> strains in this study (54.6 mol%) is about 2% lower than that reported by Gilardi et al. [9] (56.8 mol%) for group Ve-1 strains.</s><s>The reasons for this discrepancy are unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following additional strains of <i>C. polytricha</i> have been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures: B237 as NCTC 11841 and B1117 as NCTC 11842.</s><s>B5264 is available from the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as ATCC 35563.</s></p></content></protolog>