<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8243_nm.14185" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14185" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14185" rank="species">Thalassomonas actiniarum</organism><reference id="rid.8243"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hosoya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassomonas actiniarum sp. nov. and Thalassomonas haliotis sp. nov., isolated from marine animals.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>686</fpage><lpage>690</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000539-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329588</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassomonas actiniarum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassomonas actiniarum</em> (ac.ti.ni.a′rum. N.L. gen. pl. n. <em>actiniarum</em> of the Actiniaria, sea anemones and related animals).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic and rod-shaped, approximately 1.0–2.0 μm long by 0.4–0.6 μm wide.</s><s>Cells are motile by a subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Releases a stable, brown, diffusible pigment into the medium.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 25–30 °C and can grow at 15 °C, but no growth occurs at 8 or 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.5–8.5; optimum pH is 8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1/2 SP5 agar medium supplemented with 0.4–1.4× ASW [NaCl concentration range of 1.2–4.2 % (w/v)], but no growth occurs in NaCl alone.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Positive for degradation of casein, DNA, aesculin, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 and tyrosine.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite (API 20NE).</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose (API 50CH).</s><s>Does not decompose alginate, lecithin or urea.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Does not produce acid from glycogen, erythritol, dl-arabinose, ribose, dl-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for assimilation of glucose as a carbon source, but negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, n-capric acid, adipic acid, dl-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Positive for utilization of erythritol, cellobiose and glycogen as carbon sources (API 50CH).</s><s>The major respiratory quinones are Q-8, Q-9 and Q-7.</s><s>The fatty acid profile comprises C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is A5K-106<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08328<sup>T</sup> =NCIMB 14418<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 104231<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sea anemone in Futtsu, Chiba Prefecture in Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>