<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12166_nm.20158" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20158" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20158" rank="species">Bacillus methylotrophicus</organism><reference id="rid.12166"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sa</surname><given-names>T.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus methylotrophicus sp. nov., a methanol-utilizing, plant-growth-promoting bacterium isolated from rice rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2490</fpage><lpage>2495</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015487-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19966000</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus methylotrophicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus methylotrophicus</em> [me.thy.lo.tro.phi.cus. N.L. suff. <em>methylo</em> pertaining to the methyl radical; N.L. adj. <em>trophicus</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>trophikos</em>) nursing, tending or feeding; N.L. masc. adj. <em>methylotrophicus</em> feeding on methyl radical, methyl radical-consuming].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, endospore-forming, strictly aerobic, motile rods (0.63–0.64×1.8–2.7 μm) occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Colonies are creamy white, convex, translucent with regular edges, slow-growing and 0.2–0.8 mm in diameter after 96 h at 28 °C on AMS.</s><s>Grows on NA, LB, R2A, TSA, KB, 2 % MH and Colby and Zathman medium.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of &#x003E;4.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–45 °C (optimal temperature 28 °C) and at pH 2.0–10.0 (optimal pH 7.0).</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, pectinase and protease activities are positive.</s><s>Cellulase, arginine dihydrolase, urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and hydrolysis of gelatin, glycerol tributyrate and aesculin are positive.</s><s>Tests for glucose fermentation and indole production are negative.</s><s>Methanol, trimethylamine and ethanol are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, potassium nitrate, sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride, l-alanine, l-glutamine, l-tryptophan, glycine, trimethylamine, 1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate, potassium cyanate and potassium thiocyanate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources, but urea, methylamine, l-glutamate, diphenylamine and l-aspartic acid are not utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>None of the compounds in Biolog tests are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>The following carbon and nitrogen sources are assimilated in the API 20NE test: d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate.</s><s>Negative for capric acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>The following carbon sources are assimilated in the API 32GN test: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, lactic acid, l-alanine, glycogen, d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, trisodium citrate, l-histidine and l-proline.</s><s>Negative for itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid and 4-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s><s>In API ZYM assays, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are present, but lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, a minor amount of phosphatidylcholine and two unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> anteiso.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CBMB205<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 13105<sup>T</sup>=NCCB 100236), was isolated from the rhizoplane of rice (<em>Oryza sativa</em> L. cv O-dae).</s><s>The sample was collected at reproductive stage (R9) and was obtained from the Chungbuk Provincial Agricultural Research and Extension Services, Cheongwon (3 ° 58′ 0″ N, 12 ° 57′ 0″ E), Chungbuk, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>