<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8726_nm.13185" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13185" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13185" rank="species">Streptoalloteichus tenebrarius</organism><reference id="rid.8726"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otoguro</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of 'Streptomyces tenebrarius' Higgins and Kastner as Streptoalloteichus tenebrarius nom. rev., comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Streptoalloteichus.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>688</fpage><lpage>691</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65272-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319479</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptoalloteichus tenebrarius</em> (<em>ex</em> Higgins and Kastner) nom. rev., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptoalloteichus tenebrarius</em> (te.ne.bra′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>tenebrarius</em> of or belonging to darkness, reflecting the sensitivity of the culture to light).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Originally described as ‘<em>Streptomyces tenebrarius</em>’ by Higgins &#x0026; Kastner (1967).</s><s>The description is based on data reported by Higgins &#x0026; Kastner (1967), Shirling &#x0026; Gottlieb (1972) and Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991) and data obtained in this study.</s><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.</s><s>Straight spore chains are formed on short sporophores on the substrate mycelium.</s><s>Spores possess a smooth surface and are short, non-motile rods (0.6–0.9×1.0–1.5 μm).</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced on tyrosine agar (ISP medium 7).</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed weakly; gelatin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Calcium malate is not decomposed and milk is not coagulated or peptonized.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 20–30 °C; grows at 37 °C, but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Grows on 8 % NaCl, but not on 10 % NaCl. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, arabonic acid, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-fructose, gluconate, d-glucosamine, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucose, glycogen, maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, sucrose, raffinose, salicin, starch, trehalose, adonitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, acetate, butyrate, caprate, isobutyrate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, d-lactate, dl-lactate, dl-malate, l-malate, oxaloacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, acetamidocaprate, acetyl l-glutamine, acetyl glycine, d-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, casein, l-citrulline, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-valine and ethanolamine are utilized (as sodium salts where applicable).</s><s>Major menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.6 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NBRC 16177<sup>T</sup> =ATCC 17920<sup>T</sup> =DSM 40477<sup>T</sup> =JCM 4838<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-12390<sup>T</sup> =ISP 5477<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>