<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2663_nm.3957" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3957" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3957" rank="species">Clostridium josui</organism><reference id="rid.2663"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sukhumavasi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohmiya</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimizu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueno</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium josui sp. nov., a cellulolytic, moderate thermophilic species from Thai compost.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>179</fpage><lpage>182</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-2-179</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium josui</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium josui</i> (jo.su'i.) (the first four letters were obtained by combining the initial letters of the names of the authors, and the last letter was added according to the requirements of the International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria [II])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The rod-shaped cells are gram positive, becoming gram negative as cultures reached stationary phase, and are nonmotile.</s><s>The slightly curved rods are 0.2 to 0.3 μm wide and 3 to 5 μm long and are found as individuals and short or long chains.</s><s>The organisms form terminal oval spores which cause a marked swelling of the cells (Fig. 1).</s><s>The mature spores are 0.4 to 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Endospores are still viable after heating at 80°C for 20 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In agar medium containing BMC, cultures show a clear zone around each colony within 3 days.</s><s>Deep colonies are spindle shaped and a dull yellowish color.</s><s>The clear zone of cellulolysis reaches a diameter of 10 mm after prolonged incubation.</s><s>Cellulose (1%) in agar roll tubes containing large numbers of colonies is completely hydrolyzed within 2 weeks.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 45°C, and growth occurs over a temperature range of 25 to 60°C (Table 1).</s><s>No growth is observed at temperatures lower than 20°C and higher than 65°C even after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.0.</s><s>This strain requires the Hungate (9) technique or similarly stringent anaerobic methods for cultivation (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism shows no growth when it is grown in adonitol, amygdalin, bile, dulcitol, dextrin, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, or trehalose as the only carbon source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Poor growth is observed with lactose and melibiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate growth is obtained with arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, maltose, ribose, xylose, and xylan.</s><s>The initial pH is 7.0, and the final pH is 5.5 to 5.1 after 3 days of cultivation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed, but starch is not.</s><s>Indole and nitrite are not produced.</s><s>Milk is unchanged, casein is not digested, and gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Lecithinase and lipase are not produced when cultures are grown on egg agar media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbon dioxide, hydrogen, acetate, and ethanol are produced in large quantities when cultures are grown on cellulosic materials, such as BMC, Avicel, rice straw, and corncobs, whereas propionate and butyrate are detected only in trace amounts (Table 2).</s><s>All of these compounds are negligibly produced when rice husks, sawdust, and baggase are used as main carbon sources because the isolate can barely utilize these materials.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content.</s><s>The G+C content of <i>C. josui</i> DNA is 40 mol%, as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics.</s><s>This organism is distinguished from <i>Clostridium thermocellum</i>, <i>Clostridium cellulovorans</i> (16), <i>Clostridium cellulolyticum</i> (14), <i>Clostridium stercorarium</i> (12), and <i>Clostridium populeti</i> (15) by its growth temperatures, Gram staining, and ability to produce acids from fructose, galactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, salicin, and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain III, has been deposited in the Fermentation Research Institute, Tsukuba, Japan, as strain FERM P-9684.</s></p></content></protolog>