<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3594_nm.4220" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4220" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4220" rank="species">Sedimentibacter saalensis</organism><reference id="rid.3594"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Breitenstein</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haertig</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andreesen</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Clostridium hydroxybenzoicum as Sedimentibacter hydroxybenzoicus gen. nov., comb. nov., and description of Sedimentibacter saalensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>801</fpage><lpage>807</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01998-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054241</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sedimentibacter saalensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sedimentibacter saalensis</i> (saa.len'sis. N.L. adj. <i>saalensis</i> referring to the German River Saale, from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, slightly curved rods that are 0.5-0.7 μm in diameter and 3.7-6.0 μm long, occurring singly, in pairs or in chains of up to 12 cells.</s><s>In addition, long filaments with no visible septation occur.</s><s>Motile by peritrichously arranged flagella.</s><s>Gram-staining of different growth phases gives a positive result.</s><s>The cell wall type is A1α, L-Lys-direct.</s><s>Oval spores (0.7 μm diameter) are formed on complex medium.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 14-40 °C, the optimum temperature being 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.8-8.0; there is a broad optimum range of pH 6.8-7.3.</s><s>Requires yeast extract for growth.</s><s>The addition of 25 mM pyruvate, 10 mM glycine or 10 mM L-lysine, or of combinations of glycine plus arginine or glycine plus lysine, to yeast-extract-containing medium supports growth.</s><s>The major fermentation products during growth on pyruvate are acetate and butyrate, whereas propionate, lactate and traces of isobutyrate and isovalerate are minor products (in a medium containing 0.5% yeast extract); H<sub>2</sub> is not formed.</s><s>No acid production from glucose, mannitol, lactose, sucrose, maltose, salicin, xylose, arabinose, glycerol, cellobiose, mannose, melezitose, raffinose, sorbitol, rhamnose or trehalose.</s><s>Uric acid, adenine, hypoxanthine, guanine and xanthine are not utilized.</s><s>Tests for catalase and urease activity, indole production, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, gelatin liquefaction and hydrolysis of aesculin are negative.</s><s>Forms sulfide.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 14:0, 16:1 cis-9 and 16:0.</s><s>The genomic DNA G­+C content is 34.0 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, ZF2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13558<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-283<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from freshwater sediment of the River Saale (Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>