<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6181_nm.9746" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9746" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9746" rank="species">Proteiniphilum acetatigenes</organism><reference id="rid.6181"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proteiniphilum acetatigenes gen. nov., sp. nov., from a UASB reactor treating brewery wastewater</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2257</fpage><lpage>2261</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63807-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280479</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Proteiniphilum acetatigenes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Proteiniphilum acetatigenes</em> (a.ce′ta.ti.gen.es. N.L. <em>acetas</em> -<em>atis</em> acetate; Gr. v. <em>gennao</em> produce; N.L. part. adj. <em>acetatigenes</em> acetate-producing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and general characteristics are as described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0·6–0·9×1·9–2·2 μm.</s><s>Colonies on PY agar are circular, slightly convex, white, translucent, and reach 1·5 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6·0–9·7, with optimum growth occurring at pH 7·5–8·0.</s><s>In addition to yeast extract and peptone, pyruvate, glycine and l-arginine can be used as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Weak growth is observed with tryptone, l-serine, l-threonine and l-alanine.</s><s>Acetic acid is the main product from fermentation of yeast extract, peptone, pyruvate and l-arginine.</s><s>Propionic acid is also produced from yeast extract.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine, l-glutamine, tryptophan, l-tyrosine, l-isoleucine, l-proline, l-aspartate, l-cysteine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, d-maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, salicin, sorbose, starch, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribitol, methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, citrate, fumarate, malate, succinate, malonate, hippurate, sodium gluconate, butane diacid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid, cellulose and xylan.</s><s>Milk is not curdled.</s><s>Starch and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Urease, lecithinase and lipase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from peptone or thiosulfate.</s><s>NH<sub>3</sub> is produced from yeast extract, peptone and l-arginine.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (46·21 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (8·90 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5·93 %) and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5·15 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TB107<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12891<sup>T</sup>=AS 1.5024<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the granule sludge of a UASB reactor treating brewery wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>