<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1401_nm.5271" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5271" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5271" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus schleiferi coagulans</organism><reference id="rid.1401"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Igimi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus schleiferi subsp. coagulans subsp. nov., isolated from the external auditory meatus of dogs with external ear otitis.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>409</fpage><lpage>411</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-409</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2275856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> (co.a´gu.lans. L. adj. <i>coagulans</i> curdling, coagulating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of <i>S. schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> is based on a total of 21 strains, unless noted otherwise.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci, 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, and, predominantly, in irregular clusters.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s><s>Colonies on horse blood agar after 24 h at 37°C are circular, entire, 1.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, slightly convex, and opaque with a smooth glistening surface.</s><s>Not pigmented.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs in both the aerobic and anaerobic portions of semisolid thioglycolate medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce free coagulase (test tube coagulase test with rabbit plasma) but fail to produce fixed coagulase (clumping factor with human plasma).</s><s>All strains produce β-hemolysin (hemolysis on sheep blood agar and hot-cold reaction), but α-hemolysin and δ-hemolysin are not detected.</s><s>All strains reduce nitrate and produce heat-stable nuclease, acetoin, phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, and urease.</s><s>All strains are hyaluronidase and oxidase negative.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to 1.6 μg of novobiocin per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains produce acid from glucose, mannose, fructose, galactose, and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is usually produced from ribose (95%) (negative for strain GA288) and lactose (86%) (negative for strains GA390, GA400, and GA416).</s><s>Some strains produce acid from mannitol (48%) (strains GA11, GA222, GA227, GA238, GA247, GA288, GA412, GA456, GA483, and GA499) and sucrose (24%) (GA64, GA89, GA337, GA347 and GA400).</s><s>No acid is produced from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, trehalose, raffinose, melibiose, melezitose, glycogen, sorbitol, erythritol, inositol, adonitol, dulcitol, or xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G,+C content of DNA, as determined on the basis of the melting temperature in three strains (strains GA211, GA11, and GA64), ranges from 35 to 37 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of the type strain, GA211 (=JCM 7470), are the same as these described above.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of its DNA is 35 mol%.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from canine external ear otitis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Selected characteristics that are useful in the identification of <i>S. schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> and in distinguishing this taxon from other coagulase-positive <i>Staphylococcus</i> species are listed in Table 2. <i>S. schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> is easily dserentiated from coagulase-negative <i>S. schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>schleiferi</i> on the basis of its test tube coagulase test reaction and from the other coagulase-negative species on the basis of its production of coagulase, heat-stable nuclease, and phemolysin. <i>S. schleiferi</i> subsp. <i>coagulans</i> can be distinguished from other coagulase-positive species on the basis of its acetoin production, β-hemolysin production, negative hyaluronidase activity, and lack of acid production from trehalose or maltose.</s></p></content></protolog>