<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9215_nm.14468" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14468" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14468" rank="species">Gracilibacillus saliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.9215"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus saliphilus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1620</fpage><lpage>1624</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006569-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542126</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilibacillus saliphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gracilibacillus saliphilus</em> (sa.li′phi.lus. L. n. <em>sal</em>, <em>salis</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>saliphilus</em> salt-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, aerobic, thin rods, 0.7–0.9×2.0–10.0 μm (Fig. 2).</s><s>Cells are motile and spherical endospores are produced in a terminal position.</s><s>Colonies are circular, creamy white, convex, opaque and 0.5–1 mm in diameter on modified ISP5 medium.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, growing over a wide range (1–22 %, w/v) of NaCl concentrations (optimally at 10–15 %, w/v).</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–45 °C and pH 6.0–8.0; optimal growth occurs at 28–37 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase and in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Negative (in API 20E tests) for ONPG, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, starch and urea are hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin and Tweens 40 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acids are produced (in API 50 CHB tests) from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, melibiose, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside and d-xylose.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, results are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, but negative for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, acid phosphatase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>l-Arginine, cellobiose, glycine and l-lysine are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources, but the following substrates are not: acetate, adenine, aspartic acid, citrate, dulcitol, l-histidine, hypoxanthine, inositol, propionate, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, xanthine and xylitol.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics: amikacin (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), tobramycin (10 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), neomycin (10 μg), netilmicin sulfate (30 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), penicillin (10 U), rifampicin (5 μg), trimethoprim sulfonamides (1.25 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, four unknown phosphoglycolipids, an unknown aminophospholipid and unknown glycolipids (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>The cellular fatty acid composition includes (in decreasing abundance) anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron micrograph of cells of strain YIM 91119<sup>T</sup>, showing rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Bar, 500 nm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 91119<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19802<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AA 208015<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil collected from Ebinur Lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>