<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4080_nm.5823" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5823" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5823" rank="species">Mobiluncus mulieris</organism><reference id="rid.4080"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spiegel</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mobiluncus gen. nov., Mobiluncus curtisii subsp. curtisii sp. nov., Mobiluncus curtisii subsp. holmesii subsp. nov., and Mobiluncus mulieris sp. nov., curved rods from the human vagina.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>177</fpage><lpage>184</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-177</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mobiluncus mulieris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mobiluncus mulieris</i> (mu.li.e'ris. L. gen. n. <i>mulieris</i> of a woman; from “<i>Vibrio mulieris</i>,” which was suggested by Prevot [26])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, gram negative, curved, nonsporing, rod shaped, and motile by means of multiple subterminal flagella.</s><s>Migration through soft (0.25%) agar is variable.</s><s>The cells are &#x003C;0.5 μm wide and have a mean length of 2.9 μm (Fig. 2B).</s><s>Colonies are colorless, translucent, smooth, convex, and entire and reach a maximum diameter of 2 to 3 mm after 5 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is not stimulated by arginine.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrulline, ornithine, and ammonia are not produced from arginine.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed in the absence of serum.</s><s>Strongly saccharolytic (pH &#x003C;5.5).</s><s>Cultures are more turbid in PY broth supplemented with rabbit serum and glycogen or maltose than in PY broth supplemented with rabbit serum and glucose or in PY broth supplemented with rabbit serum alone.</s><s>Other biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The fermentation products from glycogen include succinate (&#x003E;1 meq/100 ml), acetate (&#x003E;1 meq/100 ml), and trace amounts of fumarate (&#x003C;1 rneq/100 ml); 8 of 10 strains produce trace amounts of oxaloacetate (&#x003C;1 meq/100 ml), 6 of 10 strains produce trace amounts of pyruvate (&#x003C;1 meq/100 ml), and 5 of 10 strains produce trace amounts of lactate (&#x003C;1 meq/100 ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alpha-glucosidase (15 to ≥40 nmol of product), phosphoamidase (≤5 nmol), leucine aminopeptidase (&#x003C;5 to 20 nmol), and esterase lipase (&#x003C;5 nmol) are produced.</s><s>Acid phosphatase is produced by 1 of 10 strains.</s><s>Butyrate esterase, lipase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase are not produced at 35 or 42°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite by 1 of 10 strains.</s><s>A strong CAMP reaction (Fig. 3) is produced on brucella agar supplemented with 5% sheep blood when <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> ATCC 25923 is used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 49 to 50 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain SV17J (= ATCC 35243).</s></p></content></protolog>