<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12340_nm.20370" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20370" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20370" rank="species">Neisseria shayeganii</organism><reference id="rid.12340"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wolfgang</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carpenter</surname><given-names>A.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gronow</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Habura</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jose</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nazarian</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kohlerschmidt</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Limberger</surname><given-names>r.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schoonmaker-Bopp</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Musser</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Neisseria wadsworthii sp. nov. and Neisseria shayeganii sp. nov., isolated from clinical specimens</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>98</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022426-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173010</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Neisseria shayeganii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Neisseria shayeganii</em> (sha.ye.ga′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>shayeganii</em> of Shayegani, to recognize and honour over 40 years of public service and leadership by Dr Mehdi Shayegani in the Bacteriology Laboratory of the Wadsworth Center, New York State Department of Health).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are small, circular, entire, convex, moist, light yellow to grey and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped and 1.0–1.5 μm wide by 2.5–5.5 μm long.</s><s>Growth is observed between 10 and 42 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed on MacConkey agar after 5 days.</s><s>Facultative anaerobe.</s><s>Cells produce catalase and cytochrome oxidase and they reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for acid production using Hugh and Leifson O-F base with 1 % d-fructose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Except as noted, negative for acid production in peptone water sugar (containing 1 % carbohydrate) from adonitol, l-arabinose, dulcitol, d-glucose (positive for strain 871<sup>T</sup>), inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Negative for acid production (Gordon sugars) from l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Negative for utilization of Simmons' citrate, hydrolysis of aesculin, urea and gelatin, indole production, decarboxylation of lysine, ornithine and arginine using Moeller's decarboxylase medium and production of H<sub>2</sub>S in triple-sugar iron agar (Forbes <em>et al.</em>, 1998; Gordon <em>et al.</em>, 1973; Kohlerschmidt <em>et al.</em>, 2009).</s><s>Using the API NH system, both known strains are positive for <em>γ</em>-glutamyltransferase and acidification of d-glucose and negative for penicillinase, acidification of d-fructose, maltose and sucrose, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, lipase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and indole; variable for proline arylamidase (type strain negative).</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, both known strains are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase; variable for <em>α</em>-fucosidase (type strain negative).</s><s>The predominant CFAs for both known strains are 16 : 0, summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-15 : 0 2-OH), 12 : 0, 12 : 0 3-OH and 14 : 0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 871<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22246<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109933<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sputum of a 77-year-old female in New York, USA.</s><s>Reference strain 12337 (=DSM 22244 =CIP 109932) was isolated from an arm wound of a 47-year-old female in New York, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>