<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6587_nm.10977" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10977" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10977" rank="species">Pseudomonas moraviensis</organism><reference id="rid.6587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tvrzová</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedlácek</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pácová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedo</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zdráhal</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steffen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas moraviensis sp. nov. and Pseudomonas vranovensis sp. nov., soil bacteria isolated on nitroaromatic compounds, and emended description of Pseudomonas asplenii.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2657</fpage><lpage>2663</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63988-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082407</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas moraviensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas moraviensis</em> (mo.ra.vi′en.sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>moraviensis</em> pertaining to Moravia, the region of the Czech Republic where strain 1B4<sup>T</sup> was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 0.6–1.3×2–5 μm, occurring singly or in pairs and motile by polar flagella (see Supplementary Fig. S1a in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Cells form long rods (5–10 μm) in liquid medium (nutrient broth).</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, smooth and 2–3 mm in diameter (after 24 h of cultivation).</s><s>Fluorescein is produced on King B medium.</s><s>Pyocyanine is not produced on King A medium.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–35 °C, with optimum growth at 28–35 °C.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urease- and DNase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Tween 80, gelatin and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but not aesculin or starch.</s><s>Lecithinase and indole are not produced and levan is not formed.</s><s>By API 20NE, <em>β</em>-galactosidase is not produced and fermentation of d-glucose and assimilation of adipate are negative.</s><s>Caprate, malate and citrate are assimilated.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are assimilated (API 50 CH): glycerol, l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-trehalose, d-lyxose (weakly positive after 96 h), gluconate and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Negative reactions (API 50 CH) were observed for erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized (Biolog system): Tween 40, Tween 80, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-trehalose, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Negative reactions (Biolog) are observed with <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-cellobiose, erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, myo-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, xylitol, itaconic acid, sebacic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Other reactions determined by API 20NE, API 50 CH and Biolog systems are given in Table 1.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is characterized by the presence of hydroxy fatty acids and cyclopropane fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1B4<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7280<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16007<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>