<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4069_nm.8129" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8129" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8129" rank="species">Arenibacter latericius</organism><reference id="rid.4069"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vysotskii</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huq</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenibacter gen. nov., new genus of the family flavobacteriaceae and description of a new species, Arenibacter latericius sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1987</fpage><lpage>1995</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760939</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arenibacter latericius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arenibacter latericius</i> (la.te.ri'ci.us. L. adj. <i>latericius</i> of brick, here pertaining to the dark orange pigmentation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description as for the genus.</s><s>In addition, colonies are circular, low convex, shiny with entire edges on solid media containing high nutrient components.</s><s>Colonies are dark orange in colour because of non-diffusible carotenoid pigments.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are absent.</s><s>No growth is detected at 4 and 42 °C.</s><s>Alkalitolerant.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin or casein.</s><s>Produces α-N-acetylgalactosaminidase.</s><s>Utilizes α-D-glucose, L-glutamic acid, L-ornithine, uridine, glycerol, DL-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate, according to the BIOLOG system.</s><s>Dextrin, N-acetyL-D-galactosamine, N-acetyL-D-glucosamine, cellobiose, D-fructose, α-lactose, α-D-lactose lactulose, glycogen, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, dmellibiose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, sucrose, D-trehalose, DL-lactic acid, turanose, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-proline, D-serine, L-serine and L-threonine are weakly utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, ampicillin, cephaloridin and lincomycin.</s><s>Not susceptible to kanamycin, benzylpenicillin, oxacillin, neomycin, streptomycin, gentamicin and polymyxin B.</s><s>The major polar lipid is phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Sphingophospholipids are absent.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are odd-numbered, iso-branched (about 70%): 15: 0, i15:0, a15:0, i15:1, i17:0; 16: 0, 16: 1(n-7), 18:0, 18:1(n-7) in minor quantities.</s><s>TheG­C content of the DNA ranges from 37 to 38 mol%.</s><s>Type strain is KMM 426<sup>T</sup> (VKM B 2137D<sup>T</sup>=LMG 19694<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106861<sup>T</sup>), deposited in the Collection of Marine Micro-organisms (KMM) of the Pacific Institute of Bioorganic Chemistry, Vladivostok, the All-Russian Collection of Microorganisms, Moscow, Russia, and the Culture Collection of the Laboratory of Microbiology, University of Gent, Belgium.</s><s>Isolated from the marine environment (sandy sediments, holothurian, brown alga).</s></p></content></protolog>