<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4417_nm.6019" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6019" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6019" rank="species">Ornithinimicrobium humiphilum</organism><reference id="rid.4417"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ornithinimicrobium humiphilum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel soil actinomycete with L-ornithine in the peptidoglycan</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>87</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211277</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ornithinimicrobium humiphilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ornithinimicrobium humiphilum</i> (hu.mi'phil.um. L. adj. <i>humo</i> from soil; Gr. adj. <i>philus</i> liking, preferring; N.L. <i>humiphilum</i> liking soil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular short rods and cocci occurring singly, in pairs, short chains or clusters.</s><s>Cell diameters of the cocci vary from 0.7 to 1.4 μm.</s><s>The rods are 1.4-3.2x0.6-1.0 μm.</s><s>Gram-positive, not acid-fast, non-motile, no formation of spores.</s><s>Aerobic to microaerophilic.</s><s>Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies are 0.3-1.2 mm in diameter and vary in colour from whitish to bright yellow.</s><s>Colony size, colour and growth rate change depending on the composition of the medium.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-ribose and starch and in a low amount from dextrin, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid production from lactose, D-fructose, D-glucitol, glycerol, inulin, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose or salicin.</s><s>Formate is used as sole carbon source.</s><s>Utilization of malate and succinate is delayed and weakly expressed.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate and dL-tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and catalase are produced, indole and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges- Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch and xanthine are decomposed; adenine, aesculin, hippurate, Tween 80, tyrosine and urea are not.</s><s>Addition of NaCl to R medium is well tolerated up to a concentration of 6% (w/v).</s><s>Good growth occurs between 37 and 42°C; no growth at 50°C.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), neomycin (30 μg), nitrofuran (300 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), penicillin G (2 IU), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (2 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>No susceptibility to oxacillin (5 μg) or sulfonamide (300 μg).</s><s>Tested by the API ZYMenzyme assay, strain HKI 0124T is positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase and negative for lipase (C14), agalactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>The enzyme assay showed a weak reaction for trypsin and chymotrypsin.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the A4b type with an L-Orn←L- Ala←Gly←D-Asp interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The acyl type of the glycan chain of peptidoglycan is acetyl.</s><s>The fatty acids are of the iso and anteiso branched type with predominant amounts of 13-methyl tetradecanoic acid and 14-methyl pentadecanoic acid.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, three unknown glycolipids and three unknown phospholipids.</s><s>Glucose is the dominating whole cell sugar; arabinose, rhamnose and xylose are found in traces.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70 mol%.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0124<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12362<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106634<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>