<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3467_nm.8088" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8088" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8088" rank="species">Flavobacterium gillisiae</organism><reference id="rid.3467"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McCammon</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Antarctic Flavobacterium species: description of Flavobacterium gillisiae sp. nov., Flavobacterium tegetincola sp. nov., and Flavobacterium xanthum sp. nov., nom. rev. and reclassification of [Flavobacterium] salegens as Salegentibacter salegens gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1055</fpage><lpage>1063</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843045</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium gillisiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium gillisiae</i> (gil.is.i'ae. M.L. gen. <i>gillisiae</i> of Gillis, named after Monique Gillis, a microbiologist who pioneered new techniques for bacterial taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 2-5 μm in length and 0.4-0.5 μm in width.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Cell masses from aerobic cultures are orange.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments not detected.</s><s>Colonies have a butyrous consistency, are circular and convex in shape, and possess an entire edge.</s><s>Sodium nitrate, ammonium chloride, L-glutamate, peptone and Casamino acids serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Vitamins are not required for growth but are stimulatory.</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth however grows well on seawater-containing media and tolerates up to 5% NaCl.</s><s>On solid media growth occurs at 0-27 °C, with optimal growth at about 20 °C while no growth occurs at 30 °C or above.</s><s>Strictly aerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Produces acid from D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, D-fructose, sucrose, trehalose, cellobiose, maltose, D-mannitol and glycerol, but not from L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-xylose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, adonitol, D-sorbitol or inositol.</s><s>Degrades casein, starch, aesculin, chitin and Tween 80, but not gelatin, agar, alginate, CMC, pectin, DNA, urea, uric acid or xanthine.</s><s>The arginine dihydrolase test is positive.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activity is absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole from l-tryptophan, H<sub>2</sub>S production, Voges-Proskauer, Simmons' citrate and oxidase tests are negative.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Can utilize D-glucose as a sole carbon source.</s><s>DNA G­+C content is 32 mol% (determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Type strain is ACAM 601<sup>T</sup>, isolated from sea ice from Prydz Bay, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>