<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5246_nm.814" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.814" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.814" rank="species">Rhodospirillum centenum</organism><reference id="rid.5246"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Favinger</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stadtwald</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gest</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodospirillum centenum, sp. nov., a thermotolerant cyst-forming anoxygenic photosynthetic bacterium</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>55</volume><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="227">Antonie van Leeuwenhoek</source><issn>0003-6072</issn><essn>1572-9699</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2757370</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodospirillum centenum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodospirillum centenum</i> was isolated from a water sample (temperature, ca. 55°C collected at the edge of the source pool at Thermopolis Hot Springs, Wyoming. The bacterium was enriched, at 40°C, using a procedure that is selective for anoxygenic photosynthetic bacteria that fix N<sub>2</sub> readily (Gest et al. 1985). Isolation of <i>R. centenum</i> in pure culture and characterization of its morphological, physiological and other properties were accomplished using techniques detailed by Pellerin &#x0026; Gest (1983) and Gest et al. (1985). Electron micrographs of thin sections of the bacterium were made essentially as described by Gest &#x0026; Favinger (1983).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. centenum</i> cells are typically short (1 x 2 to 3 μm) and, depending on the composition of the growth medium, are vibrioid to spiral in shape.</s><s>When grown phototrophically, the cells are actively motile by means of a single, long polar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>Lamellar photosynthetic membranes are localized in the cell periphery, and the in vivo absorption spectrum of the photopigments is virtually identical to that of <i>R. rubrum</i> (peaks at ca. 800 and 875 nm; Biebl &#x0026; Drews 1969).</s><s>The bacterium requires biotin and vitamin B<sub>12</sub> for growth, whereas biotin is the only growth factor necessary for <i>R. rubrum</i>. <i>R. centenum</i> grows photoheterotrophically at temperatures up to 45°C and optimally between 40°C and 42°C, whereas most isolates of non-sulfur purple bacteria are unable to grow at temperatures above 39°C.</s><s>The G + C content of <i>R. centenum</i> DNA is 68.3 Mol% ; values reported for <i>R. rubrum</i> DNA range from 62.4 to 65 (Silver et al. 1971).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. rubrum</i> and most other non-sulfur purple bacteria readily use malate as a sole carbon source, but <i>R. centenum</i> is unable to grow on malate or related C<sub>4</sub> dicarboxylic acids.</s><s>With NH<sub>4</sub> as nitrogen source, carbon sources utilizable by <i>R. centenum</i> include pyruvate, lactate, and acetate; when supplemented with bicarbonate (9 mM), butyrate, caproate, and caprylate also support phototropic growth.</s><s>For routine purposes (for either anaerobic phototrophic or dark aerobic chemoheterotrophic growth), we employ pyruvate as the carbon source in a medium designated as CENMED, which contains per liter of deionized water: 2.2g sodium pyruvate, 0.9g K<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>, 0.6g KH<sub>2</sub>PO<sub>4</sub>, 1g NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, 5 mg disodium EDTA, 200mg MgSO<sub>4</sub>-7H<sub>2</sub>O, 1ml trace element solution (see Fry et al. 1984), 75 mg CaCl<sub>2</sub>⋄2H<sub>2</sub>O, 2 ml chelated iron solution (prepare by dissolving 1 g FeCl⋄4H<sub>2</sub>O and 2 g disodium EDTA in 1 liter deionized water, and adding 3 ml concentrated HCl), 20μg vitamin B<sub>12</sub>, 15μg biotin, 0.5 g Na<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>⋄5H<sub>2</sub>O; pH adjusted to 6.8 with NaOH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>With pyruvate as the carbon source, NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>, N<sub>2</sub>, glutamate, glutamine, and alanine serve as sole nitrogen sources for rapid phototrophic growth.</s><s>The nitrogenase activity of <i>R. centenum</i> cells grown on N<sub>2</sub> (estimated by the acetylene reduction assay) is comparable to that observed with <i>R. rubrum</i>, namely, of the order of 500-1000 nmoles acetylene reduced/hour/mg dry weight of cells (see Madigan et al. 1984 for nitrogenase activities of species in the family <i>Rhodospirillaceae</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. centenum</i> is a typical non-sulfur purple bacterium in respect to ability to grow aerobically as a chemoheterotroph in darkness on various organic carbon sources.</s><s>An unusual feature was observed in cultures growing in this way with butyrate as the sole carbon source, namely, the conversion of the spiral-shaped cells to cysts (Figs 2 and 3).</s><s>These forms were not seen in cultures grown photosynthetically on butyrate + bicarbonate.</s><s>The relative dessication resistance of cysts and growing cells was determined as follows.</s><s>The two kinds of cell forms were filtered onto separate membrane filters, which were incubated in a drying oven at 38 ~ C.</s><s>After drying for prolonged periods under these conditions, the filter discs were placed on agar growth medium in Petri dishes, and the latter incubated in illuminated Gas Pak jars.</s><s>Within 48 hours, discs of cysts that had been dried for 8 days showed extensive red growth over the entire filter whereas the controls (growing cells) dried for 4 days showed virtually no growth.</s><s>Increased resistance of cysts to desiccation has been observed in several other bacterial genera (Brock and Madigan 1988).</s><s>Cyst formation by <i>Azotobacter</i> cells has been correlated with the accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate (Stevenson and Socolofsky 1973) and this may well be the case in <i>R. centenum</i> also; <i>R. centenum</i> cells grown under cyst-forming conditions have a high content of the polymer (ca. 30% of the dry weight).</s><s>The formation of cysts and the relatively high temperature optimum for growth presumably would favor long-term survival of <i>R. centenum</i> under conditions extant in niches adjacent to hot springs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron micrographs of thin sections of <i>R. centenum</i> revealed still another remarkable feature of this organism.</s><s>The cytoplasm of many growing cells contains refractile bodies that have the unique structure shown in Fig. 4.</s><s>The refractile inclusions were kindly identified by Dr J.R.</s><s>Preer, Jr. as 'R bodies', which have been observed thus far in a very limited number of prokaryotes, notably in endosymbionts of paramecia (Preer &#x0026; Preer 1984).</s><s>In such endosymbionts, the refractile R body consists of a coiled proteinaceous 'ribbon', and in some instances is known to be a plasmid-determined trait (Ouackenbush &#x0026; Burbach 1983).</s><s>This is the first instance in which R bodies have been observed in photosynthetic bacteria, and their significance for <i>R. centenum</i> is now under investigation. <i>R. centenum</i>, strain Favinger/Gest, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (no. 43720).</s></p></content></protolog>