<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5227_nm.2797" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2797" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2797" rank="species">Psychrobacter proteolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.5227"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mark</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Turkiewicz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lubitz</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter proteolyticus sp. nov., a psychrotrophic, halotolerant bacterium isolated from the Antarctic krill Euphausia superba Dana, excreting a cold-adapted metalloprotease.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>44</fpage><lpage>53</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11403398</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Psychrobacter proteolyticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Psychrobacter proteolyticus</i> (pro.te.o.ly'ti.cus M.L. n. adj. <i>proteolyticus</i>, proteolytic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-pigmented, non-motile, non-sporeforming, rod-shaped to coccoidal.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–1.25 μm wide x 1.0–2.5 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard media are cream colored, circular, entire, convex, and of butyrous consistence; diameter is up to 1.0 mm after 2 d incubation at room temperature.</s><s>Pigments are not produced.</s><s>The following biochemical tests are positive: oxidase, catalase, urease, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valin arylamidase, acid phosphatase, and naphtol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Gelatin, casein and trybutrine are hydrolyzed, esculin, starch and DNA are not.</s><s>The following biochemical tests are negative: arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, C14 lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, nitrate reduction, and indole production.</s><s>Citrate is utilised as single carbon source.</s><s>Acid is produced from carbohydrates: glucose, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>No acid is produced from the carbohydrates: mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, and saccharose.</s><s>Phylogenetically, <i>P. proteolyticus</i> clusters with the validly published species of the genus <i>Psychrobacter</i> within the γ-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> (WOESE, 1987; STACKEBRANDT et al., 1988).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43.6 mol%.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the main respiratory lipoquinone.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol are the major polar lipids; several unknown lipids are present in minor concentrations as well.</s><s>The predominant nonpolar fatty acids are 18:1 <i>cis</i> 9 and 16:1 <i>cis</i>; 17:1 <i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>; 16:0, 18:0 and 12:0 are present in minor amounts.</s><s>The predominant 2-hydroxy fatty acid is 12:0 2-OH.</s><s>Significant trace amounts of 18:1 trans 9 <i>cis</i> 11, 17:0, 17:0 iso, 15:0 anteiso, 14:0 3-OH and 14:0 are present as well.</s><s>Source: strain 116 was isolated at the Arctowski Polish Antarctic station from a stomach specimen of the Antarctic krill <i>Euphausia superba</i> Dana caught in Admiralty Bay, King George Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s><s>Strain 116 has been deposited in the Collection de I'Institut Pasteur, France, as CIP 106830<sup>T</sup> and in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen and Zellkulturen, as DSM 13887<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>