<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5306_nm.6503" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6503" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6503" rank="species">Rhodococcus zopfii</organism><reference id="rid.5306"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stoecker</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herwig</surname><given-names>R.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus zopfii sp. nov., a toxicant-degrading bacterium.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>106</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123552</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus zopfii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodococcus zopfii</i> (zop'fi.i M.L. adj. <i>zopfii</i>, in honor of Wilhelm Friedrich Zopf, who first described the bacterium <i>R. rhodochrous</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive to gram variable, oxidase negative, and catalase positive and grow filamentously, exhibiting extensive branching and hyphal growth before fragmenting into irregular rod-shaped to coccoid units.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On glucose-yeast extract agar, colonies are red to orange and wrinkled.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 7 days of incubation at 30°C in a mineral salts medium supplemented with ammonia and trace elements, growth is produced with 1% (wt/vol) maltose, 0.1% sodium benzoate, sebacic acid, sodium pyruvate, sodium succinate, 1% (vol/vol) ethanol, and glycerol, but not with 1% inositol, mannitol, rhamnose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, or 0.1% sodium citrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose, and glucose.</s><s>The following simple fatty acids are released by acid methanolysis (relative abundance values are indicated in parentheses): C<sub>14:0</sub>, (4.3), C<sub>16:0</sub> (100), C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>cis</i> 9 (27.1), C<sub>16:1</sub> <i>trans</i> 9/15i2OH (20.4) C<sub>17:0</sub>(3.4), C<sub>18:0</sub> (25.5), C<sub>18:1</sub> cis 9 (81.7), 10CH<sub>3</sub> C<sub>18:0</sub>(tuberculostearic acid) (17.8), and C<sub>20:0</sub> (3.4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mycolic acids are present and contain between 33 and 36 carbon atoms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain T1, was isolated from a toluenephenol bioreactor operated by the Department of Civil Engineering, University of Washington.</s><s>This strain degrades chlorobenzene, 1,2 dichlorobenzene, 1,3 dichlorobenzene, and 1,4 dichlorobenzene and uses phenol and toluene as sole sources of carbon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70 mol%.</s><s>Strain T1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51349<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>