<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2682_nm.5280" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5280" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5280" rank="species">Staphylococcus vitulinus</organism><reference id="rid.2682"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engelbeen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Štetina</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petráš</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Staphylococcus pulvereri Zakrzewska-Czerwińska et al. 1995 as a later synonym of Staphylococcus vitulinus Webster et al. 1994.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2213</fpage><lpage>2215</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63080-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545460</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Staphylococcus vitulinus</em> Webster <em>et al.</em> 1994</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Biochemical test results obtained in this study were nearly in full agreement with the species description of <em>S. vitulinus</em>, including variable reactions published by Webster <em>et al.</em> (1994).</s><s>The only differences were found for acidification of mannitol (described as positive for <em>S. vitulinus</em>; we found three negative strains) and ribose (described as variable; all our strains were negative).</s><s>Contradictory results were obtained for mannose acidification (described as negative for <em>S. vitulinus</em>).</s><s>All our strains were negative for this test in ID 32 STAPH kit, but all were positive in API STAPH kit, and conventional testing revealed four positive strains.</s><s>In addition to the species description, all tested strains were positive for glucose acidification and gelatin hydrolysis; negative for acidification of melibiose and methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, Tween 80 as well as arginine dihydrolase and DNase production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differentiation of <em>S. vitulinus</em> from the other novobiocin-resistant and oxidase-positive species, <em>S. lentus</em>, <em>S. sciuri</em> (including all three subspecies) and <em>S. fleurettii</em>, remains unchanged as described by Webster <em>et al.</em> (1994) and Vernozy-Rozand <em>et al.</em> (2000) except for the mannose acidification test, which gives test-kit-dependent results as discussed above.</s><s>Moreover, a few controversial biochemical test results were noted for the <em>S. fleurettii</em> type strain in this study.</s><s>The type strain of <em>S. fleurettii</em>, CCM 4922<sup>T</sup>, described as turanose- and l-arabinose-positive, was repeatedly turanose- as well as l-arabinose-negative with the ID 32 STAPH kit and in conventional tests; similarly, trehalose acidification, described as positive for this strain, was negative in the ID 32 STAPH kit, positive in the API STAPH kit and delayed-positive (3 days) in the conventional test.</s></p></content></protolog>