<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6402_nm.7789" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7789" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7789" rank="species">Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis</organism><reference id="rid.6402"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kostanjšek</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Štrus</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drobne</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Avguštin</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>'Candidatus Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis', an intracellular bacterium from the hepatopancreas of the terrestrial isopod Porcellio scaber (Crustacea: Isopoda).</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>543</fpage><lpage>549</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02802-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023973</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis’</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>According to Murray &#x0026; Stackebrandt (1995), properties of obligate symbionts of eukaryotic cells should be recorded by a ‘<em>Candidatus</em>’ designation. For this reason, it is proposed that the intracellular hepatopancreatic bacteria from <em>P. scaber</em> should be designated ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis' [Rhab.do.chla.my′di.a. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhabdos</em> stick, rod; N.L. fem. n. <em>Chlamydia</em> taxonomic name of a bacterial genus; N.L. fem. n. <em>Rhabdochlamydia</em> rod-shaped chlamydiae, referring to the rod-like shape of elementary bodies; por.cel.li.o′nis. N.L. gen. n. <em>porcellionis</em> of <em>Porcellio</em>, pertaining to the taxonomic genus name of the host organism (a terrestrial isopod)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis' comprises intracellular bacteria within membrane-bound vacuoles in the cytoplasm of hepatopancreatic cells of the terrestrial isopod <em>Porcellio scaber</em>.</s><s>Cells are non-motile, non-cultivable on cell-free media and have the Gram-negative microscopic appearance of a cell wall without a discernible peptidoglycan layer.</s><s>Morphology of ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis' corresponds to the description of ‘<em>Chlamydia isopodii</em>’ (Shay <em>et al.</em>, 1985) and a ‘<em>Rickettsiella</em>-like organism’ (Drobne <em>et al.</em>, 1999).</s><s>Bacteria exhibit a chlamydia-like developmental cycle, in which the cells appear in three morphological forms (reticulate, intermediate and mature elementary bodies) that are packed in membrane-bound vacuoles in the cytoplasm of the host cell.</s><s>Reticulate bodies with coccoid morphology can be small (up to 1 μm in diameter), which multiply by binary fission, or larger (1–4 μm in diameter), with granular inclusions in the cytoplasm.</s><s>Morphology of intermediate bodies is coccoid (350–650 nm in diameter), with an electron-dense area in the centre of the cell.</s><s>Mature elementary bodies have a five-layered cell wall, variable rod-shaped morphology (250–700 nm in length and 100–150 nm in diameter) and oblong structures in the cytoplasm.</s><s>On the basis of its 16S rRNA gene sequence, ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis' forms a distinctive lineage within the order <em>Chlamydiales</em>, close to the family <em>Simkaniaceae</em>, with an oligonucleotide that is complementary to a unique region of the 16S rRNA gene (5′-GAAATGCAAAGGACAGCATC-3′).</s><s>Assignment to ‘<em>Candidatus</em> Rhabdochlamydia porcellionis' is based on the sequence of the 16S rRNA gene (GenBank accession no. AY223862) and the distinctive morphology of the elementary bodies.</s></p></content></protolog>