<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7255_nm.6674" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6674" rank="genus">Pseudonocardia</organism><reference id="rid.7255"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reichert</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pradella</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altendorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia asaccharolytica sp. nov. and Pseudonocardia sulfidoxydans sp. nov., two new dimethyl disulfide-degrading actinomycetes and emended description of the genus Pseudonocardia.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>441</fpage><lpage>449</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-441</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Pseudonocardia</i> Henssen 1957 (11)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The vegetative mycelium varies in thickness (0.4-2.0 μm) and in the degree of branching. Some strains form swollen hyphal segments. Aerial mycelium may or may not be present. Both types of mycelium exhibit cell division in different directions and, in some species, the hyphae are covered by an electron-dense outer layer. Spore sizes vary and spores are normally smooth; chains of spores are formed by acropetal budding or septation from the substrate or aerial mycelium. Non-motile. Biochemically versatile. Some species are facultative autotrophs and some strains can oxidize hydrocarbons. Some species can oxidize methyl sulfides to sulfate. <i>P. thermophila</i> can degrade cellulose. The major menaquinone is tetrahydrogenated with eight isoprene units [MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>)]. Isobranched fatty acids are predominant. The main compound is iso-branched hexadecanoic acid. Straight-chain hexadecanoic acid and 10-methyl hexadecanoic acid are also present. Phosphatidylmethylethanolamine is present, occurrence of phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine is variable between the species. Cell wall type IV (arabinose, galactose and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as diagnostic constituents). Mycolates are absent. The G + C content of the DNA is 68-79 mol %. Members of this genus form a coherent group on the basis of 16s rRNA sequence data. The genus contains the species <i>P. alni</i>, <i>P. asaccharolytica</i>, <i>P. autotrophica</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia azurea</i>, <i>P. compacta</i>, <i>P. halophobica</i>, <i>P. hydrocarbonoxydans</i>, <i>P. petroleophila</i>, <i>P. saturnae</i>, <i>Pseudonocardia spinosa</i>, <i>P. sulfdoxydans</i> and <i>P. thermophila</i>. The type species is <i>P. thermophila</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>