<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4516_nm.6714" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6714" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6714" rank="species">Amycolatopsis kentuckyensis</organism><reference id="rid.4516"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Donahue</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sells</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henton</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis kentuckyensis sp. nov., Amycolatopsis lexingtonensis sp. nov. and Amycolatopsis pretoriensis sp. nov., isolated from equine placentas</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1601</fpage><lpage>1605</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02691-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130055</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Amycolatopsis kentuckyensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Amycolatopsis kentuckyensis</em> (ken.tuc.ky.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>kentuckyensis</em> from Kentucky, named after the place of origin, state of Kentucky, USA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Well-developed, yellow-orange to brownish-orange substrate mycelium is produced on most media.</s><s>Aerial mycelium that ranges from light orangish-white to greyish orange-white in colour is produced on most media.</s><s>A faint brownish soluble pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics are typical of the genus <em>Amycolatopsis</em>.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine, urea and hippurate are hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Adenine, allantoin, starch and xanthine are not hydrolysed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate and citrate are assimilated.</s><s>Benzoate, lactate, malate, mucate, oxalate, propionate, succinate and dl-tartrate are assimilated weakly, if at all.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from <em>meso-</em>erythritol, mannitol, melezitose or methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside.</s><s>Grows in the presence of up to 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–42 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NRRL B-24129<sup>T</sup> (=LDDC 9447-99<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44652<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from an equine placenta in Lexington, Kentucky.</s><s>Implicated in nocardioform placentitis in mares.</s></p></content></protolog>