<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6962_nm.5254" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5254" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5254" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus hominis novobiosepticus</organism><reference id="rid.6962"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olgiate</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Pelt</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKinnon</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zimmer</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muller</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weinstein</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mirrett</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus hominis subsp. novobiosepticus subsp. nov., a novel trehalose- and N-acetyl-D-glucosamine-negative, novobiocin- and multiple-antibiotic-resistant subspecies isolated from human blood cultures.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>799</fpage><lpage>812</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-799</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus hominis</i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus <i>hominis</i></i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> (novo.bio.sep'ti.cus. M.L. adj. combination of <i>novobio</i> pertaining to the property of novobiocin resistance and <i>septicus</i> pertaining to growth in blood)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics of 26 strains isolated in 1989-1996.</s><s>Colonies are unpigmented (grey-white), opaque, entire, butyrous, slightly convex to umbonate, and grow to a diameter of 5.4±0.3 mm on P agar and 5.8±0.3 mm on TSA.</s><s>Growth in the anaerobic portion of a semi-solid thioglycollate medium is negative within 48 h.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 35°C.</s><s>Cultures grown on TSA supplemented with either sheep or bovine blood do not exhibit haemolysis.</s><s>All strains produce acid aerobically from D-glucose, β-D-fructose, maltose, sucrose and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-trehalose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, D-sorbitol, Dcellobiose, salicin and D-raffinose.</s><s>Most strains (88%) produce weak to moderate amounts of acid aerobically from α-lactose and 42% of strains produce weak to moderate amounts of acid from D-melezitose.</s><s>All strains are positive for urease activity and negative for arginine utilization.</s><s>Some strains (27%) produce acetoin from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Capsular polysaccharide/adhesin is not produced.</s><s>All strains are resistant to novobiocin, nalidixic acid, penicillin, oxacillin and streptomycin, and are resistant or have intermediate resistance to methicillin, kanamycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Until a much larger number of strains are tested for antibiotic susceptibilities, some caution should be taken concerning the identification of a specific antibiotic resistance as intrinsic to the subspecies, even though all strains tested in this study proved to be resistant to the antibiotic.</s><s>Many strains are resistant to erythromycin, clindamycin, chloramphenicol, trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole and ciprofloxacin.</s><s>Other characteristics of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> that are uniformly positive or negative for the species are listed above in the section on phenotypic characterization.</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 35 mol%. <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> is commonly isolated from human blood cultures and occasionally from other clinical specimens.</s><s>If this subspecies is a resident on human skin, it probably exists as very small populations of cells and requires enrichment, e.g. by additional growth in a suitable medium or body fluids, for detection.</s><s>Although <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> is commonly isolated from human skin and is considered to be a major species of the cutaneous ecosystem, there are no reports of the isolation of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> from human skin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>novobiosepticus</i> is R22<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700236<sup>T</sup>); it was isolated from a human blood culture.</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies described above and has the following properties listed below.</s><s>Spherical cells (diameter 1.2-1.5 μm) occur mostly in tetrads and sometimes in pairs.</s><s>Circular colonies are 5-1-55 mm in diameter on P agar and 5-5-54 mm in diameter on TSA.</s><s>They have an entire edge, slightly convex to umbonate profile, dull surface, butyrous consistency, and are opaque and unpigmented (greywhite).</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, delayed and weak growth occurs in the anaerobic portion of a thioglycollate medium.</s><s>Acetoin is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically from D-glucose, β-D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, glycerol and α-lactose, but not from D-melezitose, D-trehalose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-xylose, L-arabinose, D-sorbitol, D-cellobiose, salicin and D-raffinose.</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin, nalidixic acid, penicillin G, oxacillin, methicillin, kanamycin, gentamicin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, clindamycin and ciprofloxacin, and susceptible to tetracycline, trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole, and vancomycin.</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 35 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>