<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12649_nm.22190" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22190" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22190" rank="species">Agromyces flavus</organism><reference id="rid.12649"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>Y.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>L.-Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces flavus sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1705</fpage><lpage>1709</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023242-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20802064</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces flavus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces flavus</em> (fla′vus. L. masc. adj. <em>flavus</em> yellow, referring to the colour of the colonies).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow on ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 4 and ISP 5, cream on ISP 6 and deep yellow on Bennett’s agar.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are absent.</s><s>Diffusible pigment is not observed.</s><s>Grows at 10–40 °C (optimum 28–32 °C), with 0–3 % NaCl and at pH 5.0–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).</s><s>As sole carbon sources, utilizes acetoacetic acid, dextrin, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-inulin, lactose (bovine origin), maltose, melezitose, d-tagatose, l-malic acid, d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-glucose, d-glycogen, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, aesculin, ferric citrate, glycerol, l-arabinose and l-rhamnose, but not 3-methyl glucose, amygdalin, arbutin, citric acid, d-adonitol, d-fructose, d-fructose 6-phosphate, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, d-ribose, d-saccharic acid, d-sorbitol, d-sorbose, dulcitol, gentiobiose, erythritol, formic acid, gelatin, glycyl l-proline, inositol, l-xylose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, mucic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-neuraminic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, propionic acid, quinic acid, xylitol, lactose, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid or γ-aminobutyric acid.</s><s>As sole nitrogen sources, utilizes inosine, l-alanine, l-glycine, l-methionine, l-valine and nitrate, but not d-aspartic acid, d-serine, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-hydroxyproline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine or l-tryptophan.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disc) chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), lincomycin (2), minocycline (30), norfloxacin (10), ofloxacin (10), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30), but resistant to ampicillin (10), aztreonam (30), penicillin G (10) and rifamycin SV (50).</s><s>The amino acids in the peptidoglycan are 2,4-diaminobutyric acid, alanine, glutamic acid and glycine and the cell-wall sugars are rhamnose, glucose and galactose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-12.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and two unknown glycolipids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CPCC 202695<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 19578<sup>T</sup>  = CCM 7623<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a soil sample collected from the Qinghai–Tibet plateau, China.</s></p></content></protolog>