<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.337_nm.533" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.533" rank="genus">Meiothermus</organism><reference id="rid.337"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Thermus ruber (Loginova et al. 1984), Thermus silvanus (Tenreiro et al. 1995), and Thermus chliarophilus (Tenreiro et al. 1995) to Meiothermus gen. nov. as Meiothermus ruber comb. nov., Meiothermus silvanus comb. nov., and Meiothermus chliarophilus comb. nov., respectively, and emendation of the genus Thermus.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>604</fpage><lpage>606</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-604</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Meiothermus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Meiothermus</i> (Mei.o.ther'mus. Gr. <i>meio</i>- less, Gr. adj. <i>thermus</i> hot, M. L. masc. n. <i>Meiothermus</i>, to indicate an organism living in a less hot place)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is based on data of Loginova et al. (12) and other authors (9, 24, 25).</s><s>The cells are 0.5 to 0.8 μm in diameter; the cell length is variable, and short filaments are formed.</s><s>The cells are gram negative and not motile.</s><s>Red- or yellow-pigmented colonies are produced.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory and aerobic, but some species grow with nitrate as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Some species are catalase negative.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature varies between 50 and 65°C.</s><s>None of the species grows at 70°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is about 8.0.</s><s>Menaquinone 8 is the predominant respiratory quinone; ornithine is the principal diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern is dominated by one major phospholipid and two prominent glycolipids that migrate close to each other.</s><s>Additional phospholipids and glycolipids are minor components.</s><s>The fatty acids are predominantly iso and anteiso branched; is0 2-hydroxy fatty acids are found in all strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Proteins and peptides are hydrolyzed by all strains.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed by some species.</s><s>Hexoses, a few pentoses and polyols, disaccharides, amino acids, and organic acids are used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>All strains require yeast extract or cofactors for growth.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 59 to 70 mol%.</s><s>Strains of the genus <i>Meiothermus</i> have been isolated from terrestrial hot springs with neutral to alkaline pH values and fermentors incubated at elevated temperatures.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <i>Meiothermus ruber</i> (12).</s><s>Two other species of this genus have been described (25).</s></p></content></protolog>