<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2584_nm.10201" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10201" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10201" rank="species">Spirochaeta coccoides</organism><reference id="rid.2584"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dröge</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fröhlich</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Radek</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>König</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta coccoides sp. nov., a novel coccoid spirochete from the hindgut of the termite Neotermes castaneus.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>72</volume><fpage>392</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/AEM.72.1.392-397.2006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16391069</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirochaeta coccoides</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirochaeta coccoides</i> (coc.coi'des. Gr. n. <i>coccos</i>, a berry; Gr. n. <i>eidos</i>, shape; N.L. adj. <i>coccoides</i>, berry-shaped)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci, 0.5 to 2 μm in diameter.</s><s>Cell aggregates are formed.</s><s>Axial filaments were not observed.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth and could serve as a sole energy and carbon source.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 30°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth was between 5.5 and 9.5 with an optimum at 7.4.</s><s>Pentoses (arabinose, xylose) and oligosaccharides (maltose, cellobiose, maltotriose, and maltotetraose) stimulated growth in a medium containing 0.4% yeast extract and 0.2% peptone.</s><s>Maltose is fermented to ethanol, formate, and acetate as the main fermentation products.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, lactate, pyruvate, amino acids, and polysaccharides are not utilized.</s><s>Activities of β-D-glucosidase, α-D-glucosidase, α-D-galactosidase, α-L-arabinosidase, β-D-fucosidase, and β-D-xylosidase are exhibited.</s><s>G+C content is 56.6 to 57.4 mol%.</s><s>Based on the nucleotide sequence of the 16S rRNA gene, this spirochete belongs to the genus <i>Spirochaeta</i> (accession number AJ698092; EMBL).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: strain SPN1 was isolated from the hindgut contents of the lower dry-wood termite <i>Neotermes castaneus</i> (Burmeister) (Isoptera: Kalotermitidae).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is strain SPN1 deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (DSMZ), Braunschweig, Germany (DSM 17374) and with the American Type Culture Collection (ATTC), Manassas, Va. (ATTC BAA-1237).</s></p></content></protolog>