<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6791_nm.3817" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3817" rank="genus">Arcobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6791"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mels</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vlaes</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van den Borre</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomic study of the emended genus Arcobacter with Arcobacter butzleri comb. nov. and Arcobacter skirrowii sp. nov., an aerotolerant bacterium isolated from veterinary specimens.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>344</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-344</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1503968</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Arcobacter</i>.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arcobacter</i> (Ar'co.bac.ter.L.n.arcus, bow; Gr.n.bacter, rod; M. L. masc. n. <i>Arcobacter</i>, bow-shaped rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative nonsporeforming rods (0.2 to 0.9 μm wide and 1 to 3 μm long) that are usually curved, S-shaped, or helical.</s><s>Motile with a darting, corkscrewlike movement by means of a single polar, unsheathed flagellum.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15, 25, and 30°C; variable growth occurs at 37 and 42°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs under microaerobic conditions (3 to 10% O<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>There is no hydrogen requirement for microaerobic growth.</s><s>Aerobic growth occurs at 30°C.</s><s>Anaerobic growth occurs at 35 to 37°C.</s><s>Carbohydrates are neither fermented nor oxidized.</s><s>Organic acids and amino acids are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1% (wt/vol) pteridine vibriostatic compound 0/129.</s><s>Growth is inhibited in the presence of 0.1% TTC.</s><s>A TTC concentration of 0.04% is inhibitory to some strains.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate, hydrolysis of DNA, and growth in the presence of 1% glycine, 1% oxgall, 1.5 and 3.5% NaCl, and 8% glucose are variable.</s><s>The strains have oxidase and catalase activities.</s><s>Negative reactions in methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests, no reduction of nitrite, no urease activity, no hydrolysis of hippurate, and no production of indole.</s><s>No production of hydrogen sulfide from triple sugar iron agar or in the rapid H<sub>2</sub>S test; variable production of hydrogen sulfide from cysteine.</s><s>Esculin and starch are not hydrolyzed, and gelatin is not liquified.</s><s>Most strains are nonhemolytic; alpha-hemolysis is often observed with <i>A. skirrowii</i> strains.</s><s>Nearly all strains are susceptible to nalidixic acid; susceptibility to cephalothin (30-μg discs) is variable.</s><s>For all species examined so far, menaquinone 6 and a second atypical menaquinone 6, the identity of which remains to be established, are the major respiratory quinones.</s><s>All strains have 12:0, 14:0 3OH, 16:1 cis 9, 16:0, and 18:1 cis 11 as major fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have been isolated from root-associated sediments and roots of salt marsh plants, from aborted fetuses of several species of farm animals, and from various other animal and human sources.</s><s>The pathogenicity of these organisms is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Arcobacter nitrofigilis</i>.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 27 to 30 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>