<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6733_nm.4513" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4513" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4513" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense</organism><reference id="rid.6733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morgan</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense sp. nov., a slightly acidophilic, anaerobic thermophile isolated from various hot springs in New Zealand, and emendation of the genus Thermoanaerobacterium.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>388</fpage><lpage>396</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-388</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense</i> (ao.te.a’ro.en.se. Maori n. <i>ao</i> cloud; Maori adj. <i>tea</i>, white; Maori adj. <i>roa</i>, long; N.L. adj. <i>aotearoense</i>, long white cloud, referring to the native Maori name for New Zealand, Aotearoa, Land of the Long White Cloud)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The distribution of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium</i>-like organisms in various volcanic heated environments on several continents has been surveyed, and strains belonging to <i>Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense</i> have been isolated only from various hot springs in New Zealand.</s><s>Therefore, the species is named to indicate the geographical region of the habitat, Aotearoa, the Maori name for New Zealand.</s><s>The rod-shaped, Gram stain-negative but Gram type-positive cells are 2.1 to 14.3 μm long and 0.7 to 1.0 μm wide.</s><s>The cells are peritrichously flagellated and exhibit tumbling motility.</s><s>Oval-terminal spores are produced in late-exponential- to early-stationary-phase cultures.</s><s>The organism is a moderately acidophilic thermophile that grows at 35 to 66°C (the optimum temperature is between 60 and 63°C) and at pH 3.8 to 6.8 (the optimum pH is pH 5.2).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 34.5 to 35 mol% G+C.</s><s>Thiosulfate is converted to elemental sulfur which is deposited within the cytoplasm of the cells.</s><s>The 16s rRNA sequence is most similar to the sequences of other <i>Thermoanaerobacterium</i> species, from which the new species can be distinguished by differences in protein profiles (Fig. 7), pH and temperature ranges for growth, and substrate utilization patterns (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain JW/SL-NZ613<sup>T</sup> has a G+C content of 35 mol% and is the type strain of <i>Thermoanaerobacterium aotearoense</i>; this strain has been deposited in the German Collection of Micro-Organisms as strain DSM The pH range for growth at 60°C is pH 3.8 to 6.8.</s><s>At an initial pH of 5.2, the temperature range for growth is about 35 to 66°C.</s><s>The cells are 0.7 to 0.9 μm wide and 2.1 to 10.7 μm long.</s></p></content></protolog>