<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3805_nm.389" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.389" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.389" rank="species">Thermococcus peptonophilus</organism><reference id="rid.3805"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>González</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermococcus peptonophilus sp. nov., a fast-growing, extremely thermophilic archaebacterium isolated from deep-sea hydrothermal vents.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>164</volume><fpage>159</fpage><lpage>164</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050249</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7545383</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermococcus peptonophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermococcus peptonophilus</i> (pep.to.no'.phi.lus Gr. adj. <i>peptos</i> cooked; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>peptonophilus</i> peptone-loving, indicating that it grows only on peptides as carbon source)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci, 0.7-2 μm in diameter, occurring mostly singly or in pairs.</s><s>Multiply by constriction.</s><s>Motile with a polar tuft of flagella.</s><s>The cell envelope consists of two layers, the external one is electron-dense.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Temperature range of growth from 60 to 100°C optimum 85°C pH range of growth from pH 3 to 8, with the optimum around pH 6.</s><s>NaCl concentrations allowing growth range from 1 to 5%; optimum 3%.</s><s>Sulfur is not essential for growth, although elemental sulfur greatly stimulates growth.</s><s>Heterotrophic growth on peptone, tryptone, yeast extract, beef extract and/or non-hydrolyzed casein.</s><s>No growth on free amino acids, sugars, organic acids, or in the absence of organic substrates.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by rifampicin.</s><s>G+C content is 52 mol%.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence is deposited at the GSDB, DDBJ, EMBL, and NLBI nucleotide sequence databases under the accession number D37982.</s><s>Inhabits marine hydrothermal vents in the western Pacific Ocean, specifically found in Izu-Bonin and South Mariana Trough areas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Thermococcus peptonophilus</i> OG-1, JCM 9653, Wako-shi, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>