<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7470_nm.5481" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5481" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5481" rank="species">Facklamia tabacinasalis</organism><reference id="rid.7470"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Facklamia tabacinasalis sp. nov., from powdered tobacco.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1247</fpage><lpage>1250</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1247</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425787</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Facklamia tabacinasalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Facklamia tabacinasalis</i> (ta.ba.ci.na'sa.lis. M.L. n. <i>tabacum</i> tobacco; L. adj. <i>nasalis</i> pertaining to the nose; M.L. gen. fem. adj. <i>tabacinasalis</i> of snuff)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, large cocci that occur mostly in pairs but also singly or in short-chains.</s><s>They are α-haemolytic on horse-blood.</s><s>Colonies are of irregular size, reaching a maximum diameter of 0.5 mm after 48 h on blood agar incubated at 30°C.</s><s>The colonies are round, smooth and domed (raised) with a sharp border, and are non-pigmented.</s><s>The organism is facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Using commercial API systems, acid is not produced from D-arabitol, L-arabinose, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, melibiose, mannitol, maltose, melezitose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose or trehalose.</s><s>α-Galactosidase and ester lipase C8 (weak reaction) activity is detected.</s><s>Activity is not detected for the following: alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, chymotrypsin, trypsin, cystine arylamidase, glycyltryptophan arylamidase, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, esterase C-4, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, leucine arylamidase and urease.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 40 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>The organism is isolated from powdered tobacco.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 30090<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>