<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8309_nm.13395" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13395" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13395" rank="species">Leucobacter tardus</organism><reference id="rid.8309"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leucobacter tardus sp. nov., isolated from the phyllosphere of Solanum tuberosum L.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2574</fpage><lpage>2578</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001065-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984695</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leucobacter tardus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leucobacter tardus</em> (tar′dus. L. masc. adj. <em>tardus</em> slow, pertaining to the slow reactions in several physiological tests).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are asporogenous, non-motile, short rods (0.4–0.6×0.8–1.6 μm), which occur singly or in pairs, sometimes forming small irregular clusters.</s><s>Gram-positive and strictly aerobic.</s><s>The lemon-yellow colonies found on nutrient agar are smooth with regular margins.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 21–30 °C; no growth at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Catalase activity is present, but urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase activities are absent.</s><s>Citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production from sodium thiosulfate, tryptophan deaminase, indole production from l-tryptophan and reduction of nitrate are negative.</s><s>Does not produce acetoin from sodium pyruvate.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Weak oxidase reaction.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not starch, casein or gelatin.</s><s>Oxidative acid production occurs on API 50CH and API 20E substrates for d-fructose, melezitose, raffinose and l-rhamnose, but not for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, amygdalin, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol or d- or l-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, adenosine, l-alaninamide, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-glucose 6-phosphate, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-lactic acid, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl pyruvate, putrescine, pyruvic acid, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinamic acid, succinic acid, thymidine, Tweens 40 and 80, uridine and d-xylose on Biolog GP2 MicroPlates.</s><s>Weak utilization is observed for d-fructose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-mannitol, palatinose, d-psicose and d-tagatose.</s><s>Acetic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, AMP, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, l-asparagine, d-cellobiose, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, d-fructose 6-phosphate, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, l-glutamic acid, glycogen, glycyl l-glutamic acid, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, inosine, inulin, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d- and l-malic acid, maltose, maltotriose, mannan, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, sucrose, TMP, trehalose, turanose, UMP and xylitol are not assimilated.</s><s>Cell-wall amino acids are DAB, alanine, glycine and glutamic acid.</s><s>The main menaquinones are MK-10, MK-11 and MK-9.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists predominantly of anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0,</sub> anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> are present in minor amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is K 70/01<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19811<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24388<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the phyllosphere of potato plants in Dahnsdorf (Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>