<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8516_nm.13266" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13266" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13266" rank="species">Cellulomonas chitinilytica</organism><reference id="rid.8516"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cellulomonas chitinilytica sp. nov., a chitinolytic bacterium isolated from cattle-farm compost.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1878</fpage><lpage>1884</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64768-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676473</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cellulomonas chitinilytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cellulomonas chitinilytica</em> (chi.ti.ni.ly′ti.ca. N.L. n. <em>chitinum</em> chitin; Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> able to loosen, able to dissolve; N.L. adj. <em>lytica</em> dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>chitinilytica</em> decomposing chitin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, convex, entire, smooth and yellowish within 3 days at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows between 4 and 30 °C, the optimum temperature being 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.0–8.5, with an optimum between pH 6.9 and 7.5.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth; 2 % (w/v) NaCl is tolerated.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar and TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite aerobically but not anaerobically.</s><s>Hydrolyses chitin, xylan, CM-cellulose (weakly) and starch, but not casein, collagen or DNA.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-galactose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-xylose, d-xylose, d-lyxose, maltose, trehalose, raffinose, d-lactose, melibiose, cellobiose, sucrose, gluconate, acetate, formate, phenyl acetate, malonate, pyruvate, dulcitol, methanol, glycerol, xylitol, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, d-adonitol, amygdalin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, l-cysteine and l-glutamate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: l-rhamnose, l-fucose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, ethanol, inositol, dextran, inulin, citrate, lactate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, fumarate, malate, succinate, itaconate, propionate, caprate, glutarate, adipate, suberate, benzoate, maleate, oxalate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, tartrate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartate, l-asparagine, l-glutamine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-valine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan and l-tyrosine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and the Voges–Proskauer reaction give weakly positive results, gelatin hydrolysis give a positive result and arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulphide and indole production produce negative results.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from l-arabinose, but acid is not produced from d-glucose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, amygdalin, sucrose or melibiose.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and unidentified phospholipids and phosphoglycolipids are the major polar lipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (61.3 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (15.9 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5.4 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 73.6 mol%.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains l-Orn–d-Glu (type A4<em>β</em>).</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose, ribose, xylose and rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, X.bu-b<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19133<sup>T</sup> =DSM 17922<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from compost at a cattle farm near Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>