<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2278_nm.9598" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9598" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9598" rank="species">Paenibacillus wynnii</organism><reference id="rid.2278"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodelas</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus wynnii sp. nov., a novel species harbouring the nifH gene, isolated from Alexander Island, Antarctica</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2093</fpage><lpage>2099</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63395-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus wynnii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus wynnii</em> (wynn′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>wynnii</em> of Wynn, in honour of the late Dr. David Wynn-Williams, the Antarctic microbiologist who developed Mars Oasis as a research site).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, motile, curved rods that occur singly or in pairs and have slightly tapered ends.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal or oval and lie paracentrally and subterminally in sporangia that may be swollen.</s><s>Occasionally, the swelling may be at the opposite pole of the sporangium to the spore (Fig. 1).</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·5–0·7 μm and cell lengths range from 3–5 μm.</s><s>After 3 days incubation on nutrient agar at 20 °C, the maximum colony diameter is 2 mm.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex and glossy with entire margins.</s><s>Smaller colonies are transparent and whitish, while larger colonies are pale yellow–orange with whitish margins and darker centres.</s><s>They bear a watery biomass, but may be mucoid.</s><s>Older colonies are firmly attached to the agar.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 20 °C.</s><s>Some strains grow at 37 °C, but none grow at 40 °C.</s><s>Growth in broth at 4 °C appears within 7 days.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 6·0 and 6·5, optimum pH is 7·0–8·0 and the maximum pH lies between 9·5 and 10·0.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Does not tolerate the presence of 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth on skimmed milk agar plates is scarce and casein is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed.</s><s>The species fixes nitrogen as demonstrated by the presence of the <em>nifH</em> gene in all strains and acetylene reduction in most of them.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis is variable and nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, Voges–Proskauer reaction and gelatin hydrolysis reactions are negative.</s><s>In the API 50CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium, hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates: amygdalin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, galactose, d-gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-raffinose, salicin, starch, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid production is variable for l-arabinose, arbutin, gluconate, glycerol, inulin, d-melezitose, methyl-xyloside, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol and xylitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from: adonitol, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, 2-keto- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl d-glucoside, methyl d-mannoside, l-sorbose, d-tagatose and l-xylose.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, each present at about 33 %.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller, decreasing amounts (between about 7 and 1 %) C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (detailed FAME data are given in Supplementary Tables S1 and S2 available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The DNA G+C composition of LMG 22176<sup>T</sup> is 44·6 mol%.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain is positive or weakly positive for: <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis and acid production from gluconate, glycerol, inulin, d-melezitose, rhamnose, sorbitol and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 22176<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108306<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from the Mars Oasis, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>