<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12729_nm.22499" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22499" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22499" rank="species">Marinobacter oulmenensis</organism><reference id="rid.12729"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kharroub</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aguilera</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiménez-Pranteda</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>González-Paredes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteoliva-Sánchez</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter oulmenensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from brine of a salt concentrator</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2210</fpage><lpage>2214</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027284-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20935087</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter oulmenensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter oulmenensis</em> (oul.me.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>oulmenensis</em> belonging to Ain Oulmene salt concentrator, where the species was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, motile rods, 0.3–0.5 µm wide and 1.6–3.0 µm long.</s><s>Colonies are cream, small, circular and smooth and 2–3 mm in diameter after growth on MH medium containing 7.5 % (w/v) NaCl for 3 days at 37 °C.</s><s>Moderately halophilic and capable of growth with 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 5–7.5 %, w/v, NaCl).</s><s>Grows at 30–45 °C (optimum 37–40 °C) and at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum pH 6.5–7.0).</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Aesculin, DNA, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar and hydrolyses tyrosine with production of pigment.</s><s>Positive for β-galactosidase, but negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and glucose fermentation.</s><s>Positive for Simmons’ citrate test, but does not reduce nitrate or nitrite and negative for respiration of nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-mannitol, dulcitol, glycerol, acetate, malate, malonate, succinate, oxalate, formate, fumarate, d-glucuronic acid and arginine.</s><s>Does not utilize d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, cellobiose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose, d-xylose, adonitol, glycerol, benzoate, phenylacetic acid, dl-lactate, l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-alanine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan, l-glycine, l-asparagine or l-glutamate.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-mannitol and dulcitol, but not from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, cellobiose, l-arabinose, raffinose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-xylose, glycerol or adonitol.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to (µg per disc unless otherwise stated) chloramphenicol (30), kanamycin (30), penicillin G (10 U), gentamicin (10) and erythromycin (15), but resistant to ampicillin (10), clindamycin (2 U) and novobiocin (30).</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-9; a small amount of Q-8 is present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, summed feature 7 (C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo ω10<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>19 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and unknown phospholipids and phosphoglycolipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Set74<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7499<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22359<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from brine of a salt concentrator at Ain Oulmene, Algeria.</s></p></content></protolog>