<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2599_nm.11566" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11566" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11566" rank="species">Methylobacterium platani</organism><reference id="rid.2599"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>H.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium platani sp. nov., isolated from a leaf of the tree Platanus orientalis</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2849</fpage><lpage>2853</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65262-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048737</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium platani</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium platani</em> (pla.ta′ni. L. gen. n. <em>platani</em> of <em>Platanus orientalis</em>, referring to the tree species from which the micro-organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods measuring 1.4–1.5×2.0–6.5 μm, occurring singly, in pairs or in rosettes.</s><s>Cells are motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells are slow-growing on nutrient agar and TYG agar and produce small, smooth, pink-pigmented colonies.</s><s>Methanol, formaldehyde and formate are utilized by strain PMB02<sup>T</sup> as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of ≥1 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Optimum temperature range for growth is 25–30 °C, but growth does occur at 20–30 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is between 6.0 and 7.0, but growth does occur between pH 6.0 and 8.0.</s><s>Oxidizes the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, d-fructose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline and l-threonine.</s><s>Does not utilize the following compounds as a carbon and energy source: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, l-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxyl l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are <em>cis</em>-vaccenic acid (C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 81.0 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (7.6 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.46 %), summed feature 3 (2.24 %) comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH or both, summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH/iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I, 1.98 %) and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (1.71 %).</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content (by HPLC) is 68.5 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PMB02<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12901<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14648<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a leaf from a tree (<em>Platanus orientalis</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>