<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9947_nm.14926" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14926" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14926" rank="species">Aidingimonas halophila</organism><reference id="rid.9947"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aidingimonas halophila gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3088</fpage><lpage>3094</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010264-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643876</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aidingimonas halophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aidingimonas halophila</em> (ha.lo′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>halophila</em> salt loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Colonies are colourless to yellow brown, flat and opaque with slightly irregular edges on modified ISP 2 medium.</s><s>Cells are straight rods (0.1–0.3×0.7–1.5 μm).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C, at pH 5.0–10.0 and in 1–25 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimal growth at 37 °C, pH 7.0–8.0 and 5–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Non-endospore-forming.</s><s>Does not contain poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules or produce exopolysaccharide.</s><s>Growth occurs under anoxic conditions in the presence of nitrate ion as electron acceptor.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is variable.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Milk peptonization and coagulation and the methyl red test are negative.</s><s>Gelatin, aesculin, casein, starch, and Tweens 40, 60 and 80 are not hydrolysed, but positive for hydrolysis of Tween 20 and urea.</s><s><em>o</em>-Nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, phenylalanine deaminase and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative, but positive for arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Citrate can be utilized.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, gentiobiose, d-fucose and potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50CHB).</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon or nitrogen and energy sources in the Biolog GN2 system: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-proline, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates in the Biolog GN2 system are negative: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, lactulose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, dl-carnitine, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (per disc): amoxicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), netilmicin (10 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), penicillin (10 U), sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to clindamycin (2 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), novobiocin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tobramycin (10 μg).</s><s>The fatty acids (&#x003E;1 %) are C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>10 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 90637<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12885<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB 207002<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang province, north-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>