<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6689_nm.8719" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8719" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8719" rank="species">Mycobacterium neworleansense</organism><reference id="rid.6689"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schinsky</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morey</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Douglas</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daneshvar</surname><given-names>M.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown-Elliott</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McNeil</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic variation in the Mycobacterium fortuitum third biovariant complex: description of Mycobacterium boenickei sp. nov., Mycobacterium houstonense sp. nov., Mycobacterium neworleansense sp. nov. and Mycobacterium brisbanense sp. nov. and recognition of Mycobacterium porcinum from human clinical isolates.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1653</fpage><lpage>1667</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium neworleansense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium neworleansense</em> (new.or.le.an.sen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>neworleansense</em> pertaining to New Orleans, LA, USA, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms are acid-fast, Gram-positive, pleomorphic bacilli.</s><s>Long filamentous forms are often observed, but spores and capsules are absent.</s><s>Colonies are white to slightly beige and small in diameter (approx. 1 mm) after incubation on heart infusion agar with 5 % (v/v) rabbit blood for 2 days at 35 °C.</s><s>Colonies are rough, wrinkled, irregular-edged and do not demonstrate aerial hyphae.</s><s>Growth occurs on Löwenstein–Jensen medium at 35 °C in less than 7 days, but no growth occurs at 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on 5 % NaCl and on MacConkey's agar without crystal violet at 28 °C.</s><s>Semi-quantitative catalase activity is positive (&#x003E;45 mm).</s><s>The isolate has arylsulfatase activity by 3 days, utilizes acetamide, reduces nitrate, exhibits iron uptake and produces urease and thermostable catalase.</s><s>It does not utilize citrate or grow in lysozyme.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-glucose, i-<em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, salicin, d-trehalose and d-xylose but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-galactose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, starch or sucrose.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, erythromycin and vancomycin, but susceptible to amikacin, amoxycillin/clavulanate, ciprofloxacin, doxycycline, imipenem, minocycline, sulfamethoxazole, trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole and vancomycin.</s><s>The type strain has a DNA G+C content of 60 mol%.</s><s>The nearest phylogenetic neighbours, according to 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity, are <em>Mycobacterium boenickei</em> ATCC 49935<sup>T</sup> and all <em>M. porcinum</em> isolates studied.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was recovered from a scalp wound, is W6705<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 49404<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44679<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>DNA relatedness among the strains in the species and their relatedness to other strains of the <em>M. fortuitum</em> third biovariant complex and related species are available in IJSEM Online.</s></p></content></protolog>