<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7347_nm.2905" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2905" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2905" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas tunicata</organism><reference id="rid.7347"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmström</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>James</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neilan</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>White</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kjelleberg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas tunicata sp. nov., a bacterium that produces antifouling agents.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1205</fpage><lpage>1212</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828422</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoalteromonas tunicata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas tunicata</i> (tu.ni.ca'ta L. fem. n. <i>tunicata</i> shirt-like classical piece of Roman underwear, tunic; L. fem. adj. <i>tunicata</i> clothed with a tunic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultative anaerobic Gram-negative rod shaped cells that are 2.0-3.4 μm in length.</s><s>Motile by means of a polar sheathed flagellum.</s><s>Growth on VNSS medium results in dark-green-pigmented colonies while growth on TSB medium results in white colonies.</s><s>Does not ferment sugar in the Hugh-Leifson test.</s><s>Sodium ions are required for growth with the optimal NaCl concentration of 1-2%.</s><s>Cannot grow at pH 5 or 11: optimal pH range for growth is pH 7-8.</s><s>Slow growth occurs at 4°C and no growth is detectable at 37°C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Utilizes trehalose. glucose, maltose and Tween 20 at a concentration of 4 g l<sup>-1</sup> but can not grow on galactose, fructose, xylose, sucrose, lactose, raffinose, melibiose, glycerol, mannitol, rhamnose, sorbitol, inositol, dulcitol, melexitose, xylitol, erythritol, glycine, threonine, arabinose, L-aspargine and L-histidine.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin.</s><s>Sensitive to erythromycin, rifampicin, gentamicin, tetracycline, ampicillin, neomycin, kanamycin and nalidixic acid at a concentration of 100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup> and is sensitive to the vibriostatic agent 0/129 at a concentration of 150 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 42.2 ± 0.7 mol%.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are 16:1ω7c, 16:0, 18:1ω7c and 16:1ω7t, respectively.</s><s>Strain D2<sup>T</sup> is negative for H<sub>2</sub>S and NO<sub>2</sub> production and no β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase activity has been detected.</s><s>Isolated from an adult tunicate, <i>Ciona intestinalis</i>, collected from water off the western coast of Sweden.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Culture Collection of University of Goteborg as strain CCUG 26757<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>