<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7100_nm.6360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6360" rank="species">Mycobacterium hiberniae</organism><reference id="rid.7100"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kazda</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cooney</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monaghan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quinn</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daffé</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Müller</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tarnok</surname><given-names>Z.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium hiberniae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>352</fpage><lpage>357</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-352</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7684243</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Taxonomic description of <i>Mycobacterium hiberniae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium hiberniae</i> (hi.ber'ni.ae. L. gen. n. <i>hiberniae</i>, of Hibernia, the Latin name for Ireland, the source of these strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>M. hiberniae</i> presented below is based on a study of 13 strains which shared the characteristics shown in Table 1.</s><s>Cells are acid-alcohol fast, polymorphic, beaded rods (0.9 by 1.2 to 1.5 pm) which very often form clumps but not cords.</s><s>Spores, capsules, true branching, and aerial hyphae do not occur.</s><s>Colonies on Löwenstein-Jensen and Middlebrook 7H10 agar are smooth and glistening with rose-pink pigmentation but become rough and dry later.</s><s>The colonies with the unique pigment production are 1 to 1.5 mm in diameter; optimum growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>They grow at 22 and 31°C but not at 42 or 45°C.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The strains are mycobacteria with limited enzymatic activity.</s><s>They possess acid phosphatase, nitrate reductase, and arylsulfatase.</s><s>For all strains, amidase activities and acid production from glucose and mannose are negative.</s><s>These organisms tolerate 0.1% NaNO<sub>2</sub> but not 0.2% picric acid.</s><s>The strains are resistant to antituberculous drugs, except to 5 μg of ethambutol (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains have a mycolate pattern similar to that of the <i>M. avium</i>-<i>M. intracellulare</i> complex, but they release by pyrolysis their mycolate C-22 and C-24 fatty esters, a unique characteristic for <i>M. hiberniae</i>.</s><s>The strains which were tested are not pathogenic for rabbits, guinea pigs, or mice.</s><s>They provoke a nonspecific skin hypersensitivity reaction to bovine tuberculin.</s><s>The type strain of <i>M. hiberniae</i> is Hi 11.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49874.</s><s>Strains of <i>M. hiberniae</i> have been isolated from true moss, sphagnum, and soil in Ireland.</s></p></content></protolog>