<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12897_nm.22716" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22716" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22716" rank="species">Catenovulum agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.12897"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Catenovulum agarivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a peritrichously flagellated, chain-forming, agar-hydrolysing gammaproteobacterium from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2866</fpage><lpage>2873</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027565-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257691</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Catenovulum agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Catenovulum agarivorans</em> (a.ga.ri.vo′rans. N.L. neut. n. <em>agarum</em> agar; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, destroying; N.L. part. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, the following are observed.</s><s>Forms colonies with smooth surfaces that are thin, circular in shape and pale yellow in colour when grown on MA for 3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Cells form long chains end-to-end that split into single cells after 24 h of cultivation.</s><s>Marked viability loss occurs within 5 days on MA at 28 °C accompanied by fading of the pale yellow colour of the colonies, indicating that cells need to be transferred every 3 days.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.8–1.5 µm long and 0.4–0.6 µm wide.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Buds and prosthecae are not observed when the isolate is grown at 16 °C for 5 days on PYG agar.</s><s>Abundant growth occurs on MA and marine agar R2A, but not on MB, LB agar or NA.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0.5–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl and can be stimulated by seawater salts and yeast extract.</s><s>pH range for growth is 7.5–10.0.</s><s>Grows from 10 to 42 °C; no growth is detected at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth conditions are 28 °C and pH 8.0–9.0 on MA.</s><s>Agar, cellulose, starch, aesculin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but egg yolk, gelatin, urea and casein are not.</s><s>Does not ferment carbohydrates.</s><s>Acid production from d-glucose and melibiose by oxidation is apparently positive; reactions with sucrose and amygdalin are delayed, and negative for d-mannitol and inositol.</s><s>Weakly positive for arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4) and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Positive for β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphoamidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase; negative for lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, lipase (C14), leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase (API ZYM and API 20NE).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilizes the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, acetic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid and capric acid.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, adipic acid, malic acid, citrate, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, α-, β- and γ-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate (Biolog).</s><s>Susceptible to norfloxacin (10 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), neomycin (30 µg), polymyxin B (300 U), ciprofloxacin (5 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), ampicillin (10 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), piperacillin (100 µg), amikacin (30 µg), rocephin (30 µg) and fortum (30 µg) and intermediately susceptible to cefazolin V (30 µg).</s><s>Resistant to furaxone (300 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), carbenicillin (100 µg), oxacillin (1 µg), doxycyclin (30 µg), minocin (30 µg) and penicillin (10 U).</s><s>Distinctive traits are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM01<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.10245<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23111<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16580<sup>T</sup>), isolated from seawater of the Yellow Sea in China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>