<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7171_nm.4180" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4180" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4180" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus ivorii</organism><reference id="rid.7171"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murdoch</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magee</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of three new species of the genus Peptostreptococcus from human clinical specimens: Peptostreptococcus harei sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus ivorii sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus octavius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>781</fpage><lpage>787</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-781</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus ivorii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus ivorii</i> (i.vo'ri.i. M. L. gen. n. <i>ivorii</i>, of Ivor, a British microbiologist who first isolated the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, gram-positive cocci which vary in size (diameter, 0.4 to 1.5 μm) and occur in clumps.</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are tiny after incubation for 48 h but by 5 days are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, yellow-white, low convex, entire, circular, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>Indole, urease, ALP, coagulase, and ADH are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Catalase production is variable.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, fructose, raffinose, trehalose, sorbitol, cellobiose, arabinose, ribose, mannose, or mannitol.</s><s>When the ATB 32A preformed enzyme system (API-BioMerieux) is used, saccharolytic enzymes are not detected, and proline AMD is the only proteolytic enzyme formed.</s><s>The major VFAs produced in Robertson's cooked meat broth are butyric and isovaleric acids, and smaller, variable quantities of acetic, propionic, isobutyric, and n-valeric acids are also produced. <i>P. ivorii</i> has been isolated from a leg ulcer, a preputial sac, and an intrauterine contraceptive device (20).</s><s>The type strain, DSM 10022, was isolated from a leg ulcer; it was cocultured with <i>P. magnus</i>, <i>Klebsiella oxytoca</i>, and <i>Bacteroides ureolyticus</i>.</s><s>Strain DSM 10022<sup>T</sup> does not form catalase.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain DSM 10022<sup>T</sup> is 29 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>