<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7154_nm.1860" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1860" rank="genus">Thiomonas</organism><reference id="rid.7154"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moreira</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amils</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny of Thiobacillus cuprinus and other mixotrophic thiobacilli: proposal for Thiomonas gen. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>522</fpage><lpage>528</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-522</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103643</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiomonas</i> (Thi.o.mo'nas. Gr. n. <i>thios</i>, sulfur; Gr. fem. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; M.L. fem. n. <i>Thiomonas</i>, sulfur monad)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic description of the genus <i>Thiomonas</i> is the same as the description of general traits published previously in Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology (19) for the species belonging to group II of the genus <i>Thiobacillus</i>.</s><s>The cells of <i>Thiomonas</i> species are gram-negative, non-spore-forming, short rods that are about 0.3 to 0.5 μm wide and 1 to 3 μm long.</s><s>Each cell is motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Obligate aerobes.</s><s>The optimum temperature is between 30 and 36°C for the mesophilic species and 50°C for the moderately thermophilic species.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 3 and 6.</s><s>Not able to denitrify.</s><s>Facultative chemolithoautotrophs.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs in mixotrophic media supplemented with reduced sulfur compounds and organic supplements, such as yeast extract, peptone, some sugars, and some amino acids.</s><s>Organotrophic growth occurs on yeast extract, peptone, Casamino Acids, and meat extract.</s><s>Lithoautotrophic growth occurs on thiosulfate, tetrathionate, H<sub>2</sub>S, and elemental sulfur.</s><s>No oxidation of ferrous iron occurs.</s><s>Sulfuric acid is formed during lithotrophic growth.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin.</s><s>Contains ubiquinone 8.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is between 61 and 69 mol%.</s><s>These characteristics of the members of the genus <i>Thiomonas</i> are summarized and compared with the characteristics of some representative species of the genus <i>Thiobacillus</i> in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Thiomonas</i> intermedia; the type strain of this species is strain ATCC 15466.</s><s>In addition to this type species, the genus comprises <i>Thiomonas cuprina</i> (13), <i>Thiomonas perometabolis</i> (24), and <i>Thiomonas thermosulfata</i> (34).</s></p></content></protolog>