<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.449_nm.3320" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3320" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3320" rank="species">Serratia grimesii</organism><reference id="rid.449"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Irino</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Biochemical characterization of Serratia liquefaciens sensu stricto, Serratia proteamaculans and Serratia grimesii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>69</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01568416</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serratia grimesii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serratia grimesii</i> (<i>grimesii</i> is a Modern Latin, genitive, masculine form of Grimes, in honor of Michael Grimes, Irish bacteriologist, who first described this group)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain ATCC 14460 and 10 other strains (group Cld) that correspond to the description given by Grimes [9] form a discrete biochemical and genomic group.</s><s>This group is distinct from all other <i>Serratia</i> species and from other genera in the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> by DNA-relatedness criteria. <i>Serratia grimesii</i> with strain ATCC 14460 as the type strain. <i>S. grimesii</i> has been isolated from the natural environment and from human clinical specimens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group Adc might be a subspecies of <i>S. grimesii</i>.</s><s>However, only three strains of this rare group were studied.</s><s>No taxonomic proposal will be made until more strains are available for study.</s><s>Carbon-source utilization tests are useful in the identification of newly described <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>These tests might be difficult to carry out in clinical laboratories unless carbon-source utilization tests are included in commercial identification kits.</s><s>For those laboratories which cannot differentiate <i>S. liquefaciens sensu stricto</i>, <i>S. proteamaculans</i>, and <i>S. grimesii</i>, we suggest the use of the vernacular name "<i>S. liquefaciens</i>-like".</s></p></content></protolog>