<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5534_nm.5936" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5936" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5936" rank="species">Brevibacterium iodinum</organism><reference id="rid.5534"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Keddie</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Chromobacterium iodinum (Davis) in a redefined genus Brevibacterium, Breed as Brevibacterium iodinum nom. rev., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>120</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Brevibacterium iodinum nom.rev., comb.nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>This description is based on studies of strains NCDO 613, NCIB 8179, ATCC 15728, and ATCC I5729 (Clemo &#x0026; Daglish, 1950; Gilman, 1953; Sneath, 1956,1960; Steele, 1961 ; Colwelf et a!., 1969: Fiedler et a!., 1970; Jones, 1975; the present work).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on nutrient agar are 0.75 to 1 mm diam. after 1 to 2 d, becoming larger (2 to 5 mm) on extended incubation; convex with entire margin, shiny.</s><s>Blue to purple extracellular crystals of iodinin visible within 2 d in areas of heavy growth.</s><s>Iodinin production not influenced by light but better production on certain media (Colwell et al., 1969).</s><s>Cotour reactions typical of <i>B. linens</i> growth absent (Jones, 1975).</s><s>Cultures on suitable media show the rod/coccus growth cycle and staining reactions described for the genus (Fig. 3).</s><s>Gram-positive, but may appear Gram-negative (Jones, 1975).</s><s>In very young cultures (about 8 h) cells frequently stain one-half Gram-positive, the other Gram-negative (Colwell et al., 1969).</s><s>Optimum growth temperature 25 °C; growth at 30 °C, but poor or absent at 5 and 37 °C.</s><s>Aerobic: mode of metabolism respiratory.</s><s>Acids not formed from glucose and other sugars in peptone media.</s><s>Catalase positive, strongly oxidase positive.</s><s>Gelatin hydrolysed, extracellular DNAase produced, weak hydrolysis of casein, hippurate not hydrolysed (Jones, 1975).</s><s>The cell wail peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid (Fiedler et al., 1970).</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal isoprenoid quinones are dihydrogenated menaquinones with eight isoprene units.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is mainly <i>anteiso</i>- and <i>iso</i>-methyl-branched acids with small amounts of straight-chain acids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 14-methylhexadecanoic (<i>anteiso</i> C<sub>17</sub>) and 12-methyltetradecanoic (<i>anteiso</i> C<sub>15</sub>).</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and dimannosyl diacylglycerol comprise the polar lipids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA, determined by estimation of the melting point is, 63 mol % (Colwell ef al., 1969).</s><s>The type strain is NCDO 613.</s></p></content></protolog>