<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12915_nm.22740" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22740" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22740" rank="species">Bacillus hemicentroti</organism><reference id="rid.12915"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus hemicentroti sp. nov., a moderate halophile isolated from a sea urchin</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2950</fpage><lpage>2955</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026732-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21278416</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus hemicentroti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus hemicentroti</em> [he.mi.cen.tro′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>hemicentroti</em> of <em>Hemicentrotus</em> (<em>Hemicentrotus pulcherrimus</em>, a sea urchin), the source of isolation of the organism].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-motile, facultatively anaerobic, straight rods, approximately 0.6–0.9 µm wide and 2.5–3.5 µm long, occurring singly, as pairs or as short chains and producing ellipsoidal endospores that lie in subterminal unswollen or slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, flat and opaque, have smooth surfaces and circular margins and are 3–4 mm in diameter on MA supplemented with 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Moderately halophilic and facultatively alkaliphilic; growth occurs with 0.5–25 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 5–8 %), at pH 6.0–10.5 (optimum pH 8.0) and at 5–40 °C (optimum 30–35 °C).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrite is not reduced further.</s><s>Positive for glucose fermentation, methyl red test and urease, but negative for phenylalanine deaminase, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production and the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but cellulose, DNA, hypoxanthine, Tween 80 and xanthine are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycogen, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, sucrose, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol, but not from cellobiose, d-galactose, lactose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, trehalose, d-xylose, amygdalin, d-salicin, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol or <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>As sole sources of carbon or carbon and nitrogen, utilizes l-arabinose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, melibiose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-mannitol, gluconate, l-alanine and l-asparagine, but not cellobiose, d-galactose, glycogen, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, d-xylose, amygdalin, d-salicin, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, acetate, butyrate, citrate, propionate, succinate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine or l-valine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes are acid and alkaline phosphatases, α-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but not cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone and diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and one unidentified phospholipid as the polar lipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 076093<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23007<sup>T</sup> = KCTC 13710<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a homogenate of a sea urchin (<em>Hemicentrotus pulcherrimus</em>) collected from Naozhou Island in the South China Sea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.8 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>