<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2587_nm.11442" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11442" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11442" rank="species">Reinekea blandensis</organism><reference id="rid.2587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pinhassi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lekunberri</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>González</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pedrós-Alió</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reinekea blandensis sp. nov., a marine, genome-sequenced gammaproteobacterium</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2370</fpage><lpage>2375</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65091-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Reinekea blandensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Reinekea blandensis</em> (blan.den′sis. L. fem. adj. <em>blandensis</em> pertaining to Blande or Blanda, the name the Romans used for the city of Blanes, which has given its name to the Bay of Blanes, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, chemo-organotrophic bacterium.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Cells are straight or slightly bent motile rods, 0.3–0.7 μm in diameter and 1.2–2.8 μm long.</s><s>Gas vesicles are not observed.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are produced.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>At least 0.3 % (w/v) marine salts is required; up to 12 % (w/v) salts is tolerated.</s><s>Positive for growth at 15–42 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Casein, starch, Tween 80 and DNA are hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin (no growth in medium), alginate, agar or lecithin.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and indole production from tryptophan.</s><s>Utilizes the following compounds as carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, maltose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-gluconate, propionate, pyruvate, acetate, citrate, 2-ketoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, lactate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-leucine, l-tyrosine and l-arginine.</s><s>Weakly positive results are obtained on d-galactose, melibiose, salicin, butyrate, malate, l-glutamate and l-ornithine.</s><s>Growth is negative on d-ribose, d-xylose, trehalose, l-rhamnose, amygdalin, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, d-saccharate, d-glycerate, glycine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-alanine, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-citrulline, l-histidine, l-aspartate, l-lysine, l-sarcosine, betaine and putrescine.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are, in decreasing order of abundance, 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/15 : 0 iso 2-OH, 16 : 0 iso, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 16 : 0.</s><s>The whole pattern and relative abundances are given in Table 2.</s><s>Polar lipids consist of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, three unidentified phospholipids, an unknown aminolipid and a lipid.</s><s>Main respiratory quinone is Q-8 (92 %); Q-9 is present in minor amounts.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MED297<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7120<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 52066<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water from the Mediterranean Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>