<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.55_nm.8122" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8122" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8122" rank="species">Flavobacterium yabuuchiae</organism><reference id="rid.55"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A taxonomic study of Flavobacterium spiritivorum and Sphingobacterium mizutae: proposal of Flavobacterium yabuuchiae sp. nov. and Flavobacterium mitzutaii comb. nov.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>348</fpage><lpage>353</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium yabuuchiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium yabuuchiae</i> (ya.bu.u'chi.ae N.L. gen. n. <i>yabuuchiae</i>, in honor of Eiko Yabuuchi)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of <i>Flavobacterium yabuuchiae</i> are given below.</s><s>The cells of the strains are strictly aerobic, gramnegative, uniformly staining rods, 1.0 μm long, with parallel sides and rounded ends.</s><s>After 48 h, colonies on nutrient agar, are circular, low convex, smooth, and opaque.</s><s>Strain F8116 colonies are 1 to 3 mm in diameter; pinpoint colonies occur.</s><s>A pale yellow pigment is produced that neither diffuses in nutrient agar nor fluoresces on King medium B when exposed to ultraviolet light.</s><s>Neither strain produces a dark-brown pigment on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Growth is optimal at 30°C.</s><s>In this study all biochemical tests, unless specified otherwise below, were carried out at 30°C.</s><s>The strains grow at room temperature (18 to 22°C) and at 37°C (and are nonmotile in hanging drop preparations at both temperatures), but do not grow at 5 or 42°C.</s><s>Hemolysis is absent after aerobic growth for 1 day on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In all, 118 characteristics are common for the two strains (either all positive or all negative).</s><s>We found 11 characteristics in which the two strains differ (Table 4).</s><s>The two strains have the following characteristics in common: production of catalase and cytochrome oxidase; oxidative reaction in glucose oxidation-fermentation medium; hydrolysis of tributyrin, Tween 20, Tween 80, and gelatin as determined by the plate method (but no liquefaction of a nutrient gelatin stab); no hydrolysis of tyrosine; no production of opalescence on lecithovitellin agar; no reduction of nitrate or of nitrite; no production of indole; no production of hydrogen sulfide (as determined by the lead acetate paper and triple sugar iron agar methods); growth on β-hydroxybutyrate (without production of lipid inclusion granules) and on MacConkey agar without crystal violet, but not on cetrimide agar; hydrolysis of esculin but not starch; no alkali production on Christensen citrate; no utilization of citrate (Simmons medium) or of malonate; no oxidation of gluconate; no digestion of casein; no production of arginine desimidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, or ornithine decarboxylase; no production of 3-ketolactose; no reduction of selenite and no deamination of phenylalanine; production of deoxyribonuclease , urease, β-D-galactosidase (<i>o</i>-nitrophenyl- β-D-galactopyranoside test), and phosphatase; no tolerance for KCN; production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from D-glucose, D-cellobiose, ethanol, D-(-)-fructose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-(+)- xylose; no production of acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from adonitol, L-(+)-arabinose, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, L-(+)-rhamnose, or sorbitol; production of acid from 10% (wt/vol) glucose and lactose; and no production of acid or gas from glucose in peptone-water medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are hydrolyzed (tests done with API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 8.5; 2- naphthyl caprylate ; and 4-methylumbelliferylcellobiopyranoside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are not hydrolyzed (tests done with API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl butyrate; 2-naphthyl myristate; L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide; L-valyl-2-naphthylamide; L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide; N-glutaryl-phenylalanine- 2-naphthylamide; 2-naphthyl phosphate at pH 5.4; 6-bromo-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside; 2- naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside; naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronic acid; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside; 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D- mannopyranoside; 2-naphthyl-α-D-fucopyranoside6;- bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-xylopyranoside; bis-(<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl)phosphate; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-xylopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D- fucopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-L-fucopyranoside; <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide; <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-lactopyranoside; <i>p</i>-nitrocathecol sulfate; L-tyrosyl-β-naphthylamide; L-pyrrolidonyl-β-naphthylamide; L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide; L-hydroxyprolyl-β-naphthylamideg; lycyl-β-naphthylamide; L-arginyl-β-naphthylamide; γ-L-glutamyl-β-naphthylamide; N-benzyok-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide; S -benzyl-L-cysteine-β-naphthylamide; DL-methionyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide hydrobromide; glycyl-L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide; glycyl-L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide; L-leucyl-glycyl-β-naphthylamide; L- seryl-L-tyrosyl- β-naphthylamide; L-glutamine-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; L-isoleucyl-β-naphthylamide; L-ornithyl-β-naphthylamide ; L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride; L-seryl-β-naphthylamide; L-threonyl-β-naphthylamide; L-tryptophane-β-naphthylamide; and N-carbobenzoxy-glycylglycyl-L-arginine-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of cultures 14 and 19 were 41.4 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain F8081 (=D7529=NCTC 12113) (culture 14).</s><s>Characteristics for the practical identification of the new species are shown in Table 3.</s><s>Culture 19 has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures as strain NCTC 12114</s></p></content></protolog>