<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7273_nm.2372" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2372" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2372" rank="species">Legionella oakridgensis</organism><reference id="rid.7273"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Orrison</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cherry</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tyndall</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fliermans</surname><given-names>C.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gough</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McDougal</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibb</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella oakridgensis: unusual new species isolated from cooling tower water.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>536</fpage><lpage>545</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6830217</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella oakridgensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella oakridgensis</i> (oak.ridg.en'sis sp. nov., M.L. fem. adj. <i>oakridgensis</i> coming from Oak Ridge, Tenn., the city where the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology and staining characteristics.</s><s>All cultures of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> were gram-negative rods consistent in size with members of the genus, i.e., 0.3 to 0.9 μm wide by 2 to 20 μm in length (7).</s><s>They took the safranin counterstain readily (20 s).</s><s>Their cells appeared thicker than those of most legionellae in DFA-stained smears, apparently because of a large amount of extracellular envelope material.</s><s>When they were stained with Sudan black B, very few cells contained stained storage material.</s><s>All cultures were nonmotile by microscopic examination, and flagella were not observed.</s><s>All cultures were nonsporeforming, non-encapsulated, and non-acid fast (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural tests.</s><s>All strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> grew slowly on CYE agar when first isolated and were stimulated by incubation in candle jars.</s><s>They failed to grow on Trypticase soy agar with and without the addition of blood.</s><s>Cultures on CYE agar did not give blue autofluorescence.</s><s>Colonies appeared on CYE agar plates after 3 to 5 days of incubation and were typical of the legionellae (34).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The basic CYE agar medium was tested for its ability to support the growth of legionellae under four conditions: (i) when added L-cysteine-HCl was omitted, (ii) when Fe<sup>3</sup> was omitted, (iii) when both were omitted, and (iv) when L-cysteine, Fe<sub>3</sub>, and Norite SG all were omitted.</s><s>Only <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and <i>L. jordanis</i> among the species and serogroups of legionellae, including five environmental isolates of <i>L. pneumophila</i>, grew on CYE without L-cysteine. <i>L. oakridgensis</i> adapted to the deficient medium on the first transfer from complete CYE medium and appeared to grow as well as it did on the complete CYE agar. <i>L. jordanis</i> (strains ABB-9 and BL-540) grew slowly at first and never as vigorously as did <i>L. oakridgensis</i> (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Three of the <i>L. oakridgensis</i> strains (OR-10, -23, and -24) were transferred serially 10 times on CYE agar slants without added L-cysteine; the other seven OR strains were transferred serially 5 times.</s><s>All strains gave excellent growth (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The eight strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> that were tested were transferred serially five times on CYE agar slants without added Fe3.</s><s>The omission of Fe3 did not appear to diminish growth (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All seven species, including the six serogroups of <i>L. pneumophila</i> and the two serogroups of <i>L. longbeachae</i>, also grew well through two serial transfers on CYE agar slants from which Fe<sub>3</sub> was omitted (Table 2).</s><s>They were not examined further.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Eight of the OR strains were transferred serially five times on CYE agar slants from which both L-cysteine and Fe<sub>3</sub> were omitted.</s><s>Growth appeared to be equal to that on the complete CYE agar medium (Table 2).</s><s>When Norite SG, L-cysteine, and Fe<sub>3</sub> were omitted from CYE agar medium, <i>L. oakridgensis</i> cultures either did not grow at all or grew poorly in streaks where the inoculum was very heavy (Table 2).</s><s>A total of 5% sheep blood could not replace the Norite SG in the L-cysteine- and Fe<sub>3</sub>-deficient media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Eight OR strains, strains of three different serogroups of <i>L. pneumophila</i>, and a strain of <i>L. jordani</i> grew poorly in yeast extract broth incubated stagnantly.</s><s>Cultures of all of these strains gave good to heavy growth when shaken during 48 h of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> grew slowly on CYE agar at 25°C, and in 4 to 5 days the growth equaled that obtained at 35°C in 2 days.</s><s>They failed to grow at 42.5 to 43°C within 7 days or after removal to 35°C for an additional 3 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DFA tests of isolates with conjugates for recognized serogroups and species of legionellae.</s><s>No fluorescence was observed when cultures of the 10 strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> were tested with the working dilutions of polyvalent and monovalent conjugates for the seven species and eight serogroups of legionellae listed in Materials and Methods.</s><s>The OR-10 conjugate was tested against OR-10 and seven other OR isolates.</s><s>The homologous 4+ staining titer was 1:64: heterologous 4+ titers were either 1:32 or 1:64.</s><s>The isolates were identical or very similar by these tests.</s><s>Smears of the cultures of the seven species (including eight serogroups) of legionellae were stained with the working dilution (1:32) and with a fourfold-higher concentration (1:8 dilution) of the OR-10 conjugate.</s><s>All tests were negative.</s><s>Thus, by these reciprocal DFA tests <i>L. oakridgensis</i> is unrelated to any other described legionellae.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological tests.</s><s>In Table 1, we list the important phenotypic characteristics of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and compare them with those of <i>L. jordanis</i> and <i>L. pneumophila</i>.</s><s>All 10 strains of<i>L. oakridgensis</i> gave identical reactions in all tests.</s><s>The major difference between <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and the other described species of <i>Legionella</i> was its lack of a requirement for added L-cysteine for serial transfer on laboratory media.</s><s>Lack of a requirement for added Fe<sub>3</sub> was shared by all other legionellae species and serogroups under the same conditions.</s><s>The OR strains also differed from all other legionellae in alkaline phosphatase activity by being the only described species in which this enzyme was not active at pH 8.5.</s><s>At pH 10.5 the alkaline phosphatase of <i>L. jordanis</i> was very weak; at pH 8.5 it was strong. <i>L. micdadei</i> strains (TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA) have alkaline phosphatase activity at pH 8.5 but not at pH 10.5.</s><s>Like all other species and serogroups of legionellae except <i>L. pneumophila</i>, <i>L. oakridgensis</i> failed to hydrolyze sodium hippurate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the 19 API ZYM tests, the <i>L. oakridgensis</i> strains resembled other legionellae in having strong acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase activity, moderately strong leucine aminopeptidase activity, weak valine aminopeptidase and C4 and C8 esterase activity, and lack of both proteolytic (trypsin and chymotrypsin) and carbohydrate-degrading enzyme activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>GLC studies of cellular fatty acids.</s><s>A representative chromatogram of the cellular fatty acids of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> is shown in Fig. 1.</s><s>The major fatty acid was identified as a saturated branched-chain C<sub>16</sub> fatty acid with the methyl branch in the iso position of the carbon chain (i-16:0).</s><s>The other acids present in large to moderate amounts were a monounsaturated C<sub>16</sub> acid (16:1), saturated C<sub>16</sub> (16:0) and C<sub>18</sub> (18:0) acids, and a C<sub>17</sub> cyclopropane acid (17CYC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The average percentages of the cellular fatty acids of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> and seven other species of Legionella are shown in Table 3.</s><s>The values for <i>L. oakridgensis</i> are averages calculated after each of six strains (OR-10, OR-12, OR-15, OR- 16, OR-18, OR-19) was grown four different times and analyzed for cellular fatty acids.</s><s>Small amounts (1% or less) of hydroxy acids were found in some of the OR strains, but they were not included because their identities have not been confirmed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The data in Table 3 show that <i>L. oakridgensis</i> can be readily distinguished from <i>L. micdadei</i>, <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, and <i>L. jordanis</i> by the low concentrations of the anteiso-C<sub>15</sub> and -C<sub>17</sub> branched-chain acids (a-15:0 and a-17:0).</s><s>These two acids accounted for only 2 and 5%, respectively, of the total fatty acids in <i>L. oakridgensis</i>, whereas in the other four species they were the two most abundant acids and together accounted for 48 to 64% of the total fatty acids. <i>L. pneumophila</i>, <i>L. longbeachae</i>, and <i>L. gormanii</i> contained a combined total of 20 to 38% of these two fatty acids.</s><s>All of the strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> contained lower concentrations (2 to 3%) of a-15:0 acid and higher concentrations (9%) of a 17CYC acid than have been reported in other species (Table 3).</s><s>The fatty acid composition of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> was qualitatively similar to <i>L. pneumophila</i> and <i>L. longbeachae</i>, as shown by the presence of large to moderate amounts of i-16:0, 16:1, and 16:0 acids.</s><s>It could be differentiated from these two as well as the other five species, however, by the presence of moderately large amounts (13%) of the 18:0 acid that never exceeded 3% in any of the other seven <i>Legionella</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty acid composition of the OR-23 and OR-24 isolates was essentially the same as that shown in Table 3 for the other six strains of <i>L. oakridgensis</i>.</s><s>When isolates OR-6 and OR-30 were tested, however, quantitative differences appeared in the concentrations of the i-16:1 and 16:1 acids that seemed to be related to the age of the culture.</s><s>In cultures incubated for 60 h or less, the major fatty acid was 16:1, and its relative concentration was 26%; in cultures incubated for a longer period of time (at least 72 h), i-16:0 was the major fatty acid, with a relative concentration of 21%.</s><s>Regardless of the age of the OR-6 and OR-30 strains, the relative percentages of all other fatty acids found were essentially the same as those reported for <i>L. oakridgensis</i> (Table 3).</s><s>Although a variation in the relative amounts of i-16:0 and 16:1 acids has also been reported in isolates of <i>L. longbeachae</i>, these changes were not consistent and did not appear to be related to the age of the culture (29).</s><s>Experiments to define these variations in the ratios of the C16 acids are currently under study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antimicrobial susceptibility.</s><s>The in vitro antimicrobial susceptibility data for OR strains varied little from the patterns of susceptibility of some of the other legionellae (31).</s><s>The OR strains were more susceptible to trimethoprim, being similar to <i>L. bozemanii</i>, <i>L. dumoffii</i>, <i>L. gormanii</i>, and <i>L. longbeachae</i>.</s><s>The OR strains and <i>L. jordanis</i> were the least susceptible to erythromycin, with minimal inhibitory concentrations of 4 μg/ml, compared with <i>L. pneumophila</i>, the most erythromycin-susceptible species with geometric mean minimum inhibitory concentrations of 0.75 μg/ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA studies.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content was determined in triplicate on DNAs from five <i>L. oakridgensis</i> strains.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content range was 42.3 to 43.9%, with an average value of 43.2%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA from the OR-10 strain of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> was labeled with <sup>32</sup>p in vitro and tested for relatedness to DNAs from five other Oak Ridge isolates and to strains of all named Legionella species (Table 4).</s><s>The OR isolates were 90 to 100% related to the OR-10 strain in tests done at both optimal and stringent incubation temperatures.</s><s>Divergence within related DNA sequences was 0.5% or less.</s><s>In contrast, DNA from OR-10 was only 5 to 8% related to DNAs from the seven other <i>Legionella</i> species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Animal pathogenicity.</s><s>Two guinea pigs each received intraperitoneal injections of the following numbers of cells of the OR-23 strain: 1.2 x 10<sup>4</sup>, 1.2 x 10<sup>5</sup>, 1.2 x 10<sup>6</sup>, and 1.2 x 10<sup>7</sup>.</s><s>All animals showed symptoms typical of <i>Legionella</i> infection; i.e., within 1 to 2 days, they had temperatures above 40°C, ruffled hair, lethargy, and lacrimation.</s><s>Tissues from one animal of each pair were examined by DFA staining tests and cultured. <i>L. oakridgensis</i> cells were present in large numbers in the peritoneal exudate of all four animals by DFA tests, and <i>L. oakridgensis</i> was cultured from all animals.</s><s>Two of the remaining four guinea pigs died of the infections, and the other two were killed while moribund.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Inhibition of growth of legionellae on CYE lacking L-cysteine or Fe<sup>3</sup> when inoculated directly from animal tissue.</s><s>In Table 5 the growth of legionellae from spleen homogenates of guinea pigs and from a human lung homogenate when inoculated on complete CYE agar is compared with that obtained on deficient CYE agar. <i>L. oakridgensis</i> strains required added L-cysteine for isolation from tissue, although it was not needed for growth when the culture was transferred from the complete CYE isolation medium to deficient CYE medium.</s><s>Unless the inoculum was very heavy, the OR-23 isolate also required added Fe3 for normal good growth from tissue (Table 5). <i>L. micdadei</i>, <i>L. dumoffli</i>, and <i>L. pneumophila</i> required the addition of both Fe<sup>3</sup> and L-cysteine to the CYE agar for growth from tissue, and they required added L-cysteine, but not added Fe<sup>3</sup>, for normal growth in further transfers on CYE agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Legionella oakridgensis</i> is proposed for the species represented by the 10 strains isolated from industrial cooling tower water.</s><s>The type strain of <i>L. oakridgensis</i> is OR-10 (ATCC 33761).</s></p></content></protolog>