<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12547_nm.21408" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21408" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21408" rank="species">Paracoccus isoporae</organism><reference id="rid.12547"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus isoporae sp. nov., isolated from the reef-building coral Isopora palifera</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1138</fpage><lpage>1143</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023333-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543151</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus isoporae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus isoporae</em> (i.so.por′ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>isoporae</em> of <em>Isopora</em>, a genus of coral, from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, aerobic, rod shaped (0.5–0.7×0.7–1.5 µm) and motile by means of monopolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies are a creamy white colour, circular and convex with entire edges and are ~0.6–0.8 mm in diameter on MA after 48 h of incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–40 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), pH 7–10 (optimum pH 9–10) and in 0–12 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 3–5 %).</s><s>Negative for poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granule accumulation.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase and DNase activities and hydrolysis of aesculin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for lipase activity (hydrolysis of corn oil) and hydrolysis of casein, starch, alginate and chitin.</s><s>In API 20 NE tests: positive for aesculin hydrolysis and β-galactosidase activity; negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, gelatin hydrolysis, d-glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase and urease activities.</s><s>In API ZYM tests: positive for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities; negative for cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucouronidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN2 microplate: dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, α-, β and γ-hydroxybutyric acid, 2,3-butanediol and glycerol.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 microplate are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to rifampicin, nalidixic acid, kanamycin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, novobiocin, streptomycin, tetracycline, ampicillin, penicillin G and sulphamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid is summed feature 8 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>).</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The polar lipids are DPG, PG, PC, an unidentified aminolipid (AL1), two unidentified glycolipids (GL1 and GL2) and four unidentified phospholipids (PL1–4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SW-3<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 25205<sup>T</sup>  = BCRC 17967<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a reef-building coral, <em>Isopora palifera</em>, collected off the coast of Southern Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>