<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6710_nm.3791" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3791" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3791" rank="species">Campylobacter concisus</organism><reference id="rid.6710"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Badger</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Listgarten</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Visconti</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Socransky</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wolinella gen. nov., Wolinella succinogenes (Vibrio succinogenes Wolin et al.) comb. nov., and description of Bacteroides gracilis sp. nov., Wolinella recta sp. nov., Campylobacter concisus sp. nov., and Eikenella corrodens from humans with periodontal disease.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>432</fpage><lpage>445</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-432</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter concisus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter concisus</i> (con cis'us. L. part. adj. <i>concisus</i> brief, concise)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Predominantly small, curved, unbranched cells, occasionally straight or helical, 0.5 to 1 by 4 μm, having rounded ends.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Rapid, darting motility in young broth cultures is by means of a single, polar flagellum.</s><s>Endospores are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Inner and outer cell membranes follow a twisted, undulating course.</s><s>There is no distinct cell wall peptidoglycan layer.</s><s>Caplike cytoplasmic condensations occur at the flagellated pole.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are convex, translucent, 1 mm in diameter, and entire.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Microaerophilic to anaerobic; grows anaerobically and in the presence of 5% oxygen but not in air containing 10% carbon dioxide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbohydrates are not fermented and do not support growth.</s><s>Growth is stimulated in broth cultures by formate and fumarate.</s><s>Hydrogen and formate are used as energy sources.</s><s>Formate is oxidized to produce hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Fumarate is reduced to succinate.</s><s>Nitrates, nitrites, neutral red, and benzyl viologen are reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is produced but catalase is not.</s><s>The benzidine test is positive.</s><s>Lysine, ornithine, and arginine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Starch, dextran, esculin, casein, DNA, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide, urease, lecithinase, lipase, indole, ammonia, and acetylmethylcarbinol are not produced.</s><s>Gas is not formed under an agar layer that is over a broth culture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 34 to 38 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in gingival crevices of humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is FDC 484 (= ATCC 33237).</s></p></content></protolog>