<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9924_nm.14892" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14892" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14892" rank="species">Herbidospora osyris</organism><reference id="rid.9924"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Herbidospora osyris sp. nov., isolated from surface-sterilized tissue of Osyris wightiana Wall. ex Wight</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3123</fpage><lpage>3127</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010579-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643877</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Herbidospora osyris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Herbidospora osyris</em> (o.sy′ris. N.L. gen. n. of <em>Osyris</em>, the plant genus from which this species was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms yellow–white to yellowish brown substrate mycelia on the media tested.</s><s>When sporulation occurs, the surface of the colony is white.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced on nutrient, Czapek's, ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 4, ISP 5, PDA or YIM 38 agars.</s><s>Short chains of spores (10–25 spores per chain) are borne at the tips of sporophores, which are derived from the vegetative mycelia in clusters.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C and pH 6.0–8.0.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated at up to 3 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Negative for the Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests, for the oxidase reaction, for production of H<sub>2</sub>S, for nitrate reduction and for milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Tweens 20 and 40 and urea are hydrolysed, but Tween 80, gelatin, starch and cellulose are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose, d-galactose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, sodium dl-malate, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>d-Adonitol, d-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-lactose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose and xylitol are not utilized.</s><s>Adenine, l-alanine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine and xanthine can be used as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, hypoxanthine, dl-methionine or l-valine.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and ribose, glucose, galactose, madurose and trace amounts of mannose are present in the whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>0</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>0</sub>) are also present as moderate to minor components.</s><s>Phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, two unknown phosphoglycolipids, glucosamine-containing phospholipid, diphosphatidylglycerol and two phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Fatty acids are C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 10-methyl, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em> 9, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 65070<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208019<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45214<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface sterilized plant sample, <em>Osyris wightiana</em> Wall. ex Wight, collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 70.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>