<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6854_nm.7428" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7428" rank="genus">Streptosporangium</organism><reference id="rid.6854"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jahnke</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kemmerling</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gürtler</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Streptosporangium viridogriseum (Okuda et al. 1966), Streptosporangium viridogriseum subsp. kofuense (Nonomura and Ohara 1969), and Streptosporangium albidum (Furumai et al. 1968) to Kutzneria gen. nov. as Kutzneria viridogrisea comb. nov., Kutzneria kofuensis comb. nov., and Kutzneria albida comb. nov., respectively, and emendation of the genus Streptosporangium.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>265</fpage><lpage>269</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Streptosporangium</i> Couch 1955, 14SAL emend. Stackebrandt et al. 1994.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on the characteristics given by Nonomura (18). Stable branched mycelium produces globose sporangia up to 10 μm in diameter on the aerial mycelium. The sporangiophores are short (up to 10 μm long). The sporangiospores are spherical-oval or rod shaped (0.2 to 1.3 by 0.2 to 1.5 μm) and nonmotile and are formed by septation of a coiled, unbranched hypha within the sporangium. Cell walls contain N-acetylated muramic acid and mesu-diaminopimelic acid, but no characteristic sugar occurs in whole-cell hydrolysates. Madurose may be present. The major phospholipids include phosphatidylethanolamine, hydroxyphosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol, and an N-acetylglucosamine-containingp hospholipid but no phosphatidylcholine. The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(II,VIII-H4), MK-9, and/or MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>). The characteristic fatty acids are 13:0, iso-14:0, 14:0, 15:0, iso-16:0, <i>cis</i>9-16: 1, 16:0, 10-methyl-16:0, <i>cis</i>9-17: 1,17:0, 10-methyl-17:0, and 18:0 fatty acids. 2-OH-iso-16:0 fatty acid is present. No 2-OH-anteiso-17:O fatty acid is present. Gram positive. Aerobic. Mesophilic. Chemoorganotrophic. Some species require vitamin B for growth. Natural habitat: soil. The G+C content of the DNA is 69 to 71 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method). Type species: <i>Streptosporangium roseum</i> Couch 1955, 151</s></p></content></protolog>