<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12322_nm.20343" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20343" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20343" rank="species">Scardovia wiggsiae</organism><reference id="rid.12322"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mantzourani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hooper</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nicholson</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Scardovia wiggsiae sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity and clinical material, and emended descriptions of the genus Scardovia and Scardovia inopinata</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>25</fpage><lpage>29</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019752-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20139283</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Scardovia wiggsiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Scardovia wiggsiae</em> (wiggs′i.ae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>wiggsiae</em> of Wiggs, named in honour of Lois Wiggs, American microbiologist, for her contributions to anaerobic microbiology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on five strains isolated from the human oral cavity and one strain isolated from an infected arm wound.</s><s>Gram-positive, anaerobic, non-spore-forming and non-motile bacilli (0.6–0.7 μm×1.6–4 μm).</s><s>Cells are pleomorphic with straight, slightly curved and some club-shaped forms arranged singularly, in pairs or in short chains, with some branched and diphtheroidal arrangements.</s><s>After 7 days on FAA, colonies are pleomorphic, 0.4–1.2 mm in diameter, circular, irregular or molar tooth in shape, entire or undulate, grey, off-white or cream, convex and opaque.</s><s>Growth in broth produces a moderate turbidity that is enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Saccharolytic.</s><s>Ferments d-arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, maltose, raffinose, ribose and sucrose without production of gas; weakly ferments mannose; does not ferment cellobiose, dextran, mannitol, melezitose, rhamnose, sorbitol, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Fermentation of lactose, melibiose and salicin is variable.</s><s>Major amounts of acetic acid and minor-to-moderate amounts of lactic acid are produced in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is variable; l-arginine, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, catalase and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The Rapid ID 32A profile is 4 <sup>4</sup>/<sub>5</sub><sup>0</sup>/<sub>1</sub> 4 0335 05.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Cellular polar lipids include a variety of glycolipids together with diphosphatidylglycerol, an unidentified phospholipid and an unidentified phosphoglycolipid.</s><s>No respiratory quinones are detectable.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the type A4<em>α</em> l-Lys–Thr–Glu, with l-lysine partially replaced by l-ornithine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is C1A_55<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22547<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 58090<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the human oral cavity and an arm wound of an intravenous drug user.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55 mol%.</s><s>The species is Human Oral Taxon 195 in the Human Oral Microbiome Database (http://www.homd.org).</s></p></content></protolog>