<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4046_nm.11777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7497" rank="species">Nonomuraea dietzii</organism><reference id="rid.4046"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wink</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonomuraea dietzii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1437</fpage><lpage>1441</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491343</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nonomuraea dietzii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nonomuraea dietzii</i> (diet'zi.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>dietzii</i> of Dietz, named in honour of the American microbiologist Alma Dietz)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>The aerial mycelium develops different colours depending upon the ISP medium used: red/brown (ISP2), beige (ISP3), pink (ISP4 and ISP7), antique rose (ISP5) and white (ISP6); after approximately 14 d, the aerial hyphae develop masses of long spore chains, each containing up to 30 spores.</s><s>Spore chains may be stalked or may form clusters emerging directly from the agar.</s><s>Sporangia are not detected.</s><s>Depending upon the ISP medium used, the nonfragmenting substrate mycelium is brown (ISP2), beige (ISP3), pink (ISP3, ISP 7) or rose (ISP5, ISP6) in colour.</s><s>DL-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic amino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Cell hydrolysates contain galactose, glucose and ribose but not arabinose, xylose or rhamnose; madurose occurs in minor amounts.</s><s>The phospholipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylethanolamine, methyl-phosphatidylethanolamine and N-acetylglucosamine phospholipid; some unspecified glycolipids also occur.</s><s>The principal menaquinones are MK-9(III, VIII H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) ; small amounts of MK-9 and MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) occur.</s><s>The pattern of fatty acid methyl esters is composed mainly of iso- (iso-C<sub>14:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>) and 10-heptadecanoic (10-methyl-C<sub>17:0</sub>) branched fatty acids.</s><s>Smaller amounts of fatty acids are unbranched and saturated (C<sub>15:0</sub>;C<sub>17:0</sub>) and unsaturated fatty acids (<i>cis</i>9-C<sub>17:1</sub>) and 2-hydroxy (iso- C<sub>16:0</sub> 2-OH) fatty acid methyl esters can be found.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, citrate and L-rhamnose are utilized, but not <i>m</i>-inositol, sucrose, xylose, D-mannose, D-raffinose or cellobiose.</s><s>Positive for gelatinase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Positive for acetoin and H<sub>2</sub>S production; negative for tryptophan deaminase, lysine decarboxylase and indole production.</s><s>Shows no antibacterial effect on <i>Micrococcus luteus</i>, <i>Streptococcus murinus</i>, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>, <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i>, <i>Escherichia coli</i>, <i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i>, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i>, <i>Aspergillus niger</i> or <i>Candida albicans</i>.</s><s>The isolation source is not recorded.</s><s>The type strain is DSM 44320<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL 11111<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>