<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6825_nm.5206" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5206" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5206" rank="species">Planomicrobium koreense</organism><reference id="rid.6825"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kho</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planomicrobium koreense gen. nov., sp. nov., a bacterium isolated from the Korean traditional fermented seafood jeotgal, and transfer of Planococcus okeanokoites (Nakagawa et al. 1996) and Planococcus mcmeekinii (Junge et al. 1998) to the genus Planomicrobium.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1511</fpage><lpage>1520</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491353</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planomicrobium koreense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planomicrobium koreense</i> (ko.re.en'se. M.L. adj. <i>koreense</i> referring to Korea, the country where strain JG07<sup>T</sup> was isolated and taxonomically studied)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci or short rods in the early growth phase but soon change to rods.</s><s>Strictly aerobic and nonspore- forming.</s><s>Gram-positive, and Gram-variable in old cultures.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, low convex and yellow to orange in colour.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase- and urease-negative.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Arbutin, elastin, starch and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4-38 °C, but weakly at 39 °C and does not occur at 40 °C.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 20-30 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is 7.0-8.5, and growth is inhibited at pH 5.5 and 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.6% NaCl but weakly in the presence of 7%NaCl and does not occur in the presence of more than 8% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal concentration of NaCl for growth is 1.4%.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose and 5-ketogluconate, and weakly from glucose.</s><s>No acid is produced from glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyL-D-xyloside, galactose, fructose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyL-D-mannoside, α-methyL-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, D-turanose, dlyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, larabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A4α (L-Lys-D-Glu).</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-8, MK-7 and MK-6.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile contains major amounts of saturated, unsaturated and branched fatty acids.</s><s>The cellular phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and bisphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The G­C content is 47 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the the Korean traditional fermented seafood jeotgal.</s><s>The type strain is strain JG07, which has been deposited in the Korean Collection for Type Cultures as KCTC 3684<sup>T</sup> and the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as JCM 10704<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>