<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4546_nm.5539" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5539" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5539" rank="species">Enterococcus haemoperoxidus</organism><reference id="rid.4546"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Švec</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doškař</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus haemoperoxidus sp. nov. and Enterococcus moraviensis sp. nov., isolated from water.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1567</fpage><lpage>1574</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491359</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus haemoperoxidus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus haemoperoxidus</i> (hae.mo.per.o'xi.dus. G. n. <i>haema</i> blood; <i>per</i> G. prefix intensification; <i>oxys</i> G. adj. sour; N. L. adj. <i>haemoperoxidus</i> blood peroxide, derived from the ability of the species to decompose hydrogen peroxide into oxygen and water when cultivated on blood-agar media)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, ovoid cocci, occurring in pairs, short chains or small groups.</s><s>They are elongated in the direction of the chains.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>A slightly yellowish pigment may be produced; this pigment is most readily visible when growth is collected from plates within inoculation loops.</s><s>A positive catalase reaction is clearly evident when cultivated on blood agar, but cells grown on blood-free medium are catalase-negative.</s><s>Weakly positive in the amylase test.</s><s>Streptococcal group D antigen-positive.</s><s>Growth characteristics and physiological traits are as described above.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, ribose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, β-gentiobiose and maltotriose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from starch.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, D- or L-arabinose, D- or L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, inulin, D-raffinose, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D- or L-fucose, D- or L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Most strains do not produce acid from glycogen and D-turanose.</s><s>Mannitol acidification is variable.</s><s>Positive in tests for acetoin, hippurate, aesculin, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and arginine dihydrolase; negative for bglucuronidase, β-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase and urease.</s><s>Most strains are α-galactosidase-negative.</s><s>Positive enzymic hydrolysis of 4-methylumbelliferyl (4MU) β-D-glucoside, L-pyroglutamic acid 7-amido-4-methyl coumarin (AMC), L-tryptophan, 4MU <i>N</i>-acetyl β-D-glucosaminide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-dcellobioside and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl α-D-maltoside; mostly positive for L-phenylalanine AMC, 4MU α-D-glucoside, proline and leucine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide and o-nitrophenyl β-D-galactoside.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of L-valine, 4MU phosphate, 4MU β-D-glucuronide and L-isoleucine.</s><s>Variable enzymic hydrolysis of pnitrophenyl β-D-glucoside and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate.</s><s>The type strain, 440<sup>T</sup> (=CCM4851<sup>T</sup>=LMG19487<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from service (non-potable) water and its characteristics agree with the species description above.</s><s>Tests that are variable for <i>E. haemoperoxidus</i> strains give the following results for strain 440<sup>T</sup>: positive acidification of starch; negative for mannitol, glycogen and D-turanose.</s><s>Weakly positive for agalactosidase.</s><s>Positive for enzymic hydrolysis of 4MU α-D-glucoside, L-phenylalanine AMC, proline and leucine <i>p</i>-nitroanilide, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-galactoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl β-D-glucoside and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate.</s><s>The strain is not pigmented.</s><s>The G+­C content of strain 440<sup>T</sup> is 35.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>