<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1559_nm.1531" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1531" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1531" rank="species">Ancylobacter rudongensis</organism><reference id="rid.1559"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ancylobacter rudongensis sp. nov., isolated from roots of Spartina anglica.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>388</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02466-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023948</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ancylobacter rudongensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ancylobacter rudongensis</em> (ru.dong.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>rudongensis</em> referring to Rudong County, Jiangsu Province, P.R. China, where the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative curved rods, 0·6–0·8 μm in diameter, non-motile, without capsule and gas vesicles.</s><s>Intracellular granules of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate are formed.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, round, opaque, entire and 0·5–1·0 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation on <em>Ancylobacter</em>–<em>Spirosoma</em> agar.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 28–30 °C; no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is 6·8–7·0; no growth occurs at pH 5·5 or 10·0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–5·0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Microaerophilic in semi-solid, nitrogen-free medium to fix free nitrogen.</s><s>Delayed growth occurs in the presence of KCN.</s><s>Fluorescent pigment is not produced.</s><s>Urease-, arginine decarboxylase- and lysine decarboxylase-positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, ornithine decarboxylase, DNase and lipase (Tween 80) are negative.</s><s>Alkali is produced from litmus milk.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced.</s><s>Growth does not occur anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, but starch is not.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are used as sole carbon sources: starch, maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, adonitol, glycerol, glucose, ribose, inulin, l-arabinose, fructose, galactose, mannitol, xylose, aesculin, sorbitol, sodium gluconate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, alanine, proline, sodium acetate, fumaric acid, sodium malonate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sodium lactate, sodium malate, sodium propionate, methanol, sodium formate, sodium pyruvate, amaroid, sucrose, dextrin and cellobiose; trehalose, sorbose, raffinose, melibiose, mannose, lactose, dulcitol, inositol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, rhamnose, melizitose, arginine, sodium tartrate, sodium hippurate and salicin are not used.</s><s>Acid is formed from mannose, ribose, glycerol, mannitol, sorbitol, galactose, cellobiose, rhamnose, salicin, glucose, maltose, l-arabinose, trehalose, xylose, melibiose, adonitol, fructose and lactose, but not from inositol, raffinose, inulin, melizitose, starch, glycogen, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, sorbose, sodium gluconate, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol or dextrin.</s><s>No gas is formed from these carbohydrates.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 68·2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AS 1.1761<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 11671<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the roots of <em>Spartina anglica</em> in Rudong County, Jiangsu Province, P.R. China.</s></p></content></protolog>