<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.204_nm.5828" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5828" rank="genus">Micrococcus</organism><reference id="rid.204"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koch</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gvozdiak</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic dissection of the genus Micrococcus: Kocuria gen. nov., Nesterenkonia gen. nov., Kytococcus gen. nov., Dermacoccus gen. nov., and Micrococcus Cohn 1872 gen. emend.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>682</fpage><lpage>692</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-682</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547287</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Micrococcus</i> Cohn 1972, 151<sup>AL</sup> Stackebrandt et al. 1995.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on characteristics given in references 9, 22, 25, 26, 29, 43a, 45, and 46 and this paper. Cells are spherical and nonmotile. Endospores are not formed. Gram positive. Aerobic. Chemoorganotrophic; metabolism is strictly respiratory. Catalase and oxidase positive. Mesophilic. Nonhalophilic. The peptidoglycan contains L-lysine as the diagnostic amino acid. The peptidoglyan variation is either A2, with the interpeptide bridge consisting of a peptide subunit, or A4α. The predominant menaquinones are either MK-8 and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) or MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>); MK-7 or MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) occur in minor amounts. The cytochromes are cytochromes <i>aa</i><sub>3</sub>,<i>b</i><sub>557</sub>,<i>b</i><sub>567</sub>, and <i>d</i><sub>626</sub>; cytochromes <i>c</i><sub>550</sub>, <i>c</i><sub>551</sub>,<i>b</i><sub>563</sub>, <i>b</i><sub>564</sub>, and <i>b</i><sub>567</sub> may be present. Mycolic acids and teichoic acids are absent; teichuronic acids may be present. Mannosamine-uronic acid may be present as an amino sugar in the cell wall polysaccharide. The cellular fatty acids are iso- and anteiso-branched fatty acids, with anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> predominating. The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, and unknown ninhydrin-negative phospholipids and glycolipids; phosphatidylinositol may be present. The major aliphatic hydrocarbons (br-Δ-C) are C<sub>27</sub> to C<sub>29</sub> hydrocarbons. The G+C content of the DNA is 69 to 76 mol% (as determined by the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method). The primary habitat is mammalian skin. The type species is <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> (Schroeter) Cohn 1872, 153<sup>AL</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>