<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2282_nm.9701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9701" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9701" rank="species">Paenibacillus mendelii</organism><reference id="rid.2282"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Šmerda</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Páčová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Durnová</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smíšková</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Havel</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus mendelii sp. nov., from surface-sterilized seeds of Pisum sativum L</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2351</fpage><lpage>2354</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63759-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280495</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus mendelii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus mendelii</em> (men.de′li.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>mendelii</em> of Mendel, to honour J. G. Mendel, the founder of genetics).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-variable rods.</s><s>Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Spores are oval with a subterminal position in a swollen sporangium.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 25 and 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are circular, smooth, flat, bright, translucent with entire edges and about 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Positive tests for catalase, oxidase, lecithinase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and hydrolysis of aesculin, for anaerobic growth and for growth at pH 8·5.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, rhamnose, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, d-raffinose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-turanose, l-fucose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Negative tests for production of acetoin and indole, utilization of citrate, haemolysis, arginine dihydrolase and DNase, and for hydrolysis of casein, starch, hippurate, urea, gelatin, Tween 80 and tyrosine.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and no growth occurs at 50 °C or in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of agar is not observed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, l-xylose, adonitol, d-mannose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, inulin, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Sensitive to erythromycin, tetracycline, vancomycin, cephalothin and piperacillin and resistant to clindamycin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50·8 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat not known; the type strain, C/2<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 4839<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23002<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface-sterilized pea seeds.</s></p></content></protolog>