<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6792_nm.4222" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4222" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4222" rank="species">Sporanaerobacter acetigenes</organism><reference id="rid.6792"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hernandez-Eugenio</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macarie</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sporanaerobacter acetigenes gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel acetogenic, facultatively sulfur-reducing bacterium.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1217</fpage><lpage>1223</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01992-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148631</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sporanaerobacter acetigenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sporanaerobacter acetigenes</i> (a.ce.ti.ge'nes. L. n. <i>acetum</i> vinegar; Gr. v. <i>gennano</i> to produce; N.L. adj. <i>acetigenes</i> producing acetate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties listed in the genus description, the following properties are reported.</s><s>Cells are 0.4-0.5x3-5 lm.</s><s>Electron microscopy of sections of cells reveals a 33-nm-thick, layered Grampositive- type cell wall, composed of three dense layers (two thick layers and a middle thinner layer) separated by two light spaces.</s><s>Grows at temperatures ranging from 25 to 50 °C, with optimum growth at 40 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl at concentrations ranging from 0 to 40 g l<sup>-1</sup>, with optimum growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is around 7.5 and growth occurs between pH 5.5 and 8.5.</s><s>Heterotrophic.</s><s>Gelatin and casein are not used as energy sources, but peptone, bio-Trypcase and Trypticase soy are fermented.</s><s>The following amino acids are used as energy sources in the presence of yeast extract (2 g l<sup>-1</sup>): arginine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, methionine, phenylalanine, tryptophan and valine.</s><s>In the presence of elemental sulfur as a terminal electron acceptor, the use of the amino acids cited above, with the exception of arginine, is improved.</s><s>Lysine is only oxidized in the presence of elemental sulfur.</s><s>Valine is oxidized to isobutyrate, leucine to isovalerate, isoleucine to methyl 2-butyrate, phenylalanine to phenyl acetate, lysine to acetate and histidine to acetate and an unidentified compound.</s><s>Peptone is fermented to acetate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> as the major end products of metabolism.</s><s>Traces of isobutyrate and isovalerate are also detected.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted to acetate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Utilizes D-glucose, D-ribose and fumarate, but not D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, maltose, D- or L-xylose, acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, malate or succinate.</s><s>Acetate is the only fatty acid produced from glucose metabolism (Table 1).</s><s>Adverse effects on animals and humans are not known.</s><s>Because of its ability to degrade amino acids and peptides, the possibility of harmful effects cannot be excluded.</s><s>Cautious handling and autoclaving of cultures before disposal is recommended.</s><s>The G+C content is 32.2 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from a UASB reactor in Mexico.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Lup 33<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13106<sup>T</sup>= CIP 106730<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>