<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1405_nm.245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.245" rank="genus">Methanohalophilus</organism><reference id="rid.1405"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Paterek</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanohalophilus mahii gen. nov., sp. nov., a methylotrophic halophilic methanogen.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>123</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-122</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanohalophilus</i> gen nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanohalophilus</i> (Me. tha. no. ha. lo. phi’lus. M. L. n. <i>methanum</i> methane; Gr. n. <i>halo</i> salt; Gr. no. <i>philos</i> lover; M. L. n. <i>Methanohalophilus</i> methane-producing salt lover)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of this genus are nonsporeforming, nonmotile, irregular cocci which stain gram negative and occur singly or in small clumps.</s><s>Cells lyse in the presence of 0.001% Triton X-100 or 0.05% sodium dodecyl sulfate and in solutions with NaCl concentrations less than 0.3 M.</s><s>Surface colonies are cream to pale yellow and circular and often appear foamy due to trapped gases.</s><s>The colonies fluoresce yellowish green under 420-nm excitation.</s><s>Growth and methanogenesis require sodium, magnesium, iron, and potassium, with the maximum response occurring at a sodium concentration between 0.5 and 2.5 M.</s><s>Methanol, methylamine, dimethylamine, and trimethylamine support growth and methane production.</s><s>No growth occurs with hydrogen-carbon dioxide, acetate, formate, methionine, choline, or betaine.</s><s>Organisms are found in anaerobic sediments with salinity levels at or above seawater concentration.</s></p></content></protolog>