<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1483_nm.4999" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4999" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4999" rank="species">Bacillus thiaminolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.1483"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus thiaminolyticus sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>242</fpage><lpage>246</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-242</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397192</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus thiaminolyticus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus thiaminolyticus</i> (thi.am.in.o.ly'tic.us. M. L. n. <i>thiamina</i>, thiamine; M. L. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; M. L. adj. <i>thiaminolyticus</i>, decomposing thiamine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods that are 0.5 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 3.0 μm.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Ellipsoidal spores are formed in swelling sporangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, thin, smooth, circular, entire, and 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth (test for acetylmethylcarbinol production) ranges from 4.9 to 5.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is usually reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Starch and casein are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urea, Tween 80, and egg yolk lecithin are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine, lysine, ornithine, and phenylalanine are not decomposed.</s><s>Tyrosine is degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate, citrate, fumarate, malate, and succinate are utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth occurs at pH 5.6 or 5.7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No change occurs in litmus milk in 7 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains grow in the presence of 5% NaCl; no growth occurs in the presence of 7% NaCl.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by 0.001% lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature is 28°C; the maximum temperature for growth is 45°C; and the minimum temperature for growth is 20°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid, but no gas, is produced from cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Variable acid production is observed with L-arabinose, D-mannitol and D-sorbitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-rhamnose and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant density is 1.7055 to 1.7075 g/cm<sup>3</sup>; the G+C content is 52 to 54 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human fecal material and honey bee larvae.</s><s>The ability to decompose thiamine is a unique characteristic of this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain NRRL B-4156, has been deposited in the Agricultural Research Culture Collection at the Northern Regional Research Center, Peoria, Ill.</s></p></content></protolog>