<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10357_nm.16874" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16874" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16874" rank="species">Halomonas johnsoniae</organism><reference id="rid.10357"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas stevensii sp. nov., Halomonas hamiltonii sp. nov. and Halomonas johnsoniae sp. nov., isolated from a renal care centre</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>377</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004424-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas johnsoniae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas johnsoniae</em> (john.so′ni.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>johnsoniae</em> of Johnson, named after Ms. Nancy Johnson, a registered nurse who isolated and characterized the first strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-stain-negative and non-spore-forming rods (0.7–0.9×1.5–4.0 μm).</s><s>Cells are motile with lateral/polar flagella.</s><s>PHB is accumulated.</s><s>EPS is not produced.</s><s>Colonies are cream-coloured, smooth, translucent and circular with entire edges.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C (optimum 30–35 °C) and at pH 7–10 (optimum pH 8–9).</s><s>Growth occurs at sea-salt concentrations of 0–20 % (w/w) (optimum 0–5 %, w/v).</s><s>Good growth is observed on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed on solid MH medium.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from l-cysteine.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, but nitrite is not.</s><s>Selenite is reduced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Utilization of glucose is oxidative.</s><s>Gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>Respiration on nitrate, nitrite or fumarate is negative.</s><s>Tween 20, Tween 80 and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin, starch and <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside are not.</s><s>Blood is not haemolysed.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lecithinase, phosphatase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, ethanol, d-fructose, fumarate, gluconate, d-glucose, glycerol, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, propionate, sorbitol, succinate, sucrose and trehalose are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy, but adipate, adonitol, aesculin, amygdalin, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, formate, d-fucose, d-galactose, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, malonate, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, starch and d-xylose are not.</s><s>l-Alanine, dl-isoleucine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine are utilized as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy, but l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-lysine and l-methionine are not.</s><s>In the API 50CH gallery, acid is produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, melezitose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose, but not from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, d-adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-tagatose, xylitol, d-xylose or l-xylose.</s><s>According to results from API ZYM tests, l-leucyl 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl butyrate and 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside are hydrolysed, but <em>N</em>-benzoyl-dl-arginine 2-naphthylamide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, l-cystyl 2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-glutaryl-phenylalanine 2-naphthylamide, naphthol-AS-BI-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate, 1-naphthyl <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, 2-naphthyl caprylate, 2-naphthyl <em>α</em>-l-fucopyranoside, 2-naphthyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl myristate, 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 5.4), 2-naphthyl phosphate (pH 8.5) and l-valyl 2-naphthylamide are not.</s><s>Susceptible to amoxicillin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, cefoxitin, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, polymyxin B, rifampicin, sulphamide, tetracycline and tobramycin.</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin, kanamycin, neomycin, streptomycin, trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole and vancomycin.</s><s>Susceptibility to chloramphenicol and penicillin G is strain-dependent.</s><s>The predominant quinone is ubiquinone Q-9; a small amount of Q-8 is also present.</s><s>The fatty acids C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are predominant.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.4−65.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, T68687<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22157<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21197<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a waste handling option port of a dialysis machine.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>