<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12636_nm.22175" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22175" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22175" rank="species">Bacillus graminis</organism><reference id="rid.12636"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bibi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus graminis sp. nov., an endophyte isolated from a coastal dune plant</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1567</fpage><lpage>1571</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023820-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656804</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus graminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus graminis</em> (gra′mi.nis. L. gen. neut. n. <em>graminis</em> of grass).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, facultatively anaerobic rods to coccoid rods, 0.7–1.0×1.2–2.2 µm.</s><s>They bear an ellipsoidal endospore that lies in a subterminal position.</s><s>Motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>After 2 days on 1/2 R2A, colonies are semi-transparent and whitish in colour with opaque centres.</s><s>Cells usually occur singly or in pairs; tetrad-like cells are common.</s><s>Cells are catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows at 15–45 °C (optimum 30–35 °C), but not at 10 or 50 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–8.5 but not at pH 5.5 or 9.0.</s><s>Growth is observed in R2A broth containing 8 % (w/v) NaCl but not 9.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive; weakly positive for hydrolysis of casein and cellulose.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin, chitin or urea.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Indole production and egg-yolk reaction are negative.</s><s>In API 20E tests, nitrate is reduced to nitrite; negative for ONPG reaction, activities of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, the Voges–Proskauer reaction, indole production and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>Positive for acid production from l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and amygdalin, but negative for acid production from erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, inulin, melezitose, gentiobiose, raffinose, d-lyxose, d-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Positive for utilization of d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, sucrose, d-mannose, d-mannitol and amygdalin.</s><s>The major respiratory menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid of the cell-wall peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;10 % of the total) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol; an unknown phospholipid, an unknown glycolipid and two unknown lipids are minor components.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 41.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YC6957<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 13779<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22162<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from internal tissue of roots of <em>Elymus mollis</em> Trin. growing on the coast of Namhae Island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>