<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2397_nm.11231" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11231" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11231" rank="species">Undibacterium pigrum</organism><reference id="rid.2397"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hermansson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Persson</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Undibacterium pigrum gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from drinking water.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1510</fpage><lpage>1515</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64785-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625185</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Undibacterium pigrum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Undibacterium pigrum</em> (pig′rum. L. neut. adj. <em>pigrum</em> inactive).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shares all characteristics listed in the genus description.</s><s>Polyamine pattern, quinone system, polar lipid profile and fatty acid patterns are those listed in the genus description.</s><s>Additionally, phosphatidylserine and three aminolipids are present in the polar lipid profile.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A agar.</s><s>No growth on TSA, nutrient agar or MacConkey agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Beige, translucent and shiny colonies with entire edges form within 24 h, with a diameter of approximately 2 mm.</s><s>l-Alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) is hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, bis-pNP phenylphosphonate, bis-pNP phosphorylcholine, l-aniline pNA, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pna and l-proline pNA.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole sources of carbon: d-gluconate, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, suberate, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>No acids are produced from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 49009<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109318<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated by one of us (F. P.) from drinking water on 10 March 2004 in Göteborg, Sweden.</s><s>A second strain, CCUG 49012 (=CIP 108976), is also allocated to this genus at present.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of this strain is 50.6 mol%.</s><s>This strain shares 96.8 % 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity with strain CCUG 49009<sup>T</sup> and a DNA–DNA relatedness of 20 %.</s><s>Phenotypically, it is very similar to strain CCUG 49009<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The strain represents a genomovar of <em>U. pigrum</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>