<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1883_nm.9634" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9634" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9634" rank="species">Dyadobacter hamtensis</organism><reference id="rid.1883"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chaturvedi</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dyadobacter hamtensis sp. nov., from Hamta glacier, located in the Himalayas, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2113</fpage><lpage>2117</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63806-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166718</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dyadobacter hamtensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dyadobacter hamtensis</em> (ham.ten′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>hamtensis</em> pertaining to the Hamta glacier).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of strain HHS 11<sup>T</sup> on nutrient agar medium are round (2–3 mm in diameter) and light yellow.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative rods and are non-motile.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 37 °C and at pH 6–8, but not at pH 10.</s><s>The optimum temperature and pH for growth are 22 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 11·6 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar medium, Ayers' agar and R2A medium.</s><s>The strain is positive for catalase, oxidase, phosphatase, arginine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for gelatinase, urease, lipase, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, utilization of citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production, the methyl red test, the indole test, the Voges–Proskauer test, hydrolysis of aesculin, hydrolysis of starch and reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-xylose, d-arabinose and d-glucose, but not from d-ribose, d-fructose, d-galactose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-lactose, d-maltose or d-mannose.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, l-fucose, melezitose, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, d-lactose, d-raffinose, cellulose, amygdalin, dextran, glycogen, arbutin, salicin, glycerol, d-erythritol, d-adonitol, citrate, malonate, lactic acid, citric acid, 2-ketogluconate, inulin, sodium formate, sodium fumarate, sodium malate, sodium tartrate, sodium acetate, PEG, l-glycine, l-alanine, l-valine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-lysine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamine, l-asparagine, l-methionine, l-cysteine, l-tyrosine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, l-proline, l-histidine and l-creatinine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize d-rhamnose, d-arabinose, l-melibiose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-ribose, d-maltose, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, gluconate, hydroxybutyric acid, sodium succinate, sodium pyruvate, thioglycolate, starch, methanol or agar as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) ciprofloxacin (30), cefoperazone (75), cephotaxime (10), doxycycline (30), colistin (10), sulphamethazole (50), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), nalidixic acid (30), chloramphenicol (25), rifampicin (25), streptomycin (10), trimethoprim (25), norfloxacin (10), lomefloxacin (30), tobramycin (15) and amikacin (30), but resistant to cotrimoxazole (25), roxithromycin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), penicillin (10), cefuroxime (20), lincomycin (20), cefazolin (30), novobiocin (30), ampicillin (25 μg μl<sup>−1</sup>), amoxicillin (30), bacitracin (10), vancomycin (10) and erythromycin (15).</s><s>The pigment is flexirubin-like.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 49 mol%.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HHS 11<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12919<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 7023<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a glacial water sample.</s></p></content></protolog>