<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.60_nm.11719" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11719" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3188" rank="species">Erwinia persicinus</organism><reference id="rid.60"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kosako</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia persicinus, a new species isolated from plants.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>379</fpage><lpage>383</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-379</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2275853</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia persicinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia persicinus</i> (per. si' ci. nus. M. L. masc. adj. <i>persicinus</i>, peach color, because of the pinkish or peach-colored pigment of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive, fermentative (producing acid but not gas) rods (0.5 to 0.6 by 1.0 μm) that are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and to the general definition of the genus <i>Erwinia</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are chemoorganotrophic and grow well on nutrient agar and tryptic soy, peptone-yeast extract, and other common laboratory media.</s><s>Colonies on peptone-yeast extract agar are circular, smooth, and entire to slightly erose.</s><s>These organisms grow well at 25, 30, and 37°C, but not at 5 or 41°C, and they are somewhat more active metabolically at 25 or 30°C than at 37°C.</s><s>They produce a water-soluble pink pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions in commonly used tests are described above.</s><s>In addition, these organisms are positive in tests for alkaline phosphatase and β-glucosidase and negative in tests for arylsulfatase, esterase, β-glucuronidase, nucleoside phosphotransferase, pectinase, DL-tartrate utilization, tetrathionate reductase, Tween 80 hydrolysis, and tyrosine clearing.</s><s>They produce acid from fermentation of arbutin, ribose, and fructose, but not from amygdalin, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, D-fucose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, glycogen, inulin, 2-ketogluconate ,5-ketogluconate, D-lyxose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, melezitose, sorbose, starch, D-tagatose, D-turanose, xylitol, and L-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole sources of carbon: acetate, aconitate, DL-α-alanine, amygdalin, L-arabinose, arbutin, L-aspartate, cellobiose, citrate, erythritol, esculin, fructose, fumarate, D-galactose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, D-glucose, L-glutamate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, L-histidine, i-myoinositol, DL-lactate, lactose, L-malate, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, L-proline, raffinose, L-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, L-serine, D-sorbitol, sucrose, succinate, and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No strain utilizes any of the following substrates as a sole carbon source: adipate, D-arabinose, L-arabitol, benzoate, butyrate, caprylate, cysteine, dulcitol, D-fucose, L-glycine, L-histamine, inulin, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-lyxose, melezitose, L-ornithine, propionate, L-sorbose, spermine, starch, D-tagatose, L-threonine, tryptamine, D-turanose, urea, and L-valine.</s><s>Strains vary in their ability to utilize adonitol, L-arginine, β-gentiobiose, and glucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to amikacin, chloramphenicol, clindamycin, erythromycin, gentamicin, lincomycin, minocycline, nitrofurantoin, polymyxin B, streptomycin, and tetracycline, and all strains are resistant to penicillin G.</s><s>Resistance to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cefazolin, cephalothin, colistin, kanamycin, mydecamycin, nalidixic acid, sulfisoxazole, and tobramycin varies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 52 to 54 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from tomatoes, a banana, and a cucumber.</s><s>There are no human isolates and no evidence for pathogenicity for either plants or animals.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Erwinia persicinus</i> is strain HK 204 (= A52716 = CDC 9108-82 = IAM 12843 = JCM 3704 = ATCC 35998).</s><s>This strain was isolated from a tomato by Komagata and Okada in 1962.</s><s>Its biochemical reactions are typical of those of the species.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 54 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>