<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12917_nm.22742" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22742" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22742" rank="species">Alkalibacterium subtropicum</organism><reference id="rid.12917"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishizaki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kodama</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okamoto-Kainuma</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koizumi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alkalibacterium subtropicum sp. nov., a slightly halophilic and alkaliphilic marine lactic acid bacterium isolated from decaying marine algae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2996</fpage><lpage>3002</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027953-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21296925</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alkalibacterium subtropicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alkalibacterium subtropicum</em> (sub.tro′pi.cum. L. pref. <em>sub</em> under, below, slightly; L. neut. adj. <em>tropicum</em> tropical; N.L. neut. adj. <em>subtropicum</em> subtropical, referring to the subtropical region where strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-sporulating, non-motile, straight rods measuring 0.5–0.9×3.0–20.0 µm, occurring singly, in pairs or in short chains and elongated in older cultures (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>Deep colonies in 2.5 % NaCl GYPF agar medium are creamy white, opaque and lenticular, with diameters of 1.0–2.0 mm after 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Surface colonies are round, convex, entire, creamy white and transparent, with diameters of 0.5–1.0 mm after 3 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Aerotolerant.</s><s>Grows evenly throughout a column of semi-solid agar medium.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Quinones are not detected.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, gelatin liquefaction and production of ammonia from l-arginine.</s><s>Slightly halophilic; optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 1.0–3.0 % (type strain); grows in 0–17.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; the optimum pH for growth is 8.0–8.5; grows at pH 7.5–9.5 (type strain).</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 40 °C, with optimum growth at 20–30 °C.</s><s>Lactic acid is the major fermentation product from d-glucose; other products are formate, acetate and ethanol in a molar ratio of approximately 2 : 1 : 1, without gas formation.</s><s>Lactate produced is of dl-type.</s><s>d-Glucose is aerobically metabolized to acetate and lactate (analysed for the type strain).</s><s>The following carbohydrates and related compounds are fermented: d-ribose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol (weak for O25-2), d-dulcitol (weak), glycerol (weak), d-salicin, sodium gluconate, starch and inulin.</s><s>d-Arabinose and l-rhamnose are not fermented.</s><s>Variable reactions are observed for l-arabinose, d-galactose, melezitose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol and methyl α-d-glucoside.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by ampicillin (10 µg), chloramphenicol (weakly; 2 µg), kanamycin (2 µg) and trimethoprim (10 µg).</s><s>The peptidoglycan is A4β, Orn-d-Asp type.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is O24-2<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23664<sup>T</sup> = NBRC 107172<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a decaying marine alga, <em>Galaxaura</em> sp., collected at a foreshore site near the Oujima Islet in Okinawa Prefecture, a subtropical area of Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain O24-2<sup>T</sup> is 43.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>