<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7217_nm.8307" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8307" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8307" rank="species">Hymenobacter actinosclerus</organism><reference id="rid.7217"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>I.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patterson</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic characterization of a novel radiation-resistant bacterium from irradiated pork: description of Hymenobacter actinosclerus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>731</fpage><lpage>734</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758882</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Hymenobacter actinosclerus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hymenobacter actinosclerus</i> (ac.ti.no.scle'rus. Gr. n. <i>actis</i>, <i>actinos</i> ray, beam; Gr. adj. <i>scleros</i> hard; M.L. masc. n. <i>actinoscleros</i> hard against rays, pertaining to the organism's radiation resistance)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, ranging from 0.5 to 0.6 μm in width and 2.0 to 3.6 μm in length, which are non-motile in hanging drops.</s><s>No variation in cell morphology is observed in old cultures.</s><s>Colonies on YP agar are circular, entire, opaque and not easily emulsified.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic (metabolism respiratory).</s><s>Water-insoluble red pigment is produced.</s><s>Fluorescent pigments are not produced on King's A or B media.</s><s>Aerobic, with ability to grow under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid and gas are not produced from d-glucose.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed, but aesculin is not.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, ester lipase C8, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and phosphoamidase activity are detectable.</s><s>Lipase C14, chymotrypsin, trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, α-mannosidase and urease activity are not detectable.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production and indole production are negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 42°C but not at 5°C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25-30°C.</s><s>Highly radiation-resistant with D<sub>10</sub> in sodium phosphate buffer of 3.45 kGy and on minced pork of 5.05 kGy.</s><s><i>meso</i>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell wall murein.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are of the iso-/anteiso-methyl branched and hydroxy iso-methyl branched types.</s><s>DNA base composition is 62 mol% G+­C (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Isolated from pork chops irradiated to a dose of 1.75 kGy.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 39621<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>