<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5732_nm.4408" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4408" rank="genus">Pectinatus</organism><reference id="rid.5732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Juvonen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suihko</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Megasphaera paucivorans sp. nov., Megasphaera sueciensis sp. nov. and Pectinatus haikarae sp. nov., isolated from brewery samples, and emended description of the genus Pectinatus.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>695</fpage><lpage>702</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63699-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585679</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Pectinatus</em> Lee <em>et al.</em> 1978</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pectinatus</em> [Pec.ti.na′tus. L. part. adj. <em>pectinatus</em> combed (bacteria)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, slightly curved to helical rods, 0·4–0·9×2–50 μm or more, with rounded ends and a Gram-negative cell wall.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs or rarely in short chains.</s><s>Cells are usually motile by means of comb-like flagellation which emanates from only one side of a cell.</s><s>Cadaverine or putrescine is found in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Organisms are strictly anaerobic mesophiles with fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Glucose and fructose are mainly metabolized to acetic and propionic acids.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin and occasionally minor amounts of succinic acid are produced.</s><s>Cells do not synthesize cytochrome oxidase, desulfoviridin or indole, hydrolyse arginine or gelatin or reduce nitrate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 38–41 mol%.</s><s>The species of the genus can be separated from each other by using various genetic and phenotypic criteria.</s><s>Isolated from beer and brewing processes.</s><s>The type species is <em>Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus</em> Lee <em>et al.</em> 1978 emend. Schleifer <em>et al.</em> 1990.</s></p></content></protolog>