<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.13408_nm.6471" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6471" rank="genus">Rhodococcus</organism><reference id="rid.13408"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus cercidiphylli sp. nov., a new endophytic actinobacterium isolated from a Cercidiphyllum japonicum leaf</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>31</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>108</fpage><lpage>113</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2008.03.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18485653</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodococcus cercidiphylli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodococcus cercidiphylli</em> (cer.ci.di.phyl′li. N.L. gen. neut. n. <em>cercidiphylli</em>, of <em>Cercidiphyllum</em>, isolated from <em>Cercidiphyllum japonicum</em>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, aerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming, not acid-fast, catalase positive, oxidase negative actinobacterium that shows a rod–coccus life cycle.</s><s>Colonies on TSA plates are smooth, opaque and orange in colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–35 °C and pH 5.0–9.0.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is up to 7%.</s><s>Negative for Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole, nitrate reduction, milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolyzed, but not gelatin, urea, starch and cellulose.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>β</em>-fucosidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, d-galactose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, salicin, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-saccharose, d-trehalose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol and potassium 5-keto-gluconate as sole carbon sources, but erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, esculin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, inulin, amidon, glycogen, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-keto-gluconate are not utilized.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, and arabinose and galactose are dominant in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol and one unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub> (5.06%), C<sub>15:0</sub> (12.8%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (26.91%), C<sub>17:1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (4.21%), 10-methyl C<sub>17:0</sub> (1.84%), C<sub>18:1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (15.35%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (4.18%), 10-methyl C<sub>18:0</sub> (tuberculostearic acid) (9.22%), C<sub>19:0</sub> (2.33%), iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>2-OH/C<sub>16:1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (8.67%) and C<sub>19:1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>/C<sub>19:1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> (6.01%).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67.2 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, YIM 65003<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207160<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45141<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface sterilized leaf sample of <em>C. japonicum</em> collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>