<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3825_nm.5783" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5783" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5783" rank="species">Actinomyces gerencseriae</organism><reference id="rid.3825"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces georgiae sp. nov., Actinomyces gerencseriae sp. nov., designation of two genospecies of Actinomyces naeslundii, and inclusion of A. naeslundii serotypes II and III and Actinomyces viscosus serotype II in A. naeslundii genospecies 2</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>273</fpage><lpage>286</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-273</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397195</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces gerencseriae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces gerencseriae</i> (ge.ren.cse'ri.ae. N. L. gen. n. <i>gerencseriae</i>, of Gerencser, named in honor of Mary Ann Gerencser, an authority on Actinomyces species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Formerly, this taxon was called <i>A. israelii</i> serotype II, but genetically it is unrelated to the type strain of <i>A. israelii</i>.</s><s>The DNAs of two strains of <i>A. gerencseriae</i> that were tested, strains VPI 12594 (= ATCC 23860<sup>T</sup>) and VPI D140D-18, have reassociation values of 82%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on a study of 22 strains that reacted with the <i>A. israelii</i> serotype II antisera and not with the antiserum of any of the other serotypes tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain and 12% of the other strains tested are obligately anaerobic.</s><s>The strains that grow on the surfaces of blood agar plates incubated in air enriched to 10% with CO<sub>2</sub> produce scant to moderately good growth.</s><s>After incubation for 48 h, surface colonies of the type strain cultured anaerobically on blood agar plates are 0.2 mm in diameter, circular, peaked to pulvinate, lumpy, opaque, and white.</s><s>Colonies of other strains are 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter (range, 0.2 to 2.0 mm), slightly irregular to circular, usually opaque (smaller colonies are transparent to translucent), lumpy (90%), and white (87%) or buff (13%).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from 24-h peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth cultures are gram-positive, nonmotile, nonsporing, and usually filamentous with swellings in the cells.</s><s>Branching cells are seen in some cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in prereduced anaerobically sterilized broth is crumby (44%), stringy (22%), flaky (22%), or grainy (11%) and usually without turbidity (89%).</s><s>Growth in peptone-yeast extract medium is moderate to good; excellent growth occurs in medium containing a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The pH of cultures in peptone-yeast extract basal medium inoculated under CO<sub>2</sub> is 6.13 (range, 5.7 to 6.6), and the pH of cultures in peptone-yeast extract medium inoculated aerobically is 7.0 (range, 6.6 to 7.5).</s><s>The pH in peptone-yeast extract-glucose-Tween 80 medium incubated for 3 to 5 days is 4.7 (range, 4.3 to 5.3).</s><s>The acid products (in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture) of peptone-yeast extract-glucose-Tween 80 cultures are as follows: lactic acid, 2.1 (range, 0.3 to 4.4); succinic acid, 1.0 (range, 0.2 to 3.0); formic acid, 0.7 (range, 0.2 to 2.0); and acetic acid, 0.6 (range, 0.1 to 1.8).</s><s>Pyruvate accumulates in about 20% of the cultures (average, 0.1 meq/100 ml of culture; range, 0.1 to 0.8 meq/100 ml in those cultures that are positive).</s><s>Similar ratios of products are obtained under anaerobic or restoppered inoculation conditions.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Addition of Tween 80 to broth medium increases the growth of 25% of the cultures and does not affect the growth of 75%.</s><s>No strain produces lecithinase or lipase on egg yolk agar or urease (urease broth method) (13).</s><s>Glycerol is not fermented by any of the 16 strains tested.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 16:O and 18:l <i>cis</i>-9.</s><s>Additional characteristics of the species are shown in Tables 3 and 4.</s><s>Differential characteristics are shown in Table 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is distinct from <i>A. israelii</i> serotype I as determined by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis banding patterns (23), serological reactions, and the inability of strains of <i>A. gerencseriae</i> to ferment L-arabinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most (89%) of the strains of <i>A. israelii</i> serotype I ferment arabinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CDC W838 (= VPI 12594 = ATCC 23860), which was isolated from a human parotid abscess.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70 to 71 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human gingival crevices, mandibular abscesses, cervicofacial actinomycosis patients, retroperitoneal abscesses, hand abscesses, and various other clinical specimens. <i>A. gerencseriae</i> accounts for 1.2% of the human healthy periodontal flora and occurs in 14% of the samples examined (Table 6).</s></p></content></protolog>