<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4333_nm.5366" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5366" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5366" rank="species">Lactobacillus fornicalis</organism><reference id="rid.4333"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Silvester</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus fornicalis sp. nov., isolated from the posterior fornix of the human vagina.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1253</fpage><lpage>1258</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843070</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus fornicalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus fornicalis</i>(for.nic.a'lis. L. gen. n. <i>fornicalis</i> of the posterior fornix)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive rods.</s><s>Non-motile, non-sporulating, catalase-negative and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on MRS agar are round, smooth, white and approximately 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 20 and 40 °C on MRS agar, with the optimum temperature between 35 and 37 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, but grows well on the surface of MRS agar when not incubated under microaerophilic conditions.</s><s>Obligately homofermentative, with no gas production from glucose or gluconate. d(-)- and l-lactic acid are produced from glucose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer-negative.</s><s>Indole is not formed and nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Polysaccharides are not produced from sucrose. <i>Lactobacillus fornicalis</i> is distinguished from <i>L. johnsonii</i>, <i>L. acidophilus</i>, <i>L. gallinarum</i>, <i>L. crispatus</i>, <i>L. gasseri</i> and <i>L. jensenii</i> on the basis of a few carbohydrate fermentation reactions (Table 2).</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, melezitose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Arabinose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, starch and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>The G­+C content of the type strain is 37 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from the posterior fornix fluid of the human vagina.</s><s>The type strain is TV 1018<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13171<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 700934<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>