<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4663_nm.5596" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5596" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5596" rank="species">Weissella hellenica</organism><reference id="rid.4663"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Samelis</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Metaxopoulos</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallbanks</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on some Leuconostoc-like organisms from fermented sausages: description of a new genus Weissella for the Leuconostoc paramesenteroides group of species.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>75</volume><fpage>595</fpage><lpage>603</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8294308</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Weissella hellenica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Weissella hellenica</i> (Gr. adj. <i>Hellenikos</i>, Greek; N.L. fem. adj. <i>hellenica</i>, Greece, from where the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporeforming, spherical but sometimes lenticular cells usually occurring in pairs or short chains, with a tendency to form clusters.</s><s>Growth in MRS broth is slow with cells tending to precipitate.</s><s>Colonies are small, often pin-point, smooth, round and greyish white.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>All strains grow at 10°C and 4°C (delayed).</s><s>Hetero-fermentative but gas production is relatively poor.</s><s>All strains produce more than 98% D(-)-lactate.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Arginine is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Growth occurs in 8% NaCl, but not in 10% NaCl or on acetate agar (pH 5.6).</s><s>All strains fail to acidify <i>Lactobacillus</i> broth below pH 44-50.</s><s>Slime is not produced from sucrose.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test negative.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide is produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, glucose, fructose, mannose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, Nacetyl- glucosamine, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, D-arabitol and gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, ribose, xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, fucose, L-arabitol, 2-ceto-gluconate and 5-ceto-gluconate.</s><s>A very weak and delayed reaction with galactose, D-turanose and melibiose may be observed.</s><s>The cell wall murein is type Lys-L-Ala-L-Ser(L-Ala).</s><s>The DNA base compositions of strains LV346 and LV338 were 39-4 and 40.0 mol% G + C (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) respectively.</s><s>The type strain is NCFB 2973 ( = LV346).</s><s>Isolated from fermented sausages.</s></p></content></protolog>