<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9253_nm.14527" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14527" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14527" rank="species">Actinoallomurus iriomotensis</organism><reference id="rid.9253"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishida</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nozawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Otoguro</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Actinomadura spadix Nonomura and Ohara 1971 to Actinoallomurus spadix gen. nov., comb. nov., and description of Actinoallomurus amamiensis sp. nov., Actinoallomurus caesius sp. nov., Actinoallomurus coprocola sp. nov., Actinoallomurus fulvus sp. nov., Actinoallomurus iriomotensis sp. nov., Actinoallomurus luridus sp. nov., Actinoallomurus purpureus sp. nov. and Actinoallomurus yoronensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1867</fpage><lpage>1874</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006858-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567582</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinoallomurus iriomotensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinoallomurus iriomotensis</em> (i′ri.o.mo.ten′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>iriomotensis</em> pertaining to Iriomote Island, Japan, where the organism was originally isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colour of the aerial mycelium is white.</s><s>The tips of the aerial mycelium divide into oval to rod-shaped, irregular-sized spores (0.5–0.7×0.6–1.2 μm) at maturity.</s><s>The mass colour of the substrate mycelium is yellow to orange.</s><s>Spore chains form compact hooks or spirals.</s><s>Spores are wrinkled to smooth.</s><s>The substrate mycelium is long, well-developed and branched.</s><s>Grows at 20–37 °C, at pH 5.0–6.0 and at up to 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Glycerol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and l-fucose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Tests for aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and catalase, pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are positive.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the three known strains is 71–73 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TT02-47<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 103685<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 19539<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from meadow soil on Iriomote Island, Okinawa, Japan.</s><s>Strains TT99-68 (=NBRC 103681) and TT02-22 (=NBRC 103684), isolated from soil on the same island, are also strains of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>