<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.649_nm.5324" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5324" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5324" rank="species">Lactobacillus acetotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.649"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Entani</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Masai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus acetotolerans, a New Species from Fermented Vinegar Broth</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>544</fpage><lpage>549</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-4-544</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus acetotolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus acetotolerans</i> (a. ce. to. tole. rans L. n. <i>acetum</i> vinegar; L. pres. part. <i>tolerans</i> tolerating, enduring; M. L. part, adj. <i>acetotolerans</i> vinegar tolerating.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, nonsporeforming rods (generally 0.4 to 0.5 by 1.1 to 3.4 μm) that occur singly, in pairs, or occasionally in short chains.</s><s>The colonies are 0.3 to 1.5 mm in diameter, circular to irregular, convex, opaque, yellowish white, rough, and undulate when grown at 30°C for 14 days on Briggs agar (pH 5.0).</s><s>Growth is generally observed at pH 3.3 to 6.6 and at 23 to 40°C.</s><s>Resistant to 4 to 5% and 9 to 11% of acetic acid at pH 3.5 and 5.0, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic and produces DL-lactic acid homofermentatively , but catalase and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or produce hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>No gas is produced from D-glucose or D-gluconate.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed; arginine and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Milk is not curdled.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, trehalose, esculin, and salicin but not from D-gluconate, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, D-galactose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, melezitose, starch, or D-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid production from D-ribose, maltose, cellobiose, and D-mannitol varies with the strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Riboflavin, pantothenic acid, folic acid, uracil, and Tween 80 are required for growth, but thiamine, p-aminobenzoic acid, biotin, adenine, guanine, xanthine, mevalonic acid, acetic acid, and ethanol are not required.</s><s>Some strains require pyridoxal, nicotinic acid, vitamin B<sub>12</sub>, and peptides.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan is of the Lys-Asp type, and DNA base composition is 35.3 to 36.5 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat of the species is fermented vinegar broth.</s><s>The type strain is NBI 3014 (=JCM 3825).</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biovars of <i>L. acetotolerans</i>.</s><s>Biovars I and II of L. acetotoleruns correspond to groups I and II, respectively, of the isolates.</s><s>Strains of biovar I produce acid from D-mannitol but not from cellobiose.</s><s>In contrast, strains of biovar II produce acid from cellobiose but not from D-mannitol.</s><s>Strains of biovar II are more fastidious than those of biovar I.</s><s>Only the strains of biovar II require nicotinic acid, vitamin B<sub>12</sub>, and peptides in addition to the common growth factors.</s></p></content></protolog>