<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9873_nm.5636" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5636" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5636" rank="species">Streptococcus ferus</organism><reference id="rid.9873"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaneechoutte</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Streptococcus ferus
isolated from pigs and rats</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>143</fpage><lpage>146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02246-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656166</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Streptococcus ferus</em> (<em>ex</em> Coykendall 1977) Coykendall 1983</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, relatively small, lanceolate coccobacilli that occur singly or in pairs or short chains.</s><s>They are non-sporulating and catalase-negative.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small, dry, white and adhering, pitting and corroding the agar surface.</s><s>Growth is slightly enhanced in the presence of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub> and is strongly inhibited at 25 °C and to a lesser extent, at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth is equally good at 42 and 37 °C.</s><s>Cells precipitate in brain/heart infusion broth and strains are unable to grow in the presence of 6·5 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth on Edwards' medium occurs but no browning or blackening of the medium is observed.</s><s>On Slanetz–Bartley agar (Oxoid), containing sodium azide, isolates grow well and form white colonies.</s><s>They are resistant to bile, as tested by inoculating organisms onto aesculin/bile agar (Difco).</s><s>No Lancefield carbohydrate antigens (Streptococcal grouping kit, Oxoid) are detected.</s><s>Positive for amylase production, as tested by spot inoculation onto Columbia agar without added blood and flooding the plates with Gram's iodine after overnight incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced (API 50 CH, bioMérieux) from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, cellobiose, d-fructose, galactose, d-glucose, glycogen, β-gentiobiose, lactose, d-mannose, maltose, maltotriose, sucrose, salicin, starch and trehalose.</s><s>Variable acidification of d-tagatose, arbutin, inulin, mannitol, melibiose, d-raffinose and sorbitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, d- or l-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gluconate, glycerol, inositol, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, d-lyxose, melezitose, methyl β-glycoside, methyl α-d-mannoside, methyl α-d-glycoside, rhamnose, ribose, l-sorbose, d-turanose, xylitol or d- or l-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>S. ferus</em> strains are positive in tests (API 20 STREP, bioMérieux; BBL Crystal Gram-positive ID kits, Becton Dickinson) for aesculin, leucine arylamidase, enzymic hydrolysis of 4-methylumbelliferyl (4MU) β-d-glucoside, l-valine 7-amido-4-methylcoumarin (AMC), l-phenylalanine AMC, 4MU α-d-glucoside, l-tryptophan AMC, methyl α- and β-glucoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) β-d-glucoside, pNP β-d-cellobioside, proline and leucine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide, pNP phosphate and pNP α-d-maltoside.</s><s>They are usually positive in tests for acetoin, l-arginine AMC and l-isoleucine AMC and variable for alkaline phosphatase and α-galactosidase.</s><s>Negative for hippurate, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase and hydrolysis of arginine (in API 20 Strep), l-pyroglutamic acid AMC, 4MU <em>N</em>-acetyl β-d-glucosaminide, 4MU phosphate and 4MU β-d-glucuronide.</s><s>An adhesive glucan is produced from sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 43 mol% and the characteristic tDNA-PCR fingerprint is composed of fragments of 71·5, 81·5, 157, 255·4 and 262·5 bp, as determined by fluorescent capillary electrophoresis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain LMG 16520<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 33477<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a rat.</s></p></content></protolog>