<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12585_nm.21843" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21843" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21843" rank="species">Flavobacterium macrobrachii</organism><reference id="rid.12585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>T.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium macrobrachii sp. nov., isolated from a freshwater shrimp culture pond</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1402</fpage><lpage>1407</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601490</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium macrobrachii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium macrobrachii</em> (ma.cro.brach′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>macrobrachii</em> of <em>Macrobrachium</em>, a genus of freshwater shrimp, isolated from the surrounding environment of shrimp belonging to the genus <em>Macrobrachium</em>.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, aerobic, non-flagellated, non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation at 25 °C on R2A agar, cell size is 0.3–0.5×0.8–2.0.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are yellow, round, smooth and convex, have entire margins and are ~0.8–1.5 mm in diameter after 72 h of incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–30 °C (optimum 25 °C), at pH 7–8 (optimum pH 8) and in 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0 %).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase positive.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein, starch, DNA and Tweens 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for lipase and urease activities and hydrolysis of chitin, CM-cellulose and agar.</s><s>Congo red adsorption is negative and flexirubin-type pigments are not present.</s><s>In API 20 NE tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose acidification, aesculin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease and β-galactosidase activities and assimilation of all carbohydrates tested.</s><s>In API 20 E tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis but negative for hydrogen sulfide production, ONPG hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, indole production, urea hydrolysis, acetoin production, citrate and malonate utilization, glucose, mannitol, xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, arabinose, adonitol, raffinose and salicin fermentation and lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and arginine dihydrolase activities.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-B1-phosphophydrolase activities but negative for C4 esterase, C14 lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN2 microplate system: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, α-d-glucose, α-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, acetic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine and uridine.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 microplate system are not utilized.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline but resistant to sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The polar lipid profile comprises phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, phosphatidylserine and several uncharacterized polar lipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, an-8<sup>T</sup> ( = BCRC 17965<sup>T</sup> = LMG 25203<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a freshwater culture pond in the Pingtung countryside, southern Taiwan, which was used for culturing giant river shrimp.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type stain is 39.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>