<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6952_nm.2115" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2115" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2115" rank="species">Rheinheimera baltica</organism><reference id="rid.6952"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brettar</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Höfle</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rheinheimera baltica gen. nov., sp. nov., a blue-coloured bacterium isolated from the central Baltic Sea.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1851</fpage><lpage>1857</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02151-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361297</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rheinheimera baltica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rheinheimera baltica</i> (bal'ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <i>baltica</i> from the Baltic Sea, referring to the source of the type strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex, entire and opaque with a blue colour.</s><s>Colony colour ranges from intense dark blue to light blue.</s><s>Colonies can be stained entirely or only in the centre of the colony.</s><s>Cells are variable in shape, ranging from rod-shaped to coccoid, and size (width 0.5-1.5 μm, length 0.9-2.5 μm).</s><s>They occur typically as single cells with a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Strains are not halotolerant (no growth at &#x003E;6% NaCl); NaCl stimulates growth, but is not required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth was observed at 1% NaCl.</s><s>Growth temperature ranges from 4 to 30°C, with an optimum at 20-25°C.</s><s>Aerobic and chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Sugars such as glucose are not metabolized with the production of acid.</s><s>No growth occurs under anoxic conditions, even in the presence of electron acceptors such as TMAO or thiosulphate.</s><s>Strains are able to use a wide spectrum of carbohydrates such as D-glucose, N-acetyl glucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, starch, glycogen and β-gentiobiose.</s><s>Strains show good assimilation of glucose, N-acetyl glucosamine and maltose.</s><s>Strains show a broad spectrum of enzymic activities such as β-glucosidase, protease, aminopeptidase, phosphatase (alkaline), leucine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Starch, gelatin, Tween 80 and lecithin are hydrolysed.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 47.8-48.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain OSBAC1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14885<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21511<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain OSBAC5 has been deposited as DSM 14891.</s></p></content></protolog>