<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.216_nm.1734" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1734" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1734" rank="species">Alcaligenes piechaudii</organism><reference id="rid.216"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kiredjian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guilvout</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alcaligenes piechaudii, a new species of the human clinical specimens and the environment.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>282</fpage><lpage>287</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alcaligenes piechaudii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alcaligenes piechaudii</i> (pie.chau'di.i M.L. gen. n. <i>piechaudii</i> from Piechaud, to honor M. Piechaud, a bacteriologist at the Institut Pasteur, Paris, France)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The seven strains which we studied were isolated from different sources (Table 1) and are strictly aerobic, gram-negative, uniformly staining, straight rods which are 0.5 to 1 μm in diameter and 1.0 to 1.5 μm long and have parallel sides and rounded ends; the cells occur singly and are nonsporulating and noncapsulated.</s><s>The cells are motile in hanging-drop preparations after overnight growth in nutrient broth incubated at either 37°C or room temperature (18 to 22°C) by means of two to eight peritrichous flagella, which have one or two wavelengths (Fig. 2).</s><s>At the optimum temperature (28 to 30°C) they produce visible growth within 24 h.</s><s>Liquid cultures (in nutrient broth medium) are uniformly turbid; cultures on Trypticase soy agar produce small smooth colonies (diameter, 0.2 mm).</s><s>Colonies are 1 mm in diameter after 48 h of incubation; no pigment or odor is produced.</s><s>Circular, smooth, entire colonies develop on nutrient agar after incubation for 24 h; colonies are nonhemolytic on 5% (vol/vol) horse blood agar.</s><s>The organisms are not fluorescent on King medium B and do not produce a brown diffusible melaninlike pigment on tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A total of 153 characteristics are shared by all strains (either all positive or all negative), and there are 18 characteristics in which one or more of the strains differ (Table 4).</s><s>Strains CIP 60.75<sup>T</sup> and CIP 55774 are the least typical strains; these strains differ from the other six strains in five and two biochemical characteristics, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at room temperature and 37°C but not at 5 or 42°C (optimal growth temperature, 28 to 30°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows without NaCl in peptone-water medium and at a maximum NaCl concentration of 7% (wt/vol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alkaline reaction in glucose oxidation-fermentation medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes tributyrin and tyrosine but not gelatin (as determined by both stab liquefaction and plate methods), Tween 20, or Tween 80.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not digest casein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce extracellular deoxyribonuclease or opalescence on lecithovitellin agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reduces nitrate but not nitrite; no anaerobic respiration in the presence of nitrate or nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridinep hosphate (vibriostatic agent 0/129).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce indole or urease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces hydrogen sulfide, as determined by the lead acetate paper method but not as determined by the triplesugar-iron agar method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not reduce thiosulfate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows on β-hydroxybutyrate (with production of lipid inclusion granules), on cetrimide, and on MacConkey agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not hydrolyze esculin or starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Producer alkali on Christensen citrate (as determined by the NCTC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tolerates KCN at a concentration of 0.0075%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilizes citrate (Simmons medium) as determined by the IP method but not as determined by the NCTC method; does not utilize malonate (as determined by the NCTC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oxidizes gluconate as determined by the IP method but not as determined by the NCTC method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce arginine desimidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, or ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce 3-ketolactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not reduce selenite and does not deaminate histidine, leucine, phenylalanine, or tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce β-D-galactosidase (as determined by the <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside test) or phosphatase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In minimal synthetic medium assimilates <i>n</i>-valerate, isovalerate, D-gluconate, mesaconate, and itaconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not assimilate carbohydrates in minimal synthetic medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from ethanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce acid in ammonium salt medium under aerobic conditions from D-glucose, adonitol, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dulcitol, D-fructose, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce acid from 10% (wt/vol) D-glucose or 10% (wt/vol) lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not produce acid or gas from D-glucose in peptone-water medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes the following substrates (determined by using API ZYM galleries): L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, glycyl-pnaphthylamide, L-aspartyl-β-naphthylamide , L-arginyl-β-naphthylamide, L-alanyl-β-naphthylamide, and L-leucylglycyl-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not hydrolyze the following substrates (determined by using API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl phosphate (at pH 8.5), 2-naphthyl caprylate, 2-naphthyl myristate, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide, L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide, N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphodiamide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronic acid, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 6- bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, 6-bromo-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside, α-D-galactopyranoside, β-D-galactopyranoside, β-D-galactopyranoside-6-phosphate, α-L-arabinofuranoside, α-D-glucopyranoside, β-D-glucopyranoside, β-D-galacturonide, β-D-glucuronide, α-maltoside, β-maltoside, N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminide, N-acetyl- β-D-glucosaminide, α-L-fucopyranoside, β-D-fucopyranoside, β-L-fucopyranoside, β-D-lactoside, α-DL-mannopyranoside, β-D-mannopyranoside , α-D-xylopyranoside, β-D-xylopyranoside, L-tyrosyl-β-naphthylamide, L-phenylalanyl-β-naphthylamide, L-hydroxyprolyl-β-naphthylamide, L-histidyl-β-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-L-leucyl-β-naphthylamide, S-benzyl-L-cysteyl-β-naphthylamide, glycyl-L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide, N-carbobenzoxy-L-arginine-4-methoxy-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride, L-isoleucyl-β-naphthylamide, L-prolyl-β-naphthylamide hydrochloride, L-threonyl-β-naphthylamide, L-tryptophyl-β-naphthylamide, and N-carbobenzoxy-glycyl-glycyl-L-arginine-β-naphthylamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although strains of <i>Alcaligenes piechaudii</i> have been recovered mainly from human clinical material, few clinical details are available, so the clinical significance of the new species has not been determined yet.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs of the seven strains included in this study are between 64 and 65 mol% (Table 2), and the G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 65 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CIP 60.75.</s><s>Although phenotypically the least typical strain, strain CIP 60.75 is designated the type strain for historical reasons, as it was the first strain to be recognized as representing a new species (5, 9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>With regard to rRNA cistrons, we found (Table 3) that at the supraspecific level <i>Alcaligenes piechaudii</i> is more closely related to <i>Alcaligenes xylosoxidans</i> subsp. <i>xylosoxidans</i> (synonym, <i>Achromobacter xylosoxidans</i>) and <i>Alcaligenes xylosoxidans</i> subsp. <i>denitrificans</i> (synonym, <i>Alcaligenes denitrificans</i>) than to <i>Alcaligenes faecalis</i>.</s><s>The DNA-DNA hybridization data also show the same trend (Table 2).</s><s>Characteristics that can be used for differentiating the new species from the other <i>Alcaligenes</i> taxa (7) are shown in Table 5.</s></p></content></protolog>