<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6301_nm.9976" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9976" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9976" rank="species">Ethanoligenens harbinense</organism><reference id="rid.6301"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xing</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ethanoligenens harbinense gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from molasses wastewater.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>755</fpage><lpage>760</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63926-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16585689</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ethanoligenens harbinense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ethanoligenens harbinense</em> (har.bin′en.se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>harbinense</em> from Harbin, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>General morphological, chemotaxonomic and growth characteristics are as described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0·4–0·8×1·5–8·0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on PYG agar are milk-white, circular, opaque, slightly concave with an obvious ring margin, reaching 1·5–3·0 mm in diameter after cultivation at 35 °C for 48 h.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 35 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 3·5–9·0, with optimum growth at pH 4·5–5·0.</s><s>Acid is produced from a few sugars, including d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, cellobiose, d-maltose, sucrose, raffinose, ribose, trehalose, d-lactose, d-turanose, mannose, melibiose and salicin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, inulin, sorbose, rhamnose, glycogen, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, sorbitol, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, arabitol or fucose.</s><s>No acid is produced from the following compounds: methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, pyruvate, fumarate, malate, succinate, malonic acid, hippurate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid or xylan.</s><s>Curdles milk.</s><s>Urease is produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lecithinase and lipase are not produced.</s><s>Positive for esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Positive for indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Does not use sulfate or nitrate as electron acceptor.</s><s>No H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from peptone or thiosulfate.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (44·18 %), iso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (26·67 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5·25 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (4·98 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YUAN-3<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12961<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.5033<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the anaerobic sludge of molasses wastewater in a CSTR.</s></p></content></protolog>