<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12833_nm.22635" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22635" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22635" rank="species">Halomonas alkaliantarctica</organism><reference id="rid.12833"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Poli</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Esposito</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Orlando</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lama</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giordano</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Appolonia</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nicolaus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gambacorta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas alkaliantarctica sp. nov., isolated from saline lake Cape Russell in Antarctica, an alkalophilic moderately halophilic, exopolysaccharide-producing bacterium</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>30</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>38</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2006.03.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16621401</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>H. alkaliantarctica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>H. alkaliantarctica</em> (al.ka.li.an.tarc’ti.ca. Arabic word alkali, al-qaliy) the ashes of saltwort; L. adj. antarcticus -a -um, southern, Antarctic; N.L. fem. adj. alkaliantarctica; related to the ability to grow at pH alkaline and isolated from Antarctica).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alkalitolerant and halotolerant microorganism of domain <em>Bacteria</em>.</s><s>Cells are rod (1.35 μm).</s><s>They are Gram-negative, aerobic and lack endospores.</s><s>Colonies on medium A were creamy, smooth and circular.</s><s>It is mesophilic exhibiting optimum growth temperature of 30 °C, but is able to grow between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>It presents an optimum pH at 9.0, a pH range of 7.4–9.6 and it tolerates up to 22.2% NaCl.</s><s>It is able to grow on sucrose, glucose, galactose, ribose, fructose, trehalose, sodium acetate, maltose, cellobiose, lactic acid, glycerol when the medium was supplemented with 50 μg/l of thiamine.</s><s>It is oxidase, nitrate reduction and indole production positive, but negative with respect to catalase, casein, starch and gelatine hydrolysis, nitrite reduction.</s><s>The strain was able to synthetise <em>α</em>-glucosidase which had a maximum activity at 35 °C and pH 9.0.</s><s>Q9 is the only ubiquinone and the predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol (PG), diphosphatidylglycerol (DPG) and phosphatidylethanolamine (PEA). <em>n</em>C16:0, branched C16:0, C16:1 and C18:1 are the main cellular fatty acids, minor components are <em>n</em>C14:0, branched C15:0 and C18:0.</s><s>Strain CRSS accumulates glycine–betaine as major component, ectoine and glutamate as minor osmoprotectants.</s><s>The mol% G+C content of DNA is 55.0 mol%, and this species is phylogenetically related to <em>H. boliviensis</em>, <em>H. neptunia</em> and <em>H. variabilis</em> on the basis of 16S rDNA gene sequence.</s><s>The following antibiotics inhibited the growth of the strain CRSS: tetracycline (50), chloramphenicol (10), neomycin (30), gentamycin (10), erythromycin (30), streptomycin (25) but it grew in the presence of penicillin G (10), kanamycin (30), nystatin (1 0 0), tylosin (30), lincomycin (15), bacitracin (10), novobiocin (30), neomycin (5), cycloheximide (30), vancomycin (30), fusidic acid (10) and ampicillin (25).</s><s>CRSS is able to produce EPS but not PHB. <em>H. alkaliantarcti</em>ca was isolated from salt in the saline lake Cape Russell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain CRSS has been deposited in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen Collection, Braunschweig, Germany (DSM 15686<sup>T</sup>) and in American Type Culture Collection, University Boulevard, Manassas, USA (ATCC BAA-848<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of CRSS is <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=search&#x0026;db=nucleotide&#x0026;doptcmdl=genbank&#x0026;term=AJ564880[accn]" target="externObjLink">AJ564880</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>