<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1037_nm.7980" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7980" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7980" rank="species">Bacteroides pyogenes</organism><reference id="rid.1037"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides pyogenes sp. nov., Bacteroides suis sp. nov., and Bacteroides helcogenes sp. nov., new species from absesses and feces of pigs</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>396</fpage><lpage>407</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides pyogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides pyogenes</i> (py.o'ge.nes. Gr. n. <i>pyum</i> pus; Gr. v. <i>gennaio</i> produce; M.L. adj. <i>pyogenes</i> pus-producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmented, non-spore forming rods.</s><s>Gram strains of single colonies from agar plates show predominantly short, Gram-negative rods, single or, occasionally, in pairs with longer rods (0.3 to 0.5 μm by 0.5 to 5.0 μm).</s><s>After 2 days of incubation surface colonies to opaque, cream to light grey, shiny and smooth.</s><s>Usually hemolysis on blood agar plates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth on the surface of blood agar plates incubated in a candle-extinction jar or in an aerobic atmosphere.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth cultures are moderately turbid, sometimes with a slight, smooth sediment.</s><s>Growth somewhat enhanced in broth with a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>Best growth at 37°C; not growth at 15°C.</s><s>The pH of PYG medium is decreased after good growth to about 5.0.</s><s>Strains do not grow well in PYFG-20% bile broths.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from glucose, ribose, mannose, fructose, galactose, lactose, and glycerol.</s><s>Some strains ferment sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, inulin, sorbitol, salicin, and amygdalin.</s><s>Arabinose, xylose, gum arabic and xylan are not fermented.</s><s>Indole is not produced, nitrate is not reduced, gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Some strains hydrolyze acsculin and starch.</s><s>Major amounts of succinic and acetic acids are produced in PYFG broth together with minor amounts of propionic and isobutyric acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All the strains are susceptible to penicillin (10 μg/ml).</s><s>Seventy percent of the strains are susceptible to cephalothin (10 μg/ml), colistin (10 μg/ml) and erythromycin (60 μg/ml).</s><s>The strains of <i>B. pyogenes</i> are divided into four subgroups (subgroups a, b, c, and d) on the basis of fermentation patterns and esculin and starch hydrolysis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA is 46.1-47.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: swine abscess and feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 20611 ( = P39-88), isolated from abscess in pig.</s></p></content></protolog>