<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8354_nm.13217" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13217" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13217" rank="species">Arcicella rosea</organism><reference id="rid.8354"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arcicella rosea sp. nov., isolated from tap water.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>341</fpage><lpage>344</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002675-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196775</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arcicella rosea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arcicella rosea</em> (ro′se.a. L. fem. adj. <em>rosea</em> rose-coloured, rosy).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth is observed after 48 h on R2A agar and K7 agar; no growth occurs on nutrient agar or tryptic soy agar at 15–36 °C.</s><s>Colonies on K7 agar are smooth, pale pinkish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges and become mucoid with age of the culture.</s><s>Unable to grow at 5 or 42 °C.</s><s>The polyamine pattern shows the characteristic major compound spermidine.</s><s>The quinone system comprises menaquinone MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown aminophospholipid, moderate amounts of three unknown polar lipids, one aminophospholipid and one aminolipid and minor to trace amounts of two glycolipids, three polar lipids and five aminolipids.</s><s>After two-dimensional TLC, a single red spot is visible that exhibits strongly hydrophobic chromatographic behaviour.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>,<em>t</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 2-OH iso, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources (positive after prolonged incubation for 14 days, according to the method of Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991): d-glucose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose and acetate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: d-gluconate, propionate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, mesaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, suberate, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s><em>bis</em>-<em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) phosphate, <em>bis</em>-pNP phenylphosphonate and <em>bis</em>-pNP phosphorylcholine are hydrolysed on the basis of the method described by Kämpfer <em>et al.</em> (1991).</s><s>The following compounds are not hydrolysed: pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-aniline <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA and l-proline pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is TW5<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 55942<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7523<sup>T</sup>), isolated from tap water.</s></p></content></protolog>