<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12661_nm.22393" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22393" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22393" rank="species">Tessaracoccus oleiagri</organism><reference id="rid.12661"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinarimonas ramus sp. nov. and Tessaracoccus oleiagri sp. nov., isolated from a crude oil-contaminated saline soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1767</fpage><lpage>1775</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025932-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20802058</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tessaracoccus oleiagri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tessaracoccus oleiagri</em> (o.le.i.ag′ri. L. n. <em>oleum</em> <em>-i</em> oil; L. n. <em>ager</em> -<em>gri</em> productive land, a field; N.L. gen. n. <em>oleiagri</em> of an oilfield, the place where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive staining, facultatively anaerobic, non-endospore-forming, acid-fast, oval to rod-shaped (0.48×0.5–1.0 µm) without flagella.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular convex and bright yellow on ASW agar at 30 °C for 7 days.</s><s>Good growth occurs on Luria–Bertani medium and tryptic soy agar.</s><s>The optimum growth conditions are pH 7.0, 28 °C and 4 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase and <em>α-</em>glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for β-galactosidase, lipase (C14), α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, hydrolysis of cellulose and for the assimilation of d-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosamine, maltose, caprate, adipate, malate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Utilizes sodium citrate, xylose, d-ribose, rhamnose, raffinose, dulcitol, α-lactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, salicin, inulin, succinate, benzoate, d-mannitol, formate, sorbitol, d-galactose, trehalose and inositol, but not l-arabinose as sole carbon source.</s><s>Does not utilize alanine, l-proline, glycine, histidine, tryptophan, l-aspartate, phenylalanine or arginine as sole nitrogen source.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin (10 µg), polymyxin B (300 IU) and neomycin (30 µg).</s><s>Sensitive to streptomycin (300 µg), ceftazidime (30 µg), amoxicillin (10 µg), rifampicin (5 µg), midecamycin (15 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), ciprofloxacin (5 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), penicillin G (10 IU), novobiocin (5 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), cefotaxime (30 µg) and sulfamethoxazole (300 µg).</s><s>Other physiological and biochemical properties are given in Table 2.</s><s>ll-DAP is the diagnostic diamino acid in cell wall.</s><s>The sugars in whole-cell hydrolysates of the three isolates are rhamnose, ribose, mannose, glucose and galactose.</s><s>MK-9 (H<sub>4</sub>) is the only menaquinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are DPG, PG, PIM, PI and PL.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SL014B-20A1<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22955<sup>T</sup> = CGMCC 1.9159<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a crude oil-polluted saline soil from Shengli Oilfield, eastern China.</s><s>Strains SL014B-76A1 and SL014B-79A are additional strains.</s><s>The G+C contents of the genomic DNA of all three strains are 65.65–67.17 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>