<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4921" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4921" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4921" rank="species">Bacillus horikoshii</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus horikoshii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus horikoshii</i> (ho.ri.ko'shi.i, ML gen. n. <i>horikoshii</i> of Horikoshi; named after the Japanese microbiologist Koki Horikoshi, who has made fundamental contributions to the study of alkaliphilic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is taken from this study based on strains of DNA hybridization group 8b.</s><s>Colonies are small, circular with an entire margin, shiny surface and a cream-white colour.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.6-0.7 x 2.0-4·0 μm) with ellipsoidal spores (0.5-0.7 x 0.7-1.2 μm) located subterminally in a sporangium which may be slightly swollen.</s><s>Strains of this species hydrolyse casein, hippurate, gelatin, pullulan and starch.</s><s>Three of the four strains hydrolyse Tween 40 and 60.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 7.0, with an optimum at about pH 8,0.</s><s>Strains grow between 10 and 40°C.</s><s>Salt tolerance is moderate, with a maximum at 8-9 % NaCl.</s><s>Strains do not hydrolyse MUG or Tween 20, do not deaminate phenylalanine and do not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>No growth is observed on ribose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, galactose, rhamnose, sorbitol, lactose, melibiose, melizitose, D-raffinose or D-tagatose.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 41.1 and 42.0 mol%.</s><s>G + C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil samples.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-121 (= DSM 8719).</s></p></content></protolog>