<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1188_nm.9477" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9477" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9477" rank="species">Enterobacter radicincitans</organism><reference id="rid.1188"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruppel</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Remus</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter radicincitans sp. nov., a plant growth promoting species of the family Enterobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>28</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>213</fpage><lpage>221</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2004.12.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15900968</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterobacter radicincitans</em> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>E. radicincitans</em> (ra.di.ćin.ci.tans, L. n. radix -icis, a root; L. part. adj. incitans, promoting the growth; N.L masc. or fem. or neut. Substantive, radicincitans, a rod promoting root growth of plants).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mesophilic, chemoorganotrophic, facultatively anaerobic, but anaerobic growth is weak.</s><s>Acid is produced from various sugars. <em>E. radicincitans</em> forms rod-shaped cells 0.8–1.2 μm in length and 1.0–1.6 μm in width.</s><s>Gram stain is negative.</s><s>Cells are motile.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are beige pigmented, 2–3 mm in diameter and mucoid.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is about 30 °C, growth does not occur at 10 °C and below and at 45 °C and above.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase negative and catalase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain D5/23<sup>T</sup> showed a positive arginine dihydrolyse reaction and was urease, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase negative.</s><s>Esculin was positive.</s><s>Tryptophane deaminase, indole production and H<sub>2</sub>S production were negative.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test was positive after 48 h of incubation.</s><s>Citrate and malonate were positive.</s><s>Acid was produced from the following compounds: glucose, lactose (after 48 h), sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, sorbitol, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, and d-mannose.</s><s>No acid production was observed for adonitol, inositol, raffinose, methyl-d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, and d-arabitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilization of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutine, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-fructose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicine, d-trehalose, d-xylose, d-maltitol, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, acetate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-lactate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-aspartate, l-alanine, l-proline, and l-serine was positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, adonitol, <em>i</em>-inositol, putrescine, propionate, adipate, azelate, 4-aminobutyrate, dl-3 hydroxybutyrate, mesaconate, itaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, suberate, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-tryptophane, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, and phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The chromogenic substrates ONPG, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP-phosphate, l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-pNA, and l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide were hydrolyzed.</s><s>The following compounds were not hydrolyzed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNPG, pNP-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphate and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline.</s><s>The strain D5/23<sup>T</sup> shows nitrogenase activity, auxine and cytokinine production.</s><s>The plant growth promoting features have been described extensively <a href="#bib17">[17]</a>, <a href="#bib19">[19]</a> and <a href="#bib21">[21]</a>.</s><s>Strain D5/23<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany as strain DSM 16656<sup>T</sup> in the Collection Institut Pasteur CIP 108468<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The EMBL data base accession number of the partial 16S rRNA gene for strain D5/23<sup>T</sup> is AY563134.</s><s>The EMBL data base accession number of the <em>rpoB</em> sequence gene for strain D5/23<sup>T</sup> is <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=search&#x0026;db=nucleotide&#x0026;doptcmdl=genbank&#x0026;term=AJ783915[accn]" target="externObjLink">AJ783915</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>