<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2831_nm.7949" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7949" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7949" rank="species">Bacteroides endodontalis</organism><reference id="rid.2831"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Steenbergen</surname><given-names>T.J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Winkelhoff</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayrand</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grenier</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Graaff</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides endodontalis sp. nov., an asaccharolytic black-pigmented Bacteroides species from infected dental root canals</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>118</fpage><lpage>120</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-118</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides endodontalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides endodontalis</i> (en. do. don'ta. lis. Gr. prep. <i>endon</i> within; Gr. n. <i>odon</i> tooth; <i>endodontalis</i> within teeth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of <i>B. endodontalis</i> strains are obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile, gram negative, and rod shaped.</s><s>Cells grown in broth are 0.4 to 0.6 by 1.0 to 1.5 μm.</s><s>The organisms require hemin and vitamin K1 or menadione for growth.</s><s>Colonies grow slowly on blood agar plates.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation colonies are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, low convex, circular, smooth, and entire.</s><s>Dark brown or black pigmentation develops only after incubation for more than 7 days at 37°C.</s><s>When hemolyzed sheep blood is used, pigmentation develops within 3 days.</s><s>Hemolysis is visible on blood agar plates after incubation for 24 h in air.</s><s>The organisms do not ferment any of the sugars listed above.</s><s>The final pH in broth containing glucose is 6.8 to 7.2.</s><s>Acetic, propionic, butyric, isobutyric, and isovaleric acids are produced.</s><s>Phenylacetic acid is not produced.</s><s>No collagenolytic or proteolytic activity is detected, except for a positive gelatinase reaction.</s><s>API ZYM tests show no trypsin-like activity and strong acid and alkaline phosphatase and phosphoamidase activities.</s><s>The organisms do not produce hemagglutin or catalase; indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are produced.</s><s>Arginine is hydrolyzed; starch and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The protein patterns of the three strains which we studied were not identical, although similar bands were present throughout the gel.</s><s>However, the general pattern of these three strains was very different from the patterns of <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i> and <i>B. gingivalis</i> isolates (Fig. 1).</s><s>A serological analysis using an indirect fluorescence antibody staining method showed that all three isolates react poorly or not at all (reactions of 0 or 1+ with an antiserum diluted 1 in 20) with antisera directed against <i>B. gingivalis</i> or <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i>.</s><s>The homologous strains and antisera gave results of 3+ or 4+ (with an antiserum diluted 1 in 640).</s><s>These data indicate that the three strains which we studied do not share common antigens with <i>B. gingivalis</i> or <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>B. endodontalis</i> is strain HG370 (= ATCC 35406).</s></p></content></protolog>