<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2412_nm.11281" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11281" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11281" rank="species">Chitinophaga terrae</organism><reference id="rid.2412"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinophaga terrae sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1721</fpage><lpage>1724</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64964-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684244</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinophaga terrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinophaga terrae</em> (ter′rae. L. gen. n. <em>terrae</em> of the earth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile rods that are 0.3–0.5 μm in width and 0.6–0.8 μm in length after 3 days culture on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies grown on LB agar for 3 days are smooth, circular, convex and yellowish.</s><s>Grows at 15–42 °C and at pH 6.0–9.0, but grows slowly at 42 °C and pH 9.0.</s><s>Can reduce nitrate to nitrate but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Enzyme activities, substrate assimilation and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>Produces <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), protease (gelatin hydrolysis) or urease.</s><s>Assimilates l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and salicin.</s><s>Does not assimilate acetate, adipate, caprate, citrate, gluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactate, l-malate, malonate, phenylacetate, propionate, suberate, n-valerate, d-ribose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-proline, l-serine or glycogen.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH are the predominant cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 46.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KP01<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12836<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24015<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a field near Daejeon, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>