<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11906_nm.13787" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13787" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13787" rank="species">Tateyamaria omphalii</organism><reference id="rid.11906"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sass</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Köpke</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rütters</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Feuerlein</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dröge</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cypionka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engelen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tateyamaria pelophila sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic alphaproteobacterium isolated from tidal-flat sediment and emended description of Tateyamaria omphalii</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1770</fpage><lpage>1777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013524-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Tateyamaria omphalii</em> Kurahashi and Yokota 2007</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tateyamaria omphalii</em> (om.phal′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>omphalii</em> of <em>Omphalius</em>, the genus of the top shell, from which the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <em>Tateyamaria omphalii</em> is as given by Kurahashi &#x0026; Yokota (2007) with the following additions.</s><s>Growth is observed between pH 5.4 and 8.9 and at salinities from 0.2 to 6.0 %.</s><s>Substrates used aerobically are: peptone, Casamino acids, yeast extract, starch, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, dl-lactate, malonate, succinate, fumarate, dl-malate, 2-ketoglutarate, ethanol, <em>n</em>-propanol, ethylene glycol, glycerol, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-glutamate, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-valine and benzoate.</s><s>Grows anaerobically for a few transfers on complex media such as R2A or MB.</s><s>Under anoxic conditions, nitrate and TMAO can serve as electron acceptors, whereas DMSO, nitrite, sulfite, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, ferric citrate, iron hydroxide, manganese oxides, AQDS or humic acids are not reduced.</s><s>No growth is observed with chitin, laminarin, cellulose, lactose, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, dl-tartrate, formate, caproate, caprylate, crotonate, glycolate, dl-alanine, l-arginine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine, methanol, <em>n</em>-butanol, betaine, methylamine, ethanolamine, DMSO, dimethylsulfide, salicylate or nicotinate.</s><s>Elemental hydrogen, thiosulfate, sulfite, elemental sulfur and Mn<sup>2+</sup> are not oxidized.</s><s>Agar, agarose, alginate, casein, Tween 20, Tween 80, tyrosine and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Arginine deaminase, tryptophan deaminase, leucine arylaminidase, valine arylaminidase, ornithine deaminase and phosphatase are present.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, lipase and cysteine arylaminidase.</s><s>Phenylacetate is not utilized.</s><s>Produces acid from d-mannose, but not from d-fructose, cellobiose, d-xylose or trehalose.</s><s>Requires biotin and pantothenate for growth, but not <em>p</em>-aminobenzoate, folate, lipoate, nicotinate, pyridoxine, thiamine, cyanocobalamin or riboflavin.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, penicillin G and trimethoprim, but are resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MKT107<sup>T</sup> (=IAM 15108<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12333<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the gastrointestinal tract of the molluscan top shell <em>Omphalius pfeifferi pfeifferi</em> at Chiba, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>