<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12684_nm.22423" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22423" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22423" rank="species">Streptococcus rupicaprae</organism><reference id="rid.12684"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vela</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mentaberre</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marco</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velarde</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lavín</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domínguez</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernández-Garayzábal</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus rupicaprae sp. nov., isolated from a Pyrenean chamois (Rupicapra pyrenaica)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1989</fpage><lpage>1993</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026187-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851916</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus rupicaprae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus rupicaprae</em> (ru.pi.cap′rae. L. fem. n. <em>rupicapra</em> chamois; L. fem. gen. n. <em>rupicaprae</em> of a chamois).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, non-spore-forming cocci, 0.7–1 µm in diameter, occurring in pairs or chains commonly over 7–10 cells long.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small, circular and non-pigmented, 0.75–1.0 mm in diameter and α-haemolytic at 37 °C.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic, catalase-negative and non-motile.</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield group D antisera.</s><s>Cells are able to grow at 22, 30, 37 and 42 °C but do not grow at 15 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 9.6 and in the presence of 3 % NaCl but not in broth containing 4.5 or 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>With the API 50 CH and Rapid ID32 Strep kits, cells are able to produce acid from d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, melibiose, pullulan, l-arabinose, gentiobiose and methyl β-d-glucopyranoside but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inositol, dulcitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, melezitose, turanose, d-lyxose, xylitol, d-fucose, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, cyclodextrin or tagatose.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, β-galactosidase (API ZYM), β-glucuronidase (API ZYM and Rapid ID32 Strep), β-mannosidase and alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep) are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, valine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin (API ZYM), <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase (API ZYM and Rapid ID32 Strep) or pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Cells produce β-glucosidase and α-galactosidase using the Rapid ID32 Strep system.</s><s>Arginine is hydrolysed but not hippurate or urea (Rapid ID32 Strep).</s><s>Type strain (2777-2-07<sup>T</sup>) does not produce glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase (Rapid ID 32 Strep).</s><s>Acetoin is not produced (Rapid ID 32 Strep).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 2777-2-07<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7718<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 59652<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the liver of a chamois with septicaemia.</s><s>Full range of habitat is not known.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>