<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2122_nm.4079" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4079" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4079" rank="species">Caloramator proteoclasticus</organism><reference id="rid.2122"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tarlera</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muxí</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soubes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stams</surname><given-names>A.J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Caloramator proteoclasticus sp. nov., a new moderately thermophilic anaerobic proteolytic bacterium.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>651</fpage><lpage>656</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-651</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226895</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Caloramator proteoclasticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Caloramator proteoclasticus</i> (pro.te.o.clas'ti.cus. Gr. adj. <i>protos</i>, first; Gr. adj. <i>clasticus</i>, breaking, from Gr. part. perf. <i>klastos</i>, broken; M.L. masc. adj. <i>proteoclasticus</i>, protein breaking)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, straight or slightly curved rods, 2.4 to 4 μm long and 0.4 μm wide, with pointed ends.</s><s>Stains gram negative but cell wall type is atypical gram positive.</s><s>Peritrichous motility and thermoresistant spores are observed in late exponential phase in cultures grown on yeast extract and gelatin.</s><s>Lysis occurs in stationary phase in cultures grown on sugars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic and moderately thermophilic.</s><s>The minimum temperature for growth is 30°C, optimum temperature is 55°C, and the maximum temperature is 68°C; pH range for growth is 6.0 to 9.5, and optimum pH is 7.0 to 7.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Casein, gelatin, peptone, and Casamino Acids are fermented to acetate, propionate, butyrate, branched-chain fatty acids, formate, and hydrogen.</s><s>Glutamate, arginine, and histidine are fermented to acetate, hydrogen, and formate.</s><s>Alanine is produced as a reduced end product from glutamate.</s><s>Threonine and methionine are fermented to propionate, hydrogen, and formate.</s><s>Branched-chain amino acids, alanine and glycine, are degraded, with a yeast extract concentration of 1 g/liter in the medium, to branched-chain fatty acids and acetate, respectively.</s><s>A complete Stickland reaction is observed with leucine and glycine.</s><s>Growth is observed with glucose, fructose, mannose, and cellobiose.</s><s>Starch and pyruvate are also utilized.</s><s>Major end products are acetate, lactate, ethanol, formate, and hydrogen.</s><s>Ornithine, proline, acetate, H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> (80:20), formate, α-ketoglutarate, lactose, xylose, malate, xylan, and cellulose are not fermented.</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, nitrate, and fumarate are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cellular DNA G+C content is 31 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain U (= DSM 10124).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a mesophilic UASB reactor that was fermenting whey.</s></p></content></protolog>