<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1848_nm.5706" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5706" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5706" rank="species">Acetoanaerobium noterae</organism><reference id="rid.1848"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sleat</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acetoanaerobium notera gen. nov., sp. nov.: an anaerobic bacterium that forms acetate from H2 and CO2</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>10</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-1-10</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetoanaerobium noterae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetoanaerobium noterae</i> (no'ter.ae. L. adj. <i>noterae</i> pertaining to Notera; named for its source, the Notera oil exploration site in Israel)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell are straight rods that are 0.8 μm wide and 1 to 5 μm long.</s><s>Motile. with three or four peritrichous flagella (Fig. 6).</s><s>Cells stain gram negative; the cell wall is atypical and, as determined by transmission electron microscopy, is composed of two distinct layers, a darker inner layer and lighter outer layer.</s><s>Colonies are rhizoid, opaque, and granular (Fig. 7).</s><s>Young colonies are white, but older colonies are brownish and up to 2 cm in diameter after 1 month of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract, maltose, and glucose are used for heterotrophic growth.</s><s>Compounds not supporting growth include arabinose, rhamnose, ribose, xylose, fructose, galactose, cellobiose, lactose, mannose, sucrose, melezitose, trehalose, erythritol, adonitol, arabitol, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, formate, acetate, pyruvate, lactate, malate, fumarate, succinate, citrate, glutamate, methylamine, trimethylamine, and methanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract is required for growth and H<sub>2</sub> utilization.</s><s>Growth on yeast extract and H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> is biphasic, with an initial rapid growth phase independent of the presence of H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>This is followed by H<sub>2</sub>-dependent acetate production during the second slower growth phase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells produce acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, butyrate, and isovalerate (and little or no H<sub>2</sub>) during growth on yeast extract alone.</s><s>When either glucose or maltose serves as a substrate, acetate is the only fermentation product.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Growth is most rapid at 37°C and pH 7.6 (pH range, 6.6 to 8.4).</s><s>Minimum doubling times are 2.8 h for heterotrophic growth and 27 h for H<sub>2</sub>-dependent growth.</s><s>Vitamins are not required.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by erythromycin, chloramphenicol, penicillin, cephalosporin, and cycloserine at concentrations of 100 ng/liter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 37 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sediment near the Notera oil drilling site in the Hula swamp area of Galilee, Israel.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NOT-3 (= ATCC 35199).</s></p></content></protolog>