<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12672_nm.22409" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22409" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22409" rank="species">Paracoccus caeni</organism><reference id="rid.12672"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>S.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus caeni sp. nov., isolated from sludge</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1968</fpage><lpage>1972</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017897-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20851920</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paracoccus caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paracoccus caeni</em> (ca.e′ni. L. gen. neut. n. <em>caeni</em> of sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative and non-motile, 0.4–0.6 µm wide and 1.4–1.7 µm long.</s><s>After 3 days on R2A agar, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, pale yellow, circular and convex and contain PHB granules.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs on R2A agar, nutrient agar, TSA, MacConkey agar and LB agar.</s><s>In LB broth, grows at 25–30 °C (optimum 30 °C), but not at 4 or 37 °C, at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 6.5–7.0) and with 0−6 % NaCl (optimum 3–4 % NaCl).</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase (C8) and leucine arylamidase, but negative for β-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase (<em>o</em>-nitrophenyl β-galactoside and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis), α-glucosidase (starch hydrolysis), β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, protease (gelatin hydrolysis), trypsin and urease.</s><s>Acid is produced from 5-ketogluconate, d- and l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, ribose, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, l-xylose, methyl α-d-glucoside, d-adonitol (ribitol), d-arabitol, dulcitol (galactitol), erythritol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, xylitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and arbutin; acid is not produced from 2-ketogluconate, gluconate, raffinose, d-tagatose, methyl α-d-mannoside, methyl β-d-xyloside, l-arabitol, amygdalin, aesculin, inulin, salicin, glycogen or starch.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized: 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, acetate, citrate, gluconate, lactate, l-malate, phenylacetate, propionate, n-valerate, l-arabinose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, l-alanine, l-proline, malonate, l-rhamnose, sucrose, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-histidine, salicin, l-serine and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: adipate, caprate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, itaconate, suberate, l-fucose, melibiose, d-ribose and glycogen.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 7 (comprising one or more of C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω12<em>t</em>), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MJ17<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22480<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16385<sup>T</sup>  = KEMB 9004-001<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge at the Daejeon sewage disposal plant in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>