<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11714_nm.19332" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19332" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19332" rank="species">Odoribacter laneus</organism><reference id="rid.11714"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alistipes indistinctus sp. nov. and Odoribacter laneus sp. nov., common members of the human intestinal microbiota isolated from faeces</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1296</fpage><lpage>1302</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014571-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667375</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Odoribacter laneus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Odoribacter laneus</em> (la′ne.us. L. masc. adj. <em>laneus</em> woollen, soft as wool, referring to the growth appearance in liquid medium and to the cellular characteristics of the resulting fluffy precipitate after centrifugation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, pleomorphic rods (0.4–1.9×1.4–19.1 μm) that hydrolyse gelatin and are positive for indole production.</s><s>Catalase, urease and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Colonies after 4 days anaerobic incubation on GAM agar are 0.1–0.5 mm in diameter, circular, grey–beige and slightly opaque.</s><s>After 7–10 days culture on sheep blood agar, colonies are surrounded by a clear haemolytic zone and demonstrate pigmentation after &#x003E;2 weeks.</s><s>Analysis of metabolic end products by HPLC from PY and PYG broth reveals small amounts of succinic, acetic and iso-valeric acids.</s><s>Asaccharolytic.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Using the commercially available API test systems (API ZYM and rapid ID 32A), positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase, but negative for <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, cystine arylamidase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, proline arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Weak activity is detected for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 12061<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22474<sup>T</sup>=JCM 16069<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>