<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9940_nm.14917" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14917" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14917" rank="species">Rhizobium alkalisoli</organism><reference id="rid.9940"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Y.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium alkalisoli sp. nov., isolated from Caragana intermedia growing in saline-alkaline soils in the north of China</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3006</fpage><lpage>3011</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007237-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643906</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhizobium alkalisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhizobium alkalisoli</em> [al.ka.li.so′li. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> (from Arabic al-qaliy), alkali; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>alkalisoli</em> of alkaline soil, referring to the fact that the bacterium was isolated from <em>Caragana intermedia</em> grown in saline-alkali soil].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming rods, 0.3–0.5 μm wide and 1–3 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on YMA medium are circular, convex, white and opaque, with a diameter of 1–2 mm within 2–3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on YMA agar in 0–3 % NaCl (optimum, 1 %).</s><s>Growth occurs at 12–37 °C and pH 5–10 on YMA, with optimum growth at 28 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Catalase, urease and oxidase are present, but not l-phenylalaninase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and reduction of methyl blue is not observed.</s><s>Nile blue reduction is observed.</s><s>Lactic acid production, reduction of litmus and acid curd formation are produced in litmus milk tests.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse gelatin, casein, starch, DNA or Tween 80.</s><s>Indole is produced, but not H<sub>2</sub>S, and the Voges–Proskauer and methyl red reaction are negative.</s><s>Resistant to (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>): ampicillin (300), kanamycin sulfate (50), neomycin sulfate (5), streptomycin sulfate (5), bacitracin (300), erythromycin (50) and chloramphenicol (5).</s><s>Growth occurs on YMA with Bismarck brown (0.1 %), congo red (0.1 %), erythrosin B (0.1 %), neutral red (0.1 %) and sodium deoxycholate (0.1 %).</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, melezitose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, dl-malate, glucose, inositol, l-methionine, l-rhamnose, l-proline, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, raffinose, salicin, sodium citrate, d-sodium gluconate, sodium maltose, sodium pyruvate, sodium succinate, sucrose and trehalose as sole carbon sources, and (+)-l-aspartic acid, (+)-l-glutamic acid, d-glutamic acid, dl-alanine, d-threonine, glycine, hypoxanthine, l-arginine, l-cystine, l-hydroxyproline, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine and l-valine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Does not utilize adipic acid, vanillic acid, calcium gluconate, calcium malonate, d-amygdalin, melibiose, d-xylose, dextrin, dl-asparagine, dulcitol, glycine, inulin, l-arginine, l-threonine, sodium acetate, sodium formate, sodium tartrate, soluble starch, sorbose or syringic acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 65.47 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCBAU 01393<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24763<sup>T</sup>=HAMBI 3051<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from nodules of <em>Caragana intermedia</em> grown in saline-alkaline soils in Qingshuihe city, Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p></content></protolog>