<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12799_nm.22594" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22594" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22594" rank="species">Metallosphaera cuprina</organism><reference id="rid.12799"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>You</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Metallosphaera cuprina sp. nov., an acidothermophilic, metal-mobilizing archaeon</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2395</fpage><lpage>2400</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026591-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21057050</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Metallosphaera cuprina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Metallosphaera cuprina</em> (cu′pri.na. L. n. <em>cuprum</em> copper; L. suff. -<em>inus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> suffix used with the sense of belonging to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>cuprina</em> belonging to copper, describing its ability to extract copper ions from ores).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular cocci (0.9–1.0 µm), Gram-staining-negative and motile by means of flagella.</s><s>Clones on modified Allen plates supplemented with potassium tetrathionate are semi-transparent, smooth, rounded and convex with a diameter of 0.2–0.3 mm.</s><s>Clones on modified Allen plates supplemented with FeSO<sub>4</sub> are brown, circular and flat.</s><s>Growth occurs in extremely acidothermophilic conditions with growth temperatures from 55 to 75 °C (optimum 65 °C) and at pH 2.5 to 5.5 (optimum pH 3.5).</s><s>Cells grow well in modified Allen medium containing 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl and growth is inhibited by 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Aerobic, facultatively chemolithoautotrophic growth on elemental sulfur, K<sub>2</sub>S<sub>4</sub>O<sub>6</sub>, FeSO<sub>4</sub>, pyrite (or FeS) and chalcopyrite.</s><s>Chemolithoautotrophic growth is stimulated by yeast extract.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced when grown on elemental sulfur and hydrogen under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Organotrophic growth on yeast extract, beef extract, peptone, Casamino acids, l-tryptophan, d-arabinose, d-xylose and d-glucose; weak growth on sucrose, raffinose, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid and l-alanine.</s><s>The main cellular lipids are calditoglycerocaldarchaeol (CGTE) and caldarchaeol (DGTE).</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence similarity between <em>M. cuprina</em> and <em>M. hakonensis</em> DSM 7519<sup>T</sup>, <em>M. sedula</em> DSM 5348<sup>T</sup> and <em>M. prunae</em> DSM 10039<sup>T</sup> is 97.7 %, 97.0 % and 96.8 %, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Ar-4<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 15769<sup>T</sup> = CGMCC 1.7082<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from muddy water samples from a sulfuric hot spring of Tengchong county, Yunnan province, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>