<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6732_nm.1096" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1096" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1096" rank="species">Paracoccus alcaliphilus</organism><reference id="rid.6732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamaoka</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus alcaliphilus sp. nov., an alkaliphilic and facultatively methylotrophic bacterium.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>116</fpage><lpage>121</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Destription of <i>Paracoccus alcaliphilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paracoccus alcaliphilus</i> (al.cal.i.phil'us. M.L. <i>alcali</i>, Eng. alkali from the Arabic <i>al</i>, the end, and qaliy, soda ash; Gr.adj.<i>phila</i>, loving; M.L. adj. <i>alcaliphilus</i>, with an affinity for alkalinity [i,e., alkaline media])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccoid cells (diameter, 0.5 to 0.9 μm) or short rods (length, 0.9 to 2.0 μm) occur singly, in pairs, or in clusters.</s><s>Colonies are white to light yellow.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid accumulate in the cells.</s><s>Growth in nutrient broth is very poor, but growth in nutrient broth adjusted to pH 9.0 is abundant.</s><s>Growth in peptone water is poor or nonexistent (Table 2), but growth in peptone water adjusted to pH 9.0 is abundant.</s><s>A water-soluble fluorescent pigment is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin and starch is not observed.</s><s>Ammonia is produced.</s><s>Denitrification is not performed.</s><s>Litmus milk is not changed.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, inositol, glycerol, succinic acid, citric acid, acetic acid, ethanol, and methanol are utilized, but maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, soluble starch, formic acid, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, methane, and hydrogen are not utilized.</s><s>Utilization of monomethylamine differs among the strains.</s><s>Biotin is required as an essential supplement.</s><s>Ammonia, nitrate, urea, and peptone are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Growth is observed between pH 7.0 and 9.5; no growth occurs below pH 6.5 and above pH 10.0.</s><s>The optimum cultural pH is pH 8.0 to 9.0.</s><s>Growth is observed at 30"C, but not at 37°C.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 3% sodium chloride is weak.</s><s>Urease, oxidase, and catalase are produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory and not fermentative.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 64 to 66 mol% G+C.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is straight-chain unsaturated C<sub>18:1</sub> acid.</s><s>The major hydroxy fatty acids are 3-hydroxy C<sub>10:0</sub> acid and 3-hydroxy C<sub>14:0</sub> acid.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone Q-10, with Q-9 and Q-11 as minor components.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Variations in phenotypic characteristics, DNA base composition, and DNA-DNA homology in the species are shown in Tables 2, 3, 5, and 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain TK 1015.</s><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain TK 1015<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain utilizes monomethylamine.</s><s>Its DNA base composition is 64.4 mol% G+C.</s><s>This strain was isolated from soil by T.</s><s>Urakami (isolation number 0-100).</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Institute of Physical and Chemical Research, as strain JCM 7364.</s></p></content></protolog>