<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3459_nm.6984" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6984" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6984" rank="species">Streptomyces europaeiscabiei</organism><reference id="rid.3459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouchek-Mechiche</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jouan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>DNA relatedness among strains of Streptomyces pathogenic to potato in France: description of three new species, S. europaeiscabiei sp. nov. and S. stelliscabiei sp. nov. associated with common scab, and S. reticuliscabiei sp. nov. associated with netted scab</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>99</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces europaeiscabiei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces europaeiscabiei</i> (eu.ro.pa.ei.sca'bi.ei. L. adj. <i>europaeus</i> european; L. n. <i>scabies</i> mange; M.L. n. <i>europaeiscabiei</i> referring to the European origin of the strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are grey and are borne in mature spiral chains.</s><s>Melanin is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>All ISP sugars are used: L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, inositol, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, D-xylose.</s><s>Degradation of xanthine differed between the strains studied.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to 20 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 0.5 μg crystal violet ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>They are not susceptible to 25 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> or 10 IU penicillin G ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>They utilize <i>trans</i>-aconitate, D(­+)trehalose, OMPG, melibiose, 5-keto-D-gluconate and most (about 78%) of the strains assimilate gentisate.</s><s>They do not use betain, mucate, D-saccharate, DL-lactate and turanose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 71.3 mol%.</s><s>These strains were isolated from common scab lesions, mostly on potato, but also on carrot and beet and have been confirmed to be pathogenic on potato cvs Bintje and Urgenta, on carrot cv. Premia and on radish cv. Polka.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the French Collection of Phytopathogenic Bacteria (Collection Française des Bacteries Phytopathogènes) as CFBP 4497<sup>T</sup>, the International Collection of Microorganism from Plants as ICMP 13714<sup>T</sup>, and the National Collection of Plant Pathogenic Bacteria as NCPPB 4039<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>This strain was isolated from common scab lesions on potato in France.</s><s>It has the physiological and biochemical characteristics of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>