<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4232_nm.6399" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6399" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6399" rank="species">Mycobacterium septicum</organism><reference id="rid.4232"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schinsky</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McNeil</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitney</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lasker</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hogg</surname><given-names>G.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium septicum sp. nov., a new rapidly growing species associated with catheter-related bacteraemia</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>575</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758863</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium septicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium septicum</i> (sep'ti.cum. M.L. adj. for spread of bacteria in blood, referring to the condition from which this species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism was isolated from and was the aetiological agent of catheter-related bacteraemia in a 2- year-old child diagnosed with metastatic hepatoblastoma (Hogg et al., 1999).</s><s>The cells are acid-fast, Gram-positive, pleomorphic coccobacilli.</s><s>Longer filamentous forms are often observed but spores and capsules are absent.</s><s>Colonies are cerebriform, slightly beige, with an irregular edge and do not demonstrate aerial hyphae.</s><s>Growth occurs on Lowenstein-Jensen medium at 35°C in less than 7 d, at 28°C in 5% NaCl and on MacConkey agar without crystal violet.</s><s>The isolates reduce nitrate, have arylsulfatase activity by 14 d and exhibit iron uptake.</s><s>They do not hydrolyse acetamide, utilize citrate or grow in lysozyme. <i>M. septicum</i> produces acid from D-fructose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>i</i>-<i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-mannose, salicin, D-trehalose and D-xylose, but not from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, <i>i</i>-erythritol, galactose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, lrhamnose, D-sorbitol, starch or sucrose.</s><s>This organism is resistant to ampicillin, cefamandole, cefotaxime, ceftriaxone and streptomycin but susceptible to amikacin, amoxicillin-clavulanate, cipro¯oxacin, doxycycline, erythromycin, imipenem, minocycline, sulfamethoxazole, trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole, vancomycin, tobramycin, gentamicin, neomycin and kanamycin. <i>M. septicum</i> has a G­C content of 64 mol%.</s><s>The nearest phylogenetic neighbours of <i>M. septicum</i> by 16S rRNA gene sequencing are <i>M. peregrinum</i>, <i>M. senegalense</i> and <i>M. fortuitum</i>.</s><s>The type strain of <i>M. septicum</i> is W4964<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from the catheter tip of a 2-year-old child with metastatic hepatoblastoma.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 44393<sup>T</sup> and in the ATCC as ATCC 700731<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>