<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.385_nm.4986" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4986" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4986" rank="species">Bacillus sporothermodurans</organism><reference id="rid.385"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pettersson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lembke</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hammer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus sporothermodurans, a new species producing highly heat-resistant endospores.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>759</fpage><lpage>764</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-759</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus sporothermodurans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus sporothermodurans</i> (spo. ro. ther. mo. du. ians, Gr. n. <i>sporos</i>, seed, spore; Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, warm, hot; L. adj. part. <i>durans</i>, resisting. M. L. adj. part. <i>sporothermodurans</i>, with heat-resisting spores)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells from laboratory media are typically long (&#x003E;30 μm), filamentous rods about 0.7 μm in diameter which stain unevenly with the Gram reaction to produce a granular or string-of-pearls appearance.</s><s>Rods 3.4 to 8.2 μm long are also seen, especially following primary isolation from milk.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagellae.</s><s>Spores are ellipsoidal, about 1.7 μm long, and located terminally and do not distend the sporangium but are rarely seen in normal laboratory culture.</s><s>Colonies are small, smooth, and off-white to beige.</s><s>There is no soluble pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows poorly, if at all, on nutrient agar; BHI agar is a suitable routine medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic; catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative, and acid is not produced from a variety of sugars, including cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, salicin, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains hydrolyze esculin, and most produce weak hydrolysis of casein.</s><s>Arbutin, arginine, gelatin, starch, and urea (one exception) are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized as a carbon source.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20 to 45°C, and some strains, including the type strain, are capable of growth at 50°C.</s><s>The optimum is around 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 36 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is M215, which was isolated from UHT-treated milk and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSMZ 10599.</s></p></content></protolog>