<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2679_nm.968" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.968" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.968" rank="species">Rickettsia peacockii</organism><reference id="rid.2679"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Niebylski</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schrumpf</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burgdorfer</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gage</surname><given-names>K.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schwan</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia peacockii sp. nov., a new species infecting wood ticks, Dermacentor andersoni, in western Montana.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>446</fpage><lpage>452</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-446</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia peacockii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia peacockii</i> (pea.cock'i.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>peacockii</i> of Peacock, named after rickettsiologist M. G. Peacock)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose for a <i>Rickettsia peacockii</i> new SFG rickettsial species which maintains natural infections in wood ticks via transstadial and transovarial transmission.</s><s>Although <i>R. peacockii</i> could not be maintained in laboratory tissue culture, there is precedent for naming and describing uncultivable prokaryotes (1, 22).</s><s>A type strain (Skalkaho) was characterized directly from an infected <i>D. andersoni</i> tick (SK-594) which was used to generate 16s rDNA and rOmpA gene sequences (Tables 4 and 5), RFLP profiles (Fig. 2), and IFA reactivity data (Table 3) and to establish an infected laboratory tick colony (RML-795).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The localization of <i>R. peacockii</i> Skalkaho<sup>T</sup> in tick ovarial tissue, our inability to maintain infections in mammalian systems, the apparent lack or truncation of the rOmpA surface antigen, and the gene sequence data indicate that this fastidious microorganism is a unique rickettsial species.</s><s>With its stable maintenance in ticks, <i>R. peacockii</i> Skalkaho<sup>T</sup> appears to be an endosymbiont whose biology contrasts with the biology of other rickettsiae.</s><s>Continued studies on the organism should contribute to our understanding of rickettsia-vector-mammalian host dynamics and the mechanisms which virulent rickettsiae employ to infect and ultimately damage host cells.</s></p></content></protolog>