<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12542_nm.21403" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21403" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21403" rank="species">Celerinatantimonas diazotrophica</organism><reference id="rid.12542"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cramer</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haghshenas</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bagwell</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsui</surname><given-names>G.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lovell</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Celerinatantimonas diazotrophica gen. nov., sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium representing a new family in the Gammaproteobacteria, Celerinatantimonadaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1053</fpage><lpage>1060</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017905-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511455</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Celerinatantimonas diazotrophica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Celerinatantimonas diazotrophica</em> [di.a′zo.tro′phi.ca. Gr. adv. <em>dis</em> twice, doubly; N.L. n. <em>azotum</em> nitrogen; N.L. pref. <em>diazo</em>- pertaining to dinitrogen; N.L. fem. adj. <em>trophica</em> (from Gr. fem. adj. <em>trophikê</em>) nursing, tending; N.L. fem. adj. <em>diazotrophica</em> growing on dinitrogen].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Grows at 17–49 °C, with optimal growth at 31 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.5–8.0 %, with optimal growth at 7.0–7.5 %.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 3.5–8.0, with optimal growth at pH 6.0.</s><s>Does not produce the extracellular enzymes amylase, gelatinase, casein protease or lipase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Known strains are positive for the production of acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α- and β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>The type strain produces <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase (chitinase), but the other known strains do not.</s><s>Negative for α-fucosidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and β-glucuronidase.</s><s>Strain J-G1-2 produces weakly positive reactions for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase and trypsin with API ZYM test strips; all other strains give negative results.</s><s>Strain J-G1-5 produces a weakly positive reaction with valine arylamidase with API ZYM test strips; all other strains are positive.</s><s>Utilizes <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, glycerol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, dextrin, glycogen, l-proline and malate.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, i-erythritol, l-fucose, xylitol, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-galacturonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, l-alaninamide, α-cyclodextrin, d- or l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- or l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine or thymidine.</s><s>Variable results are seen for utilization of adonitol, maltose, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, dl-lactic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, Tweens 40 and 80, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid and γ-aminobutyric acid.</s><s>Of these carbon sources, the type strain utilizes maltose, d-psicose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, dl-lactic acid, glucuronamide and l-glutamic acid.</s><s>The type strain also produces α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase and acid and alkaline phosphatases.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, S-G2-2<sup>T</sup> ( = ATCC BAA-1368<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 18577<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a <em>Spartina alterniflora</em> root sample from the North Inlet salt marsh near Georgetown, SC, USA.</s><s>Other strains of the species, isolated from similar sources, are J-G2-2 ( = DSM 18573), J-G1-1w ( = DSM 18574), J-G1-5 ( = DSM 18575) and J-G1-2 ( = ATCC BAA-1369  = DSM 18576).</s></p></content></protolog>