<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6794_nm.5266" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5266" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5266" rank="species">Staphylococcus pulvereri</organism><reference id="rid.6794"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zakrzewska-Czerwińska</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gaszewska-Mastalarz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lis</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gamian</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mordarski</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus pulvereri sp. nov., isolated from human and animal specimens.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>169</fpage><lpage>172</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-169</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857796</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus pulvereri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Staphylococcus pulvereri (pul'.ver. er.i. L. gen. n. <i>pulvereri</i>, in honor of the German microbiologist Gerhard Pulverer for contributions to the study of staphylococcal infections in clinical microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species <i>S. pulvereri</i> is based on a total of five strains isolated from different sources.</s><s>The cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-positive cocci.</s><s>Agar colonies are circular, entire, smooth, nonpigmented or white with yellowish tint, and 4.0 to 8.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>All strains are facultative anaerobes which grow best under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Anaerobic growth on Wilkins agar is evident after 24 to 48 h.</s><s>The strains cannot be cultivated in semisolid thioglycolate medium.</s><s>NaCl does not affect the growth up to concentrations of 15%; the strains are killed in the presence of 17.5% NaC1.</s><s>Colonies develop at 25 and 37°C after 48 and 24 h, respectively.</s><s>Weak growth is observed at 1O"C, while at 45°C there is no growth.</s><s>The five strains produce neither extracellular nor cell-associated coagulase (clumping factor).</s><s>All of them are resistant to novobiocin.</s><s>The characteristics are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 27.0 to 30.0 mol% G+C.</s><s>The peptidoglycan structure is of the L-Lys-Ala-Gly, type.</s><s>The cell wall teichoic acids contain glycerol, ribose, and N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are iso and anteiso branched with 15, 17, and 19 carbon atoms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain, NT215 (=PCM 2443<sup>T</sup>; Polish Collection of Microorganisms, Wroctaw, Poland), was isolated from a hip infection.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are the same as those given above for the species and in Table 2.</s><s>The G+C content is 27 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The selected characteristics are sufficient to differentiate <i>S. pulvereri</i> from other novobiocin-resistant, coagulase-negative <i>Staphylococcus</i> species (Table 5). <i>S. pulvereri</i> can be distinguished from other species by its production of acids from maltose and sucrose (but not from raffinose and D-turanose), by its lack of esculin activity, its peptidoglycan type, and its comparatively low G+C content.</s></p></content></protolog>