<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1309_nm.5492" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5492" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5492" rank="species">Carnobacterium gallinarum</organism><reference id="rid.1309"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferusu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Lactobacillus divergens, Lactobacillus piscicola, and some catalase-negative asporogenous, rod-shaped bacteria from poultry in a new genus, Carnobacterium.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>310</fpage><lpage>316</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-310</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Carnobacterium gallinarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Carnobacterium gallinarum</i> (gal.li.na'rum. L. fem. n. <i>gallina</i>, a hen; L. fem. gen. pl. n. <i>gallinarum</i>, of hens).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonsporeforming, straight, slender rods which occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, shiny, and circular.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0 and 35°C but not at 40°C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>L-(+)-Lactic acid is produced.</s><s>No gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, D-lyxose, mannitol, melibiose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, xylitol, and L-xylose.</s><s>Acid from amidon variable.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze esculin and are arginine dihydrolase and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>All strains are lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan desaminase, and urease negative.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types with tetradecanoic, hexadecanoic, and 9,lO-octadecenoic acids predominating.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA ranges from 34.3 to 36.4 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>Isolated from ice slush from around chicken carcasses.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCFB 2766<sup>T</sup> (MT44).</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to that of the species, except that acid is not produced from amidon.</s></p></content></protolog>