<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3403_nm.1978" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1978" rank="genus">Prolinoborus</organism><reference id="rid.3403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Intra- and intergeneric relationships of the genus Aquaspirillum: Prolinoborus, a new genus for Aquaspirillum fasciculus, with the species Prolinoborus fasciculus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>44</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-1-44</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prolinoborus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prolinoborus</i> (Pro.li.no'bo.rus. L. N. <i>prolina</i>, the amino acid proline; Gr. adj. <i>boros</i>, voracious; M. L. masc. n. <i>Prolinoborus</i> [bacteria] that readily consume proline)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from references 32 and 53.</s><s>The gram-negative cells are straight rods with diameters of 0.7 to 0.9 μm (mean values).</s><s>The cells are approximately 5 to 10 μm long, but old cultures may contain cells up to 42 μm long.</s><s>After prolonged serial transfer, curved or S-shaped variants may occur (53).</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is formed.</s><s>A polar membrane underlies the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Coccoid bodies are formed in old cultures.</s><s>Initial isolation cannot be achieved by ordinary streaking onto agar media and can be achieved only after prolonged enrichment by the pour plate method, using L-proline as the sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>Cells occur in flocs upon initial isolation.</s><s>After several serial transfers, the floc-forming ability can gradually be lost, and eventually the strains exhibit homogeneous, turbid growth.</s><s>Flagellation is bipolar with the flagella occurring in fascicles and is clearly visible by phase-contrast or dark-field microscopy.</s><s>The flagella exhibit an unusual and distinctive behavior when cells are suspended in ordinary nonviscous media.</s><s>The flagella exhibit helical wave propagation and basal bending and have the ability to coil up like springs.</s><s>The behaviors of the fascicles at the opposite poles are not coordinated.</s><s>Free cells or cells at the periphery of flocs in ordinary media are not motile or their motility is irregular over short distances.</s><s>Within the flocs or in media having greater viscosity (10 to 200 cP, obtained by using, e.g., methylcellulose 400 cP), the cells move in a steady straight-line pattern.</s><s>The ability to swim only in viscous media may represent an adaptation to the viscous conditions that occur within cell flocs.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic with a respiratory type of metabolism and with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Optimum temperature, 30°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 20 or 40°C.</s><s>Cells grow anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Gelatin, esculin, hippurate, casein, and starch are not attacked, and indole is not formed.</s><s>NaCl and glycine (1%) are not tolerated.</s><s>The enzymes catalase, oxidase, and phosphatase are present.</s><s>When cells are cultured in semisolid test medium lacking (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, nitrogenase activity occurs.</s><s>The sole nitrogen sources utilized include nitrate, ammonium salts, and 10 amino acids, with L-proline and L-alanine being the most effective.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Carbohydrates are not catabolized , and tricarboxylic acid cycle intermediates can be used as sole carbon sources with (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, as the sole nitrogen source.</s><s>Pyruvate and proline are the most effective sole carbon sources.</s><s>Isolated from pond water.</s><s>The DNA base content ranges from 62 to 65 mol% G+C.</s><s>As determined by DNA-rRNA hybridization experiments, the genus <i>Prolinoborus</i> belongs to rRNA superfamily 111, with a difference in <i>T<sub>m(e)</sub></i>, value of more than 6°C versus rRNA from <i>A. serpens</i> biovar bengal ATCC 27641<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Prolinoborus fasciculus</i>, the only species at present.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 27740 (= LMG 6233).</s></p></content></protolog>