<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8498_nm.13673" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13673" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13673" rank="species">Vibrio areninigrae</organism><reference id="rid.8498"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio areninigrae sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from black sand.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1903</fpage><lpage>1906</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65726-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18676477</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio areninigrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio areninigrae</em> (a.re.ni.nig′rae. L. fem. n. <em>arena</em> sand; L. adj. <em>niger</em> -<em>gra</em> -<em>grum</em> black; N.L. gen. n. <em>areninigrae</em> of black sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, slightly curved and rod-shaped, 0.5–0.8 μm wide by 2.0–3.0 μm long in 3-day cultures growing at 30 °C on MA plates.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of at least one flagellum per cell.</s><s>Colonies are circular to slightly irregular, smooth, low-convex, pale yellow and 2–3.5 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1–7.5 % NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–45 °C and at pH 5–10.</s><s>No growth occurs below pH 4.5 or above pH 11.</s><s>Cells are catalase- and oxidase-positive, urease- and arginine dihydrolase-negative and indole-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Produces acid but no gas from glucose.</s><s>Susceptible to the vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Glycogen, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inosine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate can be utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy, but not <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, l-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d- or l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- or l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol or dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase activities (API ZYM).</s><s>No esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase activity.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (approximately 37.21, 26.92 and 12.28 % of the total, respectively).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, J74<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22122<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14949<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from black sand from Soesoggak, Jeju island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>