<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1318_nm.7693" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7693" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7693" rank="species">Bifidobacterium globosum</organism><reference id="rid.1318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Electrophoretic patterns of proteins in the genus Bifidobacterium and proposal of four new species.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Bifidobacterium globosum</i> (ex Scardovi, Trovatelli, Crociani, and Sgorbati 1969) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium globosum</i> (glo.bo'sum. L. adj. <i>globosus</i> globelike, referring to the oval and round cells that are produced in some cultures)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain in peptone yeast extract-glucose broth cultures are oval rods that are 1.4 to 1.5 by 1.5 to 2.8 μm and occur in pairs, short chains, and clumps.</s><s>Cells from colonies on the surface of blood agar incubated anaerobically, in air with 10% CO<sub>2</sub>, or in candle jars are longer and often club shaped.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on the surface of blood agar are punctiform, circular, entire, convex, gray or white, shiny, and smooth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Heavy turbidity and a “breadcrumb” sediment are produced in peptone-yeast extract broth containing a fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The final pH is 4.1 to 4.6.</s><s>Slight turbidity is produced in peptone-yeast extract broth containing carbohydrates that are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the type strain and other strains of this species are given in Tables 1, 2, and 5, in Fig. 6 and 13, and by Scardovi et al.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 25865, was isolated from bovine rumen contents.</s></p></content></protolog>