<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6862_nm.9547" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9547" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9547" rank="species">Bizionia saleffrena</organism><reference id="rid.6862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae from Antarctic maritime habitats including Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii gen. nov., sp. nov., Subsaximicrobium saxinquilinus sp. nov., Subsaxibacter broadyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Lacinutrix copepodicola gen. nov., sp. nov., and novel species of the genera Bizionia, Gelidibacter and Gillisia</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bizionia saleffrena</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bizionia saleffrena</em> [sal.ef.fre′na. L. masc. n. <em>sal</em> salt; L. fem. adj. <em>effrena</em> unbridled; N.L. fem. adj. <em>Saleffrena</em> unbridled by salt (referring to the species' good growth on salt-containing media)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-like, 0·4–0·5×1·5–5 μm.</s><s>Colonies are golden-yellow, circular and convex, with an entire edge and a butyrous consistency on MA.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at −2 °C in marine broth.</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA at 1–20 °C.</s><s>Growth is poor at 25 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 30 °C or higher.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup> ions for growth.</s><s>Grows in 0·2–3·0 M NaCl, with optimal growth occurring in approximately 1·0 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows well in media prepared with 4× strength sea salts.</s><s>Does not grow on TSA containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl, TSA or NA.</s><s>Requires yeast extract or peptone for growth, and cannot use inorganic nitrogen sources such as sodium nitrate or ammonium chloride.</s><s>Does not utilize any of the common substrates tested as sole carbon and energy sources (see Table 3 for substrates tested).</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates on Leifson's O–F medium is undetectable.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, casein, elastin, Tween 80, l-tyrosine and DNA, but not starch, aesculin or DNA.</s><s>Produces lecithinase.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic data are shown in Table 3.</s><s>Mean DNA G+C content is 40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HFD<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1059<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108534<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from sea-ice brine, drained and collected from fast sea-ice cores obtained from the coastal areas of the Vestfold Hills, an ice-free region of East Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>