<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7110_nm.4049" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4049" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4049" rank="species">Clostridium ultunense</organism><reference id="rid.7110"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schnürer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svensson</surname><given-names>B.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium ultunense sp. nov., a mesophilic bacterium oxidizing acetate in syntrophic association with a hydrogenotrophic methanogenic bacterium.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1145</fpage><lpage>1152</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1145</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863449</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium ultunense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium ultunense</i> (ul.tu.nen' se. <i>Ull</i>, ancient Nordic god associated with winter sports and duels; <i>tuna</i>, place of worship; L. ending <i>ense</i>; M. L. adj. <i>ultunense</i>, referring to <i>ultuna</i>, the area where the Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences is located)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight or slightly curved rod-shaped cells are 0.5 to 7 by 0.5 to 0.7 μm and occur singly, in pairs, or in chains.</s><s>In the early exponential growth phase, cells are motile by means of a polar flagellum; later the cells are nonmotile.</s><s>Cell chains, as well as swelling cells, are formed in the late exponential growth phase.</s><s>Occasionally, terminal round spores are formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative, with capsular material outside the cell wall.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on agar are 0.5 to 1 mm in diameter, disc shaped, and whitish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>The substrates used as carbon and energy sources include formate, glucose, cysteine, pyruvate, betaine, and ethylene glycol.</s><s>The substrates that are not utilized as carbon and energy sources include sugars other than glucose, H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, CO, methoxylated aromatic compounds, alcohols, and all amino acids except cysteine.</s><s>The main fermentation product is usually acetate, but sometimes formate is also formed in roughly the same amount.</s><s>Small amounts of alanine are formed from cysteine and betaine.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, sulfur, nitrate, fumarate, malate, glycine, and ferric ion are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Acetate is oxidized in the presence of a hydrogen-utilizing methanogenic bacterium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Produces indole from tryptophan and does not liquefy gelatin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Moderate growth occurs in mineral medium supplemented with yeast extract; better growth occurs in modified IRCM mineral medium supplemented with yeast extract, peptone, starch, and Lab Lemco powder.</s><s>Growth in mineral medium depends on the presence of yeast extract, peptone, Casitone, or tryptone (&#x003E;0.1 g/liter).</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range, 5 to 10.</s><s>The optimum pH is around 7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range, 15 to 50°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: anaerobic digester sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain BS, which has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10521.</s></p></content></protolog>