<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9147_nm.14340" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14340" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14340" rank="species">Streptomyces sedi</organism><reference id="rid.9147"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces sedi sp. nov., isolated from surface-sterilized roots of Sedum sp.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1492</fpage><lpage>1496</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007534-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502341</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces sedi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces sedi</em> (se′di. N.L. gen. n. <em>sedi</em> of <em>Sedum</em>, the plant genus from which this species was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms extensively branched substrate mycelia; aerial mycelia differentiate into spiral spore chains.</s><s>Spores are elliptical or short rods.</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are white; vegetative mycelia are yellow–white to light grey–yellow.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is up to 5 %.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Negative for Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests, oxidase reaction, production of H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction and milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Urea and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but cellulose, gelatin and starch are not.</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, aesculin, d-fructose and maltose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from aesculin and maltose.</s><s>d-Arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-galactose, inositol, d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sodium malate, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, trehalose, xylitol and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-histidine, dl-methionine, l-proline, l-serine and l-tyrosine can be used as sole nitrogen sources, but not adenine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, l-valine or xanthine.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid in the peptidoglycan is ll-diaminopimelic acid, and glucose, galactose and madurose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates (cell-wall type I).</s><s>Phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol, with trace amounts of two phosphatidylinositol mannosides and four unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The quinone system is composed of the major compounds MK-11(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and moderate to minor amounts of MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-11(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-11(H<sub>4</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 71.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 65188<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208020<sup>T</sup>=DSM 41942<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface-sterilized sample of <em>Sedum</em> sp. collected in Yunnan province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>