<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.359_nm.5116" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5116" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5116" rank="species">Paenibacillus apiarius</organism><reference id="rid.359"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus apiarius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>688</fpage><lpage>693</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-688</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782677</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus apiarius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus apiarius</i> (a.pi.a'ri.us. L. adj. <i>apian'us</i>, relating to bees)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods that are 0.7 to 0.8 by 3.0 to 5.0 μm, as determined from a photomicrograph.</s><s>Gram staining is variable.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Spores have thick walls, appear to be rectangular, and are produced in swollen sporangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are nonpigmented, translucent, thin, smooth, circular, and entire, and the average diameter is about 1.0 mm after 24 h of incubation on TGY agar at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol, dihydroxyacetone, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth (test for acetylmethylcarbinol production) ranges from 4.4 to 5.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Starch, casein, tyrosine, and urea are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Tween 80 and egg yolk lecithin are not decomposed.</s><s>Lysine, ornithine, arginine, and phenylalanine are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Citrate is utilized; propionate is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.7, in the presence of 0.001% lysozyme, and in the presence of 5% NaCl; growth is inhibited by 7% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature is 28°C; the maximum temperature is 40°C; and the minimum temperature is 15°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from cellobiose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose (weak), melibiose, D-ribose (weak), salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, lactose, mannitol, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, and D-xylose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant density ranges from 1.7055 to 1.7075 g/cm<sup>3</sup>; the G+C content is 52 to 54 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from honeybees, their larvae, and their hives.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain NRRL NRS-1438 has been deposited in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection at the National Center for Agricultural Utilization Research in Peoria, Ill.</s></p></content></protolog>