<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2476_nm.11410" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11410" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11410" rank="species">Burkholderia bryophila</organism><reference id="rid.2476"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Opelt</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Knöchel</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schönmann</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Brandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eberl</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia bryophila sp. nov. and Burkholderia megapolitana sp. nov., moss-associated species with antifungal and plant-growth-promoting properties</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2228</fpage><lpage>2235</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65142-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911288</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia bryophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia bryophila</em> (bry.o.phi′la. Gr. n. <em>bryon</em> moss; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>bryophila</em> moss-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile (except for strain LMG 22946), non-sporulating, straight rods.</s><s>Growth is observed at 28 °C.</s><s>No acid production is observed in O/F medium with d-glucose (except for two isolates that yield weak growth), maltose, adonitol, d-fructose or d-xylose as carbon source.</s><s>No production of fluorescent pigment.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activity are present (although some strains, including strain 1S18<sup>T</sup>, give a weak reaction).</s><s>No growth is observed on cetrimide agar (except for strain A20, which is weakly positive), on 10 % lactose medium, in the presence of acetamide or in the presence of 0.5 (except for strain LMG 22946), 1.5 (except for strain LMG 22946, which exhibits weak growth), 3.0, 4.5 or 6.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows on blood agar at 30 °C but not on Drigalski agar (four strains, including strain 1S18<sup>T</sup>, produce weak growth), on blood agar at 37 °C or on nutrient agar at 42 °C.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate or nitrite or denitrification.</s><s>No liquefaction of gelatin.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is strain-dependent: only strain 1S18<sup>T</sup> is clearly positive, two strains are weakly positive, while the others are negative.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed (except for strain LMG 22946).</s><s>Haemolysis of horse blood is not observed.</s><s>No production of acid or H<sub>2</sub>S in triple-sugar-iron agar and no indole or pigment production.</s><s>Strains are resistant to penicillin (10 μg per disc) except for strain A5.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity (ONPG test) is present (except in strain A2).</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, DNase and urease (except for two isolates that are weakly positive) activities are not detected.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arginine, l-arabinose (five isolates produce only weak growth), d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-gluconate (weak growth for two isolates), caprate (five isolates produce only weak growth), l-malate (except for one strain with a weak reaction), citrate (except for one strain with a weak reaction), phenylacetate (except for three strains with a weak reaction and one strain which is negative), dl-lactate (except for one strain with a weak reaction) and dl-lactate with methionine (except for one strain with a weak reaction), but not trehalose (except for strain LMG 22946, which exhibits weak growth), dl-norleucine, maltose or sucrose.</s><s>Assimilation of adipate is strain-dependent: two isolates including strain 1S18<sup>T</sup> are negative, six give a weak reaction and the others are positive.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase (except for strain LMG 22946, which exhibits weak reactions), leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase (except for strain LMG 22946, which exhibits a weak reaction) activities are present.</s><s>Activity of esterase C4 is strong in six strains and weak in the remaining isolates, including strain 1S18<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Activity of ester lipase C8 is weak except for one strain which gives a strong reaction and one strain which is negative.</s><s>Amylase (except in two strains where a weak reaction is observed), lipase C14 (except in one strain where a weak reaction is observed), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is about 62 mol%.</s><s>Strains have so far been isolated from moss gametophytes in northern Germany and from agricultural soil (UK) and grassland (The Netherlands).</s><s>Plant-growth-promoting experiments demonstrate a clear effect on overall plant length (+55 %) and root length (+22 %) and primary leaf length (+50 %) (means of all strains in lettuce seedling assay in comparison with untreated controls).</s><s>Indole-3-acetic acid production determined according to Sarwar &#x0026; Kremer (1995) is not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 1S18<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23644<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 52993<sup>T</sup>), isolated from <em>Sphagnum rubellum</em> at Graal-Müritz, Ribnitzer Großes Moor, in November 2001.</s><s>A number of reference strains of this species have been identified (Table 1).</s></p></content></protolog>