<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3459_nm.7284" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7284" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7284" rank="species">Streptomyces stelliscabiei</organism><reference id="rid.3459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouchek-Mechiche</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jouan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>DNA relatedness among strains of Streptomyces pathogenic to potato in France: description of three new species, S. europaeiscabiei sp. nov. and S. stelliscabiei sp. nov. associated with common scab, and S. reticuliscabiei sp. nov. associated with netted scab</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>99</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces stelliscabiei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces stelliscabiei</i> (stel.li.sca'bi.ei. L. n. <i>stellatus</i> star; L. n. <i>scabies</i> mange; M.L. n. <i>stelliscabiei</i> referring to lesions from which these strains were isolated, which look like stars)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are grey and are borne in mature spiral chains.</s><s>Melanin is produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>All ISP sugars are used: L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose D-mannitol, inositol, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, D-xylose.</s><s>Most strains studied degrade xanthine.</s><s>All strains are susceptible to 20 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 0.5 μg crystal violet ml<sup>-1</sup>, 100 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>They are not susceptible to 25 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> or 10 IU penicillin G ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>They utilize <i>trans</i>-aconitate, D(+­)trehalose, α-D(+­)melibiose but do not assimilate 5-keto-D-gluconate, OMPG, betain, mucate, D-saccharate, DL-lactate, gentisate or turanose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 71.7 mol%.</s><s>These strains were isolated from star-like common scab lesions on potato cv. Belle de Fontenay and have been confirmed to be pathogenic on potato cvs Bintje and Urgenta, on carrot cv. Premia and on radish cv. Polka.</s><s>The type strain is CFBP 4521<sup>T</sup> (=ICMP 13715<sup>T</sup>=NCPPB 4040<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>This strain was isolated from star-like common scab lesions on potato tubers cv. Belle de Fontenay in France.</s><s>This strain has the physiological and biochemical characteristics of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>