<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12473_nm.21304" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21304" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21304" rank="species">Henriciella litoralis</organism><reference id="rid.12473"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shim</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>H.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Henriciella litoralis sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat, transfer of Maribaculum marinum Lai et al. 2009 to the genus Henriciella as Henriciella aquimarina nom. nov. and emended description of the genus Henriciella</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>722</fpage><lpage>727</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Henriciella litoralis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Henriciella litoralis</em> (li.to.ra′lis. L. fem. adj. <em>litoralis</em> of or belonging to the seashore).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, motile rods (0.4–0.6 µm wide and 0.8–2.8 µm long) with a polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MA are yellow, convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C), at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 6.5–8.5) and in the presence of 1–10 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 2–5 %).</s><s>Division mode is binary fission.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>In the API 20NE kit, negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification and arginine dihydrolase activity and for assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, maltose, d-mannitol, malic acid, potassium gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Urea and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API ZYM kit, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin and acid phosphatase activities are present and weak enzymic activities are observed for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase, but β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-galactosidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase and α-mannosidase are absent.</s><s>Positive for utilization of Biolog GN2 MicroPlate system substrates dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol<sub>,</sub> d-mannose, methyl β-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, turanose, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in the Biolog GN2 microplate are not oxidized.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>Contains PG, MGDG, GUDG and two unidentified glycolipids as polar lipids.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.2 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SD10<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 13700<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22014<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a tidal flat of the Taean coast in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>