<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8831_nm.13369" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13369" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13369" rank="species">Hymenobacter soli</organism><reference id="rid.8831"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hymenobacter soli sp. nov., isolated from grass soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>945</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64447-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hymenobacter soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hymenobacter soli</em> (so′li. L. neut. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>Obligately aerobic, chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Cells are 0.6–1.0 μm wide and 2.0–4.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells grow on R2A agar, but not on trypticase soy agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular, entire, smooth, red–pink, transparent and slimy.</s><s>Cells produce extracellular polymer and form thin, spreading layers around colonies on agar surfaces.</s><s>A capsule is observed in negatively stained cells.</s><s>Cells become shorter and almost coccoid in the stationary growth phase on R2A agar.</s><s>No flexirubin-type pigments are formed.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s><s>The presence of more than 1 % NaCl inhibits growth on R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic or denitrifying conditions.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.8 mol%.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/<em>t</em>), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse agar, xylan, cellulose, skimmed milk, chitin or olive oil.</s><s>Arbutin, aesculin, d-galactose, 5-ketogluconate and d-mannose are assimilated.</s><s>Weakly positive for assimilation of glycerol and d-ribose.</s><s>The following substrates are not assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-adonitol, starch, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol and d- and l-xylose (API 50 CH).</s><s>Negative for assimilation of caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate (API 20NE).</s><s>Negative for lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activities and for production of hydrogen sulfide and indole.</s><s>Weakly positive for acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer reaction).</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or sucrose (API 20E).</s><s>Positive for arginine dihydrolase, urease and aesculin hydrolysis and negative for glucose acidification (API 20NE).</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive results are obtained for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase, weakly positive results are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase and negative results are obtained for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PB17<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12607<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24240<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from grass soil in Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>