<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.276_nm.3008" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3008" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3008" rank="species">Vibrio tapetis</organism><reference id="rid.276"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Borrego</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Castro</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luque</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paillard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maes</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio tapetis sp. nov., the causative agent of the brown ring disease affecting cultured clams.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>480</fpage><lpage>484</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio tapetis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio tapetis</i> (ta.pe'tis. L. gen. n. <i>tapetis</i>, of clams [the genus <i>Tapes</i>])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative coccobacilli (1.0 to 1.5 by 0.5 μm) motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Grows on marine agar (Difco) and tryptone soya agar (Oxoid) containing 2% NaCl.</s><s>Colonies develop within 48 h at 20 ± 2°C and are circular, regular in shape, translucent, and unpigmented.</s><s>Grows on thiosulfate-citratebile-sucrose agar (green colonies).</s><s>Swarming has not been detected in any of the media tested.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase, and nitrate reduction to nitrite are positive.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl in the culture medium.</s><s>The salt requirement is specific for sodium ion.</s><s>Grows in media supplemented with 1 to 3% (wt/vol) NaCl but not in media with salinity higher than 5% NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to vibriostatic agent 0/129 (150 μg).</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 22°C but not at higher temperatures.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 18 ± 2°C.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S production, arginine dehydrolase, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylase negative but indole production and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>The strains degrade casein, gelatin, starch, and Tween 80 but are not able to hydrolyze urea and alginate.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose, D-glucose, D-galactose, D-mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, and maltose but not from sucrose, L-arabinose, D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, mannitol, or lactose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. tapetis</i> B1090<sup>T</sup> utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: D-fructose, α-D-glucose, N-acetylglucosamine, D-psicose, D-trehalose, Tween 40, succinate, and propionate.</s><s>Other substrates specified in Table 2 are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. tapetis</i> has been isolated exclusively from manila and fine clams (<i>T. philippinarum</i> and <i>T. decussatus</i>), in which it causes the brown ring disease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of strain B1090<sup>T</sup> is 43.2 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s><s>The type strain of <i>V. tapetis</i> is strain B1090 (CECT 4600).</s></p></content></protolog>