<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6490_nm.10218" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10218" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10218" rank="species">Brevibacterium samyangense</organism><reference id="rid.6490"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium samyangense sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from a beach sediment</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1889</fpage><lpage>1892</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64269-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902026</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium samyangense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium samyangense</em> (sam.yang′en.se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>samyangense</em> of Samyang Beach, Jeju, Republic of Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>On YE-SW agar, an apparent rod–coccus growth cycle is observed: after 6 h growth, cells are coccoid, occurring singly or in pairs, with the rare occurrence of short rods; after 12 and 16 h growth, most cells are irregular and slender rods, arranged in V-forms; after 24 and 72 h growth, cells are coccoid, occurring singly, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Colonies are opaque, convex, circular and bright yellow in colour with an entire edge.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–45 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 4 or 55 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the pH range 6.1–10.1, with better growth at higher pH.</s><s>NaCl tolerance for growth is observed, with good growth at 0–5 %, moderate growth at 6–9 % but only weak growth at 10 or 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Degradation of dl-tyrosine is observed but not of casein or xanthine.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources for growth in Biolog GP2 tests: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, methylpyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates in the Biolog GP2 system are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, d-malic acid, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and d-fructose 6-phosphate.</s><s>In the API CORYNE system, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculin hydrolysis), urease, gelatin hydrolysis and fermentation of d-ribose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-lactose and glycogen are negative.</s><s>Acid production from d-glucose, d-maltose and sucrose are weakly positive.</s><s>In additional tests with the API ZYM system, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive.</s><s>Valine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase are weakly positive.</s><s>The following give negative responses: lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The phospholipid profiles contain diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SST-8<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-41420<sup>T</sup>=KCCM 42316<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sand sediment of Samyang Beach, Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>