<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1339_nm.6733" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6733" rank="genus">Kibdelosporangium</organism><reference id="rid.1339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shearer</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colman</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferrin</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nisbet</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>New genus of the Actinomycetales: Kibdelosporangium aridum gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kibdelosporangium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kibdelosporangium</i> (Kib. del.' o. spo. ran.' gi. um. Gr. adj. <i>kibdelos</i> false, ambiguous; Gr. n. <i>spora</i> seed; Gr. n. <i>aggeion</i> vessel; <i>Kibdelosporangium</i> vessel containing false seeds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are aerobic, gram-positive, non-acid-fast, filamentous organisms that form a mycelium differentiated into (i) a substrate mycelium that penetrates the agar and forms a compact layer on top of the agar and (ii) an aerial mycelium originating from the substrate mycelium.</s><s>The well-developed substrate mycelium may exhibit varying degrees of fragmentation and usually bears specialized structures which appear to be dichotomously branched, septate hyphae radiating from a common stalk.</s><s>The aerial mycelium bears long chains of spores and sporangiumlike structures.</s><s>These sporangiumlike structures are surrounded by well-defined walls but do not contain spores.</s><s>They germinate directly, producing one or more germ tubes when they are placed on agar.</s><s>No motile elements are present in either the aerial or substrate mycelium.</s><s>The cell wall is type IV (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, D-glutamic acid, DL-alanine, muramic acid, N-acetyl- D-glucosamine, D-galactose, and arabinose) (30); no mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern is type A (arabinose and D-galactose) (30); traces of madurose are usually present.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern is type PII (phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine; phosphatidylmethylethanolamine may also be present) (28).</s><s>The type species is <i>Kibdelosporangium aridum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>