<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5926_nm.10095" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10095" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10095" rank="species">Ornithinibacillus bavariensis</organism><reference id="rid.5926"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mayr</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Worliczek</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ehling-Schulz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scherer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ornithinibacillus gen. nov., with the species Ornithinibacillus bavariensis sp. nov. and Ornithinibacillus californiensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1383</fpage><lpage>1389</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64038-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738118</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ornithinibacillus bavariensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ornithinibacillus bavariensis</em> (ba.va.ri.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>bavariensis</em> of Bavaria, indicating the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are regular, motile rods, 0.4 μm wide and 2–6 μm long, which occur singly or sometimes in short chains.</s><s>Gram-behaviour of vegetative cells is positive with staining and in the KOH and aminopeptidase tests.</s><s>Because of the presence of an oval spore in a terminal position, the swollen sporangium (width approx. 0.8 μm) appears racket-shaped.</s><s>On TSA, the type strain grows strictly aerobically, forming round, raised, slightly brownish/orange colonies with small regular margins.</s><s>Within 10 days at 30 °C, the diameter of a single colony reaches about 10 mm.</s><s>Halotolerant on PYE agar.</s><s>Growth occurs with NaCl at 0–10 % (w/v), with a growth optimum at 0.5–4 %.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15 and 45 °C, but not at 7 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed at 42 °C.</s><s>Grows occurs at pH 7–10 on PYE agar but not at pH 6.</s><s>Catalase-, oxidase- and gelatinase-positive.</s><s>Results for acid production from carbohydrates (API 50 CHB) within 6 weeks and from Biolog GP2 testing are summarized in Table 2.</s><s>Tests for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, l-alanine aminopeptidase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, production of indole, production of acetoin, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction (API 20E), egg-yolk lecithinase, starch hydrolysis and formation of dihydroxyacetone are negative.</s><s>Haemolysis is observed after incubation for 2 days at 37 °C on blood agar.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type, quinone system and polar lipid profile are as given in the genus description, but, in addition, an unknown polar lipid is present that cannot be stained with any of the specific spray reagents.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile consists of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (39.0 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (19.9 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (8.0 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (7.7 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (6.7 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (5.7 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3.8 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> (2.8 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.4 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (1.3 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.1 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>10<em>c</em> (1.1 %), iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (1.0 %) and summed feature 4 (iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>) (0.7 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 36.4 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological characteristics of strains WSBC 24001<sup>T</sup> and MB-9<sup>T</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>API 50 CHB results were followed for up to 6 weeks at 30 °C.</s><s>Biolog GP2 microplates were incubated for 48 h at 28 °C as described in the text.</s><s>Characteristics are scored as follows: +, positive within 1–2 weeks; w, positive within 4–6 weeks (API 50 CHB) or weak colour development after 72 h (Biolog GP2); ?, plain-coloured to light-orange-coloured test volumes representing unclear results (API 50 CHB); v, not reproducible (Biolog GP2); −, negative.</s><s>The two strains tested positive for acid production (API 50 CHB) from glycerol, d-glucose, trehalose and 5-ketogluconate within 1–2 weeks and tested positive for salicin within 4–6 weeks; both showed positive reactions in the Biolog tests for acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid and pyruvic acid.</s><s>The two strains tested negative for acid production (API 50 CHB) from erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, lactose,melibiose, melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Both strains were negative in the Biolog reactions for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose,methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose,d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Strain WSBC 24001<sup>T</sup> tested negative in the following Biolog reactions: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, Tween 80, arbutin, salicin, d-trehalose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, uridine and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Strain MB-9<sup>T</sup> tested negative for the following Biolog reactions: amygdalin, d-fructose, d-sorbitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid and glycyl l-glutamic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WSBC 24001<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15681<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7096<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from pasteurized milk from Bavaria, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>