<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5911_nm.10100" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10100" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10100" rank="species">Ancylobacter polymorphus</organism><reference id="rid.5911"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ancylobacter polymorphus sp. nov. and Ancylobacter vacuolatus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1185</fpage><lpage>1188</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64118-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738088</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ancylobacter polymorphus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ancylobacter polymorphus</em> (po.ly.mor′phus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>polymorphus</em> polymorphic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, curved rods, 0.8–1.0 μm in diameter, non-motile, with a capsule and gas vesicles.</s><s>Colonies are white, convex, round, entire and 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation on nutrient broth agar plates.</s><s>Can produce pellicles when growing in liquid medium.</s><s>Produces poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Fixes free nitrogen while growing on Döbereiner nitrogen-free medium.</s><s>No growth at 4 or 50 °C or at pH 4.5.</s><s>Optimum growth at 28–30 °C and at pH 7.0.</s><s>Grows at pH 11.0.</s><s>Grows in 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-, catalase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Negative for DNase, phenylalanine deaminase, lipase (Tween 80) and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S or indole.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrates.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin but not starch.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: maltose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, adonitol, glycerol, glucose, ribose, inulin, l-arabinose, fructose, galactose, mannitol, dextrin, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, xylose, sorbitol, amygdalin, ketoglutaric acid, alanine, proline, fumaric acid, arginine, sodium acetate, sodium malonate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sodium propionate, sodium lactate, sodium malate and methanol.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates weakly as carbon and energy sources: starch, sucrose, aesculin, melezitose, sodium pyruvate, sodium formate and salicin.</s><s>Does not utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: trehalose, sorbose, cellobiose, raffinose, melibiose, mannose, lactose, dulcitol, inositol, rhamnose, sodium gluconate, sodium tartrate and sodium hippurate.</s><s>Forms acid but no gas from mannose, ribose, glycerol, mannitol, inulin, sorbitol, galactose, cellobiose, rhamnose, salicin, glucose, maltose, l-arabinose, xylose, melibiose, adonitol, fructose and lactose; forms neither acid nor gas from inositol, raffinose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, sucrose, sorbose, trehalose, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol and dextrin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 2457<sup>T</sup> (=AS 1.2800<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 10516<sup>T</sup>), isolated from river mud (Maclennan <em>et al.</em>, 1974).</s></p></content></protolog>