<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1363_nm.11683" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11683" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6264" rank="subspecies">Clavibacter michiganense sepedonicum</organism><reference id="rid.1363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillaspie</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clavibacter: a new genus containing some phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria, including Clavibacter xyli subsp. xyli sp. nov., subsp. nov. and Clavibacter xyli subsp. cynodontis subsp. nov., pathogens that cause ratoon stunting disease of sugarcane and bermudagrass stunting disease.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clavibacter michiganense</i> subsp. <i>sepedonicum</i> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The morphological and biochemical characteristics of the strains from sugarcane and Bermudagrass indicate that these organisms are related to the phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria which contain 2,4-diaminobutyric acid in their cell wall peptidoglycans. All of the strains were gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-endospore-forming, pleomorphic rods. True mycelia were absent, but primary branching was observed infrequently. Cells were frequently arranged in V formations, which are characteristic of coryneform bacteria undergoing snapping or bending division. The amino acid and sugar compositions of the cell wall peptidoglycans of the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains (Table 4) were similar to the compositions found in some phytopathogenic and saprophytic coryneform bacteria in this study and previous studies (4, 7, 33-37, 40, 50). The distinctive feature of the cell walls was the presence of 2,4-diaminobutyric acid. In addition, 2,4-diaminobutyric acid was found in the cell wall of <i>Corynebacterium michiganense</i> subsp. <i>tessellarius</i>, supporting the recent classification of this organism (1). The non-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids of the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains consist of predominately <i>anteiso</i> and <i>iso</i>-methyl branched acids; only small amounts of straight-chain saturated acids are present (M. Sasser, personal communication). The DNAs of both the sugarcane bacteria and the Bermudagrass bacteria contained 66 mol% G+C, and this is within the range (64 to 74 mol%) for both phytopathogenic and saprophytic coryneform bacteria with cell wall compositions similar to those of the sugarcane and Bermudagrass strains (27,47). The sugarcane and Berrnudagrass strains had many polypeptides of apparent common molecular mass as determined by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, but the two groups of strains were clearly distinguished. Both bacteria had polypeptides that were more similar to the polypeptides of the <i>Corynebacterium michiganense</i> subspecies than to the polypeptides of other 2,4-diaminobutyric acid-containing coryneform phytopathogens. It is noteworthy that we confirmed the close relationship of the <i>Corynebacterium michiganense</i> subspecies to each other (Fig. 3, lanes h and i), which has been observed previously for cells grown in a different medium (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of phenetic and numerical phenetic studies (1, 16, 23) and cell wall (4, 7, 26, 33-37, 40, 50), DNA base and DNA homology (1, 15, 43, 49), fatty acid (3, 7, 4 3 , polar lipid (3, 7, 45), and menaquinone (3, 5, 7, 51) analyses, we agree with most other workers that the phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria do not belong in the genus <i>Corynehacterium</i>.</s><s>We believe that valid suggestions have been made for transfer of <i>Corynebacterium fascians</i> to the genus <i>Rhodococcus</i> (6, 20), transfer of <i>Corynebacterium ilicis</i> to the genus <i>Arthrobacter</i> (9), and transfer of <i>Corynebacterium flaccumfaciens</i> subsp. <i>flaccumfaciens</i>, <i>Corynebacterium flaccumfaciens</i> subsp. <i>betae</i>, <i>Corynebacterium flaccumfaciens</i> subsp. <i>poinsettiae</i>, and <i>Corynebacterium flaccumfaciens</i> subsp. <i>oortii</i> to the genus <i>Curtobacterium</i> (8, 50).</s><s>However, there appears to be no genus presently circumscribed that can readily accommodate the phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria with peptidoglycans based on 2,4-diaminobutyric acid.</s><s>Therefore, we propose that a new genus, <i>Clavibacter</i>, be recognized to accommodate these organisms.</s><s>The saprophytic coryneform bacteria with similar cell wall compositions might also belong in this new genus, but further comparative studies seem to be warranted before such a transfer can be made with confidence.</s></p></content></protolog>