<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7199_nm.1286" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1286" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1286" rank="species">Rhizobium giardinii</organism><reference id="rid.7199"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Amarger</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macheret</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laguerre</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium gallicum sp. nov. and Rhizobium giardinii sp. nov., from Phaseolus vulgaris nodules</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>996</fpage><lpage>1006</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-996</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336898</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium giardinii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium giardinii</i> (giar.di'ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>giardinii</i>, of Giardini, in memory of Roberto Giardini, a Brazilian rhizobiologist who first isolated the organism during a doctoral stay in the Laboratoire de Microbiologie des Sols)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, motile, nonspore-forming rods that are 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide by 1.6 to 2.2 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on Bergersen's medium are circular, convex, white, translucent, and usually 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 2 to 3 days at 28°C.</s><s>These bacteria are unable to grow in Luria broth.</s><s>They utilize a wide range of carbohydrates as sole carbon sources for growth and a wide range of amino acids as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>They grow on lactate but not on erythritol or dulcitol and are resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>At the molecular level this species can be differentiated from other Rhizobium species and related genera by the results of DNA-DNA hybridization experiments, by the sequence of the 16s rRNA gene, and by amplified 16s rDNA restriction analysis data.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. giardinii</i> bv. giardinii strains nodulate <i>Phaseolus</i> spp., L. <i>leucocephala</i>, and <i>Macroptilium atropurpureum</i>.</s><s>They are not able to fix nitrogen with <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level this biovar can be differentiated from the other biovar by the absence of hybridization with a probe containing the nitrogenase reductase gene <i>nifH</i>, even under very low-stringency conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. giardinii</i> bv. phaseoli strains nodulate <i>Phaseolus</i> spp.</s><s>They can also nodulate <i>Macroptilium artropurpureum</i> but do so with a delay of at least 1 month after inoculation.</s><s>They do not nodulate <i>L. leucocephala</i>.</s><s>They are only weakly efficient in nitrogen fixation with <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level this biovar can be differentiated from the other biovar by the presence of three copies of the nitrogenase reductase gene <i>nifH</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain H152, which was isolated from a nodule of <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> grown in Bretennieres, France, is the type strain.</s><s>This strain has the characteristics described above for <i>R. giardinii</i> bv. giardinii.</s><s>Strain H152<sup>T</sup> and all of the other strains of <i>R. giardinii</i> have been deposited in the culture collection of the Laboratoire de Microbiologie des Sols, Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique, Dijon, France.</s><s>Strain H152<sup>T</sup> has been deposited as strain MSDJ0144<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>