<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4447_nm.3798" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3798" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3798" rank="species">Campylobacter hominis</organism><reference id="rid.4447"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>On</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stanley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter hominis sp. nov., from the human gastrointestinal tract.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>651</fpage><lpage>660</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter hominis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter hominis</i> (hom.in'is. L. gen. n. <i>hominis</i> of man, from which the bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods 0.25-0.5 μm wide and 0.5-1.8 μm long after 10 d incubation (first subculture following initial isolation) on FAA in an anaerobic atmosphere.</s><s>Colonies pinpoint to 1.0 mm in diameter, grey, some convex and entire, others flat and spreading.</s><s>Cells are straight, blunt-ended bacilli or coccobacilli.</s><s>Non-motile: flagella are not evident but certain isolates produce numerous irregular fimbriaelike structures (4-8 nm wide and &#x003E;1.0 μm long).</s><s>Optimal growth achieved on FAA under anaerobic conditions at 37 °C, but strains will grow on standard 5% blood agar media after adaptation to laboratory conditions.</s><s>Neither green or blue-green pigmented growth is observed on BA.</s><s>Pitting of the agar growth medium is absent.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>No, or extremely poor, growth is attained on either FAA or BA when incubated microaerobically at 37 °C.</s><s>No growth under aerobic conditions at either 25 or 37 °C.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Catalase, hippuricase, urease and alkaline phosphatase are not produced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is not produced in triple-sugar iron medium.</s><s>Indoxyl acetate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Neither triphenyltetrazolium chloride (TTC) nor selenite is reduced.</s><s>All strains grow under anaerobic conditions on media containing 1.0% glycine, 5-fluorouracil (100 U l<sup>-1</sup>), 0.1% sodium fluoride and 0.1% trimethylamine.</s><s>Moxide (TMAO).</s><s>No growth observed under anaerobic conditions at room temperature (18-22 °C), 25 °C or 42 °C, or on media containing 4.0% NaCl, 0.04% TTC, 0.1% potassium permanganate, 0.001%sodium arsenite, 32 mg cephalothin l<sup>-1</sup>, 4 mg metronidazole l<sup>-1</sup>, 32 mg carbenicillin l<sup>-1</sup> (nutrient and blood agar bases), 0±005% basic fuchsin, 0.0005% crystal violet, 0.1% janus green, 0.1% sodium deoxycholate or 0.02% pyronin.</s><s>No growth similarly observed on a minimal medium, or MacConkey, casein or tyrosine media.</s><s>Strains may differ in their ability to reduce nitrate, and grow on media containing 1.0%and 2.0% bile, and nalidixic acid (32 mg l<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>NCTC 13146<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 19568<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain of <i>C. hominis</i> sp. nov.</s><s>This strain conforms to the species description given above.</s><s>The G­+C content of NCTC 13146<sup>T</sup> DNA was 32.5 mol%.</s><s>The strain was isolated from the faeces of a healthy adult human male (London, UK) in 1998.</s></p></content></protolog>