<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3272_nm.11787" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11787" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6510" rank="species">Tsukamurella strandjordae</organism><reference id="rid.3272"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kattar</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cookson</surname><given-names>B.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carlson</surname><given-names>L.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stiglich</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schwartz</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names>T.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daza</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallis</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yarfitz</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coyle</surname><given-names>M.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella strandjordae sp. nov., a proposed new species causing sepsis</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>1467</fpage><lpage>1476</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.39.4.1467-1476.2001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11283073</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella strandjordae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella strandjordae</i> sp. nov. (strandjordae, in honor of Paul Strandjord, founder and chair of the Department of Laboratory Medicine, University of Washington, from 1969 to 1994)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, long, gram-positive rods and are slightly acid-fast with the modified Kinyoun stain.</s><s>Abundant growth is observed after 48 h on Trypticase soy agar, Middlebrook 7H11 agar, nutrient agar, and MacConkey agar without crystal violet.</s><s>Colonies are rough and pigmented tan to yellow, and range in size from 2 to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>The organism grows at 28 and 35°C but not at 42°C.</s><s>On tap water agar it produces short, branching substrate hyphae and diphtheroid forms but no aerial hyphae.</s><s>It does not hydrolyze xanthine, hypoxanthine, or tyrosine.</s><s>It is positive for semi quantitative catalase and 68°C heat-stable catalase, Tween 80 hydrolysis at 5 days, urease, pyrazinamidase, 5% NaCl tolerance, and iron uptake.</s><s>It does not hydrolyze nitrate at 2 weeks and is negative for arylsulfatase at 3 and 14 days.</s><s>The numerical profile with the API Coryne system after 2 days is 2550004, that with the RapID CB Plus system after 4 h is 0627511, and that with the API 20C AUX system after 6 days is 6063160.</s><s>In the API 50 CH system it can utilize galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, maltose, saccharose, trehalose, melezitose, D-turanose, L-fucose, gluconate, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, arbutine, salicine, and 2-ketogluconate as a sole carbon source and hydrolyzed esculin.</s><s>It does not utilize erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, amygdaline, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, inuline, D-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-fucose, L-fucose, gluconate, or 5-ketogluconate as a sole carbon source.</s><s>In the API ZYM system it is positive only for 2-naphthylphosphate, 2-naphthylcaprylate, L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, and bromo-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>It contains short, straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated fatty acids and tuberculostearic acid and long-chain mycolic acids, forming a single cluster of peaks on HPLC.</s><s>It can be distinguished from <i>T. paurometabola</i> and <i>T. pulmonis</i> by assimilation of inositol, D-mannose, arbutine, salicin, and inulin and can be distinguished from <i>T. inchonensis</i> and <i>T. tyrosinosolvens</i> by the absence of growth at 42°C and a lack of assimilation of hypoxanthine and tyrosine.</s><s>By the E-test it is susceptible to imipenem, amikacin, clarithromycin, ciprofloxacin, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>It has intermediate susceptibility to gentamicin and is resistant to cefoxitin, cefotaxime, tobramycin, erythromycin, and azithromycin (Schwartz et al., submitted).</s><s>It is characterized by a unique 16S rRNA gene sequence (GenBank accession no. AF283283).</s><s>The type strain has been deposited at the ATCC as strain ATCC BAA-173.</s></p></content></protolog>