<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3415_nm.1199" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1199" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1199" rank="species">Sphingomonas trueperi</organism><reference id="rid.3415"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Pseudomonas azotocolligans Anderson 1955, 132, in the genus Sphingomonas as Sphingomonas trueperi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>577</fpage><lpage>583</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-577</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103654</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingomonas trueperi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingomonas trueperi</i> (true'per.i. N. L. gen. n. <i>trueperi</i>, of Trüper, in honor of Hans G. Trüper, a German microbiologist, in recognition of his numerous contributions to the taxonomy of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Sphingomonas trueperi</i> is a gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming, motile, peritrichously flagellated organism (5).</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, entire, low convex, and smooth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 10% sodium chloride and 0.02% sodium azide.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Indole, urease, and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>β-Galactosidase positive.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>The following compounds are hydrolyzed: <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, <i>p</i>-nitrophe-nyl-α-L-arabinopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galacuronide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-glucopyranoside,<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucuronidpe, <i>p</i>nitrophenyl-β-D-melibiose, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-xyloside, bis-<i>p</i>-nitrophenylphosphate, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phenyl-phosphonate, <i>p</i>-nitrophenylphosphoryl-choline, 2-deoxythymidine-5'-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, D-alanine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, L-alanine-<i>p</i>nitroanilide, L-arginine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, γ-L-glutamate-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, glutamate-1-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, glycine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, L-lysine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, L-phenylalanine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, and L-valine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>p</i>-Nitrophenyl-N-acetyl-α-D-glucosaminep,- nitrophenyl-α-L-fucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactosaminide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-cellobioside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-fucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-lactoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-maltoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-Dmaltoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-L-rhamnopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-sulfate, acetyl-L-alanine-<i>p</i>-nitro-anilide, L-glutamate-γ-3-carboxyl-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, succinyl-L-phenylalanine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, acetyl-L-leucine<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, benzoyl-DL-arginine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, and L-proline-<i>p</i>-nitroani-lide are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are assimilated: D-glucose, L-arabhose, D-mannose, D-xylose, D-fructose, α-methyh-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, esculin, salicin, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, D-raffinose, amidon, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, L-fucose, L-malate, DL-malate, succinate, fumarate, DL-lactate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, <i>p</i>-arbutin, D-cellobiose, D-galactose, D-glucosamine, D-glucuronate, lactulose, D-maltose, D-mannoheptulose, α-D-melezitose, α-Dmelibiose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methybglucopyranoside, starch, D-sucrose, D-trehalose, acetamidocaprate, acetyl-L-glutamine, acetyl-L-proline, L-alanine, DL-2-aminoadipate, L-asparagine, L-aspartate, DL-aspartate, D-glutamate, L-glutamate, L-glutamine, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, phenylglycine, L-proline, L-valine, casein, malitol, tributyrin, DL-2-hydroxyisobutyrate, 2-hydroxyvalerate, oxalacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, 2-oxoisocaprate, L-butanol, L-leucineamide, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and protocatechuate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, lactose, lactulose, D-mannose, salicin, D-trehalose, D-turanose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, ribose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, sorbitol, inulin, glycogen, L-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, 5-ketogluconate, N-acetylgalactosamine, amygdalin, α-D-galacturonate, D-glucarate, D-glucosaminic acid, glycogen, glycyrrhizinate, L-mannose, β-methyl-D-xyloside, mucate, 5-oxogluconate, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, <i>m</i>-erythritol, i-inositol, D-mannitol, D-xylitol, 1-hexanol, acetyl-L-glutamate, acetylglycine, acetyl-DL-methionine, D-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, L-arginine, betaine, L-citrulline, dimethylglycine, L-histidine, L-hydroxyproline, DL-isoleucine, D-leucine, L-lysine, D-norvaline, L-norvaline, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, D-proline, sarcosine, L-serine, L-threonine, carnitine, creatine, putrescine, spermidine, tyramine, allantoine, cytosine, glycinamide, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, <i>n</i>-valerate, isovalerate, N-caproate, heptanoate, caprylate, pelargonate, caprate, oxalate, malonate, maleate, glutarate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, glycerophosphate, glyoxylate, 4-hydroxybutyrate, DL-2-hydroxyisovalerate, D-lactate, L-lactate, mesoxalate, 2-butanol, ethanol, hippurate, thiamine, ureidosuccinate, L-valinamide, anthranilate, 3-aminobenzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, 3-hydroxyphenylacetate, 4-hydroxyphenylacetate, quinate, salicylate, tropic acid, vanillate, glycolate, DL-glycerate, D-malate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>m</i>-tartrate, levulinate, 2-ketogluconate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, aconitate, citrate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalate, isophthalate, terephthalate, arabonic acid, dextran, sorbate, ~-2-hydroxyisocaprate, DL-isocitrate, tartronate, 1,8-octandiol, β-alanine, DL-aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-2-aminoisobutyrateam, inoxyacetate, D-arginine, D-asparagine, L-cysteinate, DL-2,4-diaminobutyrate, diaminopimelate, 2,3-diaminopropionate, L-glycine, glycinanhydride, D-histidine, L-homoserine, DL-δ-hydroxylysine, D-lysine, D-methioninesulfone, L-norleucine, D-phenylalanine, serine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, butylamine, cadaverine, ethanolamine, ethylamine, urea, hexylamine, spermine, taurine, trigonelline, tryptamine, acetamide, indole-3-acetate, oxamide acid, salicylamide, uracil, furan-2-carbonic acid, 2-hydroxyphenylacetate, phenoxyacetate, phenyllactate, phenylpropionate, and phenylpyruvate.</s><s>Acetate, butyrate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, malonate, glutarate, glycerate, glycolate, and propionate are weakly assimilated after 7 days of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acid is produced from D-arabinose, arabonic acid, dextran, α-D-galacturonate, gluconate, glucuronate, inulin, lactobionic acid, L-lyxose, D-maltose, glycogen, α-D-melezitose, α-D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-sucrose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, methyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, mucate, α-D-raffinose, D-ribose, L-sorbose, starch, D-tagatose, L-xylose, dulcitol, <i>m</i>-erythritol, glycerol, i-inositol, maltitol, D-xylitol, and tributyrin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 65.6 mol% (5).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>The main component in the polyamine pattern is <i>sym</i>-homospermidine (4).</s><s>The major nonpolar fatty acids are 18:1 and 16:0, and the major 2-hydroxy fatty acid is 14:0 2OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sphingoglycolipid, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, and an unknown lipid are the predominant polar lipids.</s><s>Phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine and four unknown lipids are present in minor concentrations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCIMB 9391 (=ATCC 12417=LMG 2142=DSM 7225).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The 16s rDNA sequence has been deposited in the EMBL data bank under accession number X97776.</s></p></content></protolog>