<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2384_nm.11241" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11241" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11241" rank="species">Pelagibacillus goriensis</organism><reference id="rid.2384"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>H.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pelagibacillus goriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halotolerant bacterium isolated from coastal water off the east coast of Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1554</fpage><lpage>1560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64820-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625193</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pelagibacillus goriensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pelagibacillus goriensis</em> (go.ri.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>goriensis</em> from Gori, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.7 μm wide and 1.5–4.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells produce ellipsoidal spores subterminally or centrally positioned within swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are circular, creamy white in colour and 3–5 mm in diameter on PYA plates after cultivation for 1 day.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 0–2 % (w/v), with a range of 0–14 % (at pH 7.5).</s><s>Growth is observed within the temperature range 15–43 °C (optimum, 30 °C), at pH values between 5.5 and 9 (optimum, pH 7.5).</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, Tweens 40, 60 and 80 and starch and is catalase- and DNase-positive.</s><s>According to the API 20NE system, hydrolysis of aesculin, gelatin and PNPG (<em>β</em>-galactosidase activity) occur, but indole is not produced and urease, arginine dihydrolase and nitrate reductase activities are absent.</s><s>According to the API 20E system, hydrolysis of gelatin and ONPG (<em>β</em>-galactosidase activity) occur, but arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are absent.</s><s>According to the API 50 CH system, acids are produced from d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-trehalose, aesculin, glycerol, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, salicin, arbutin, gentiobiose, d-tagatose and sucrose, but not from erythritol, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-turanose, l-lyxose, dl-fucose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, dl-arabinose, d-ribose, dl-xylose, inositol, d-sorbitol, d-maltose or inulin.</s><s>Utilizes citrate, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-raffinose, d-salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, lactose, l-ascorbate, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and pyruvic acid as sole carbon sources, but not acetate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, benzoate, dl-cysteine, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, glycerol, glycine, glycogen, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, l-arabinose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-proline, succinate, sucrose or tartrate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-GR16<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42329<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18252<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal water off the east coast of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>