<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9272_nm.14553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14553" rank="species">Aliagarivorans marinus</organism><reference id="rid.9272"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jean</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>S.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shieh</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aliagarivorans marinus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Aliagarivorans taiwanensis sp. nov., facultatively anaerobic marine bacteria capable of agar degradation</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1880</fpage><lpage>1887</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008235-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567569</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aliagarivorans marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aliagarivorans marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Cells during late exponential to early stationary phase of growth in broth cultures are straight rods, approximately 1.4–2.0 μm long and 1.0–1.2 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies produced on marine agar and PY plate medium at 30 °C for 4–7 days are circular (approx. 1–2 mm in diameter), off-white, opaque, convex, non-luminescent and agarolytic; agarolytic activity is indicated by the development of softening and depressions, but not by liquefaction of the agar surrounding the colonies.</s><s>Swarming does not occur.</s><s>Able to ferment d-glucose, d-arabinose (weakly), l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose (weakly), d-galactose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose (weakly), sucrose (weakly), trehalose, d-xylose, dulcitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol (weakly fermentative), d-mannitol and d-sorbitol (weakly) with production of acid, but no gas.</s><s>Unable to ferment d-ribose.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate is accumulated as an intracellular reserve product.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 37 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C; no growth occurs at 4–10 or 40–42 °C.</s><s>Sodium ions are required for growth; growth occurs at NaCl levels of 1–7 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 2–3 %, and no growth occurs at 0 or 8–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Able to grow over the pH range 7–9, but not at pH 5–6.</s><s>Not haemolytic.</s><s>Agar, alginate and gelatin are hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, cellulose, chitin, DNA, lecithin, starch, Tween 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are absent.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: leucine arylamidase, esterase (C4), <em>β</em>-galactosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Able to grow on the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, acetate, fumarate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate and l-glutamine.</s><s>Unable to grow on the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-xylose, trehalose, salicin, dulcitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, citrate, lactate, malate, succinate, tartaric acid, l-arginine, l-citrulline, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is AAM1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17888<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15522<sup>T</sup>), isolated from shallow coastal water from An-Ping Harbour, Tainan, Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>