<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3421_nm.6215" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6215" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6215" rank="species">Corynebacterium falsenii</organism><reference id="rid.3421"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izquierdo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akervall</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of some coryneform bacteria isolated from human clinical specimens as Corynebacterium falsenii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>69</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-69</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542078</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium falsenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium falsenii</i> (fal.se'ni.i. of N.L. gen. n. <i>falsenii</i> of Falsen, to honour the contemporary Swedish microbiologist and taxonomist Enevold Falsen, curator of the CCUG, for his lifelong contributions to bacterial taxonomy as well as for the systematic collection and characterization of prokaryotes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the characteristics given below is based on the results of studies of four strains.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and nonmotile.</s><s>They are typically club-shaped rods which appear as single cells, in pairs or in small clusters.</s><s>Colonies are whitish, circular with entire edges, convex, glistening, up to 2 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation, of creamy consistency, and start to develop a yellowish pigment after 72 h incubation.</s><s>Weak anaerobic growth.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, galactose, 5-keto-gluconate, glycerol, ribose and trehalose, but not from sucrose, mannitol, xylose, adonitol, amygdaline, arabinose, arabitol, arbutine, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, N-acetyl-glucosamine, methyl α-D-glucoside, glycogen, inositol, inulin, D-lyxose, methyl α-D-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, D-raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, D-turanose, xylitol and β-methyl-xyloside.</s><s>Acid production from maltose, fructose, lactose, rhamnose, D-tagatose is variable.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea hydrolysis is positive but delayed.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, tyrosine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>) and phosphoamidase activities are detected, but pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, agalactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Lipase, leucine arylamidase and cystine arylamidase activities are variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain CCUG 33651 has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg, Sweden.</s></p></content></protolog>