<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9676_nm.14815" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14815" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14815" rank="species">Arthrobacter psychrochitiniphilus</organism><reference id="rid.9676"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>f.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter psychrochitiniphilus sp. nov., a psychrotrophic bacterium isolated from Antarctica</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2759</fpage><lpage>2762</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008912-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625417</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter psychrochitiniphilus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter psychrochitiniphilus</em> (psy.chro.chi.ti.ni.phi′lus. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; N.L. n. <em>chitinum</em> chitin; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>psychrochitiniphilus</em> a cold, chitin-loving bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Individual cells show a distinct rod–coccus cycle.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative with motile rods.</s><s>Spores or capsules are not seen.</s><s>Colonies in LB medium at 20 °C are yellow, circular and convex.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–25 °C, the optimal growth temperature is around 20 °C.</s><s>Grows well at between 0 % and 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at pH 6–8.</s><s>Tween 80, starch, cellulose, lactose and chitin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin, lecithin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced and NH<sub>3</sub> production is positive.</s><s>Production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S is negative.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Growth occurs on lactose or chitin as the sole carbon source.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid pattern is dominated by anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A3<em>α</em>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Biolog tests show that the following compounds are utilized for respiration: dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, d-psicose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GP3<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13874<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6355<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the guano of Adélie penguins, Antarctica.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>