<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9283_nm.14568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1670" rank="subspecies">Polynucleobacter necessarius necessarius</organism><reference id="rid.9283"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brandt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Q.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheuerl</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Polynucleobacter and the species Polynucleobacter necessarius and proposal of two subspecies, P. necessarius subsp. necessarius subsp. nov. and P. necessarius subsp. asymbioticus subsp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2002</fpage><lpage>2009</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005801-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567561</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> subsp. <em>necessarius</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> subsp. <em>necessarius</em> (nec.es.sa′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>necessarius</em> indispensable, necessary).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Possesses the characteristics previously described by Heckmann &#x0026; Schmidt (1987) for the species <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em>.</s><s>Contains <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> strains obligately living as endosymbionts in cells of the ciliates <em>E. aediculatus</em> and <em>E. harpa</em>.</s><s>Includes <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> reference material contained in the <em>E. aediculatus</em> ‘stock 15’ culture (=E24=ATCC 30859) (Heckmann &#x0026; Schmidt, 1987) and the endosymbiontic strain STIR1 contained in the <em>E. aediculatus</em> STIR1 culture (Petroni <em>et al.</em>, 2002; Vannini <em>et al.</em>, 2007), as well as three strains detected in three cultures of the brackish water ciliate <em>E. harpa</em> (Vannini <em>et al.</em>, 2005, 2007).</s><s>Currently, it is assumed that <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> symbionts of different <em>Euplotes</em> species descended from a single endosymbiosis event; however, all phylogenetic analyses so far performed (Fig. 1) leave the possibility open of a polyphyletic origin by ancestry of endosymbionts of different <em>Euplotes</em> species from different free-living <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> strains.</s><s>Strains usually have elongated cells with cell lengths &#x003E;2.5 μm, and usually possess multiple nucleoid-like structures.</s><s>Genome size ranges from 1.5 to 1.8 Mbp.</s><s>All attempts to cultivate the obligate endosymbionts outside of their host cells have failed so far; therefore the subspecies lacks a type strain cultivated as a pure culture.</s><s>Thus the type of <em>Polynucleobacter necessarius</em> is a description based on endosymbionts in the culture ‘stock 15’ of the ciliate <em>E. aediculatus</em> (Heckmann &#x0026; Schmidt, 1987) deposited at the ATCC (as <em>E. aediculatus</em> E24, =ATCC 30859).</s><s>No strain designation exists.</s></p></content></protolog>