<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1410_nm.4016" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4016" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4016" rank="species">Clostridium scindens</organism><reference id="rid.1410"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Morris</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ritchie</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bokkenheuser</surname><given-names>V.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium scindens sp. nov., a human intestinal bacterium with desmolytic activity on corticoids.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>478</fpage><lpage>481</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-478</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium scindens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium scindens</i> (scin'dens [pronounced “skin'dens” or “sin'dens”] L. part. adj. <i>scindens</i>-splitting, because it produces a desmolase)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are nonmotile and stain gram positive.</s><s>Endospores are terminal and wider than the vegetative cell.</s><s>The spores are difficult to demonstrate microscopically but are observed in stains from chopped meat agar slants incubated at 30°C for 3 weeks.</s><s>Cultures from egg yolk agar plates incubated anaerobically at 30°C for 7 days survive heating at 80°C for 10 min and treatment with absolute ethanol for 30 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron microscopy.</s><s>This strain showed considerable pleomorphism.</s><s>Cells in the log phase of growth are rod shaped and slightly curved (about 0.5 to 0.7 by 1.0 to 2.5 μm) and occurred singly or in chains (Fig. 1).</s><s>Mesosomes are prominent at the septae in larger dividing cells.</s><s>Daughter cells usually share unequal amounts of cellular mass.</s><s>Small coccus-shaped cells (0.4 to 0.6 μm) occasionally are observed.</s><s>Cell walls separated from the cell are typically amorphous.</s><s>More than 40% of the cells are fimbriated, with fimbriae of 3.0 to 3.5 nm in diameter.</s><s>The fimbriae often are fascicled in clusters of 2 to 10 or more strands.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial morphology.</s><s>Colonies on anaerobically incubated blood agar plates (GasPak; BBL) are minute (little more than 0.1 mm in diameter) when first isolated.</s><s>In subsequent subcultures on blood agar plates, two colony types are observed: a small, common type with a diameter of 0.3 to 0.7 mm and a rarer type with a diameter of 1.3 to 2.0 mm.</s><s>After repeated subculturing, the larger colonies became more common.</s><s>All colonies are circular to slightly irregular, low convex, smooth, glistening, and greyish white with an entire periphery.</s><s>Neither sheep nor rabbit erythrocytes are hemolyzed.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 42°C;</s></p><p class="description"><s>good growth occurred at 37 and 45°C; growth is slow at 25°C, and none occurs at 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth growth.</s><s>Growth in glucose broth is turbid, with a smooth sediment after incubation for 24 h.</s><s>A mucoid sediment formed after incubation for 48 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic reactions.</s><s>D-Fructose, D-glucose, lactose, D-mannose, D-ribose, and D-xylose are fermented (pH 4.9 to 5.5).</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is detected in sulfide-indole-motility medium.</s><s>Abundant gas is produced in peptone-yeast extractglucose (1%) agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Amygdalin, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, esculin, glycogen, <i>myo</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, D-rafhose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, starch, sucrose, and D-trehalose are not fermented.</s><s>Gelatin, milk, and meat are not digested.</s><s>Neither indole, lecithinase, lipase, nor catalase is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Neither starch nor esculin is hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products of fermentation in peptone-yeast extractglucose broth are acetic acid and ethanol.</s><s>Abundant hydrogen is produced.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted to acetate; lactate is not utilized.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of deoxyribonucleic acid as determined by the thermal melting point methods (9, 13), is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is susceptible to penicillin G (2 U/ml) but resistant to chloramphenicol 12 μg/ml), clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enzymatic activity on steroids and bile acids. <i>C . scindens</i> synthesizes at least four enzymes active on steroidal substrates (24).</s><s>The steroid desmolase cleaves the C17-C20 bond of a variety of 17α-hydroxy steroids (Table 2).</s><s>In the absence of a hydroxyl group at C17, the side chain could not be removed, but the C<sub>2</sub>0 keto group of corticoids was reduced to a hydroxyl function in the α position.</s><s>Moreover, the organism synthesizes a 7α-dehydroxylase active on cholic and chenodeoxycholic acids and a 7β-dehydrogenase</s></p><p class="description"><s>active on ursodeoxycholic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerotolerance.</s><s>Pure cultures of <i>C. scindens</i> seeded on blood agar plates, left at room temperature under ordinary atmospheric conditions for 4, 8, and 24 h, and then incubated anaerobically at 37°C for 2 days form colonies; desmolase activity is retained (1)</s></p></content></protolog>