<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11685_nm.19291" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19291" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19291" rank="species">Georgenia halophila</organism><reference id="rid.11685"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Georgenia halophila sp. nov., a halophilic actinobacterium isolated from a salt lake</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1317</fpage><lpage>1321</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014993-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667374</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Georgenia halophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Georgenia halophila</em> (ha.lo.phi′la. Gr. n. <em>hals</em>, <em>halos</em> salt; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>halophila</em> salt-loving, referring to the ability of the type strain to grow at high NaCl concentrations).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile, non-endospore-forming, short rods (0.2–0.5 μm in diameter).</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, opaque, slightly convex, smooth and approximately 1.0 mm in diameter after 24 h at 37 °C.</s><s>No water-soluble exopigment is formed.</s><s>Grows at 10–45 °C, at pH 6.0–9.0 and in the presence of 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl; no growth is observed at 4 or 50 °C, above pH 10 or in the presence of 16 % NaCl; optimal growth occurs in the presence of 5–10 % NaCl, at pH 7.0–8.0 and at 37 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests are negative.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of starch, aesculin and Tween 80, but negative for hydrolysis of gelatin, chitin, cellulose, dextrin, urea, casein and Tweens 20, 40 and 60.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive.</s><s>In the API 50CHB system, acid is produced from glycerol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, aesculin, salicin, sucrose, d-lyxose, l-fucose and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-fructose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, dl-arabitol, potassium gluconate or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>In the API Coryne system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, pyrazinamidase and aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease and gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase, but negative for valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A4<em>α</em>.</s><s>The major whole-cell-wall sugars are rhamnose, glucosamine and galactose.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides, an unknown glycolipid and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>; minor straight-chain fatty acids are detected.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 70.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 93316<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21365<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AB 208144<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt lake sample collected from Qijiaojing Lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>