<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6247_nm.869" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.869" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.869" rank="species">Acetobacter indonesiensis</organism><reference id="rid.6247"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lisdiyanti</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawasaki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchimura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Systematic study of the genus Acetobacter with descriptions of Acetobacter indonesiensis sp. nov., Acetobacter tropicalis sp. nov., Acetobacter orleanensis (Henneberg 1906) comb. nov., Acetobacter lovaniensis (Frateur 1950) comb. nov., and Acetobacter estunensis (Carr 1958) comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>147</fpage><lpage>165</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12483588</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetobacter indonesiensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetobacter indonesiensis</i> (in.do.ne.si.en’sis. M. L. adj. <i>indonesiensis</i>, referring to Indonesia where most strains studied were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This group includes <i>A. pasteurianus</i> strains LMG 1571 and LMG 1588 and 15 Indonesian isolates.</s><s>No type strains of species or subspecies in the genus <i>Acetobacter</i> are included in this group.</s><s>Therefore a new species <i>Acetobacter indonesiensis</i> sp. nov. is proposed for this group.</s><s>Fifteen isolates were obtained from Indonesian fruits (banana, papaya, zirzak, and mango) and flowers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, measuring 0.8 to 1.0 by 1.8 to 2.0 μm, occurring singly, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, glistening, and nonpigmented.</s><s>No growth on D-mannitol.</s><s>Positive for catalase activity, oxidation of ethanol to acetic acid, oxidation of acetate and lactate to carbon dioxide and water, production of D-gluconate and 2-keto-D-gluconate from D-glucose, and acid production from D-glucose.</s><s>Acid production from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-galactose, and D-mannose is variable from strain to strain.</s><s>Negative for oxidase activity, formation of γ-pyrones from both D-glucose and D-fructose, and ketogenesis from glycerol.</s><s>The major quinone is Q-9.</s><s>The range of the G+C content of DNA is 53.3 to 55.1 mol%.</s><s>The level of 16S rDNA sequence similarity is in a range of 96.7 to 98.9% between the type strain of <i>A. indonesiensis</i> and the type strains of other <i>Acetobacter</i> species.</s><s>Found in fruits and flowers.</s><s>The type strain is 5H-1<sup>T</sup>, of which the G+C content is 53.7 mol%.</s><s>This strain was isolated from fruit of zirzak (<i>Annona muricata</i>).</s><s>The type strain has been deposited at the Culture Collection Center, Tokyo University of Agriculture, Tokyo, Japan, with the accession number NRIC 0313<sup>T</sup>, and at the Japan Collection of Microorganisms with the accession number JCM 10948 and the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, Japan, with the accession number IFO 16471<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>