<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9112_nm.14309" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14309" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14309" rank="species">Gracilimonas tropica</organism><reference id="rid.9112"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Noh</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilimonas tropica gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a Synechococcus culture.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1167</fpage><lpage>1172</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005512-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406813</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gracilimonas tropica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gracilimonas tropica</em> [tro′pi.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>tropica</em> tropical, of or pertaining to the tropic(s), relating to its isolation from a tropical ocean].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are long and thin rods, approximately 0.2–0.3 μm wide and 6.5–17.7 μm long.</s><s>Cells are non-motile.</s><s>On MA, colonies are circular, entire, convex, opaque and orange.</s><s>Does not produce flexirubin pigments.</s><s>Grows within the temperature range of 20–40 °C (optimum 35 °C), at pH 6–10 and at sea salt concentrations of 1–20 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth without sea salts in the medium.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, gelatin and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, positive for gelatinase activity but negative for nitrate reductase, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities, indole production, acid production from glucose and aesculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose in ZOF medium.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), weak lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, whereas <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Growth occurs on fructose, glucose and aspartate but not on acetate, citrate, galactose, mannitol, inositol, lactose, succinate or sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-CB462<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 90063<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19535<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a <em>Synechococcus</em> culture established from surface water of the tropical Pacific Ocean.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>