<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8773_nm.13779" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13779" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13779" rank="species">Singulisphaera acidiphila</organism><reference id="rid.8773"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kulichevskaya</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanovna</surname><given-names>A.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baulina</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bodelier</surname><given-names>P.L.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Damsté</surname><given-names>J.S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Singulisphaera acidiphila gen. nov., sp. nov., a non-filamentous, Isosphaera-like planctomycete from acidic northern wetlands.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1186</fpage><lpage>1193</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65593-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450711</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Singulisphaera acidiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Singulisphaera acidiphila</em> (a.ci.di′phi.la. N.L. n. <em>acidum</em> acid from L. adj. <em>acidus</em> sour; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>acidiphila</em> acid-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Has the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Mature cells are 1.6–2.6 μm in diameter.</s><s>Crateriform pits are scattered over the whole cell surface.</s><s>Carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v) include glucose, fructose, galactose, lactose, cellobiose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, trehalose, sucrose, xylose, leucrose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and salicin.</s><s>Ability to utilize fucose, lactate and pyruvate is variable.</s><s>Unable to utilize raffinose, sorbose, melezitose, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, starch, glucuronic acid, benzoate, caproate, citrate, formate, formaldehyde, fumarate, glutarate, malate, succinate, propionate, mannitol, tartrate, alanine, arginine, asparagine, aspartate, cysteine, cystine, glutamine, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, leucine, lysine, methionine, norleucine, ornithine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine or valine.</s><s>Capable of hydrolysing laminarin, pectin, chondroitin sulfate, aesculin, gelatin, pullulan, lichenan and xylan.</s><s>Unable to hydrolyse starch, chitin or cellulose.</s><s>Shows the following enzyme activities: alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API ZYM test).</s><s>Able to utilize the following nitrogen sources (0.05 %, w/v): ammonia, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, Bacto peptone, Bacto yeast extract, alanine, aspartate, arginine, glutamine, threonine, tryptophan and glycine.</s><s>Some strains can also utilize asparagine, isoleucine, lysine, phenylalanine, proline and valine.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not utilized.</s><s>Vitamins are not required.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, lincomycin, kanamycin and novobiocin, but sensitive to neomycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Capable of growth between pH 4.2 and 7.5 (optimum at pH 5.0–6.2) and at temperatures between 4 and 33 °C (optimum at 20–26 °C).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 0.5 % (w/v).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA varies between 57.8 and 59.9 mol% (59.9 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MOB10<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1392<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2454<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18658<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Obukhovskoe, Yaroslavl region, northern European Russia.</s><s>Strains PO2, MPL1015 and BG32, isolated from similar acidic wetlands, are also included in the species.</s></p></content></protolog>