<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5743_nm.6646" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6646" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6646" rank="species">Nocardioides plantarum</organism><reference id="rid.5743"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cockcroft</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallbanks</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analysis of a new LL-diaminopimelic acid-containing coryneform bacterium from herbage, Nocardioides plantarum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>523</fpage><lpage>526</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-523</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520740</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardioides plantarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardioides plantarum</i> (plan. tar' um. M. L. gen. pl. n. <i>plantarum</i>, of plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, short rods; coccoid forms also occur.</s><s>Neither substrate mycelium nor primary mycelium is formed.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, convex, smooth, shiny, and nonpigmented.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5 and 30°C, but not at 37°C or in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Thiamine is required for growth.</s><s>A wide range of organic compounds are utilized as sole or principal carbon and energy sources for growth; these compounds include cellobiose, fructose, glycerol, glucose, maltose, melezitose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, D-xylose, isobutyrate, propionate, fumarate, and succinate.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-galactose, histidine, histamine, malonate, phenol, azelate, suberate, crotonate, pentoate, thymine, and uracil are not utilized.</s><s>Some strains utilize L-proline and tetradecane.</s><s>Casein, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, and gelatin are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Cellulose, chitin, urea, starch, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The cell wall murein contains LL-A<sub>2</sub>pm as the diamino acid.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) is the main menaquinone component; a minor amount of MK-7(H<sub>4</sub>) is also produced.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of saturated, unsaturated, and iso-, anteiso-, and 10-methyl-branched types.</s><s>Small amounts of 2-hydroxy fatty acids are also synthesized.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 69 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from herbage.</s><s>The type strain is NCIMB 12834 (= Grainger 570).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to that of the species given above, except that L-proline and tetradecane are not utilized.</s></p></content></protolog>