<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7486_nm.4554" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4554" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4554" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter siderophilus</organism><reference id="rid.7486"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuznetsov</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kostrikina</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chernyh</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonch-Osmolovskaya</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermoanaerobacter siderophilus sp. nov., a novel dissimilatory Fe(III)-reducing, anaerobic, thermophilic bacterium.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1478</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555328</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter siderophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter siderophilus</i> (si.de.ro'phil.us. Gr. n. <i>sideros</i> iron; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>siderophilus</i> iron-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight-to-curved rods, 0.4-0.6 μm in diameter and 3.5-9.0 μm in length, forming round, refractile, heat-resistant endospores in terminally swollen sporangia.</s><s>Cells occur singly and exhibit slight tumbling motility due to peritrichous flagellation.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 39-78°C, with an optimum at 69-71°C.</s><s>Neutrophilic: pH range for growth is from 4.8 to 8.2, with an optimum at 6.3-6.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in an NaCl concentration range of 0-3.5 % (w/v).</s><s>The substrates utilized in the presence, as well in the absence, of Fe(III) as an electron acceptor include peptone, yeast extract, beef extract, starch, glycerol, pyruvate, glucose, sucrose, fructose, maltose, xylose, cellobiose and sorbitol.</s><s>Utilizes molecular hydrogen in the presence of Fe(III).</s><s>No growth occurs with formate, acetate, lactate, methanol, ethanol, propan-1-ol, propan-2-ol, butan-1-ol, propionate, <i>n</i>-butyrate, succinate, malate, maleate, glycine, alanine, arginine, L-arabinose, olive oil, xylan or cellulose, either with or without Fe(III) as an electron acceptor.</s><s>The fermentation products from glucose are ethanol, lactate, H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Reduces amorphous iron(III) oxide, AQDS, sulfite, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur and MnO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The products of amorphous iron(III) oxide reduction are magnetite and siderite.</s><s>Sulfite, thiosulfate and elemental sulfur are reduced to hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate or sulfate and is incapable of growth with O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, neomycin, polymyxin B and kanamycin but not by penicillin, ampicillin, streptomycin or novobiocin.</s><s>G + C content of DNA of the type strain is 32 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is hydrothermal vents in the area of Karymsky volcano on the Kamchatka peninsula, Russia.</s><s>The type strain is SR4<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen under the accession number DSM 12299<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>