<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10_nm.6804" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6804" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6804" rank="species">Saccharothrix cryophilis</organism><reference id="rid.10"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lechevalier</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amendment of the genus Saccharothrix Labeda et al. 1984 and descriptions of Saccharothrix espanaesis sp. nov., Saccharothrix cryophilis sp. nov, and Saccharothrix mutabilis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>420</fpage><lpage>423</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-420</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s><i>Saccharothrix cryophilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix cryophilis</i> (cry. o. phil’ is. L. adj. <i>cryophilis</i>, cold loving, referring to the low permissive temperature range for growth).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pale yellow substrate mycelium is produced on most media.</s><s>White to yellowish white aerial mycelium is produced, particularly on inorganic salts-starch agar or glycerol-asparagine agar.</s><s>No soluble pigments are produced.</s><s>Esculin, tyrosine, and urea are hydrolyzed or decomposed, but adenine, allantoin, casein, hippurate, hypoxanthine, starch, and xanthine are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced.</s><s>Acetate, DL-lactate, DL-malate, oxalate, propionate, and succinate are assimilated; benzoate, citrate, mucate, and DL-tartrate are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, and trehalose; no acid is produced from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, dulcitol, meso-erythritol, melibiose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-xylose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, and β-methyl-D-xyloside; and acid production from glycerol and raffinose is variable.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 4% NaCl but not in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 33°C.</s><s>The guanine-pluscytosine content of the DNA is 71.4 mol% (thermal denaturation midpoint method).</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>Produces the antibiotic dopsisamine.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. cryophilis</i> is strain NRRL B-16238 (= IF0 14475 = Y.</s><s>Okami TS-1980).</s></p></content></protolog>