<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3007_nm.14003" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14003" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7532" rank="species">Nocardiopsis albus</organism><reference id="rid.3007"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grund</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chemotaxonomy and numerical taxonomy of the genus Nocardiopsis Meyer 1976.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-5</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis albus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis albus</i>  (al' bus. L. adj. <i>albus</i>, white, referring to the white aerial mycelium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on our observations of strains DSM 43119 (= IMRU 711), DSM 43120 (= IMRU 1572), DSM 43377<sup>T</sup> (= Goodfellow A29<sup>T</sup>), and DSM 43378 (= Goodfellow A119)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A slightly yellow substrate mycelium with white aerial mycelium is formed on all complex media which have been tested.</s><s>The spore chains are recti-flexibilis, and in early stages of sporulation a zigzag-shaped aerial mycelium is observed.</s><s>The best formation of aerial mycelium appears when the organism is grown on Czapek-Dox agar supplemented with yeast extract (2.0 g/liter), Casamino Acids (6.1 g/liter), and tryptophan (20 mg/liter).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin, adenine, hypoxanthine, and xanthine are hydrolyzed by all four strains of <i>Nocardiopsis albus</i> subsp. <i>albus</i>; tyrosine is hydrolyzed by only three strains.</s><s>Calcium oxalate crystals are not solubilized.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, cellobiose, sucrose, and dextrin are used as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>Arabinose and sorbitol are utilized by only one of the four strains.</s><s>Xylose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, lactose, adonitol, and <i>myo</i>-inositol are not utilized.</s><s>An alkaline reaction is observed with citrate, lactate, malate, and malonate; no alkaline reaction occurs with quinate as the carbon source.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5% NaCl and not in the presence of 50 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Benzoic acid, salicylic acid, <i>meta</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid, and parahydroxybenzoic acid are not degraded.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28°C; no growth occurs at 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Nocardiopsis albus</i> subsp. <i>albus</i> is easily differentiated from <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i> by its inability to utilize arabinose, xylose, and rhamnose and to hydrolyze calcium oxalate crystals.</s><s>Tyrosine crystals are hydrolyzed by <i>Nocardiopsis albus</i> subsp. <i>albus</i> but not by <i>Nocardiopsis dassonvillei</i>.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis albus</i> subsp. <i>albus</i> is strain DSM 43377.</s></p></content></protolog>