<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12627_nm.22163" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22163" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22163" rank="species">Primorskyibacter sedentarius</organism><reference id="rid.12627"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetashev</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Primorskyibacter sedentarius gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the class Alphaproteobacteria from shallow marine sediments</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1572</fpage><lpage>1578</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025551-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20675440</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Primorskyibacter sedentarius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Primorskyibacter sedentarius</em> (se.den.ta′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>sedentarius</em> sedentary, non-motile).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 1.2–1.5 µm in diameter and 2.5–3.5 µm long.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Produces whitish, opaque, smooth and shiny colonies with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter, on MA.</s><s>Bchl <em>a</em> is not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0.5–8 % NaCl (w/v) and is optimal in 3–5 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows in/on basal medium containing NaCl alone without any of the sea salts components MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub> and MgSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>Grows at 4–39 °C, with optimum growth at 25–30 °C; weak growth at 40 °C, and no growth above 40 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.5–9.5, with optimum growth at pH 7.5–8.5.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, chitin and starch and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of DNA, Tweens 80, 40 and 20 and l-tyrosine.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, brown diffusible pigments are produced and a clearance zone is formed.</s><s>No acid production from d-glucose, maltose, d-galactose, sucrose, lactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, melibiose, d-ribose, fructose, l-sorbose, raffinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol or d-mannitol.</s><s>In API 20NE strips, positive for the PNPG test and aesculin hydrolysis and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification under anaerobic conditions, gelatin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, urease and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In ID32 GN strips, negative for assimilation of l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, maltose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, d-mannitol, d-glucose, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, l-arabinose, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and α-glucosidase, weakly positive for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>Positive for utilization of d-glucose, maltose, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, sucrose, fructose, raffinose, cellobiose, d-mannitol, ornithine, l-tyrosine, l-asparagine, citrate, acetate, fumarate and malate as carbon and energy sources, weakly positive for utilization of d-galactose, d-mannose, glycerol, inositol, l-arginine and l-α-alanine and negative for utilization of dl-leucine, dl-β-phenylalanine, dl-lysine, l-methionine and aminoacetic acid.</s><s>Utilization of l-xylose is strain-dependent (type strain positive).</s><s>Detailed fatty acid and polar lipid compositions are listed in Table 2.</s><s>Susceptible to (amount per disc) ampicillin (10 µg), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), rifampicin (5 µg), streptomycin (30 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), ofloxacin (5 µg), oxacillin (10 µg), neomycin (30 µg), oleandomycin (15 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), cephazolin (30 µg), cephalexin (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and chloramphenicol (30 µg); resistant to kanamycin (30 µg), lincomycin (15 µg) and polymyxin (300 U).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 60.2–61.9 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain KMM 9018<sup>T</sup> ( = NRIC 0784<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16874<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sample of shallow sediment collected from the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s><s>A second strain of the species, KMM 9015, was isolated from the same sample.</s></p></content></protolog>