<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9561_nm.14734" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14734" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14734" rank="species">Corynebacterium maris</organism><reference id="rid.9561"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ben-Dov</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yosef</surname><given-names>D.Z.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pavlov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kushmaro</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium maris sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from the mucus of the coral Fungia granulosa</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2458</fpage><lpage>2463</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007468-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622641</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium maris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium maris</em> (ma′ris. L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, aerobic (catalase- and oxidase-positive), non-spore-forming coccobacilli approximately 0.5–0.8 μm in width and 0.8–1.5 μm in length.</s><s>The species is non-haemolytic and forms small colonies (approximately 1 mm and 2.5 mm in diameter after 48 and 72 h, respectively, incubation at 30 °C) that are yellowish to yellow, circular, convex, smooth and opaque.</s><s>Grows well at 0.5–4.0 % salinity, at pH 7.2–9.0 and at 30–37 °C.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and gelatin hydrolysis activities are detected.</s><s>No activity is observed for reduction of nitrates, valine and cystine arylamidases, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, urease, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The strain utilizes the following carbon compounds as sole energy sources: maltose, lactulose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, Tween 40, phenylethylamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, malonic acid, l-threonine, l-glutamic acid, l-fucose, l-alanyl glycine, inosine and, less efficiently, raffinose, d-arabitol, l-asparagine and citric acid, as determined with the Biolog GN system.</s><s>Long-chain fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated and mono-unsaturated types, with C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and tuberculostearic acid (10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>) predominating.</s><s>Mycolic acids (C<sub>30</sub>–C<sub>36</sub>) are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Coryn-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45190<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24561<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the mucus of the coral <em>Fungia granulosa</em>, Gulf of Eilat, Red Sea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>