<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2676_nm.8030" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8030" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8030" rank="species">Porphyromonas gingivicanis</organism><reference id="rid.2676"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hirasawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Porphyromonas gingivicanis sp. nov. and Porphyromonas crevioricanis sp. nov., isolated from beagles.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>637</fpage><lpage>640</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-637</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7981094</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas gingivicanis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas gingivicanis</i> (gin.gi.vi.ca'nis. L. fem. n. <i>gingiva</i>, the gums; L. gen. n. <i>canis</i>, of a dog; N. L. gen. n. <i>gingivicanis</i>, of the gums of a dog, because the organism was first isolated from gums of dogs)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from gingival crevicular fluids obtained from beagles.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, nonmotile, gram negative, and rod shaped (or coccoid) and do not form spores.</s><s>On rabbit blood agar plates, the average size of cells is 0.5 pm by 1.0 μm in diameter, and the cells occur singly.</s><s>After 72 h of incubation, surface colonies are 0.8 to 1.5 mm in diameter, circular, entire, dome shaped, opaque, and brown or black.</s><s>Vitamin K and hemin are required for growth.</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentation is not detected in medium containing glucose, mannose, lactose, sucrose, cellobiose, trehalose, xylose, or arabinose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 to 42 mol%.</s><s>The major fermentation products in GAM broth are acetic acid (average, 43.4 μmol/ml), butyric acid (average, 31.9 μmol/ml), and isovaleric acid (average, 21.O μmol/ml).</s><s>Smaller quantities of isobutyric acid (average, 8.5 μmol/ml), succinic acid (average, 8.3 μmol/ml), and propionic acid (average, 1.4 μmol/ml) are produced.</s><s>iso-C<sub>15:)</sub> acid is the major cellular fatty acid.</s><s>Malate and glutamate dehydrogenase activities are present, but 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase and glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase activities are not (Table 1).</s><s>Does not produce phenylacetic acid when cells are grown in GAM medium.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Cells neither agglutinate sheep erythrocytes nor exhibit trypsin or N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activity.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to penicillin (0.5 U/disk), amoxicillin (2 μg/disk), sulbenicillin (5 μg/disk), and erythromycin (0.5 μg/disk).</s><s>The type strain is NUM 301 (= ATCC</s></p><p class="description"><s>55562).</s></p></content></protolog>