<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.59_nm.1102" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1102" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1102" rank="species">Paracoccus kocurii</organism><reference id="rid.59"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ohara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Katayama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsuzaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamoto</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuraishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus kocurii sp. nov., a tetramethylammonium-assimilating bacterium.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>292</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-292</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397197</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Puracoccus kocurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Puracoccus kocurii</i> (ko.cu'ri.i. N. L. Gen. n. <i>kocurii</i> of Kocur; named for Miloslav Kocur, Czechoslovakian bacteriologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colonial appearance and assimilation of organic compounds of all of the isolates were quite similar.</s><s>Further characterization was carried out on strains BT, El, and F1.</s><s>The isolates are gram-negative, nonmotile, short rods (0.5 to 0.8 by 0.7 to 1.1 μm) (Fig. 1).</s><s>Colonies are pinhead size, circular, smooth, convex, entire, transparent, and yellowish white on nutrient agar and pinhead size, circular, entire, convex, transparent, and brownish white on TMA agar after 10 days of incubation.</s><s>Production of pigment was not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum temperature for the growth is between 25 and 30°C; no growth occurs at 20 or 40°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum pH for the growth is between pH 6.6 and pH 8.2; no growth occurs below pH 6.1 or above pH 8.8, which distinguishes the isolates from <i>Paracoccus alkaliphilus</i>(13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The isolate is facultatively anaerobic, uses nitrate as a terminal electron acceptor, and evolves gas.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl, but no growth is produced in 3% NaCl (Table 2), which is distinct from <i>Paracoccus halodenitrificans</i>, which grows optimally in the presence of 4.4 to 8.8% NaCl(7).</s><s>The isolates use ammonium salt as a nitrogen source but are unable to grow on nitrate or glutamate.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are produced, but urease activity is not.</s><s>Cells require thiamine for growth.</s><s>Thiosulfate does not support their growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Assimilation of organic compounds by TMA degraders is restricted to a narrow range of substrates, as shown in Table 3.</s><s>The isolates are unable to use the amino acids or sugars examined, These assimilations are different from those of <i>Paracoccus denitrificans</i>, which has versatile abilities on amino acids and sugars.</s><s>The isolate grows on TMA, trimethylamine  trimethylamine-N-oxide, dimethylamine, and methylamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major respiratory quinone is Q-10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18:1</sub> and C<sub>19cyc</sub>, as nonpolar acids, and 3-OH C<sub>10:0</sub> and 3-OH C<sub>12:0</sub>, as hydroxy acids (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The base composition of DNA of the type strain is 71 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain B (=JCM 7684).</s><s>The organism was isolated from activated sludge for the treatment of TMA hydroxide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differential characteristics among species of <i>Paracoccus</i> are given in Tables 2, 3, and 4.</s><s>Since taxonomic studies on microorganisms using the quinone system show that differentiation of taxa is at the genus level, the fact that <i>Paracoccus halodenitrificans</i> contained Q-9 as the major quinone system may indicate that further taxonomic studies are required on <i>Paracoccus halodenitrificans</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>