<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5216_nm.6615" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6615" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6615" rank="species">Propionibacterium australiense</organism><reference id="rid.5216"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shuttleworth</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Munro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forbes-Faulkner</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitt</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Norton</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionibacterium australiense sp. nov. derived from granulumatous bovine lesions.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>41</fpage><lpage>47</lpage><source id="225">Anaerobe</source><issn>1075-9964</issn><essn>1095-8274</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/anae.2000.0408</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionibacterium australiense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionibacterium australiense</i> (aus.tral.i.ense, M.L neut. n., referring to Australia, the country where the bacterium was first recovered)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacterial cells are Gram-positive, asporogenic, pleomorphic rods, observed to be variable in length with occasional branching or slightly curved forms.</s><s>The bacterium upon initial isolation may require 5 days to grow, but will grow abundantly in 24–48 h growth on BHIA at 35EC under anaerobic atmosphere after repeated subculture.</s><s>Colonies after growth on BHIA are nonhaemoytic, cream coloured, shiny, rounded, convex and are not adherent to agar.</s><s>They are able to grow poorly in 5% CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere but grow best under strictly anaerobic conditions.</s><s>They grow well in PY with or without glucose supplementation but not in the presence of 20% bile.</s><s>They are catalase and oxidase negative, and non-motile.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolysed and nitrate reduced.</s><s>They are negative for indole, gelatin hydrolysis, starch hydrolysis, urease production, meat digestion and CAMP or reverse CAMP reaction.</s><s>No gas is observed after glucose fermentation.</s><s>All strains ferment adonitol, fructose, glucose and inositol.</s><s>No strain ferments amygdalin, arabinose, cellibiose, erythritol, glycogen, maltose, melezitose, rhamnose, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>The reactions for galactose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, ribose and salicin are variable.</s><s>Products of glucose fermentation included acetic, propionic and succinic acids.</s><s>CFA composition was of the branched-chain or saturated type.</s><s>Mesodiaminopimelic acid was found in the cell wall.</s><s>The type strain 98A072 has been deposited as ATCC BAA- 264<sup>T</sup> and CCUG 46075<sup>T</sup> with characteristics as shown in Table 2.</s><s>Nearly full sequence of the 16S rRNA gene derived from the type strain has been deposited in Genbank with accession no. AF225962.</s><s>The bacterium was isolated from granulomatous lesions from bovines in Queensland, Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>