<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4444_nm.3202" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3202" rank="genus">Klebsiella</organism><reference id="rid.4444"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Drancourt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bollet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rousselier</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic analyses of Klebsiella species delineate Klebsiella and Raoultella gen. nov., with description of Raoultella ornithinolytica comb. nov., Raoultella terrigena comb. nov. and Raoultella planticola comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>925</fpage><lpage>932</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411716</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Klebsiella</i> (Trevisan 1885) Ørskov 1984</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>On the basis of the evidence presented above, it is proposed that the genus <i>Klebsiella</i> should be divided into two genera, <i>Klebsiella</i> and <i>Raoultella</i> gen. nov. and that `<i>K. oxytoca</i>' should be left as a monophyletic species. This proposal requires emending the description of the genus <i>Klebsiella</i> (érskov, 1984) together with a description of the new genus <i>Raoultella</i>. Straight rods, 0.3-1.0 μm in diameter and 0.6-6.0 μm in length, arranged singly, in pairs or short chains. Conform to the general definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>. Capsulated. Gram-negative. Nonmotile. Facultatively anaerobic, having both a respiratory and a fermentative type of metabolism. Grow on meat extract medium, producing more or less dome-shaped, glistering colonies of varying degrees of stickiness, depending on the strain and the composition of the medium. Does not grow at 10 °C. There are no special growth factor requirements. Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive. Most strains can use citrate and glucose as sole carbon source, but cannot use L-sorbose as sole carbon source. Glucose is fermented with the production of acid and gas and most strains produce 2,3-butanediol as a major end product of glucose fermentation. Voges-Proskauer test is usually positive. Recovered from mammalmucosae, including human specimens. Type species is <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subsp. <i>pneumoniae</i> and the type strain is <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subsp. <i>pneumoniae</i> ATCC 13883<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 82.91<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>