<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8755_nm.13004" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13004" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7711" rank="subspecies">Bifidobacterium longum suis</organism><reference id="rid.8755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mattarelli</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonaparte</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal to reclassify the three biotypes of Bifidobacterium longum as three subspecies: Bifidobacterium longum subsp. longum subsp. nov., Bifidobacterium longum subsp. infantis comb. nov. and Bifidobacterium longum subsp. suis comb. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>767</fpage><lpage>772</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65319-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398167</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium longum</em> subsp. <em>suis</em> (Matteuzzi, Crociani, Zani and Trovatelli 1971) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bifidobacterium longum</em> subsp. <em>suis</em> (su′is. L. n. <em>sus</em> pig; L. sing. gen. n. <em>suis</em> of a pig).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slender cells, elongated (2–6 μm long), with rare terminal bifurcations in the shape of clubs.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Colonies are circular, soft, smooth, white with entire margins.</s><s>Liquid cultures are at first turbid, after 24–36 h become clear with sediment dispersible by agitation.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> without effect on O<sub>2</sub> sensitivity or anaerobic growth.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Optimum growth at 38–39 °C, minimum 19–20 °C, maximum 44.5–45 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth at pH 7–8; no growth at pH 5.0 or 9.5.</s><s>Sugars fermented: arabinose, xylose, glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose.</s><s>Rhamnose, melezitose, cellobiose, trehalose, dextrin, starch, inulin, sorbitol, mannitol, glycerol, salicin, gluconate and lactate are never fermented.</s><s>No growth in carbohydrate-free media.</s><s>The end products of glucose fermentation are lactic (LA) and acetic acids (AA), in the ratio 1.0(LA) :  1.7(AA) to 1.0(LA)  : 2.0(AA).</s><s>Glucose is fermented by fructose-6-phosphate shunt.</s><s>Cell-free extracts contain fructose-6-phosphate phosphoketolase, aldolase and HMP dehydrogenase.</s><s>Nitrites not produced from nitrates.</s><s>Indole and acetyl-methyl-carbinol not produced.</s><s>Most strains possess a constitutive urease activity, which is not influenced by urea or organic nitrogen sources.</s><s>Skimmed milk: acidification followed by coagulation in 1–2 days.</s><s>Riboflavin is the only growth factor required for growth.</s><s>The above description is based on data obtained from Matteuzzi <em>et al.</em> (1971).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on DNA relatedness (66–81 %), this subspecies is most closely related to <em>B. longum</em> subsp. <em>infantis</em> and <em>B. longum</em> subsp. <em>longum</em> (Lauer &#x0026; Kandler, 1983; Bahaka <em>et al.</em>, 1993; Sakata <em>et al.</em>, 2002).</s><s>So far, found only in the faeces of piglets.</s><s>The genomic G+C content is 62 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Su859<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 27533<sup>T</sup>=DSM 20211<sup>T</sup>), from faeces of piglet (Matteuzzi <em>et al.</em>, 1971).</s></p></content></protolog>