<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1566_nm.10652" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10652" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4357" rank="species">Carboxydothermus ferrireducens</organism><reference id="rid.1566"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sokolova</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens as Carboxydothermus ferrireducens comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Carboxydothermus.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2349</fpage><lpage>2351</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64503-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012560</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Carboxydothermus ferrireducens</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Carboxydothermus ferrireducens</em> [fer.ri.re.du′cens. L. n. <em>ferrum</em> iron; L. part. adj. <em>reducens</em> converting to a different state; N.L. part. adj. <em>ferrireducens</em> reducing (ferric) iron].</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens</em> Slobodkin <em>et al.</em> 1997.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on that published previously for <em>Thermoterrabacterium ferrireducens</em> (Slobodkin <em>et al.</em>, 1997) with the additional data obtained by Gavrilov <em>et al.</em> (2003), Henstra &#x0026; Stams (2004) and during this study.</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, 0.3–0.4 μm in diameter and 1.6–2.7 μm in length with rounded ends.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs, with retarded peritrichous flagellation, and exhibit tumbling motility.</s><s>Spores are not observed.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Grows in mineral medium without supplementation with complex media components.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 50–74 °C with an optimum at 65 °C.</s><s>The pH<sup>65 °C</sup> range for growth is 5.5–7.6, with an optimum at 6.0–6.2.</s><s>No growth was observed at or below 48 °C, at or above 76 °C, at or below pH<sup>65 °C</sup> 5.3 and at or above pH<sup>65 °C</sup> 7.8.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations in the range of 0–1.0 % (w/v).</s><s>In the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>, the type strain is able to grow with glycerol as the only organic carbon source.</s><s>Couples the oxidation of glycerol to reduction of ferrihydrite [poorly crystalline Fe(III) oxide], Fe(III) citrate or Fe(III) EDTA as electron acceptors.</s><s>In the presence as well as in the absence of Fe(III) and in the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>, glycerol is oxidized incompletely to acetate as the only organic metabolic product, leading to a ratio of more than one acetate molecule produced per glycerol molecule consumed.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, lactate, 1,2-propanediol, glycerate, pyruvate, yeast extract and peptone.</s><s>Grows weakly on glucose, fructose and mannose, producing acetate as the only organic product.</s><s>In the presence of ferrihydrite, grows lithoautotrophically with molecular hydrogen as an electron donor and CO<sub>2</sub> as the only carbon source.</s><s>Utilizes CO with ferrihydrite, fumarate or 9,10-anthraquinone 2,6-disulfonate as electron acceptors, without the production of molecular hydrogen or acetate.</s><s>No growth occurs with acetate, methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, 2-propanol, 1-butanol, propionate, acetone, ethylene glycol, 1,3-propanediol, fumarate, succinate, phenol, benzoate, 9,10-anthraquinone 2,6-disulfonate, starch, olive oil, elemental sulfur, sucrose, galactose, xylose, cellobiose or arabinose with or without Fe(III).</s><s>Reduces Fe(III) to Fe(II), 9,10-anthraquinone 2,6-disulfonate to 9,10-anthrahydroquinone 2,6-disulfonate, fumarate to succinate, thiosulfate to elemental sulfur or sulfide, sulfite to sulfide, elemental sulfur to sulfide and nitrate to nitrite and ammonium.</s><s>Does not reduce MnO<sub>2</sub> or sulfate.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by chloramphenicol, erythromycin and rifampicin at 100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup> but not by 100 μg ampicillin, streptomycin or tetracycline ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 41 mol% G+C (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JW/AS-Y7<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11255<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2392<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a freshwater hot spring in the Calcite Springs area of Yellowstone National Park, WY, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>