<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8832_nm.13801" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13801" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13801" rank="species">Wohlfahrtiimonas chitiniclastica</organism><reference id="rid.8832"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tóth</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Borsodi</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kéki</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kovács</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márialigeti</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Wohlfahrtiimonas chitiniclastica gen. nov., sp. nov., a new gammaproteobacterium isolated from Wohlfahrtia magnifica (Diptera: Sarcophagidae).</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>976</fpage><lpage>981</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65324-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398205</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Wohlfahrtiimonas chitiniclastica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Wohlfahrtiimonas chitiniclastica</em> (chi.ti.ni.clas′ti.ca. N.L. neut. n. <em>chitinum</em>, chitin; Gr. adj. <em>klastos</em>, broken in pieces; N.L. adj. <em>clasticus</em>, breaking; N.L. fem. adj. <em>chitiniclastica</em>, chitin-cleaving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, short rods (1.5–2.0×0.5–1 μm), non-motile, occurring singly at all ages.</s><s>On King B agar medium colonies are non-pigmented, small, convex, entire, smooth and glistening.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs between pH 5.0 and 10.5, temperature optimum is at 28–37 °C.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Negative in Voges–Proskauer, aesculin, urease, indole, caseinase, gelatinase, amylase and H<sub>2</sub>S production tests, as well as for Tween 80 utilization.</s><s>Strong chitinase activity.</s><s>Based on Biolog test results, both strains were positive for oxidation of glycogen, Tween 80, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-psicose, mono-methylsuccinate, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-threonine, glycerol, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid and dl-lactic acid, but negative for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, malonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid and itaconic acid.</s><s>A varied reaction between the strains was observed for Tween 40, melibiose, methylpyruvate, l-leucine, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and 2,3-butanediol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, isolated from 3rd stage larvae of <em>Wohlfahrtia magnifica</em> (Diptera: Sarcophagidae), is S5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18708<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7401<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>