<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6231_nm.3292" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3292" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3292" rank="subspecies">Salmonella enterica enterica</organism><reference id="rid.6231"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Le Minor</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Popoff</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Request for an Opinion. Designation of Salmonella enterica sp. nov., nom. rev., as the type and only species of the genus Salmonella.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>465</fpage><lpage>468</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-465</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Salmonella enterica</i> supsp. <i>enterica</i> supsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Salmonella enterica</i> supsp. <i>enterica</i> (Gr. n. <i>enteron</i>, gut; L. adj. <i>enterica</i>, of the gut)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. enterica</i> is that of <i>S. choleraesuis</i> sensu Le Minor et al. (24).</s><s>Strains of <i>S. enterica</i> have the following properties typical of the family <i><i>Enterobacteriaceae</i></i> (3).</s><s>Gram-negative straight rods, 0.5 to 1.5 by 2.0 to 0.5 μm.</s><s>Oxidase negative, catalase positive, reduce nitrate to nitrite, ferment D-glucose, and grow well on media containing peptone or meat extract.</s><s>Usually motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Nitrate reductase is of type A (26).</s><s>Urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phenylalanine and tryptophan not deaminated.</s><s>Lipase and deoxyribonuclease not produced.</s><s>Gas usually produced from glucose and H<sub>2</sub>S produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Tetrathionate reduced to thiosulfate (20), indole not produced, citrate utilized as the sole carbon source, lysine and ornithine decarboxylated.</s><s>Acid not produced from sucrose and adonitol.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 50 to 53 mol% (7).</s><s>In contrast to the other species of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> most <i>S. enterica</i> strains of subspecies <i>enterica</i>, <i>salamae</i>, <i>diarizonae</i>, and <i>indica</i> may alternatively express two different specificities of their flagellar (H) antigen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain CIP 60.62<sup>T</sup> derived from the wild strain LT2 (H<sub>2</sub>S producing) was deposited in the Collection of the Institut Pasteur by M.</s><s>Demerec in 1960.</s><s>LT2 means Lillengen strain type 2 (25).</s><s>Genetically, it is the best known Salmonella strain (28, 29).</s><s>Many mutants have been isolated from the original strain which is prototrophic.</s><s>Some of these mutants are used in tests for detection of mutagens or carcinogens (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics of strain LT2 are typical of <i>S. enterica</i> subsp. <i>enterica</i> (21, 23, 24); acid not produced from lactose, salicine, and galacturonate; <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-<i>β</i>-Dgalactopyranoside and malonate tests negative, gelatin not hydrolyzed, no growth in the presence of KCN.</s><s>Acid produced from dulcitol, mucate, and sorbitol; L-(+)-tartrate test positive.</s><s>Lysed by phage 01.</s><s>In addition, this strain grows on a defined medium with glucose or citrate (Simmons) as sole carbon source.</s><s>Acid produced from xylose, arabinose, rhamnose, mannose, mannitol, maltose, trehalose, inositol, and melibiose.</s><s>Acid not produced from adonitol, sucrose, raffinose, cellobiose.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylated, tetrathionate reduced, γ-glutamyltransferase produced, indole and <i>β</i>-glucuronidase not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>By using specially manufactured API strips (API System, La Balme les Grottes, France), which contained sole carbon sources, and by following a method described elsewhere (P.</s><s>A.</s><s>D.</s><s>Grimont, T.</s><s>A.</s><s>Jackson, E.</s><s>Ageron, and M.</s><s>J.</s><s>Noonan, Int.</s><s>J.</s><s>Syst.</s><s>Bacteriol., in press), we found that the type strain showed the following nutritional characteristics.</s><s>Growth occurred in 4 days on N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-arabinose, L-aspartate, citrate, dulcitol, ethanolamine, D-fructose, L-fucose, fumarate, D-galactose, gentisate, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine, D-glucose, D-glucuronate, L-glutamate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, <i>meta</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, DL-lactate, L-malate, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, <i>α</i>-methyl-D-galactopyranoside , β-methyl-D-glucopyranoside, mucate, L-proline, propionate, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, D-saccharate, L-serke, D-sorbitol, succinate, D-tagatose, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, D-trehalose, tricarballylate, and D-xylose.</s><s>No growth occurred in 4 days on <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adonitol, DL-γ-aminobutryrate, DL-δ- aminovalerate, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, benzoate, betaine, caprate, caprylate, D-cellobiose, <i>m</i>-coumarate, <i>i</i>-erythritol, esculin, D-galacturonate, <i>β</i>-gentiobiose, glutarate, histamine, <i>para</i>-hydroxybenzoate, DL-<i>β</i>-hydroxybutyrate, 2-ketogluconate, α-ketoglutarate, lactose, lactulose, D-lyxose, malonate, maltitol, D-melezitose, <i>β</i>-methyl-D-galactopyranoside, 3-methylglucose, <i>α</i>-methyl-D-glucopyranoside, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, D-raffinose, L-sorbose, sucrose, trigonelline, tryptamine, D-turanose, and xylitol.</s><s>The antigenic formula is 4,5,12:i:1,2.</s><s>Factor O:1 may be expressed after phage conversion (10, 11, 37).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This strain carries a plasmid of about 90 kilobases (31, 32).</s></p></content></protolog>