<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9136_nm.14233" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14233" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14233" rank="species">Prosthecomicrobium mishustinii</organism><reference id="rid.9136"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vasil'eva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Semenov</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giniyatullina</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of soil bacteria of the genus Prosthecomicrobium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>250</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prosthecomicrobium mishustinii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prosthecomicrobium mishustinii</i> (mi.shus.tinii, is named after E. N. Mishustin, the famous Soviet microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are short thick rodes of varied size, 0.6-0.9 to 0.-8-1.2 μm in diameter and 0.8-0.95 to 1.3-1.5 μm long.</s><s>Single or paired.</s><s>Nonmotile The prosthecae are from 0.20-0.30 μm to 0.4-0.65 μm long, 0.20-0.25 μm in diameter, cylindrical, slightly narrowed to the apex.</s><s>Prosthecae are loosely located in the cell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells reproduce by budding, the buds are fixed, with prosthecae getting detached when the cells reach the size of the mother cell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They are aerobes, catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are yellowish-orange, rounded, of a thick consistency detachable from agar as a whole.</s><s>They dissociate yielding pigmentless variants.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism is a chemoorganotroph, utilizing many mono- and disaccharides and some sugar alcohols as a single carbon and energy source, tri- and polysaccharides are not utilized, but organic acids of the Krebs cycles and some amino acids are (Tables 2 and 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract or B group vitamins are required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolytic activity is absent.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 28-30°C, pH neutral.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are extremely sensitive to penicillin, MPK 0.01-0.05 μm/ml (6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The habitat: the organism is widespread in soils, manure and in places when the degradation of organic material is rapid.</s><s>It was found in soils of Colchis, in hotbed soil and in horse manure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The GC-content of DNA is from 63.7 to 65.2 mol% (by hear denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>It differs from most closely related species in the degree of DNA/DNA homology, cell size and prosthecae length.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The typical strain 17 has been deposited with the Institute of Microbiology, the USSR Academy of Sciences, Moscow, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>