<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5796_nm.4405" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4405" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4405" rank="species">Mitsuokella jalaludinii</organism><reference id="rid.5796"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>G.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>Y.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abdullah</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mitsuokella jalaludinii sp. nov., from the rumens of cattle in Malaysia.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>713</fpage><lpage>718</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01930-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054230</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mitsuokella jalaludinii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mitsuokella jalaludinii</i> (jal.al.u.di'ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>jalaludinii</i> of Jalaludin, in honour of S. Jalaludin, an animal nutritionist and Vice-Chancellor of Universiti Putra Malaysia, who has contributed significantly to rumen microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile, small, stout rods (1.2-2.4 μm in length and 0.6-0.8 μm in width).</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs, in short chains or in irregular groups.</s><s>Colonies on PYG agar after 2 d incubation are greyish-white, roughly circular and convex with smooth surfaces and regular edges.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>The final pH in PYG broth is 3.8-4.0.</s><s>There is no copious gas formation from glucose.</s><s>The major end-products from glucose fermentation are lactic acid, succinic acid and some acetic acid.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by fermentable carbohydrates but not by bile.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 45 and 47 °C.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction, indole production, catalase production, urease production, hydrogen sulfide production, Tween 80 hydrolysis, arginine acid decarboxylase and growth in 4.5%sodium chloride are negative.</s><s>The nitrate-reduction test, the methyl red test and the Voges-Proskauer reaction are positive.</s><s>Glycerol, L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, D-mannose, inositol, sorbitol, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, saccharose, trehalose, D-raffinose, amidon, D-turanose, D-arabitol and 5-keto-gluconate are fermented.</s><s>Erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-xyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, mannitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, inulin, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate are not fermented.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin, bacitracin and erythromycin.</s><s>Intolerant to 0.005% crystal violet and 0.001% brilliant green.</s><s>Full 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity and DNA-DNA relatedness to <i>Mitsuokella multacida</i> are 98.7 and 63.8%, respectively.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 56.8 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the rumens of cattle.</s><s>The type strain is M 9<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13811<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-307<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>