<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5660_nm.5515" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5515" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5515" rank="species">Isobaculum melis</organism><reference id="rid.5660"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isobaculum melis gen. nov., sp. nov., a Carnobacterium-like organism isolated from the intestine of a badger.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>210</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11837304</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Isobaculum melis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Isobaculum melis</i> (me'lis. L. fem. n. <i>meles</i> badger, L. gen. fem. n. <i>melis</i> of the badger)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of non-spore-forming, non-motile rods.</s><s>Cells mainly stain Gram-positive although some cells have a tendency to decolorize easily and appear Gram-negative.</s><s>Non-pigmented and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase- and catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows at 10 °C but not at 45 °C or in 6.5%NaCl.</s><s>Gas is not produced in deMan, Rogosa and Sharpe broth.</s><s>L(+)Lactic acid and acetic acid are the major end products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>In conventional heart infusion base medium, acid is produced from dglucose, glycerol, D-ribose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, inulin, lactose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, D-raffinose, sorbitol, sorbose or sucrose.</s><s>When API systems are used, acid is produced from D-glucose, trehalose and ribose but not from larabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, maltose, mannitol, pullulan, draffinose, sorbitol, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-xylose or methyl β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>Acid phosphatase (weak reaction), arginine dihydrolase, ester lipase C-8 (weak reaction), esterase C-4 (weak reaction), β-glucosidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, phosphoaminidase and β-mannosidase are produced.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycine tryptophan arylamidase, α-mannosidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase C-14, pyrazinamidase, trypsin, urease and valine arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>N-Acetyl-bglucosaminidase and alkaline phosphatase activities may or may not be present.</s><s>Aesculin is hydolysed but hippurate, starch and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges-Proskauernegative.</s><s>Pyruvate is not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced in litmus milk, but clotting is not observed.</s><s>Sensitive to vancomycin (30 μg disc).</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acids are C16:0, C18:0 and C18:1<i>ω</i>9<i>C</i>.Menaquinones are absent.</s><s>The cell wall contains L-lysine of the L- Lys-L-Thr-Gly type.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from the small intestine of a badger killed in a road accident.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 37660<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13760<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>