<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2852_nm.8323" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8323" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8273" rank="species">Flammeovirga aprica</organism><reference id="rid.2852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakagawa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the genus Flammeovirga and Flammeovirga aprica with the proposal of Flammeovirga arenaria nom. rev., comb. nov. and Flammeovirga yaeyamensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2095</fpage><lpage>2100</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64324-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957105</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Flammeovirga aprica</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flammeovirga aprica</em> (a′pri.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>aprica</em> sunlit, sun-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are long rods, 0.5–0.9 μm wide and 1.7–96 μm long or longer.</s><s>Colonies spread and produce large gelase fields and deep craters in agar plates.</s><s>Growth is detected at 15–30 °C, with the optimum growth yield at 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–8 with the optimum growth yield at pH 7.</s><s>Growth occurs at 1–5 % NaCl with the optimum growth yield at 3 %.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are positive.</s><s>Urease activity is negative.</s><s>Agar, alginic acid, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, aesculin and starch are degraded, but cellulose, chitin, inulin, gelatin, Tween 80 and tyrosine are not degraded.</s><s>Casein is weakly degraded.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced, but indole is not.</s><s>O–F test of glucose is fermentative.</s><s>Utilization (Biolog GN2 microplate data) is observed for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, l-fucose, glycogen, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, dl-lactic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-trehalose, lactulose, maltose, glucose 1-phosphate, cellobiose, d-mannose, monomethyl succinate, glycyl l-glutamic acid and glucose 6-phosphate, but not for d-melibiose, urocanic acid, l-ornithine, l-rhamnose, l-alanyl glycine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine or l-threonine.</s><s>Acid production (API 50CH data) is positive for d-xylose, galactose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose and weakly positive for ribose, glucose, mannose and l-fucose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from rhamnose, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, arbutin, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose or xylitol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, C20 : 4<em>ω</em>6,9,12,15<em>c</em>, C16 : 0 3-OH and C14 : 0.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NBRC 15941<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 23126<sup>T</sup>=CIP 104807<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>