<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1997_nm.11130" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11130" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11130" rank="species">Virgibacillus olivae</organism><reference id="rid.1997"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aguilera</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morillo</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteoliva-Sánchez</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus olivae sp. nov., isolated from waste wash-water from processing of Spanish-style green olives.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>906</fpage><lpage>910</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64550-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473231</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus olivae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus olivae</em> (o′li.vae. L. gen. n. <em>olivae</em> of an olive, referring to the isolation of the first strains from olive processing waste-water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved, rounded-ended, Gram-positive rods (1.8×0.26 μm), motile by means of peritrichous flagella, occurring singly or in pairs and occasionally in short chains.</s><s>Endospore formation is slow; the endospores are nearly spherical or ellipsoidal and appear in a terminal or subterminal position.</s><s>Colonies on HM 5 % sea salts medium after 24 h at 30 °C are yellow–cream, semi-translucent, oval with regular margins that may spread along the inoculation streak, slightly transparent at the edge.</s><s>They have glossy surfaces and are 0.5–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 20–45 °C and pH 4–8.</s><s>Halotolerant, being capable of growing in sea salts concentrations from 0 to 10 % (w/v).</s><s>Optimum growth at 30 °C, pH 7 and 5 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch and gelatin, but not tyrosine or Tween 20, 40 or 80.</s><s>Citrate is not used as a sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Indole, Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests are negative.</s><s>No growth on cetrimide agar.</s><s>Able to use cellobiose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose and d-glucose as sole carbon and energy sources but not d-galactose or maltose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose but not from d-glucose, cellobiose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-galactose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol or adonitol.</s><s>l-Cysteine, l-histidine, l-methionine and l-valine are not used as sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin, amikacin, clindamycin, nalidixic acid, polymyxin B, streptomycin and sulfamides.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, gentamicin, rifampicin, erythromycin, cephalotin and penicillin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 30.7–33.4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is E<sub>30</sub> 8<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23503<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18098<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain and three other strains were isolated from wastewater of Spanish green olive processing.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that of the species.</s><s>Additionally, this strain is able to grow in a medium containing 20 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>Aesculin and casein are hydrolysed.</s><s>Fumarate and propionate can be used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline and resistant to chloramphenicol.</s><s>The main fatty acids (making up 81 % of the total) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 33.4 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p></content></protolog>