<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2649_nm.11723" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11723" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6295" rank="species">Gordona hydrophobica</organism><reference id="rid.2649"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bendinger</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moormann</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klatte</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordona hydrophobica sp. nov., isolated from biofilters for waste gas treatment.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>544</fpage><lpage>548</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-544</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordona hydrophobica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gordona hydrophobica</i> (hy.dro.pho'bi.ca. Gr. n. <i>hydro</i>, water; Gr. adj. <i>phobos</i>, fear, dread; M.L. adj. <i>hydrophobica</i>, water avoiding, water repellent, related to hydrophobic)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species description below is based on our own data and additional information obtained from references 1, 2, and 3.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, regular, long rods (2 to 3 μm) that are nonmotile, grow amycelially, and undergo a rod-coccus cycle.</s><s>Light microscopy of colony or liquid culture growth shows cells mostly in aggregates.</s><s>Growth in liquid culture is clear with a pellicle on the surface that rises up at the glass wall of a culture tube.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tannish to white colonies are formed on various media.</s><s>The colony morphology of the type strain is rough and flat with irregular margins.</s><s>Upon primary isolation, colonies may also be convex with entire or undulate margins and a smooth surface.</s><s>Subcultivation of a smooth colony on complex medium agar plates yields smooth as well as rough colonies, whereas a rough variant yields only rough colonies.</s><s>Rough variants of <i>G. hydrophobica</i> have an extremely high cell surface hydrophobicity which is reduced significantly in variants forming smooth colonies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cleaves the pNP substrates pNP-phosphorylcholine and 2-deoxythymidine-5'-pNP-phosphate but not pNP-β-D-xyloside.</s><s>Uses D-galactose, citric acid (Na salt), succinic acid (Na salt), propionic acid, and leucine as sole carbon source but does not use <i>meso</i>-inositol, L-rhamnose, gluconic acid, adipic acid, 5-aminovaleric acid, aspartic acid, asparagine, ribose, and arabinose.</s><s>Does not decompose tyrosine, adenine, and xanthine and does not produce acid from sucrose aerobically or anaerobically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs on the readily volatile carbonyl compounds methylpropanal, 3-methylbutanal, 2-methylbutanal, butanone, 2-pentanone, and 4-methyl-2-pentanone when added as sole carbon sources into sealed agar slope cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the only diamino acid, arabinose and galactose as major cell wall sugars, and N-glycolyl muramic acid moieties.</s><s>The predominant isoprenolog is MK-9 (H<sub>2</sub>); minor amounts of MK-8 (H<sub>2</sub>) are also present.</s><s>The polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Contains major amounts of straight-chain, saturated, and monounsaturated fatty acids and tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids with 54 to 62 carbon atoms are present.</s><s>Upon pyrolysis gas chromatography of mycolates, the fatty acids 16:0, 17:0, 18:0, and 18:l</s></p><p class="description"><s>are released.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from packing material (tree bark compost) of bio-filters for deodorization of animal rendering emissions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 1610/1b (=DSM 44015<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>