<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5631_nm.1750" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1750" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1750" rank="species">Bordetella hinzii</organism><reference id="rid.5631"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monsieurs</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cookson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wirsing von König</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bordetella hinzii sp. nov., isolated from poultry and humans.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>37</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-37</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857806</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bordetella hinzii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bordetella hinzii</i> (hin'zii N. L. gen. n. <i>hinzii</i> [of Hinz], named in honor of K.-H. Hinz, a German microbiologist who has contributed much to our knowledge of avian isolates belonging to the genus <i>Bordetella</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>B. hinzii</i> cells are gram-negative, nonsporulating rods that are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Two distinct colony types occur.</s><s>Some strains produce round, raised, glistening, greyish colonies about 2 mm in diameter following 48 h of incubation at 37°C in air containing 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Under the same conditions other strains produce flat, dry, crinkled colonies that are up to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced, and oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>Urease activity in Christensen’s medium is strain dependent.</s><s>Alkali is produced from the following substrates: acetamide, adipate, malonamide, malonate, valerate, and propionamide.</s><s>Production of alkali from glycine is strain dependent.</s><s>As determined by the API 20NE MicroTest system, the following characteristics are always negative: reduction of nitrate, production of indole, production of acid from glucose, urease, arginine dihydrolase, and β-galactosidase activities, liquefaction of gelatin, hydrolysis of esculin, and assimilation of D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, maltose, and D-gluconate.</s><s>Assimilation of adipate, malate, citrate, and phenyl acetate and oxidase activity are always positive.</s><s>Assimilation of caprate is strain dependent.</s><s>The API 20NE profile of most strains is 0000077; the profile of other strains is 0000067, which is identical to the profile of <i>B. avium</i> strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fatty acid components of all of the strains examined are 16:0, 17:0 cyclo, and summed feature 3 (probably 14:O 3OH).</s><s>Ubiquinone 8 and trace amounts of ubiquinone 9 are the respiratory quinones.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains have been isolated from respiratory tracts of turkeys and chickens.</s><s>Experimental infections in turkey poults have shown that <i>B. hinzii</i> is nonpathogenic (19).</s><s>Recent studies at the Animal Research Institute in Yeerongpilly, Australia, have shown that the Australian isolates of <i>B. hinzii</i> are nonpathogenic for 1-day-old chickens and turkey poults (2).</s><s>The available clinical histories do not provide strong evidence that this organism plays a role in respiratory disease (3, 18).</s><s>Two strains have been isolated from humans; one was responsible for bacteremia, and the other was isolated from sputum.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is between 65 and 67 mol% G+C.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 13501 (= TC58), which was isolated from a chicken trachea in Australia; its G+C content is 66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>B. hinzii</i> strains have been deposited in the Laboratorium Microbiologie Gent Culture Collection.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxonomic position of strain LMG 13506.</s><s>Strain LMG 13506 was isolated in a mixed culture from an ear swab of a patient suffering from chronic otitis media (14).</s><s>This strain exhibited the typical biochemical reactions of <i>B. avium</i> but had a different pattern of antimicrobial resistance.</s><s>DNA-rRNA hybridization data confirmed that this strain belongs to the family <i>Alcaligenaceae</i> (Table 4).</s><s>However, the absence of significant DNA binding values when this organism was tested with reference strains belonging to all <i>Bordetella</i> and <i>Alcaligenes</i> species that have been described indicates that it represents yet another novel species within this rRNA cluster.</s><s>We provisionally designated this strain <i>Bordetella</i> sp. as it resembles or is virtually indistinguishable from <i>B. avium</i> in its biochemical, protein, and fatty acid profiles (Fig. 1 and Table 2) (14).</s></p></content></protolog>