<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12537_nm.21396" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21396" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21396" rank="species">Streptohalobacillus salinus</organism><reference id="rid.12537"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptohalobacillus salinus gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic, Gram-positive, facultative anaerobe isolated from subsurface saline soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1127</fpage><lpage>1132</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025338-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543154</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptohalobacillus salinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptohalobacillus salinus</em> (sa.li′nus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>salinus</em> salted, salty).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.2–0.4×2–8 µm, occurring as single short rods in liquid GM medium under aerobic conditions, but as long chains in exponential growth phase in liquid GM medium under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>After cultivation on GM agar at 37 °C for 4 days, colonies are circular, white, opaque, slightly convex and 0.2–0.4 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at 20–40 °C (optimum 37 °C), at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum pH 7.5) and with 0–20 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum 7 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Positive in tests for methyl red reaction, amylase, pullulanase and β-glucosidase, but negative in tests for H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, Voges–Proskauer reaction, urease production, protease, lipase, DNase, phosphatase and gelatinase.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not from l-arabinose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, arbutin, melibiose, d-sorbitol, erythritol, d-ribose, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, dulcitol, inositol, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, inulin, lactose, lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or methyl α-d-mannopyranoside.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 µg), penicillin G (10 U), cefazolin (30 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), clindamycin (2 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), norfloxacin (10 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), ciprofloxacin (5 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), neomycin (30 µg), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (5 µg), spectinomycin (100 µg), josamycin (15 µg), medicamycin (15 µg), bacitracin (0.04 U) and novobiocin (5 µg).</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.2 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, H96B60<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22440<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 1.7733<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a saline soil sample of the Qaidam basin, China.</s></p></content></protolog>