<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1389_nm.2234" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2234" rank="genus">Frateuria</organism><reference id="rid.1389"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gosselé</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Frateuria, a new genus for "Acetobacter aurantius".</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>547</fpage><lpage>556</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-3-547</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Frateuria</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Frateuria</i> after the late Joseph Frateur (1903-1974), eminent Belgian microbiologist, renowned for his important contributions to the taxonomy of the acetic acid bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell morphology.</s><s>Gram-negative, straight rods, 0.5 to 0.7 by 0.7 to 3.5 μm, which occur singly or in pairs, rarely in filaments or as irregular cells and never in chains.</s><s>Motile by means of polar flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonial morphology.</s><s>Luxuriant growth occurs on glucose-yeast extract-CaCO<sub>3</sub> medium.</s><s>After 6 days at 30°C, the brownish colonies measure 2 to 5 mm in diameter, have a dark brown center, and are glistening, flat, or raised and circular with a regular edge.</s><s>Some strains show a typical browning of the medium-due to a water-soluble pigment-after 3 days of incubation, others only after 6 to 10 days.</s><s>The color tends to become dark coffee brown.</s><s>After 4 weeks no visible crystals of Ca-gluconate are formed.</s><s>Good growth is also obtained on mannitol-yeast extract-peptone agar.</s><s>After 6 days at 30°C the colonies are yellow to orange, glistening or rough, regular or irregular, highly convex with undulate or regular edge, and 1 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>They become pale brown and reach a diameter of up to 6 mm after 6 to 19 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs in beer wort, but in peptone broth, yeast extract broth, and Hoyer medium with mannitol, growth is faint.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 3.6, in a medium containing 20% glucose, and at 30 and 34°C but not at 4°C.</s><s>One percent ethanol is tolerated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptibility towards antibiotics.</s><s>Susceptible to kanamycin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), and novobiocin (30 μg).</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), chloramphenicol(30 μg) , bacitracin (10 U) , penicillin G ( 10 U), erythromycin (10 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), colistin sulfate (10 μg), fucidin (10 μg), nitrofurantoin (200 μg), methicillin (10 μg), neomycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), and sulfafurazole (100 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical features.</s><s>Acid is formed from ethanol, glycerol, D-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, and D-mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-sorbose, raffinose, dextrin, or starch.</s><s>With D-glucose and D-xylose, the pH drops below 4.</s><s>The strains are ketogenic on glycerol, mannitol, and sorbitol.</s><s>From D-glucose, 2-keto- -and 2,5-diketogluconic acids are formed, but not 5-ketogluconic acid.</s><s>Lactate, but not acetate, is oxidized to CO<sub>2</sub> and water.</s><s>Oxidase and gelatinase are not produced.</s><s>Litmus milk is unchanged.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Catalase, a characteristic ubiquinone, Q8, and H<sub>2</sub>S are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The only species, and thus the type species, is <i>Frateuria aurantia</i> sp. nov. (au.rań tia, M.L. adj. <i>aurantius</i> gold colored; derived from <i>aurare</i>, C.L. verb, to overlay with gold; refers to the gold-yellow color of the strains on mannitolyeast extract peptone agar).</s><s>The description of this species is the same as that given above for the genus.</s><s>The type strain of <i>F. aurantia</i> is IFO 3245.</s><s>A description of this strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>Diagnostic features useful in differentiating <i>Frateuria</i> from <i>Gluconobacter</i> and <i>Acetobacter</i> can be found in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>For the genus <i>Frateuria</i> as well as for its only species, <i>Frateuria aurantia</i>, we propose as minimal standards: gram-negative, polarly flagellated if motile, strictly aerobic rods requiring no growth factors, producing a brown water-soluble pigment on glucose-yeast extract-CaCO<sub>3</sub> agar, producing the ubiquinone Q8, able to grow at pH 3.6 and on Frateur’s Hoyer mannitol medium, producing acid from ethanol, glucose, and xylose, and lacking oxidase, gelatinase, nitrate reduction, and starch hydrolysis; they produce H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>From glucose, 2-keto- and 2,5-diketogluconic acids are formed, but not 5-ketogluconic acid.</s><s>The guanine plus cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 62 to 64 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>