<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.624_nm.8528" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8528" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8528" rank="species">Burkholderia unamae</organism><reference id="rid.624"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Caballero-Mellado</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Aguilar</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paredes-Valdez</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Estrada-de Los Santos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia unamae sp. nov., an N2-fixing rhizospheric and endophytic species.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1165</fpage><lpage>1172</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02951-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280286</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia unamae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia unamae</em> [u.na′mae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>unamae</em> arbitrary name formed from UNAM, acronym for Universidad Nacional Autonóma de México. This name was chosen to commemorate the 450th anniversary of the University, which occurred in the same year as the first isolation of the species (2001)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods (1·8–2·5 μm long and 0·5–0·8 μm wide) with a single flagellum or a polar tuft of four to eight flagella.</s><s>Isolates are Gram-negative and oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Growth and acetylene reduction to ethylene is observed with different carbon sources in N-free, semi-solid media. <em>B. unamae</em> strains grow on BAc plates, forming colonies that are yellowish, round, smooth and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Isolates grew on agar media at 29 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>At 37 °C, they grew on BSE medium, but not on MacConkey agar medium.</s><s>Strains did not grow on BCSA medium with or without vancomycin.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics for the differentiation of <em>B. unamae</em> from other N<sub>2</sub>-fixing <em>Burkholderia</em> species and related species of the genus <em>Burkholderia</em> are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not to N<sub>2</sub>; there is urease activity, but not aesculin hydrolysis, liquefaction of gelatin or indole production.</s><s>Additional phenotypic characteristics are listed in Table 3.</s><s>All isolates showed the ability to produce siderophores. <em>B. unamae</em> can be differentiated phenotypically from all diazotrophic <em>Burkholderia</em> species and from <em>B. sacchari</em> and <em>B. cepacia</em> by its SDS-PAGE protein profile, electrophoretic mobility pattern of metabolic enzymes and fatty acid profile. <em>B. unamae</em> comprises strains with four different ARDRA genotypes and their 16S rDNA sequences show &#x003E;99·2 % similarity. <em>B. unamae</em> can also be differentiated genomically from all diazotrophic <em>Burkholderia</em> species and from <em>B. sacchari</em> by its ARDRA and ribotype profiles.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MTl-641<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-744<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107921<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>This strain was isolated from the rhizosphere of maize cultivated in the fields in Tlayacapan, Morelos State, Mexico.</s><s>Phenotypic and genomic characteristics of the type strain are the same as described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>