<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7221_nm.6958" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6958" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6958" rank="species">Streptomyces costaricanus</organism><reference id="rid.7221"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Esnard</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potter</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zuckerman</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces costaricanus sp. nov., isolated from nematode-suppressive soil.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>775</fpage><lpage>779</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-4-775</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7547298</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces costaricanus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces costaricanus</i> (cos.ta.ri.can'us. L. adj. <i>costaricanus</i>, referring to Costa Rica, the geographic origin of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mature spore chains are tightly coiled spirals with 10 to 50 spores per chain.</s><s>The spores are smooth and gray-brown in mature colonies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The aerial mycelial mass is grayish brown on yeast extract-malt extract agar, oatmeal agar, inorganic salts-starch agar, and glycerol asparagine agar and yellow on N-Z amine medium containing soluble starch and glucose (ATCC medium 172).</s><s>The substrate mycelium is light yellow on yeast extract-malt extract agar and glycerol-asparagine agar, golden on ATCC medium 172, brown on oatmeal agar, and yellow on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>A yellow pH-insensitive diffusible pigment is produced on yeast extract-malt extract agar and glycerol-asparagine agar.</s><s>The pigment color is orange-yellow on ATCC medium 172.</s><s>No melanoid pigment is produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar or tyrosine agar.</s><s>The color of the reverse side of the colonies is also not sensitive to pH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D-Fructose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, D-xylose, salicin, and galactose are utilized for growth, but L-arabinose, raffinose, rhamnose, and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, D-glucose, glycerol, maltose, galactose, D-mannitol, and D-xylose but not from L-arabinose, D-fructose, lactose, and sucrose.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of ribitol, galactitol, erythritol, and i-inositol; 7% NaCl is inhibitory.</s><s>Table 1 shows the tolerance of <i>S. costaricanus</i> to other toxic compounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell walls contain LL-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The most abundant hydrolyzable fatty acids are a-lS:O, 160, a-17:0, i-15:0, i-16:0, and i-17:O in cells grown on ISP medium 2 agar.</s><s>The concentration of octadecanoic acid is ninefold higher in ISP medium 2 broth (Table 2).</s><s>Isolated from a tropical soil.</s><s>Exhibits antinematodal activity against <i>C. elegans</i> and antibiotic activity against <i>R. solani</i> and <i>Pythium aphanidermatum</i>.</s><s>The type strain is strain CR-43 (=ATCC 55274=NRRL B-16897).</s></p></content></protolog>