<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12726_nm.22495" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22495" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22495" rank="species">Roseicitreum antarcticum</organism><reference id="rid.12726"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>S.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseicitreum antarcticum gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic bacteriochlorophyll a-containing alphaproteobacterium isolated from Antarctic sandy intertidal sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2173</fpage><lpage>2179</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024885-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20889763</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Roseicitreum antarcticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Roseicitreum antarcticum</em> (an.tarc′ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>antarcticum</em> southern, belonging to Antarctica).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are lemon-shaped, 0.5–0.8×1.0–2.0 µm.</s><s>Colonies on MA are pink-coloured, convex, circular, smooth and 1–2 mm in diameter after 3 days of incubation at 27 °C.</s><s>With prolonged aerobic cultivation in the light, colony colour changes to red.</s><s>Bchl <em>a</em> is produced with a single major peak at 872–874 nm in the infrared absorption spectrum.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–33 °C (optimum 25–27 °C), at pH 5–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0) and in 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 7–8 %).</s><s>Indole production and Voges–Proskauer reaction are negative.</s><s>Negative for reduction of nitrate and production of hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Positive for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase activities.</s><s>Negative for gelatinase, agarase, caseinase, amylase and lipase (Tween 80) activities.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, adipic acid, gluconate, malic acid, glycerin, amygdalin, pyruvate, casein hydrolysate and yeast extract.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as sole carbon sources: starch, d-arabinose, d- and l-fucose, fructose, lactose, d-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose, methyl-α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl-α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl-β-d-xylopyranoside, d-adonitol, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, aesculin, inulin, salicin, glycogen, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, capric acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, lactate, propionate, butyrate, benzoate, caproate, malonate, methanol, succinate, tartrate, ethanol, propanol, aspartate and glycolate.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-rhamnose and l-arabinose but not from d-glucose, melibiose, sucrose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol and amygdalin.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disk, unless otherwise stated) erythromycin (15), chloromycetin (30), ciprofloracin (5) and norfloxacin (10); resistant to amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100), cefazoline sodium (40), cefoperazone (30), ceftazidime (30), ceftriaxone sodium (5), cefuroxime (30), cotrimoxazole (75), doxycyclin (30), furazolidone (300), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), minocycline (30), neomycin (30), oxacillin (1), penicillin (75), piperacillin (100), polymyxin B (100 U), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, with C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo, C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> cyclo and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) present in smaller amounts.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ZS2-28<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.8894<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 24863<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sandy intertidal sediment samples collected from coastal regions of the Chinese Antarctic Zhongshan Station on the Larsemann Hills, Princess Elizabeth Land, East Antarctica.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.3 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>