<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1522_nm.7960" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7960" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7960" rank="species">Bacteroides loescheii</organism><reference id="rid.1522"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Bacteroides loescheii sp. nov. and emendation of the descriptions of Bacteroides melaninogenicus (Oliver and Wherry) Roy and Kelly 1939 and Bacteroides denticola Shah and Collins 1981</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>399</fpage><lpage>409</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteoides loescheii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteoides loescheii</i> (loesche'i.i. L. gen. noun <i>loescheii</i> of Loesche, named after Walter J. Loesche, an American dental microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is composed of obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile, gram-negative rods.</s><s>Cells in glucose broth were 0.4 to 0.6 by 0.8 to 15.0 μm and occurred singly, in pairs, and in short chains (Fig. 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates were 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, translucent, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>After incubation for 48 h on plates containing whole blood, colonies were white or buff.</s><s>Upon continued anaerobic incubation (up to 14 days), colonies usually became brown (often only light brown).</s><s>Although pigment developed more rapidly on media containing hemolyzed blood, definite dark brown or black colonies did not develop with some strains, even if cultures were incubated for 21 days.</s><s>The pigment is formed principally from protoporphyrin (35).</s><s>Most strains produced slight clearing or beta-hemolysis on rabbit blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose broth cultures were turbid, with a smooth sediment and a final pH of 4.9 to 5.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation acids (from 1% peptone-1% yeast extract-1% glucose broth cultures containing vitamin K1 and hemin [II]) of the type strain were succinate (2 to 3 meq/100 ml of culture) and acetate (1 meq/100 ml); sometimes traces of lactate (0.2 to 0.3 meq/100 ml) and formate (0.2 to 0.3 meq/100 ml) were also present.</s><s>No hydrogen was detected in headspace gas.</s><s>Similar products were obtained with other strains.</s><s>Neither pyruvate nor lactate was used, and threonine was not converted to propionate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hemin was required or highly stimulatory for growth.</s><s>Even in the presence of hemin, serum (10%, vol/vol) often enhanced growth and fermentation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The six strains tested were susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml) , clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml), penicillin G (2 U/ml), and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (referred to as "<i>B. oralis</i> ATCC 15930") produces sphingolipids (25).</s><s>Extracellular phospholipase A is produced (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolysis of esculin and fermentation of cellobiose are helpful in differentiating <i>B. loescheii</i> from <i>B. melaninogenicus</i> and <i>B. denticola</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from gingival crevices of humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 46 mol% (37) or 47 to 48 mol% (41; this study).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 15930 (Loesche strain 8B, NCTC 11321).</s></p></content></protolog>