<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1550_nm.11154" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11154" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11154" rank="species">Yonghaparkia alkaliphila</organism><reference id="rid.1550"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Yonghaparkia alkaliphila gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Microbacteriaceae isolated from an alkaline soil</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2415</fpage><lpage>2420</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64258-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012572</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Yonghaparkia alkaliphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Yonghaparkia alkaliphila</em> (al.ka.li.phi′la. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>alkaliphila</em> loving alkaline conditions).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are circular, slightly convex, smooth, glistening, yellow in colour and 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 10 days at 30 °C on 2× diluted NA (pH 9.0).</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 37 °C, but not at 4 or 38 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions on 2× diluted NA (pH 9.0) or on 2× diluted NA (pH 9.0) supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Starch and Tween 40 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, xanthine, l-tyrosine and Tweens 20, 60 and 80 are not.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Acetate, succinate, benzoate, l-malate, formate and l-glutamate are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Utilization of salicin is variable (positive for type strain).</s><s>Susceptible to polymyxin B, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, novobiocin, lincomycin, oleandomycin, neomycin and carbenicillin, but not to penicillin G, ampicillin, tetracycline or kanamycin.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, unidentified phospholipids and unidentified glycolipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 71.1–71.6 mol% (71.1 mol% for type strain) (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KSL-113<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19126<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108920<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an alkaline soil from Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>