<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1794_nm.2119" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2119" rank="genus">Thioalkalicoccus</organism><reference id="rid.1794"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bryantseva</surname><given-names>I.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new alkaliphilic purple sulfur bacterium with bacteriochlorophyll b.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2157</fpage><lpage>2163</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155992</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thioalkalicoccus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thioalkalicoccus</i> (Thi'o.al'ka.li.coc'cus. Gr. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; Arab. n. <i>al kali</i> potash, soda; L.masc. n. <i>coccus</i> sphere; M.L. masc. n. <i>Thioalkalicoccus</i> sulfur sphere from soda)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical or oval, typically form diplococcus-shaped cells during cell division, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>Internal membranes are of the tubular type.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <i>b</i> and carotenoids.</s><s>The metabolism is strictly anaerobic and obligately phototrophic.</s><s>During photolithoautotrophic growth with sulfide as electron donor, globules of elemental sulfur are accumulated inside the cytoplasm.</s><s>The final oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate organic substrates are photoassimilated.</s><s>Mesophilic, obligate alkaliphilic bacterium with optimum growth at 20-25 °C.</s><s>Optimal development is dependent on sodium salts in low concentrations and on alkaline conditions.</s><s>Habitat is the surface of sediments rich in organic matter and microbial mats of soda lakes containing hydrogen sulfide and exposed to light.</s><s>The DNA G­C is 63.6-64.8 mol% (thermal denaturation).</s><s>Type species is <i>Thioalkalicoccus limnaeus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>