<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2537_nm.2151" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2151" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2151" rank="species">Thiorhodovibrio winogradskyi</organism><reference id="rid.2537"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Overmann</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new purple sulfur bacterium from saline littoral sediments, Thiorhodovibrio winogradskyi gen. nov. and sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>157</volume><fpage>329</fpage><lpage>335</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00248677</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thiorhodovibrio winogradskyi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thiorhodovibrio winogradskyi</i> (wi.no.grad'sky.i.M.L, gen. n., named for S. N. Winogradsky, a Russian microbiologist, who did the first comprehensive studies on the purple sulfur bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells vibrioid- to spirilloid-shaped, 1.7 5.0 μm long, 0.7-2.1 μm wide.</s><s>Anaerobically grown cultures are pink to light pinkish-purple.</s><s>Living cell suspensions show absorption maxima at 370-372, 483 484, 510, 590-591, 794-795 and 867 nm.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll a and rhodopin as the main carotenoid component; further carotenoids are lycopene, anhydrorhodovibrin, rhodovibrin and spirilloxanthin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phototrophic under anoxic conditions, facultatively chemotrophic under mixotrophic conditions at reduced oxygen partial pressure (1% O<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Photosynthetic electron donors used: sulfide, sulfur, and thiosulfate (used by some strains).</s><s>High growth rates with elemental sulfur as electron donor.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and hydrogen carbonate, acetate and pyruvate are photoassimilated; in addition, some strains use propionate, succinate, fumarate, malate, tartrate, malonate, glycerol and peptone.</s><s>When growing on sulfide or thiosulfate, up to ten small sulfur globules are formed inside the cell, often in a row along its long axis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH Range: 7.0-7.4.</s><s>Growth temperature: 14-37 °C, optimum temperature 33 °C.</s><s>Optimum light intensity 50 μmol m<sup>-2</sup>s<sup>-1</sup>, minimum light requirement 5 μmol m<sup>-2</sup>s<sup>-1</sup> (fluorescent light).</s><s>Salinity range of growth: 0.2-7.2% NaCl, optimum salinity: 2.2-3.2%.</s><s>No vitamins required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: Strains were isolated from sulfide-containing surface layers of salt lake sediment and marine microbial mats.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G + C of the DNA of the type strain is 61.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: DSM No 6702 (strain SSP1)</s></p></content></protolog>