<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8315_nm.14140" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14140" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14140" rank="species">Dyella ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.8315"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dyella ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>460</fpage><lpage>465</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64514-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244422</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dyella ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dyella ginsengisoli</em> (gin.seng.i.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil from a ginseng field, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile and rod-shaped (0.2–0.5 μm wide and 1.5–2.1 μm long).</s><s>pH range for growth is 5.0–8.5.</s><s>Tolerates 2 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 3 %.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin and starch but not cellulose, chitin, DNA, xylan, skimmed milk or olive oil.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-xylose, l-xylose, cellobiose, trehalose, glycogen, pyruvate, acetate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, l-glutamic acid and l-glutamine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-galactose, d-lactose, d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, formate, propionate, caprate, maleate, fumarate, phenyl acetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, salicin, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, gluconate, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, amygdalin, glycerol, methanol, inulin, dextran, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>Q-8 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 66.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 3046<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12599<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18387<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>