<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1919_nm.10753" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10753" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10753" rank="species">Granulicoccus phenolivorans</organism><reference id="rid.1919"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maszenan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tay</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tay</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Granulicoccus phenolivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a Gram-positive, phenol-degrading coccus isolated from phenol-degrading aerobic granules.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>730</fpage><lpage>737</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64671-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392196</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Granulicoccus phenolivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Granulicoccus phenolivorans</em> (phe.no.li.vo′rans. N.L. neut. n. <em>phenolum</em> phenol; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, consuming; N.L. part. adj. <em>phenolivorans</em> consuming phenol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics described for the genus, results obtained with the Biolog GN and GP systems and API 20E system show that the type strain can utilize the following components: Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, adenosine, AMP, TMP, UMP and fructose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Acids and their derivatives utilized by the type strain include methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l- and dl-lactic acid, d- and l-malic acid, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglutamic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid and l-pyroglutamic acid.</s><s>The type strain can consume amino compounds including glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, inosine, uridine, thymidine and putrescine.</s><s>Gentiobiose is utilized weakly.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, amygdalin, adonitol, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, 2-aminoethanol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylmannosamine, phenyl ethylamine, deoxyadenosine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, d-galacturonic acid, formic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, malonic acid, l-aspartic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and urocanic acid are not utilized.</s><s>Enzyme activities detected by both the API ZYM and API 20E systems are alkaline phosphatase, esterase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Activities of the following enzymes are not detected with API ZYM: acid phosphatase, esterase lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Activities of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, urease and gelatinase are detected with API 20E.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activities are not detected.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-negative and does not produce acetoin or reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>The genomic G+C content of the type strain is 69 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PG-02<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1292<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17626<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from phenol-degrading aerobic granules.</s></p></content></protolog>