<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2006_nm.10602" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10602" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10602" rank="species">Aquisalimonas asiatica</organism><reference id="rid.2006"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carrasco</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cowan</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aquisalimonas asiatica gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from an alkaline, saline lake in Inner Mongolia, China</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1137</fpage><lpage>1142</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64916-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473272</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aquisalimonas asiatica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aquisalimonas asiatica</em> (a.si.a′ti.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>asiatica</em> Asian).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.7–0.9×2.0–10.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies are 1 mm in diameter, non-pigmented, circular and entire on the maintenance medium after 2 days cultivation at 37 °C.</s><s>In liquid nutrient broth, usually grows with a strong tendency to form clumps at the bottom.</s><s>Grows over a wide range (1–20 %, w/v) of salt concentrations, with optimal growth at 7–10 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>Grows at 20–50 °C (optimally at 37 °C) and pH 6.0–10.8 (optimally at pH 7.5–8.5).</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Grows anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed; Tween 80 is hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Indole and phenylalanine deaminase tests are negative.</s><s>Phosphatase test is positive.</s><s>As determined using Biolog GN plates, the following compounds are oxidized: dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, l-rhamnose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and glycerol.</s><s>The following compounds are not oxidized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30 μg) and erythromycin (15 μg).</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin (10 U), cephalothin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), neomycin (10 μg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30 μg), streptomycin (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, a phosphoglycolipid and six different unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>Additional characteristics of the strains are listed in Table 1.</s><s>Known strains were isolated from water of an alkaline, saline lake.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CG12<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7368<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7151<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6291<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18102<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Lake Chagannor in Inner Mongolia, China.</s></p></content></protolog>