<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11584_nm.18619" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18619" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18619" rank="species">Demequina salsinemoris</organism><reference id="rid.11584"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakai</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morisaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ōmura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Demequina salsinemoris sp. nov., isolated on agar media supplemented with ascorbic acid or rutin</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1206</fpage><lpage>1209</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012617-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19667388</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Demequina salsinemoris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Demequina salsinemoris</em> (sal.si.ne.mo′ris. L. adj. <em>salsus</em> salted; L. n. <em>nemus</em> -<em>oris</em> wood; N.L. gen. n. <em>salsinemoris</em> of a salted wood, isolated from soil of a salted wood, a mangrove).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods and 0.3–0.4×0.7–1.1 μm in size.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 12–34 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at initial pH values of between 5 and 9.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated, up to 8 % (w/v), but is not required.</s><s>Good growth occurs on TSB agar and YD agar.</s><s>Colonies are pale yellow.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase- and DNase-negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>With API 20NE, hydrolysis of aesculin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are positive, but nitrate reduction, indole production and acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatin are negative.</s><s>With API ZYM, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are present, but <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C4), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and trypsin and valine arylamidases are absent.</s><s>With API 50CH, aesculin, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-rhamnose, salicin and d-xylose are utilized as carbon sources but <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosamine, d-adonitol, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, gluconate, raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose and xylitol are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein and starch and decomposition of adenine, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine and xanthine are negative.</s><s>The predominant components of the cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KV-810<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22060<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 105323<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from mangrove soil of a southern island in Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70–72 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>