<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12182_nm.20183" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20183" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20183" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter gossypiicola</organism><reference id="rid.12182"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Senthikumar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundaram</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter gossypii sp. nov. and
Mucilaginibacter gossypiicola sp. nov.,
plant-growth-promoting bacteria isolated from
cotton rhizosphere soils</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2451</fpage><lpage>2457</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018713-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19946048</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter gossypiicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter gossypiicola</em> (gos.sy.pi.i.co′la. N.L. n. <em>Gossypium</em> a scientific botanical genus name; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>gossypiicola</em> <em>Gossypium</em>-dweller, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the cotton rhizosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-endospore-forming, non-motile, irregular rods, 0.2–0.3 μm wide and 0.5–0.8 μm long (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>Growth occurs on AMS agar, R2A agar and NA, but not on TSA agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are pale-pink, mucoid, convex and round with entire margins on R2A agar and AMS agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 2–8, with optimum growth at pH 6–7.</s><s>The pale-pink pigment is water-insoluble and has absorption maxima at 213, 262, 329, 346 and 479 nm in methanol.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of 1 % (w/v) NaCl or higher.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase and cellulase are positive but pectinase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>Proteolytic and lipolytic activities are present.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and CM-cellulose but negative for hydrolysis of pectin, gelatin and starch.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive but negative for indole production.</s><s>Methanol, dichloromethane, succinate and ethanol are utilized as sole carbon sources but trimethylamine, methylamine, diethanolamine, formaldehyde, acetate, formate, dimethylamine and methane are not.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, potassium nitrate, ACC, l-alanine, l-glutamine, glycine, potassium thiocyanate, triethylamine and diethylamine are utilized as nitrogen sources but sodium nitrate, ammonium sulfate, l-glutamate, l-tryptophan, urea, methylamine, potassium cyanate and diphenylamine are not.</s><s>The type strain is highly resistant (up to 500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) to spectinomycin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, bacitracin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, novobiocin, vancomycin and trimethoprim, but sensitive to (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) tetracycline (300), doxycycline (300), rifampicin (25) and cephalosporin (500).</s><s>Positive for utilization of <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in the Biolog GN2 MicroPlate are not oxidized.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The main fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gh-48<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14471<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22379<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of cotton (<em>G. hirsutum</em> L. ‘MCU-12’), the sample being collected at the flowering stage from an experimental field at the Cotton Breeding Station, TNAU, Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>