<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.614_nm.3992" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3992" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3992" rank="species">Clostridium pfennigii</organism><reference id="rid.614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Krumholz</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium pfennigii sp. nov. uses methoxyl groups of monobenzenoids and produces butyrate.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>454</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-454</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium pfennigii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium pfennigii</i> (pfen.nig'i.i L. gen. n. <i>pfennigii</i> named after Norbert Pfennig, who first documented the catabolism of methoxyl groups of benzenoid compounds by an anaerobic bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies are 2 to 3 mm in diameter, smooth, convex, entire, and opaque after 1 week of incubation in roll tube medium supplemented with 5 mM vanillate.</s><s>In liquid medium cultures are evenly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain V5-2<sup>T</sup> cells are gram positive, motile, slightly curved, rod shaped, and about 0.4 μm wide by 1.6 to 3.5 μm long and have rounded to slightly tapered ends.</s><s>The cells usually occur singly and in division stages (Fig. 1).</s><s>Electron microscopy reveals a single laterally to subterminally attached flagellum.</s><s>Spores are resistant to boiling for 3 min; they are oval, subterminal to terminal, and 0.4 μm wide by 0.4 to 0.8 μm long and slightly swell the sporangium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain V5-2<sup>T</sup>grows only with methoxybenzenoids, pyruvate, or CO added to the medium (Table 1).</s><s>Butyrate and hydroxybenzenoids are the only organic products of methoxybenzenoids.</s><s>CO is catabolized to acetate and butyrate.</s><s>Pyruvate is fermented to acetate.</s><s>The methoxybenzenoids are catabolized to hydroxybenzenoids as follows: vanillate (3-methoxy-4-hydroxybenzoate) to protocatechuate (3,4-dihydroxybenzoate); vanillin (3- methoxy-4-hydroxybenzaldehyde) to protocatechuic aldehyde and protocatechpate; ferulate [3-(3-methoxy-4-hydroxyphenyl)-2-propenoate] to caffeate [3-(3,4-dihydroxyphenyl)-2-propenoate] and hydrocaffeate [3-(3,4-dihydroxyphenyl)-propionate]; and syringate (3,5-dimethoxy-4-hydroxybenzoate) and 3,4,5-trimethoxybenzoate to gallate (3,4,5-trihydroxybenzoate).</s><s>No other substrates are utilized (Table 1).</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> is produced from CO and pyruvate, but is not significantly produced during growth on benzenoids.</s><s>No H<sub>2</sub>, other organic acids, ethanol, or methanol production have been observed.</s><s>The equations that best fit the results shown in Table 1 are as follows:</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vanillate<sup>-</sup> + 0.2 HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> ↔ Protocatechuate<sup>-</sup> + 0.3 Butyrate<sup>-</sup> + 0.1 H<sup>+</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>Vanillin + 0.3 HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> ↔ 0.75 Protocatechuic aldehyde + 0.25 Protocatechuate<sup>-</sup> + 0.325 Butyrate<sup>-</sup> + 0.275 H<sup>+</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>Ferulate<sup>-</sup> + 0.5 H<sub>2</sub>O ↔ 0.5 Caffeate<sup>-</sup> + 0.5 Hydrocaffeate<sup>-</sup> + 0.25 Butyrate<sup>-</sup> + 0.25 H<sup>+</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>Syringate<sup>-</sup> + 0.4 HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> ↔ Gallate<sup>-</sup> + 0.6 Butyrate<sup>-</sup> + 0.2 H<sup>+</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>Trimethoxybenzoate<sup>-</sup> + 0.6 HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> ↔ Gallate<sup>-</sup> + 0.9 Butyrate<sup>-</sup> + 0.3 H<sup>+</sup></s></p><p class="description"><s>Maximum optical density is linear with vanillate concentrations up to at least 10 mM.</s><s>Cell protein yield is 8.17 ± 0.53 g/mol of ferulate (mean ± standard error of three cultures containing 3 mM ferulate and three cultures containing 6 mM ferulate).</s><s>The growth yields of a number of acetogens, including <i>C. pfennigii</i>, are compared in Table 2.</s><s>There was a significant improvement in cell yields when the organisms were grown on ferulate, probably due to the reduction of the acrylate side chains (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Little is known about nutritional requirements, but growth is best with 30% rumen fluid (0, 5 , 10, 20, and 30% tested), 0.2% yeast extract, and a specific energy source(s) in medium containing bicarbonate, minerals, cysteine, sulfide, and EL mixture of water-soluble vitamins.</s><s>Very little growth occurs without rumen fluid (optical density, 0.03).</s><s>The addition of Casitone, Casamino Acids, 1,4-naphthoquinone, hemin, or a mixture of volatile fatty acids to media with or without rumen fluid does not stimulate growth.</s><s>No growth occurs without an added energy source.</s><s>Neither sulfate, thiosulfate, nitrate, nor fumarate stimulates growth on syringate, and nitrate is not reduced during growth in this medium.</s><s>The addition of sulfate does not allow growth on lactate or ethanol.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range for growth is 6.3 to at least 8.0; the optimum pH is 7.3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for growth is 23 to 39°C; the optimum temperature is 36 to 38°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid base ratio is 38 mol% guanine plus cytosine (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Habitat: isolated from rumina of cattle.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain VS-2 (= DSM 3222).</s></p></content></protolog>