<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6294_nm.7856" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7856" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7856" rank="species">Pillotina calotermitidis</organism><reference id="rid.6294"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bermudes</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margulis</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Morphology as a basis for taxonomy of large spirochetes symbiotic in wood-eating cockroaches and termites: Pillotina gen. nov., nom. rev.; Pillotina calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx gen. nov., nom. rev.; Diplocalyx calotermitidis sp. nov., nom. rev.; Hollandina gen. nov., nom.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>302</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-3-291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11542253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pillotina calotermitidis</i> (ex Gharagozlou 1968) sp.. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pillotina calotermitidis</i> (cal.o.ter.mit.'id.is. M.L. gen. <i>calotermitidis</i>, named after the termite host <i>Calotermes</i> [synonyms, <i>Kalotermes</i>, <i>Postelectrotermes</i>] <i>praecox</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells are 1.0 to 1.5 μm in diameter, with 20 parallel ridges extending in a loosen spiral around the long axis nearly the full length, seen as crenulations in cross section.</s><s>Alternate pairs of lower and higher ridges in the outer membrane are symmetrically placed on either side of the sillon.</s><s>There are approximately 70 periplasmic flagella which are 15 to 18 nm in diameter.</s><s>Angle subtended by the flagella, 350°; concavity absent; no flagellar bundle.</s><s>The distribution of the flagella is delimited by a lamina between the inner and outer membranes.</s><s>An outer coat of the outer membrane is absent.</s><s>The thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane ranges from 22 to 77 nm (measured from the bottom of the crenulations toward the center of the cell) (average, 49.5 nm).</s><s>The ratio of the thickness of the inner coat of the outer membrane to the outer membrane thickness ranges from 3.3 to 11.9 (average, 6.7).</s><s>An outer coat of the inner membrane is absent.</s><s>The protoplasmic cylinder is circular to oblong in cross section and 0.5 to 0.7 μm in diameter.</s><s>The ratio of the protoplasmic cylinder diameter to the cell diameter is 0.47 to 0.50 (average, 0.49).</s><s>Microtubules, ca. 25 nm in diameter, are occasionally found within the protoplasmic cylinder.</s><s>The type specimen (10) is from <i>Calotermes praecox</i> from the Island of Madeira, Portugal.</s></p></content></protolog>