<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11905_nm.19991" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19991" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19991" rank="species">Chitinibacter alvei</organism><reference id="rid.11905"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>C.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinibacter alvei sp. nov., isolated from stream water</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1760</fpage><lpage>1764</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016170-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinibacter alvei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinibacter alvei</em> (a1′ve.i. L. gen. n. <em>alvei</em> bed of a river, referring to the location from where the type strain was isolated.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods (0.5–0.7 μm in width and 0.8–2.5 μm in length) that are highly motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are milky white, circular and slightly convex with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after growth on R2A agar for 72 h at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C, at pH 6–8 and in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 20 °C, at pH 7.0 and in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Cells are strictly aerobic.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, DNase, and hydrolysis of chitin and Tweens 20, 40 and 60.</s><s>Negative for lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of casein, starch and Tween 80.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative for indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon substrates (Biolog GN2): dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, citric acid, d-gluconic acid, succinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-serine and glycerol.</s><s>Unable to utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-hydroxyproline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, rifampicin, sulphamethoxazole and tetracycline.</s><s>Moderately susceptible to streptomycin.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin and penicillin G.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TNR-14<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25206<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22217<sup>T</sup> =BCRC 17968<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a stream located in southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>