<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10106_nm.15063" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15063" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15063" rank="species">Arenibacter nanhaiticus</organism><reference id="rid.10106"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenibacter nanhaiticus sp. nov., isolated from marine sediment of the South China Sea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>78</fpage><lpage>83</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008573-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648347</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenibacter nanhaiticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenibacter nanhaiticus</em> (nan.hai′ti.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nanhaiticus</em> pertaining to Nanhai, the Chinese name for the South China Sea, the site where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-stain-negative rods (0.45–0.8 μm wide and 1.4–3.8 μm long) that are motile by means of gliding.</s><s>Colonies on M2 are circular, moist-appearing, glistening with a smooth surface, low convex with entire margins, dark orange in colour and 1–3 mm in diameter after 5 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C and pH 6.1–9.6.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.0–8.5.</s><s>NaCl is essential for growth.</s><s>Growth is detected in the presence of 0.5–6.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 0.5–4.0 %.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of starch, gelatin liquefaction and urease activity.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>In assays with the API 20E system, <em>β</em>-galactosidase is positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>In API ZYM strips, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are positive.</s><s>Trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are weakly positive.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are negative.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 microplates, positive for oxidation of dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and acetic acid.</s><s>l-Glutamic acid is oxidized weakly.</s><s>Susceptible to cefoperazone, clindamycin, ciprofloxacin, ceftriaxone, erythromycin, lincomycin, furazolidone, ampicillin, cephazolin, carbenicillin, rifampicin, piperacillin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol and doxycycline hydrochloride, but resistant to cephalexin, kanamycin, norfloxacin, tetracycline, metronidazole, minocycline, vancomycin, streptomycin, polymyxin B, ofloxacin, trimethoprim, oxacillin, cephradine, gentamicin and neomycin.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are straight-chain unsaturated and saturated, and branched-chain unsaturated and saturated fatty acids, namely iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s><s>The major polar lipid is phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NH36A<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24842<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AB 208315<sup>T</sup>=MCCC 1A04137<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sandy sediment sample from the South China Sea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>