<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.80_nm.1555" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1555" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1555" rank="species">Pedomicrobium ferrugineum</organism><reference id="rid.80"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gebers</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beese</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedomicrobium americanum sp. nov. and Pedomicrobium australicum sp. nov. from aquatic habitats, Pedomicrobium gen. emend., and Pedomicrobium ferrugineum sp. emend.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>303</fpage><lpage>315</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Pedomicrobium ferrugineum</i> Aristovskaya 1961</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are spherical, oval, tetrahedral, or rod or bean shaped and are 0.6 to 2 by 0.6 to 2.5 μm. At least one hypha originates laterally; less frequently, other hyphae appear polarly or subpolarly. Multiplication is by budding at the tips of the hyphae which are 0.2 μm or less in diameter. Initially, buds are spherical to oval; they are motile by a single polar to subpolar flagellum. Occasionally, intercalary buds are observed. Deposition of oxidized iron compounds occurs when cells are grown with fulvic acid iron sesquioxide complexes, elemental iron powder, FeS, or iron paper clips; there is no accumulation of manganese compounds. Depositions occur primarily on mother cells and later on hyphae. Intracytoplasrnic membranes have not been found in ultrathin sections of strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup>. The temperature for optimum growth is 29 to 30°C; the temperature range is 18 to 43°C. The pH range for growth is 6.6 to 8.7 (Table 4). <i>P. ferrugineum</i> IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> grows in 50 mM HEPES-buffered PSM (Fig. 1); however, 100 and 200 mM HEPES prevent growth. Growth in unbuffered PSM at pH 6.6 gives higher protein yields than growth in PSM buffered with 10mM HEPES or 35 mM tris(hydroxy- methyl)aminomethane	hydrochloride (Table 4). Growth	in PSM containing 10mM HEPES is best at an initial pH of 8.1. During growth, the pH of all cultures increases.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The generation time of strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> in PSM is 10 h at 30°C.</s><s>The concentration of acetate in modified PSM (containing 0.1% yeast extract) influences the generation time and maximum optical density of <i>P. ferrugineum</i> cultures; 20 mM acetate results in a minimum generation time of 15.5 h and an optical density of 210 Klett units.</s><s>With 30 mM acetate, the generation time is 20.5 h, and a value of 240 Klett units is reached; however, cells of the latter cultures produce large granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs with 10 mM fumarate or 10 mM glutamate.</s><s>Slow, poor growth occurs with 10 mM oxalate, 10 mM tartrate, 10 mM cholesterol, 10 mM aspartate, 10 mM tryptophan, 10 mM alanine, or 0.3% paraffin.</s><s>No growth occurs with 10 mM galactose, 10 mM fructose, 10 mM maltose, 10 mM sucrose, 10 mM phenylalanine, 10 mM serine, or 10 mM lysine (7).</s><s>The utilization of other substrates is shown in Table 5.</s><s>Amino acids are utilized simultaneously as nitrogen sources (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The growth of strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> in PSM supplemented with 10 mM phenol, 10 mM benzoic acid, or 10 mM toluene was monitored by determining optical density values.</s><s>In these cultures, the lag phase was increased compared with cultures in pure PSM (Fig. 2).</s><s>Benzoic acid and toluene reduced the growth of strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> only to a small extent, whereas phenol caused a strong inhibition.</s><s>A second transfer to PSM supplemented with 10 mM phenol completely prevented growth (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs with 0.05% yeast extract or 0.05% peptone as a nitrogen source.</s><s>Within 6 days, strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> removes 44 to 87% of the amino acids from PSM culture broth (Table 6).</s><s>Slow, poor growth occurs with 0.05% Soytone, 0.05% Casamino Acids, 10 mM 2-aminobenzoic acid, 10 mM NaNO<sub>3</sub>, 10 mM acetamide, 10 mM urea, 10 mM N-acetylglucosamine, or 10 mM methylamine hydrochloride; and no growth occurs with 0.01 M NaNO<sub>2</sub>, 0.58 M (4%) NaNO<sub>2</sub>, or 1.06 M (9%) NaNO<sub>3</sub> (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A vitamin mixture (24) or 1 μg of cyanocobalamin per liter is required for good growth.</s><s>The presence of 0.1% NaCl stimulates growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are positive for cytochrome oxidase and for reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P.ferrugineum</i> strains are not pathogenic for guinea pigs after intraperitoneal injection of 10<sup>8</sup> cells (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to antibiotic susceptibilities in liquid cultures (Table 7), cells of strain IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> are susceptible in agar diffusion tests (7) to rifampin, tetracycline, gentamicin, and nitrofurazone,</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition of the type strain is 65 mol% G+C (T<sub>m</sub> method) (7, 9).</s><s>The average DNA base composition of four additional	strains	is 65 mol% G + C (T<sub>m</sub> method).</s><s>These strains exhibit levels of DNA-DNA homology of 97 to 104% to <i>P. ferrugineum</i> IFAM S-1290<sup>T</sup> (11).</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology to the other <i>Pedomicrobium</i> species are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains were isolated from podzolic soils in northern Germany (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IFAM S-1290 (= ATCC 33119 = DSM 1540).</s><s>Other strains include strains IFAM P-1196 (= ATCC 33116 = DSM 1541), IFAM Q-1197 (= ATCC 33117 = DSM 1542), IFAM R-1198 (= ATCC 33118 = DSM 1543), and IFAM T-1130 (= ATCC 33120 = DSM 1544).</s></p></content></protolog>