<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1380_nm.5576" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5576" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5576" rank="species">Leuconostoc citreum</organism><reference id="rid.1380"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Facklam</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nucleic acid homologies of some vancomycin-resistant leuconostocs and description of Leuconostoc citreum sp. nov. and Leuconostoc pseudomesenteroides sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>279</fpage><lpage>283</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-279</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leuconostoc citreum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leuconostoc citreum</i> (cit're.um. M.L.adj. <i>citreum</i>, lemon colored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spherical or lenticular cells (ca. 0.5 to 0.7 by 0.7 to 1.2 μm) that occur usually in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Most strains produce a lemon yellow pigment.</s><s>Grows at 10 and 30°C; some strains grow at 37°C but not at 40°C.</s><s>Acid is produced from <i>N</i>-acetylglucosamine, esculin, D-fructose, glucose, D-mannose, maltose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, sucrose, trehalose, and D-turanose.</s><s>The vast majority of strains produce acid from amygdalin, arbutin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, D-mannitol, and salicin.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from 2-keto-gluconate, galactose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, D-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, 5-keto-gluconate7 lactose, D-lyxose, melezitose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, β-methyl-xyloside, raffinose, ribose, L-rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, starch, D-tagatose, xylitol, or L-xylose.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, β-D-xylosidase, and urease negative.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 38.0 to 40.3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Isolated from food and clinical sources.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 1837.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain corresponds to the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from amygdalin, L-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, mannitol, and salicin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from melibiose, raffinose, or D-xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>