<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9575_nm.14754" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14754" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14754" rank="species">Andreprevotia lacus</organism><reference id="rid.9575"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>T.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>D.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A. B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Andreprevotia lacus sp. nov., isolated from a fish-culture pond</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2482</fpage><lpage>2485</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009233-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622669</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Andreprevotia lacus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Andreprevotia lacus</em> (la′cus. L. gen. n. <em>lacus</em> of a lake, basin or tank, referring to the place of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are accumulated.</s><s>After 48 h growth on R2A agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is 0.5 μm in width and 1.0–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Visible, round, entire, convex and ivory-coloured colonies are formed on R2A agar.</s><s>Colony size is approximately 1.8–2.2 mm in diameter after 48 h at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C, 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl and pH 7.0–9.0 [optimum at 30 °C, 0–0.5 % (w/v) NaCl and pH 7.0].</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase activities and chitin hydrolysis.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of DNase, lipase (corn oil), Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, starch, CM-cellulose, aesculin, tyrosine and casein.</s><s>Positive (API 20NE) for nitrate reduction, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, protease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, adipate, malate and citrate; negative for indole production and assimilation of phenylacetate, gluconate and caprate.</s><s>Positive (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; negative for C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized in the API 50CH test system: d-ribose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-lyxose and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, <em>α</em>-melezitose, <em>α</em>-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, kanamycin, rifampicin, gentamicin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin and streptomycin, but resistant to ampicillin, penicillin G and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GFC-1<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17832<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24502<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a fish-culture pond located in Taoyuan County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>