<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2400_nm.3837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3837" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3837" rank="species">Helicobacter bizzozeronii</organism><reference id="rid.2400"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hänninen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Happonen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saari</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jalava</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Culture and characteristics of Helicobacter bizzozeronii, a new canine gastric Helicobacter sp.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>166</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573490</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter bizzozeronii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter bizzozeronii</i> (biz.zo'zero.ni.i. L. gen. n. bizzozeronii, of Bizzozero, referring to Guilio Bizzozero, an Italian pathologist who was one of the first scientists to describe canine gastric spiral organisms [1])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are spirals that are 0.3 by 5 to 10 μm.</s><s>They do not have periplasmic fibrils.</s><s>In older cultures coccoid forms predominate.</s><s>The cells are gram negative and nonsporulating.</s><s>They are motile by means of tufts of 10 to 20 sheathed flagella at both ends of each cell.</s><s>Individual colonies are not usually produced on agar media, but cultures grow as spreading films on fresh moist agar media.</s><s>All strains are oxidase, catalase, and urease positive.</s><s>They reduce nitrate and TTC, and they are positive in indoxyl acetate, gammaglutamyl transpeptidase, and alkaline phosphatase tests.</s><s>They are negative in hippurate hydrolysis, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, L-arginine arylamidase, and L-aspartate arylamidase tests.</s><s>They are resistant to nalidixic acid and susceptible to cephalothin, cefoperazone, and metronidazole.</s><s>They do not grow on medium containing 1% ox bile, 1% glycine, or 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>They grow at 37 and 42°C but not at 25°C.</s><s>All of the biochemical and tolerance characteristics which we studied except indoxyl acetate hydrolysis are similar to the characteristics of <i>H. felis</i> CS1.</s><s>All <i>H. bizzozeronii</i> strains and <i>H. felis</i> CS1 produce DNase.</s><s>Two strains have been deposited in the culture collection of the University of Goteborg, Sweden: CCUG 35045 and CCUG 35046.</s></p></content></protolog>