<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3738_nm.8649" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8649" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8649" rank="species">Kordia algicida</organism><reference id="rid.3738"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>T.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kordia algicida gen. nov., sp. nov., an algicidal bacterium isolated from red tide.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>675</fpage><lpage>680</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02689-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143006</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kordia algicida</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kordia algicida</em> (al.gi′ci.da. L. fem. n. <em>alga</em> -<em>ae</em> alga; L. suff. -<em>cida</em> from L. v. <em>caedere</em> to cut or to kill; N.L. n. <em>algicida</em> alga-killer).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell widths range from 0·3 to 0·5 μm; cell lengths range from 2 to 5 μm.</s><s>Resting stages are absent.</s><s>Colonies on solid media (ZoBell 2216e and TSA plus sea water) are yellowish, slightly convex (elevation), entire (margin) and round (configuration).</s><s>Urease and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (aesculinase) are absent.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s><em>α</em>-Cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, sucrose, citric acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, l-asparatic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, uridine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate are oxidized, but not Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N-</em>acetyl-d-galactosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol or dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Negative for O/F test (glucose).</s><s>Does not utilize urea, NH<sub>4</sub> or NO<sub>3</sub> as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Degrades gelatin, skimmed milk and starch, but not cellulose, CM-cellulose, agar, chitin, alginate, pectin or inulin.</s><s>Grows optimally at 30 °C, pH 7–8 and 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not grow in ZoBell 2216e broth with 0 or 6 % NaCl, nor at pH 5.</s><s>Requires sea salts (Na<sup>+</sup>, Ca<sup>2+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup>) for growth.</s><s>Distinctive features of the fatty acid profile are high levels of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (41·2 %) and the presence of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is OT-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 8814P<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 1000336<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from a sea water sample associated with red tide in Masan Bay, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>