<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3447_nm.1078" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1078" rank="genus">Maricaulis</organism><reference id="rid.3447"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strömpl</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lindholst</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christ</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bennasar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tesar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogeny and polyphasic taxonomy of Caulobacter species. Proposal of Maricaulis gen. nov. with Maricaulis maris (Poindexter) comb. nov. as the type species, and emended description of the genera Brevundimonas and Caulobacter.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1053</fpage><lpage>1073</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1053</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425763</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Maricaulis</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Maricaulis</i> (Ma.ri.cau'li.s. L. neut. n. <i>mare</i> the sea; L. masc. n. <i>caulis</i> stalk referring to a prostheca; M.L. masc. n. <i>Maricaulis</i> stalk from the sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative cells, rod-shaped, fusiform or vibroid, 0.4-0.5 by 1-2 μm.</s><s>Cells possess a prostheca, ca. 0.15 μm in diameter and of varying length depending on the species and environmental conditions, extending from one pole as a continuation of the long axis of the cell.</s><s>Adhesive material is present at the distal end of the prostheca.</s><s>Occur singly.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>At the time of separation one cell possesses a prostheca and the other a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Each new appendage occurs at the cell pole opposite to the one formed during fission.</s><s>The flagellated cell secretes adhesive material at the base of the flagellum, develops a prostheca at this site and enters the immotile vegetative phase.</s><s>Colonies circular, convex, colourless.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic aerobes, but most of the strains tested could grow anaerobically probably using amino acid as fermentable carbon source (Anast &#x0026; Smit, 1988).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite anaerobically by some strains.</s><s>Most strains can store carbon as poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid.</s><s>As well as mixtures of B vitamins and amino acids, other organic factors are required for growth.</s><s>All strains can grow on peptone yeast extract media with 5 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>; optimal growth between 20-60 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>NaCl is required for optimal growth, only a few strains tolerate salt concentrations above 100 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Growth is inhibited or cells become deformed in media containing 1% (w/v) or more organic material.</s><s>Temperature range of most isolates is 15-35°; 20-25°C is optimal.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is around neutrality, pH range is 6.0-8.0.</s><s>All strains are characterizedby three major fatty acids 16:0, 17:1isoω9<i>c</i> and sum7 (see Table 3) and the following minor compounds: 11:0iso 3-OH, 17:1ω8, 17:0iso, 17:0, and 18:1ω9.</s><s>Polar lipids are α-D-glucopyranosyl diacylglycerol, α-D-glucopyranuronosyl diacylglycerol, sulfoquinovosyl diacylglycerol, α-D-glucuronopyranosyl diacylglycerol taurine amide.</s><s>Most strains contain also phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>All isolates were obtained only from sea water.</s><s>The G + C content is 62.5-64-0 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Maricaulis maris</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>