<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6903_nm.618" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.618" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.618" rank="species">Geovibrio thiophilus</organism><reference id="rid.6903"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Geovibrio thiophilus sp. nov., a novel sulfur-reducing bacterium belonging to the phylum Deferribacteres.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1341</fpage><lpage>1347</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02116-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148649</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Geovibrio thiophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Geovibrio thiophilus</i> (thi.o'phi.lus. Gr. n. <i>theion</i> sulfur; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; M.L. masc. adj. <i>thiophilus</i> sulfur-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, spiral-shaped cells, 0.35 μm in diameter and 2.5-6 μm long, each motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Cells occur singly.</s><s>Cells contain c-type cytochromes.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 50.2 mol%.</s><s>Uses sulfur, nitrate, fumarate, DMSO and oxygen (microaerophilically) as electron acceptors.</s><s>Sulfide, hydrogen, formate and acetate act as electron donors for respiratory growth.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, nitrite and ferric iron are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Fumarate, maleate and l-malate support fermentative growth.</s><s>Neither fermentative nor respiratory growth is observed with carbohydrates, fatty acids more than two carbons long, acetone, alcohols or amino acids.</s><s>Grows best in a growth medium with less than 20 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Grows most rapidly at 37-40°C.</s><s>Growth is possible at 4°C, but not at 45°C.</s><s>Sequence analysis of the 16S rRNA gene shows that the species is closely related to <i>Geovibrio ferrireducens</i>.</s><s>The type strain, AAFu3<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from the surface sediments of a ditch in Konstanz, Germany, and has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 11263<sup>T</sup> and in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC BAA- 311<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>