<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1599_nm.10895" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10895" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10895" rank="species">Nesterenkonia jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.1599"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nesterenkonia jeotgali sp. nov., isolated from jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2587</fpage><lpage>2592</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64266-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082396</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nesterenkonia jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nesterenkonia jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci (diameter 0.5–0.8 μm) on MA at 30 °C; some cells are oval in the very early growth phase.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular, slightly convex or raised, glistening and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 5 days cultivation at 30 °C on MA.</s><s>Colonies on MA are vivid yellow in colour at 30 °C, but orange–yellow in colour at 25 °C.</s><s>Colonies on solid PYGV medium are light yellow in colour at 25 and 30 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 25–30 °C; growth occurs at 4 and 36 °C, but not at 37 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 7.5–8.5; growth occurs at pH 6.0, but not at pH 5.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2–5 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs in the presence of 0–16 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions on MA or on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Tyrosine is hydrolysed, but aesculin, casein, hypoxanthine, xanthine and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Methyl red reaction is positive.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and leucine arylamidase are present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>d-Galactose, acetate, citrate, succinate, l-malate and pyruvate are utilized.</s><s>Benzoate, salicin, formate and l-glutamate are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-ribose and sucrose, but not from d-fructose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, <em>myo</em>-inositol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Susceptible to penicillin G, chloramphenicol, ampicillin, cephalothin, novobiocin and carbenicillin, but not to polymyxin B, gentamicin, kanamycin or neomycin.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan type is l-lys-gly–d-Asp.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-7, MK-8 and MK-9.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 68.0 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JG-241<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19053<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12610<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s></p></content></protolog>