<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1384_nm.5693" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5693" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5693" rank="species">Streptococcus vestibularis</organism><reference id="rid.1384"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus vestibularis sp. nov. from human oral cavity.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>335</fpage><lpage>339</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-335</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus vestibularis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus vestibularis</i> (ves.tib.u.lar´is. L. noun <i>vestibulum</i>, entrance hall or forecourt, referring to the vestibule of the mouth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the results of the present work together with data from the study of Carlsson (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, catalase-negative cocci, approximately 1 μm in diameter, that grow in chains.</s><s>Colonies grown anaerobically at 37°C for 3 days on mitis salivarius agar are usually 2 to 3 mm in diameter, dark blue, matte, and umbonate with undulate edges.</s><s>Colonies grown aerobically on mitis salivarius agar are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, dark blue, convex, and glossy with entire edges.</s><s>Strain LV71 is an exception, producing glossy, entire colonies even under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Growth on TYC agar both anaerobically and aerobically produces colonies 1 to 2 mm in diameter that are white, convex, and glossy with entire edges.</s><s>Acid is produced from <sub>N</sub>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, salicin, and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, arabinose, dextrin, dulcitol, fucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribitol, ribose, sorbitol, starch, or xylose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from cellobiose and amygdalin.</s><s>Few strains produce acid from trehalose or D-glucosamine hydrochloride.</s><s>Only strains HV81, OP81, and LV8l ferment trehalose; these are the same three isolates which are unable to ferment cellobiose and amygdalin and constitute a separate biotype from the majority of the strains examined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Urease and hydrogen peroxide are produced.</s><s>Most strains produce acetoin and hydrolyze esculin and starch.</s><s>The type strain, strain MM1, is weakly positive in the Voges-Proskauer test and hydrolyzes both esculin and starch.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 or 45°C, in the presence of 4% (wt/vol) NaCl, or in the presence of 0.0004% (wt/vol) crystal violet.</s><s>Most strains grow in the presence of 10% (wt/vol) bile but not in the presence of 40% (wt/vol) bile.</s><s>Strain MM1<sup>T</sup> does not grow in 10% bile.</s><s>Polysaccharide is not produced intra- or extracellularly.</s><s>All strains produce alpha-hemolysis on horse blood agar.</s><s>The cellular long-chain fatty acids consist of major amounts of hexadecanoic (C16:0; palmitoleic) and octadecenoic (C18:1ω7; <i>cis</i>-vaccenic) acids together with tetradecanoic (C14:O; myristic), hexadecenoic (C16:1; palmitoleic), octadecanoic (C18:O; stearic), octadecenoic (C18:1ω9; oleic) and eicosenoic (C20:1) acids.</s><s>This organism has been isolated mainly from the vestibular mucosa of human oral cavities.</s><s>The G+C content is 38 to 40 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain MM1 (= NCTC 12166)</s></p></content></protolog>