<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7397_nm.5694" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5694" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5694" rank="species">Streptococcus waius</organism><reference id="rid.7397"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Flint</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>L.J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brooks</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus waius sp. nov., a thermophilic Streptococcus from a biofilm.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>759</fpage><lpage>767</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-759</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319500</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus waius</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus waius</i> (waius. New Zealand Maori n. <i>waiu</i> milk; N.L. gen. n. <i>waius</i> of milk)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore forming, 0.7 μm diameter cocci in pairs or short chains.</s><s>When the organism is grown on M17 agar at 37°C for 48 h, colonies are 0.5 mm in diameter, circular, convex, translucent and smooth.</s><s>The organisms are homofermentative, facultatively anaerobic and catalasenegative.</s><s>The organisms will clot milk at 45°C with an optimum temperature for growth of 38.8°C, but are capable of growing over a range of 24.5-52.4°C.</s><s>They will grow over the pH range 4.0-10.0 and are tolerant of salt up to 7 % NaCl.</s><s>They are intolerant of bile at 1 %.</s><s>The bacteria ferment galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, N-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, saccharose and D-raffinose.</s><s>The bacterium produces the following enzymes: leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase.The DNA G + C content is 34.6 mol%.</s><s>The habitat is milk and dairy products.</s><s>The type strain is 3/1<sup>T</sup> and is lodged in the New Zealand Reference Culture Collection (NZRCC 20100<sup>T</sup>) at the New Zealand Dairy Research Institute, Palmerston North, New Zealand.</s></p></content></protolog>