<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2503_nm.4463" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4463" rank="genus">Syntrophomonas</organism><reference id="rid.2503"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lorowitz</surname><given-names>W.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophomonas wolfei subsp. saponavida subsp. nov., a long-chain fatty-acid-degrading, anaerobic, syntrophic bacterium; Syntrophomonas wolfei subsp. wolfei subsp. nov.; and emended descriptions of the genus and species.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>122</fpage><lpage>126</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-122</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophomonas</i> McInerney et al. 1981,1037, emend. Lorowitz, Zhao and Bryant 1989.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophomonas</i> (Syn. tro. pho. mon' as. Gr. adj. <i>syn</i>, together with; Gr. n. <i>trophos</i>, one who feeds; Gr. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit, monad; M. L. fem. n. <i>Syntrophomonas</i>, monad which feeds together with [another species])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonsporing, gram-negative, slightly helical rods, 0.4 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 7.0 μm, with slightly tapered rounded ends.</s><s>Most cells occur singly or in pairs, with helical chains of three or more cells often observed.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Cells possess two to eight flagella (diameter, about 20 nm) that are laterally inserted in a linear fashion on the concave side of the cell about 130 nm or more apart.</s><s>Under most conditions, cells usually exhibit only sluggish twitching motility.</s><s>Cells have an unusual multilayered gram-negative wall.</s><s>Muramic and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acids are present, and the organism is susceptible to penicillin.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Cells anaerobically β-oxidize saturated fatty acids, with protons serving as the electron acceptors in cocultures with an H, scavenger.</s><s>Growth is much faster with <i>Methanospirillum hungatei</i>, which utilizes both H<sub>2</sub> and formate, than with methanogens such as <i>Methanobacterium bryantii</i>, which utilizes only H<sub>2</sub>. (It is possible that strains contain a formate-forming CO<sub>2</sub> reductase.) In coculture cells produce acetate and H<sub>2</sub> from butyrate and longer straight-chain, even-humbered-carbon fatty acids and acetate, propionate, and H<sub>2</sub> from <i>n</i>-valerate and longer straight-chain, odd-numbered-carbon fatty acids.</s><s>At least some strains produce acetate, isovalerate, and H<sub>2</sub> from iso acids, such as isoheptanoate, and some strains produce acetate, propionate, and H<sub>2</sub> from 2-methylbutyrate. (It is possible but has not yet been determined that anteiso acids, such as anteisooctanoate, are degraded to acetate, anteisohexanoate, and H<sub>2</sub>.) The strains studied so far can, with considerable difficulty, be adapted to grow slowly without coculture on crotonate, with acetate and butyrate as the products.</s><s>Carbohydrates, proteinaceous materials, alcohols, or other organic compounds do not support growth.</s><s>Common electron acceptors, such as fumarate, malate, nitrate, oxygen, sulfate, sulfite, sulfur, and thiosulfate, are not utilized with butyrate as the electron donor.</s><s>Growth may be stimulated in cocultures by factors in rumen fluid or mixtures of vitamins or both.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated as cocultures from anaerobic ecosystems, such as aquatic sediments, sewage digestor sludge, and rumen digesta where organic matter is degraded with CO<sub>2</sub> and CH<sub>4</sub> as major products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The temperature range for cocultures with <i>Methanospirillum hungatei</i> is in the broad mesophilic range, with an optimum of 30 to 37°C.</s><s>The pH range has not been determined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetically (as determined by 16s ribosomal ribonucleic acid sequencing), <i>Syntrophomonas</i> is in a so-far-unique group of gram-positive eubacteria that β-oxidize SFAs and include sporeformers without cell outer membranes and nonsporing bacteria with outer membranes.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Syntrophomonas wolfei</i> is the type species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Because of the proposed emendation of the genus and description of the new subspecies (see below), new descriptions of <i>S. wolfei</i> and <i>S. wolfei</i> subsp. <i>wolfei</i> (named to honor R.</s><s>S.</s><s>Wolfe) are needed.</s></p></content></protolog>