<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3210_nm.8386" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8386" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8386" rank="species">Propionigenium maris</organism><reference id="rid.3210"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Succinate decarboxylation by Propionigenium maris sp. nov., a new anaerobic bacterium from an estuarine sediment</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>164</volume><fpage>29</fpage><lpage>35</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02568731</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7646317</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionigenium maris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionigenium maris</i> (ma'ris, L. n. <i>mare</i> the sea; L. gen. n. <i>maris</i> of the sea; referring to the tidal mud flats from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are normally oval to round-ended short rods, 1.0 μm wide by 1.2-2.5 μm long, but under some culture conditions the cells can be up to 50 μm long.</s><s>Spores are not formed, and the cells are not motile.</s><s>The wall structure is of a gram-negative type, and the cells stain gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. maris</i> has a chemoorganotrophic, fermentative metabolism.</s><s>In the presence of yeast extract, a number of carbohydrates and amino and organic acids are fermented and increase the growth yield.</s><s>These substrates include succinate, fumarate, pyruvate, citrate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, glucose, fructose, maltose, aspartate, lysine, threonine, glutamate, and cysteine.</s><s>Typical organic end products of catabolism include formate, acetate, propionate, and butyrate.</s><s>Carbohydrates are fermented to formate, acetate, ethanol, and lactate.</s><s>Hydrogen is produced from carbohydrates and yeast extract, ammonia from amino acids, and sulfide from cysteine.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate, and nitrate are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase activity is not present.</s><s>Indole is formed from L-tryptophan.</s><s>Esculin and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth requires anoxic conditions.</s><s>The temperature optimum for growth is 34–37°C, and no growth occurs at 43°C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is between pH 6.9 and 7.7, and the limits are pH 5.3 and 8.8.</s><s>Growth is possible at 5 and at 55 g/l NaCl, but not at 2 or 60 g/l.</s><s>Optimal growth is obtained at 15-20 g/l NaCl.</s><s>No cytochromes are formed.</s><s>The DNA base ratio is 40 mol% G+C (determined by thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetic analysis reveals a close relationship between <i>P. maris</i> and <i>P. modestum</i>.</s><s>Both species form a distinct lineage within a phylogenetically coherent group characterized by <i>Leptotrichia buccalis</i>, <i>Sebaldella termitidis</i> and <i>Fusobacterium</i> spp.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>P. maris</i>, strain 10succ1 (DSM 9537), was isolated from an anoxic intertidal sediment and is deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>