<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5789_nm.4746" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4746" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4746" rank="species">Ureaplasma urealyticum</organism><reference id="rid.5789"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>J.A</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stemke</surname><given-names>G.W</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harasawa</surname><given-names>R</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thirkell</surname><given-names>D</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>F</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shepard</surname><given-names>M.C</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Ureaplasma parvum sp. nov. and emended description of Ureaplasma urealyticum (Shepard et al. 1974) Robertson et al. 2001.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>587</fpage><lpage>597</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01965-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931172</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Ureaplasma urealyticum</i> (Shepard et al. 1974) Robertson et al. 2001</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Phenotypic characteristics. Growth inhibition of cells by (or colony reaction with) polyclonal antisera to one or more of the specific antigenic determinants associated with the present T960<sup>T</sup> biovar of the human urea plasmas (serovars 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 or 13) but not to any antigenic determinants associated with the proposed <i>U. parvum</i> (parvo biovar of human ureaplasmas or its serovars 1, 3, 6 or 14). T960<sup>T</sup> biovarspecific polypeptide patterns obtained by PAGE: these may be enhanced through reaction with polyclonal antiserum or monoclonal antibodies to the antigenic specificities associated with the species. Growth is inhibited permanently in the presence of 1 mM Mn<sup>2+</sup>, with the exception of serovar 13, which shows severely delayed growth - a response which is intermediate between that shown by strains of the T960<sup>T</sup> and parvo biovars of human ureaplasmas. Genotypic characteristics. Genomes ranging from C840 to C1140 kbp which demonstrate "70% hybridization patterns with DNA of other strains of the present T960<sup>T</sup> biovar of ureaplasmas; RFLP patterns similar to those of other serovars of the T960<sup>T</sup> biovar but which differ from those characteristic of the proposed <i>U. parvum</i>; amplification with PCRs for T960<sup>T</sup> biovar-specific nucleotide sequences for the urease-associated genes, the 16S rRNA genes, the 16S-23S rRNA intergenic regions, and the 5«-end of the genes of the multiple-banded antigens, and T960<sup>T</sup>-specific randomly amplified polymorphic DNA PCR. The type strain of <i>U. urealyticum</i> will continue to be serovar 8 standard (strain T960<sup>T</sup>), represented by ATTC 27618<sup>T</sup> and NCTC 10177<sup>T</sup>. The estimated G+­C content of the DNA is 27-28 mol%; its genome size isC890 kbp. The most recent GenBank accession numbers for the sequences of its 16S rRNA and 16S-23S rRNA intergenic spacer region are AF073450 and AF059330, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>