<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2614_nm.3011" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3011" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3011" rank="species">Vibrio tubiashii</organism><reference id="rid.2614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hada</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>West</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stemmler</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio tubiashii sp. nov., a pathogen of bivalve mollusks.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>4</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-1-1</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio tubiashii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio tubiashii</i> (tu.bi.ash'i.i. L. gen. n. <i>tubiashii</i> named after H. S. Tubiash, who first isolated the organism [7])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative short rods (0.5 by 1.5 μm) that are straight or curved and motile by means of a single polar flagellum when they are grown in liquid media.</s><s>The cells do not swarm on solid media, but lateral short-wavelength flagella may be produced.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar (Difco Laboratories, Detroit, Mich.) are smooth, circular, and off-white and may be mucoid.</s><s>Colonies on TCBS agar (Oxoid Ltd., Basingstoke, England) are smooth, circular, and yellow (sucrose fermenting).</s><s>No pigments are produced, and strains do not luminesce.</s><s>Sodium chloride is required for growth, the optimum concentration being 1 to 3% (wt/vol); strains are not able to grow in 8% (wt/vol) NaC1.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose.</s><s>Kovacs oxidase positive.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Chitin, DNA, gelatin, lecithin, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine, and xanthine are hydrolyzed extracellularly , but sodium alginate and elastin are not.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Grows on simple mineral media on a variety of organic carbon sources, including glycine, mannose, and galactose but not D-sorbitol or γ-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Produces β-galactosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from sucrose and D-mannose but not from L-arabinose, arbutin, <i>m</i>-inositol, lactose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, or D-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7 diisopropylpteridine (agent 0/129) phosphate (10-μg disk) and polymyxin B (50-Iu disk).</s><s>Not able to decarboxylate lysine and ornithine.</s><s>Chicken erythrocytes are not agglutinated.</s><s>Pathogenic for oyster (<i>Crassostrea virginica</i>, <i>Crassostrea gigas</i>, and <i>Ostrea edulis</i>) and clam (<i>Mercenaris mercenaria</i>) larvae.</s><s>The characteristics which vary among strains are listed in Table 3.</s><s>The base composition of the DNA ranges from 43 to 45 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains have been isolated from diseased larvae of clams and oysters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 19109.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, and other characteristics are given in Table 3.</s><s>The base composition of the DNA is 43 to 45 mol% G+C, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics of strains ATCC 19105, ATCC 19106, and ATCC 19109<sup>T</sup> have been given elsewhere (9).</s><s>Characteristically, all strains of the species are able to hydrolyze xanthine and tyrosine extracellularly over a 14-day incubation period.</s><s>Although the zone of clearing in these tests may only be below the colony, it is a character that is easy to determine and useful for identification.</s><s>No other species of <i>Vibrio</i> described so far can degrade xanthine, and tyrosine hydrolysis is restricted to only a few strains (9).</s><s>Some strains of <i>V. tubiashii</i> are also unusual for vibrios in being able to grow on adenine and melibiose (Table 3).</s><s>In addition, strains of <i>V. tubiashii</i> can grow on glycine, are Voges-Proskauer negative, do not produce acid from L-arabinose or D-sorbitol, do not agglutinate chicken erythrocytes, and are not able to grow on sorbitol.</s><s>These features readily distinguish <i>V. tubiashii</i> from <i>V. anguillarum</i>, and <i>V. tubiashii</i> may be distinguished from other similar species of <i>Vibrio</i> on the basis of the tests shown in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>