<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.806_nm.2815" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2815" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2815" rank="species">Alteromonas distincta</organism><reference id="rid.806"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stepanenko</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of melanin-producing bacteria of the genus Alteromonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>74</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alteromonas distincta</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alteromonas distincta</i> (Dis. tin. cta. The species epithet is derived from the Latin masculine adjective distincta - distinct)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are of a rod-like form with rounded ends; the average diameter is 0.91 μm, and the average length is 2.53 μm.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of one - two polar flagella located at the same pole or three - four flagella attached laterally and at one of the poles; some cells possess five - seven lateral and polar flagella.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Spores and capsules are not formed.</s><s>On complex solid media containing seawater, the colonies are convex, smooth, glistening, translucent, black-brown pigmented, and 3 - 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>The pigment diffuses into the medium and forms a black-brown halo around the colonies in 10 - 12 h of growth.</s><s>The pigment is of a melanoid nature and is more actively produced at 4 - 15°C.</s><s>The presence of seawater or 1 - 6% NaCl is required for growth; no growth occurs without sodium ions.</s><s>Growth is possible within a pH range of 6.0 - 9.0 (with an optimum at 7.5 - 8.5) and a temperature range of 4 - 35°C (with an optimum at 20 - 25°C); no growth occurs at 40°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are chemoorganoheterotrophic.</s><s>As the sole carbon and energy source, citrate, acetate, tyrosine, and arginine can be used.</s><s>Yeast extract, casein hydrolysate, gelatin, and tween-80 are utilized.</s><s>Sugars and alcohols are not used.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Starch, alginate, N-acetylglucosamine, and chitin are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA GC content is 43.8 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KMM 638, which was isolated from a sponge collected at a depth of 350 m near the Komandorskie Islands.</s><s>The description of the strain is the same as for the species.</s><s>The strain has been deposited with the Collection of Marine Microorganisms of the Pacific Institute of Bioorganic Chemistry, Far Eastern Division of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Vladivostok.</s></p></content></protolog>