<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7251_nm.6435" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6435" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6435" rank="species">Nocardia crassostreae</organism><reference id="rid.7251"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Friedman</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaman</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gee</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hedrick</surname><given-names>R.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia crassostreae sp. nov., the causal agent of nocardiosis in Pacific oysters.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>237</fpage><lpage>246</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-237</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542093</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Nocardia crassostreae Friedman, Beaman, Chun, Goodfellow, Gee and Hedrick sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Nocardia crassostreae (crass.os'tre.ae. M.L. n. Crassostrea generic name of Pacific oyster; M.L. gen. n. crassostreae of Crassostrea, referring to the source of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, acid-fast, non-motile actinomycetes which form a branched substrate mycelium which fragments into irregular rod-shaped forms.</s><s>Pale yellow, waxy, wrinkled colonies are formed on BHI agar.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are not formed.</s><s>Strains have an oxidative metabolism and are catalase- and urease-positive but oxidase-negative.</s><s>Degrades aesculin, Tweens 20 and 80, but not casein, gelatin, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, galactose, maltose, D-mannitol, rhamnose or xylose.</s><s>Gluconic acid, propionic acid, salicin, creatine and ethanol are not used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>L-Valine is used as a sole carbon and nitrogen source but not L-arginine, lysine or ornithine.</s><s>Grows at 22-30°C and in the presence of isoniazid (200 μm ml<sup>-1</sup>), lyzozyme, sodium chloride (2%, w /v) but not at 5°C, at pH 9, or in the presence of 5-fluorouracil (20 μm ml<sup>-1</sup>), mitomycin C (5 μm ml<sup>-1</sup>), rifampicin (20 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) or sodium chloride (5%, w /v).</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-DAP and whole-organism hydrolysates have large amounts of arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The organism contains [MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>)C] menaquinones.</s><s>Cell wall mycolic acids have 46-58 carbon atoms; on Py-GLC, large amounts of C<sub>12:0</sub>, C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>Isolated from cultured Pacific oysters (<i>Crassostrea gigas</i>).</s><s>Type strain: <i>Nocardia crassostreae</i> strain NB4H (=ATCC 700418).</s></p></content></protolog>