<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3003_nm.3038" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3038" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3038" rank="species">Photobacterium profundum</organism><reference id="rid.3003"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Masui</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Photobacterium profundum sp. nov., a new, moderately barophilic bacterial species isolated from a deep-sea sediment.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s007920050036</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9676237</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Photobacterium profundum</i> Nogi, Masui, and Kato sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Photobacterium profundum</i> (pro.fun'dum L. adj.n <i>profundum</i> deep, living within the depth of the oceans)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped; cell width ranges from 0.8 to 1.0 μm, and cell length ranges from 2 to 4 μm.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative and motile by means of a single unsheathed polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on Marine Agar 2216 are entire, smooth, non-luminescent, and ivory; they are 0.7-1.0 mm in diameter after 48h of incubation at 10°C.</s><s>The bacterium is halophilic and psychrophilic.</s><s>Best growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of ca. 3%.</s><s>No growth occurs in absence of NaCl.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is between 8° and 12°.</s><s>No growth occurs at 0° or 20°C.</s><s>It is a facultatively anaerobic chemoorganotroph having both respiratory and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase.</s><s>Acids are produced from D-glucose but gas is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The organism does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: Tween 40, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-trehalose, and glycerol.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: adonitol, L-arabinose, lactose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, and turanose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 42mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are 16:1, iso-16:0, 16:0, 18:1, and 20:5 ω3c (IPA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>Photobacterium profundum</i> sp. strain DSJ4, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as strain JCM10084.</s></p></content></protolog>