<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.459_nm.2369" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2369" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2369" rank="species">Legionella micdadei</organism><reference id="rid.459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hébert</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Legionella micdadei species nova: classification of a third species of Legionella associated with human pneumonia.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>225</fpage><lpage>257</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02601800</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Legionella micdadei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Legionella micdadei</i> (pronounced mick-day'-dee, in honor of Joseph E. McDade, who first isolated <i>L. pneumophila</i>. He has contributed much to our understanding of all three <i>Legionella</i> species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>L. micdadei</i> is TATLOCK (ATCC 33218), isolated by Hugh Tatlock in 1943 [14].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Labeled DNA from TATLOCK, <i>Legionella pneumophila</i>, and <i>L. bozemanii</i> was allowed to reassociate with unlabeled DNA from TATLOCK, HEBA, PPA, and strains of <i>L. pneumophila</i> [2] and <i>L. bozemanii</i> [4].</s><s>The results (Table 1) indicate that TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA belong to the same species and that they are a separate species from <i>L. pneumophila</i> and <i>L. bozemanii</i>.</s><s>Labeled TATLOCK DNA was 90% or more related to unlabeled DNAs from HEBA and PPA in 60°C reactions.</s><s>There was no evidence of divergence (unpaired bases) within the related nucleotide sequences, and relatedness remained high in 75°C reactions in which only closely related sequences can reassociate.</s><s>Strains of a species usually are 70% or more related in 60°C reactions, contain less than 6% divergence within related sequences, and show 60% or more relatedness in 75°C reactions.</s><s>By all of these criteria, TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA belong to the same species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>TATLOCK was only minimally related to several strains of <i>L. pneumophila</i> and to the two known strains of <i>L. bozemanii</i>.</s><s>These data were confirmed in reciprocal reactions in which labeled DNA from <i>L. pneumophila</i> strain Philadelphia 1 and <i>L. bozemanii</i> strain WIGA were 5% and 0%, respectively, related to unlabeled DNAs from TATLOCK and HEBA.</s><s>Relatedness results vary considerably when the DNA preparations are labeled in vitro, as these were.</s><s>We therefore do not stress the quantitative results; however, the qualitative interpretation of these data leaves no doubt that TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA are not members of either <i>L. pneumophila</i> or <i>L. bozemanii</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA are phenotypirally identical [7,8].</s><s>They were initially isolated on CYE agar after 3-4 days of incubation in a moist atmosphere at 35°C After several transfers on CYE agar, all three strains grew on Feeley-Gorman agar [6] and caused browning of the agar.</s><s>They did not grow on commonly used laboratory media, such as blood agar or nutrient agar.</s><s>Colonies on CYE agar were a dull yeIlow under long-wavelength ultraviolet excitation.</s><s>They are Gram-negative bacilli that are not acid fast with the Ziehl-Neelsen stain for mycobacteria.</s><s>Each of these strains has a polar flagellum.</s><s>Their biochemical reactions are identical to those of <i>L. pneumophila</i>.</s><s>They do not produce urease, reduce nitrate to nitrite, or ferment carbohydrates, but they liquify gelatin, utilize starch, and produce catatase and oxidase.</s><s>Unlike <i>L. pneumophila</i>, cultures of TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA do not produce a β-lactamase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A TATLOCK direct FA reagent had the same high titer with TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA, but did not stain any of 220 other organisms tested, including <i>L. pneumophila</i> and <i>L. bozemanii</i>.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid composition of these bacteria, like that of <i>L. pneumophila</i> and <i>L. bozemanii</i>, is unusual for Gram-negative bacteria because of the large amount of total branched-chain acids.</s><s>The major acid in TATLOCK, HEBA, and PPA is a-15:0, and the second most abundant acid is a-17:0 [7,8].</s><s>They contain only trace amounts of i-I4:0 acid, and differ from other legionellae in that they contain small amounts of an a-17:l acid. <i>L. bozemanii</i> also has a-15:0 as its major acid, but i-16:0 is its next most abundant acid; a-17:0 is its third major acid; it contains small amounts of i-14:0 acid, and lacks the a-17:1 acid [7,10].</s><s>The major acid in <i>L. pneumophila</i> is the i-16:0 [11].</s></p></content></protolog>