<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4678_nm.4899" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4899" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4899" rank="species">Bacillus edaphicus</organism><reference id="rid.4678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shelobolina</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Avakyan</surname><given-names>Z.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bulygina</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Turova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osipov</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karavaiko</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of a new species of mucilaginous bacteria, Bacillus edaphicus sp. nov., and confirmation of the taxonomic status of Bacillus mucilaginosus Avakyan et al. 1986 based on data from phenotypic and genotypic analysis.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>813</fpage><lpage>822</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus edaphicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus edaphicus</i> (L. adj. <i>edaphicus</i>, living in soil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On synthetic media with carbohydrates and devoid of nitrogen sources, the colonies are mucous, transparent, convex, 0.8-2.0 cm in diameter, with an even edge and smooth surface.</s><s>On potato agar and synthetic media with carbohydrates and ammonium nitrogen, the colonies are light, flat, raised in the center, round, smooth, moist, even-edged, up to 0.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>No growth occurs on nutrient agar or nutrient broth.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile regular rods, 1.0-1.5 x 4-10 μm in size.</s><s>Cells grown on media with carbohydrates in the absence of nitrogen sources are surrounded by mucous capsules 7-12 μm thick.</s><s>On media containing ammonium nitrogen, ellipsoidal endospores (1-1.2 x 1.7-2.0 μm) are formed with eight to ten ridge-like protrusions.</s><s>The cell wall structure is of the gram-positive type.</s><s>Palmitic, anteisopentadecanoic, and stearic acids are most frequent in the cellular lipids.</s><s>The temperature interval suitable for growth is 7-45°C.</s><s>Cells are resistant to lysozyme, chemoorganotrophic, catalase-positive, and incapable of glucose fermentation or nitrate reduction.</s><s>Starch and tyrosine are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Sugars and polyols are utilized as the sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 54.6-56.5 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is T7.</s></p></content></protolog>