<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7157_nm.6166" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6166" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6166" rank="species">Beutenbergia cavernae</organism><reference id="rid.7157"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schuetze</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Augsten</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kramer</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Beutenbergia cavernae gen. nov., sp. nov., an L-lysine-containing actinomycete isolated from a cave.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1733</fpage><lpage>1740</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1733</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555355</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Beutenbergia cavernae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Beutenbergia cavernae</i> (ca.ver'nae. L. masc. n. caws cave; M.L. gen. fem. n. <i>cavernae</i> of a cave, referring to the habitat of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular rods and cocci occurring singly, in pairs, short chains or clusters and exhibit a rod-coccus growth cycle.</s><s>Cell sizes in rods vary from 1.0 to 3.1 μm in length.</s><s>The diameters of the cocci are 0.7-1.0 μm.</s><s>Gram-positive, not acid-fast, non-motile, no formation of spores.</s><s>Aerobic to microaerophilic.</s><s>Oxidasenegative, catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies are 0.7-1.8 mm in diameter, cream to bright yellow coloured, circular, convex.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, inulin, maltose, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sucrose, starch, trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid production from D-glucitol, lactose or D-mannitol.</s><s>Acetate, aconitate, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, succinate and DL-tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, H,S is produced, indole is not produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, gelatin and potato starch are decomposed; adenine, hippurate, hypoxanthine, xanthine, Tween 80 and tyrosine are not decomposed.</s><s>Urease activity is negative.</s><s>NaCl in combination with R medium is well tolerated up to a concentration of 4% (w/v).</s><s>Good growth occurs at 28°C, weak growth at 37°C, no growth at 42°C.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to ampicillin (10 μgμg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (1 5 μg), neomycin (30 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), penicillin G (2 IU) and rifampin (2 μg).</s><s>Susceptibility to polymyxin B (300 IU) is weakly expressed, no susceptibility to ciprofloxacin (5 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), nitrofuran (300 μg), oxacillin ( 5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and sulfonamide.</s><s>Tested by the API ZYM enzyme assay strain HKI 0122<sup>T</sup> is positive for phosphatase alkaline, esterase (C 4), esterase lipase (C 8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, phosphatase acid, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosamidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase, and negative for lipase (C 14), valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase and β-glucosidase.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the A4α type with an L-Lys←L-Glu interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The acyl type is acetyl.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern is of the iso and anteiso branched type.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol and three unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 71 mol %.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The habitat is soil.</s><s>The type strain is HKI 0122<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 12333<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>