<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8641_nm.13337" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13337" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13337" rank="species">Hahella antarctica</organism><reference id="rid.8641"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hahella antarctica sp. nov., isolated from Antarctic seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65389-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218930</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hahella antarctica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hahella antarctica</em> (an.tarc′ti.ca. N.L. fem. adj. <em>antarctica</em> of the Antarctic, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, non-motile, aerobic, psychrotolerant and chemoheterotrophic.</s><s>Cells are straight or irregular rods, 0.9–5.9 μm long and 0.4–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies grown on MA at 25 °C for 5 days are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, circular, pulvinate with entire margins, dry, hard and cream-coloured.</s><s>Growth occurs at 3–25 °C (optimum, 25 °C), pH 5–10 (optimum, pH 7) and with 0.5–5.0 % NaCl (optimum, 2.0 %).</s><s>Other phenotypic and physiological characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Oxidizes the following carbon substrates (Biolog GN2 microplates): melibiose, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, propionic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-serine and inosine.</s><s>Does not oxidize the following carbon substrates: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline and l-threonine.</s><s>Susceptible to gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 μg), rifampicin (50 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg), but resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Cellular fatty acid profile is given in Table 2.</s><s>Major respiratory quinone is Q-9.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 56.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC3113<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42675<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 102683<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface seawater sample from Maxwell Bay, King George Island, western Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>