<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1899_nm.11013" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11013" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11013" rank="species">Salinicoccus jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.1899"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aslam</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yasir</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus jeotgali sp. nov., isolated from jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>633</fpage><lpage>638</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64586-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329798</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-positive, coccus-shaped, non-motile and 1.0–2.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies on R2A supplemented with 5 % NaCl for 2–4 days are smooth, circular, orange-coloured with transparent edges and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.5–11.0 (optimum, pH 7.0), at temperatures of 20–30 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and in R2A media supplemented with 0.5–15.0 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum, 5.0 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Tests for catalase and oxidase activity are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Urease, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, cellulase, xylanase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, amylase, lipase, chitinase, caseinase, DNase and gelatinase are not produced.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Tryptophan deaminase activity is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-maltose, d-trehalose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine and glycerol, but not from d-mannitol, sucrose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, erythritol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, inulin, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: salicin, l-arabinose, d-glucose, citrate, histidine, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-maltose, d-lactate, l-alanine and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: mannitol, d-melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionate, caprate, valerate, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, l-proline, d-ribose, inositol, d-sucrose, itaconate, suberate, malonate, acetate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and l-serine.</s><s>The type strain is resistant to 100 μg ampicillin ml<sup>−1</sup>, 100 μg tetracycline ml<sup>−1</sup>, 100 μg rifampicin ml<sup>−1</sup> and 100 μg kanamycin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (22.8 %) and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (32.4 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 47.0 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The predominant lipoquinone is MK-6 and MK-7 is present in trace amounts.</s><s>The assumed cell-wall murein type is l-Lys–Gly<sub>5</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain S2R53-5<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13030<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23640<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood.</s></p></content></protolog>