<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2637_nm.11849" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11849" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11336" rank="species">Bacillus thioparus</organism><reference id="rid.2637"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pérez-Ibarra</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flores</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García-Varela</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Bacillus thioparus sp. nov., chemolithoautotrophic, thiosulfate-oxidizing bacterium.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>271</volume><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.2007.00729.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17451444</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>B. thioparus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>B. thioparus</i> (thi.ópar.us.Gk. n. <i>thios</i> sulfur; L. v. <i>paro</i> produce; M.L. adj. <i>thioparus</i> sulfur-producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In 48 h TSB culture, cells are Gram-variable, aerobic, motile rods occurring in pairs or short chains, measuring 0.5–0.7 by 1.0–1.7 μm.</s><s>In Sublette’s medium (SLM) thiosulfate can be used as an energy source, thus enabling chemolithtrophic growth.</s><s>Gram-stain of this culture at pH 5.8 showed endospore formation at the central position.</s><s>The medium becomes turbid and sulfur precipitates during incubation.</s><s>Colonies are bright yellow in color, small, circular with smooth margins on SMGG.</s><s>Growth occurs at 5% (w/v) NaCl but not at 10–15% (w/v).</s><s>Optimal growth temperature was 30–35°C with a pH 7.0 in TSB.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>In the API 20E and API 20NE strips, nitrate was reduced and weakly positive to gelatin, hydrolysis of aesculine, assimilation of glucose, <i>n</i>-acetyl-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, malate and citrate were positive but reactions for ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, hydrogen sulfide, urease activity, tryptophane deaminase, production of indole, acetoin, para-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranosidase, fermentation of glucose, mannitol, sucrose, amygdalin and arabinose, assimilation of mannose, capric acid, and phenyl-acetate were negative.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C15 : 0 (77.30%) and C16 : 1 (9.08%).</s><s>DNA G+C content is 43.8 mol% (Tm method).</s><s>Cell wall contains peptidoglycan of <i>m</i>-diaminopimelic acid type.</s><s>Type strain BMP-1<sup>T</sup> (BM-B-436<sup>T</sup> =CECT 7196<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The sequence of the 16S rRNA gene was deposited in GenBank with the number DQ371431 and isolated from a continuous culture system for wastewater treatment operating with a bacterial consortium.</s></p></content></protolog>