<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8627_nm.13611" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13611" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13611" rank="species">Sphingobacterium kitahiroshimense</organism><reference id="rid.8627"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Matsuyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Katoh</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohkushi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Satoh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawahara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yumoto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium kitahiroshimense sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1576</fpage><lpage>1579</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65791-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599698</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobacterium kitahiroshimense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobacterium kitahiroshimense</em> (kita.hi.ro.shim.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>kitahiroshimense</em> pertaining to Kitahiroshima city, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive, non-spore-forming, rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Cells are 0.6–0.8 μm long, 0.5–0.6 μm in diameter and are non-motile.</s><s>Circular, entire, low convex, smooth colonies develop on nutrient agar after 2 days.</s><s>A yellow or creamy white, non-fluorescent pigment is produced on nutrient agar.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C, no growth occurs at temperatures of 42 °C or above.</s><s>Gives a positive result in tests for the hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Urease, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-mannnosidase activities are detected.</s><s>Positive result in the GN2 Biolog test for the following substrates: dextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, cellobiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-threonine, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>Acid is produced from trehalose, raffinose, l-arabinose and l-xylose.</s><s>Gives a negative result in tests for indole production, hydrolysis of gelatin and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase activity is not detected.</s><s>The activities of DNase, esterase (C4), lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>Cannot utilize citrate, l-arabinose, l-histidine, adonitol, erythritol, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, inosine or glycerol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from rhamnose.</s><s>Contains branched-17 : 0 dihydrosphingosine as the main sphingosine.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (summed feature 3), 40.28 %; iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, 28.89 % and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, 12.83 %.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.9 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 10C<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14970<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 14398<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from Kitahiroshima city, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>