<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4566_nm.5757" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5757" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5757" rank="species">Olsenella profusa</organism><reference id="rid.4566"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tzellas</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coleman</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spratt</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of novel human oral isolates and cloned 16S rDNA sequences that fall in the family Coriobacteriaceae: description of olsenella gen. nov., reclassification of Lactobacillus uli as Olsenella uli comb. nov. and description of Olsenella profusa sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1797</fpage><lpage>1804</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594611</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Olsenella profusa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Olsenella profusa</i> (pro.fus'a. L. adj. <i>profusus</i> profuse, referring to the good growth of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Previously designated Eubacterium group D52 by W.E.C. and L.V.H.</s><s>Moore.</s><s>The description is based on two strains isolated from the oral cavity.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-positive, short rods, 0.6x0.8-2.0 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in chains.</s><s>After 7 d of incubation on FAA plates, colonies are approximately 1-1.3 mm in diameter, circular, entire, pulvinate to pyramidal, cream coloured and opaque when viewed under a plate microscope.</s><s>Growth in broth media is good and is stimulated only slightly by addition of Tween 80.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose are fermented.</s><s>Melezitose and rhamnose are not fermented.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but arginine and starch are not.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied and meat is not digested.</s><s>Catalase, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetate and lactate are produced as end products of metabolism.</s><s>The Rapid ID32A profile is 4516053705.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 64 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is D315A-29<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13989<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA sequence is AF292374.</s><s>Isolated from human subgingival plaque in adults with periodontitis.</s></p></content></protolog>