<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.2739" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2739" rank="genus">Rhizobacter</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Rhizobacter</em> Goto and Kuwata 1988</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Straight to slightly curved, non-spore-forming, uncapsulated, Gram-negative rods.</s><s>Motile with polar flagella or lateral flagella or both.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are formed.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Aerobic with respiratory metabolism of glucose.</s><s>Utilize d-glucose as a sole source of carbon and energy.</s><s>White or yellowish white, depending on the growth medium used (see species descriptions).</s><s>Oxidase-positive, catalase-variable.</s><s>Do not require NaCl.</s><s>The major quinone type is Q-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>; C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH fatty acid is absent while C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH is present.</s><s>Major polyamines are 2-hydroxyputrescine and putrescine; cadaverine and spermine are present as minor compounds and spermidine may be present in small amounts.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine; one unidentified aminolipid and one or two unidentified aminophospholipids are present.</s><s>On the basis of 16S rRNA gene sequence comparison, the genus is a member of the order <em>Burkholderiales</em>, having <em>Aquabacterium</em>, <em>Methylibium</em> and <em>Piscinibacter</em> as its closest neighbours.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66–71 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <em>Rhizobacter dauci</em> Goto and Kuwata 1988.</s></p></content></protolog>