<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1220_nm.5687" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5687" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5687" rank="species">Streptococcus sobrinus</organism><reference id="rid.1220"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coykendall</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus sobrinus nom. rev. and Streptococcus ferus nom. rev.: habitat of these and other mutans streptococci.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>883</fpage><lpage>885</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>streptococcus sobrinus</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>streptococcus sobrinus</i> (basionym, <i>S. mutans</i> subsp. <i>sobrinus</i> Coykendall [5]; so.bri’nus., L. masc. n. <i>sobrinus</i> male cousin on mother’s side, referring to the distant relationship between this species and <i>S. mutans</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci 0.5 μm in diameter that occur in pairs and chains, which are often long.</s><s>Mannitol and sorbitol are fermented; raffinose and melibiose are not.</s><s>An adhesive glucan is produced from sucrose.</s><s>Growth is enhanced in an atmosphere containing a reduced oxygen content.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Colonies on agar containing sucrose are about 1 mm in diameter, rough, and heaped and often have droplets of liquid (containing glucan) at the top or the border.</s><s>Hydrogen peroxide is produced.</s><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) base content is 44 to 46 mol% guanine plus cytosine (G+C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SL1 (= ATCC 33478) is the type strain (5).</s><s>This strain was isolated from a human mouth and was first mentioned by Fitzgerald and Jordan (14), but was not described by them.</s><s>Strain SLIT (T = type strain) produces acid from mannitol and sorbitol, but not from raffinose or melibiose; it does not split arginine (5).</s><s>Perch et al. (25) reported that strain SLI<sup>T</sup> is alpha-hemolytic on horse blood agar, produces H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, and does not	grow at	45°C.</s><s>Its base content is 45.1 mol% G+C as determined by thermal denaturation (3) and 44.9 mol% G+C as determined by density in CsCl (11).</s></p></content></protolog>