<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11906_nm.19992" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19992" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19992" rank="species">Tateyamaria pelophila</organism><reference id="rid.11906"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sass</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Köpke</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rütters</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Feuerlein</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dröge</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cypionka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engelen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tateyamaria pelophila sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic alphaproteobacterium isolated from tidal-flat sediment and emended description of Tateyamaria omphalii</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1770</fpage><lpage>1777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013524-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tateyamaria pelophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tateyamaria pelophila</em> (pe.lo′phi.la. Gr. n. <em>pelos</em> mud; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> -<em>ê</em> -<em>on</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>pelophila</em> mud-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, 0.7–1.4 μm wide and 1.5–3.0 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on MB agar plates are beige to pinkish.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–35 °C, with fastest growth at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth is observed between pH 6 and 9 and at salinities from 0.3 to 10.2 %.</s><s>Requires Na<sup>+</sup>.</s><s>Substrates used aerobically are: peptone, Casamino acids, yeast extract, starch, chitin, xylan, laminarin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, l-rhamnose, acetate, propionate, valerate, capronate, caprylate, glycolate, dl-lactate, pyruvate, succinate, dl-malate, citrate, glycerol, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glutamine, l-glutamate, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-ornithine and l-valine.</s><s>No growth is observed with chitin, cellulose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, formate, butyrate, crotonate, malonate, dl-tartrate, 2-ketoglutarate, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, methanol, ethanol, <em>n</em>-propanol, <em>n</em>-butanol, betaine, methylamine, ethanolamine, DMSO, dimethylsulfide, benzoate, salicylate or nicotinate.</s><s>Grows anaerobically for a few transfers with glucose as substrate or on MB.</s><s>Under anoxic conditions, TMAO serves as an electron acceptor, whereas DMSO, nitrate, nitrite, sulfite, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, ferric citrate, iron hydroxide, manganese oxides, AQDS and humic acids are not reduced.</s><s>Sulfite, thiosulfate and elemental hydrogen are oxidized lithoheterotrophically, but not elemental sulfur or carbon monoxide.</s><s>Weak manganese-oxidizing activity.</s><s>Cells exhibit oxidase and catalase activity and contain bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em>.</s><s>Sulfide is not produced from l-cysteine, l-methionine or thiosulfate.</s><s>Agar, agarose, alginate, casein, gelatin, starch, Tweens 20 and 80, tyrosine and xylan are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for arginine deaminase, tryptophan deaminase, leucine arylaminidase, valine arylaminidase and phosphatase activities.</s><s>Weak <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase activity is present.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, lipase, urease, cysteine arylaminidase and ornithine deaminase.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Phenylacetate is utilized.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-ribose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, lactose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or glycerol.</s><s>Requires biotin, pantothenate and thiamine for growth, but not <em>p</em>-aminobenzoate, folate, lipoate, nicotinate, pyridoxine, cyanocobalamin or riboflavin.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline, but are resistant to kanamycin and trimethoprim.</s><s>The major phospholipids are PE and PG.</s><s>PC and an unidentified lipid were detected only in trace amounts.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is <em>n</em>-C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present at lower concentrations: <em>n</em>-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>14 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, i-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, <em>n</em>-C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and 11-methyl-C<sub>18 : 1</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SAM4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17270<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23018<sup>T</sup>), isolated from tidal-flat sediment on the German North Sea coast.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 56.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>