<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12746_nm.22527" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22527" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22527" rank="species">Nonomuraea rhizophila</organism><reference id="rid.12746"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonomuraea rhizophila sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2141</fpage><lpage>2145</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028050-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20889768</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nonomuraea rhizophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nonomuraea rhizophila</em> (rhi.zo.phi′la. Gr. n. <em>rhiza</em> a root; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> on loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>rhizophila</em> root-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-reaction-positive, aerobic, non-motile actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelia.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are observed on any of the tested media.</s><s>Spiral spore chains composed of ~7–10 non-motile spores (0.9–1.2 µm in diameter) with a rough surface are borne directly on the aerial mycelium.</s><s>Grows at 10–37 °C (optimum 20–28 °C) and pH 6–8 (optimum pH 7).</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range for growth is up to 7 % (w/v).</s><s>Positive for catalase, milk coagulation, milk peptonization and urea hydrolysis.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, gelatin liquefaction, hydrogen sulfide production, cellulose and starch hydrolysis and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed but Tweens 40 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes cellobiose, d-fructose, glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, raffinose and l-rhamnose as sole carbon sources; l-arabinose, d-galactose, glycerol, ribose, sodium acetate, d-sorbitol, sucrose and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Does not produce acids from any carbon sources tested.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-hydroxyproline, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-valine and xanthine can be used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of the peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Cell hydrolysates contain madurose, glucose, mannose, ribose and galactose.</s><s>Polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol (DPG), phosphatidylmethylethanolamine (PME), phosphatidylethanolamine (PE), phosphatidylglycerol (PG), phosphatidylinositol (PI), an unknown glucosamine-containing phospholipid (GluNu) and some unknown phospholipids (PLs).</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>); MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 10-methyl, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> G, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 67092<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AA 209044<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 45382<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of the perennial vine <em>Tripterygium wilfordii</em> Hook. f., collected from Yunnan Province, South-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>