<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12578_nm.21832" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21832" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21832" rank="species">Ignatzschineria indica</organism><reference id="rid.12578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dharne</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rangrez</surname><given-names>A.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ghate</surname><given-names>H.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rohde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patole</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shouche</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ignatzschineria indica sp. nov. and Ignatzschineria ureiclastica sp. nov., isolated from adult flesh flies (Diptera: Sarcophagidae)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1360</fpage><lpage>1369</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018622-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20584814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ignatzschineria indica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ignatzschineria</em> <em>indica</em> (in′di.ca. L. fem. adj. <em>indica</em> Indian, named after source of isolation of the strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, non-motile, aerobic, regular short rods (0.8–1.8×0.3–0.8 µm) and non-haemolytic.</s><s>Colonies grown on MH agar at 37 °C for 48 h are small (0.5–2 mm in diameter), non-pigmented, entire, convex, translucent, occur singly and are able to grow on nutrient agar, MacConkey agar, Salmonella Shigella agar, brain heart infusion agar and King’s medium A base agar.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase reactions are positive.</s><s>The temperature, NaCl and pH ranges for growth are 4–45 °C, 0–6 % NaCl (w/v) and pH 6–9, respectively, with optima of 37 °C, 2 % NaCl (w/v) and 7.5, respectively.</s><s>Positive for phosphatase activity and the phenylalanine deaminase reaction.</s><s>Negative results in tests for urease, H<sub>2</sub>S production, nitrate reductase, aesculin, caseinase, gelatinase, amylase, pectinase, xylanase, CMCase and chitinase activity.</s><s>Indole production, Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests are negative.</s><s>Based on Biolog tests, gives a positive result for oxidation of l-histidine, l-leucine, formic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, l-phenylalanine, dl-lactic acid, l-asparagine, α-hydroxybutyric acid, l-glutamic acid, succinic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, acetic acid, bromosuccinic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, succinamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, citric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, uridine, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-proline, l-aspartic acid, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, pyruvic acid methyl ester, glycyl l-aspartic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester and γ-hydroxybutyric acid, but negative for α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, l-alanylglycine, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and α-d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>No acid production from API ID 32 GN or API 50 CHE test strips or parts A, B and C of the HiCarbohydrate kit.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 8 (C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>), CyC<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The respiratory quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Polar lipids are PG, PE, PL1, PL2 and PN.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg): amikacin (30), azithromicin (15), cefaclor (30), ceftriaxone (30), cephotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (30), clindamycin (2), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), netillin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), norfloxacin (10), ofloxacin (5), piperacillin/tazobactum (100/10), sparfloxacin (5), streptomycin (25), tetracycline (50) and tobramycin (10), but resistant to ampicillin (10), amoxicillin/clavulanate (30), aztreonam (30), cephalothin (5), colistin (50), mecillinam (25), metronidazole (5), penicillin (10 units), teicoplanin (30), ticarcillin (75) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Shows intermediate resistance to carbenicillin (30), ceftazidime (100), cephalexin (30), cephoxitin (30), colistin methane sulphate (25), co-trimoxazole (25), doxycycline hydrochloride (30), gatifloxacin (30), sulphamethoxazole (25), sulphatriad (200) and trimethoprin (1.25).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FFA1<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 22309<sup>T</sup> = KCTC 22643<sup>T</sup> = NCIM 5325<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the gut contents of the adult flesh fly (Diptera: Sarcophagidae).</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 41.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>