<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7512_nm.4251" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4251" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4251" rank="species">Eubacterium fossor</organism><reference id="rid.7512"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium fossor sp. nov., an agar-corroding organism from normal pharynx and oral and respiratory tract lesions of horses.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>383</fpage><lpage>387</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-3-383</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium fossor</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium fossor</i> (fos'sor. L.n. <i>fossor</i> a digger, delver)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Eubacterium fossor</i> is an obligately anaerobic gram-positive bacterium whose cells vary from coccobacillary to rod shaped with parallel sides and rounded ends and measure 0.5 to 0.9 by 0.3 μm.</s><s>Polar pili are present, and it is nonmotile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On SBA colonies after 24 h are minute, enlarging to 1 mm after 48 h, at which time they appear to be set in small pits (0.3 mm) deep in the agar.</s><s>After 4 days the colonies have umbonate to raised centers (1 mm) with either a roughened depressed region or a series of concentric rings radiating outward for an additional 1 to 2 mm from the center of the colony.</s><s>The pit formed by the colony is 3 mm wide and 0.3 mm deep.</s><s>Hemolysis does not occur.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in broth is improved by the addition of Tween 80 (0.75%, vol/vol) or serum (5%, vol/vol).</s><s>The organisms form dense growth with uniform turbidity and a fine granular deposit when they are grown in prereduced peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth or cooked meat-glucose broth.</s><s>Acetic and lactic acids (lactic acid &#x003E; acetic acid) are the major fermentation products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gas is not detected in PYT-glucose deep agar cultures; hydrogen sulfide and ammonia are produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannose, and glucose is fermented weakly by the type strain and 10 of the remaining 12 strains.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, esculin, fructose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>Indole, catalase, acetylmethylcarbinol, lecithinase, lipase, and urease are not produced.</s><s>Esculin, starch, Tween 20, Tween 40, and Tween 80 are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no reaction in milk and no digestion of gelatin.</s><s>Bile neither stimulates nor inhibits growth.</s><s>Cells do not survive heating for 10 min at 80°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains tested are susceptible to penicillin (2 U/ml), ampicillin (4 μg/ml), carbenicillin (100 μg/ml), doxycycline (6 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), and erythromycin (3 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 44 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>E. fossor</i> is strain NCTC 11919, which was isolated from the pharynx of a normal horse. <i>E. fossor</i> was present in the pharynxes of all seven normal horses examined.</s><s>In the three cases of parapharyngeal or tooth root abscesses cultured, the species was present in large numbers and represented 7% of the total isolates.</s><s>In the case of pleuropneumonia, <i>E. fossor</i> and <i>Streptococcus zooepidemicus</i> were the most frequent organisms isolated from both pulmonary abscesses and pleural fluids. <i>E. fossor</i> has not been found as a sole isolate in specimens, and it remains to be determined whether <i>E. fossor</i> is pathogenic alone or in combination with other bacteria.</s><s>It appears to be present as part of the normal oropharyngeal flora of horses and may contribute to purulent disease after gaining entry along with other bacteria to an unusual site.</s></p></content></protolog>