<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6691_nm.10572" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10572" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6084" rank="species">Agromyces fucosus</organism><reference id="rid.6691"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ortiz-Martinez</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gonzalez</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jurado</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laiz</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saiz-Jimenez</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Agromyces fucosus subsp. hippuratus as Agromyces hippuratus sp. nov., comb. nov. and emended description of Agromyces fucosus</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1553</fpage><lpage>1556</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02856-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Agromyces fucosus</em></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description is based on phenotypical data of Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em> (1992), Malysheva (1994), Groth <em>et al.</em> (1996), Suzuki <em>et al.</em> (1996), Altenburger <em>et al.</em> (1997) and Dorofeeva <em>et al.</em> (2003).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on nutrient media are opaque, entire and convex, and occasionally penetrate into the agar media.</s><s>Produces a yellow carotenoid pigment.</s><s>Branching hyphae (width, 0·2–0·6 mm) break into diphtheroid and rod-like, irregular, non-motile fragments.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Mesophilic; optimum growth is at 26–30 °C.</s><s>Strains are able to grow at 7 °C; no or weak growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>d-Arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, methyl d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are used for growth as sole carbon sources in a salt medium supplemented with 0·1 % (w/v) yeast extract (Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em>, 1992).</s><s>Dulcitol, erythritol, lyxose, d-mannitol, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-arabinopyranoside and l-sorbose are not used as sole carbon sources in the same medium.</s><s>Some strains, including the type strain, use melibiose for growth, whereas adonitol and <em>meso</em>-inositol are not used by most of the strains, including the type strain.</s><s>Acids are usually produced from l-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, inulin, lactose, maltose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and d-xylose by most strains (reactions of the type strain are positive or variable).</s><s>Acetate, malate and pyruvate are utilized.</s><s>Alkaline reactions with fumarate and propionate are variable (type strain is positive).</s><s>Some strains utilize citrate and succinate (type strain is negative).</s><s>Ascorbate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, gluconate, oxalate, salicylate and tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Production of H<sub>2</sub>S is variable; the type strain shows a positive reaction.</s><s>Arbutin, aesculin and starch are hydrolysed; adenine, elastin, guanine, pectin, testosterone, urea and xanthine are not decomposed or hydrolysed.</s><s>Hippurate, hypoxanthine, Tween 40 and tyrosine are decomposed by some strains, including the type strain.</s><s>Casein is usually not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate reduction test is negative or weak reaction is observed.</s><s>No growth occurs on media supplemented with 5 % NaCl, 0·01 % sodium azide or 0·0175 % potassium tellurite.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-12; the second most common component is MK-13.</s><s>Polyamine content is low; putrescine and 1,3-diaminopropane are the predominant compounds (data for the type strain only).</s><s>Cell wall sugars are galactose, rhamnose, fucose and minor mannose (type strain); glucose may occur but fucose is lacking in other strains.</s><s>Cell wall contains 1,3-poly(glycerol phosphate) teichoic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 70–72 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-1345<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 8597<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of this strain is AY158025.</s></p></content></protolog>