<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1335_nm.2080" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2080" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2080" rank="species">Chromatium tepidum</organism><reference id="rid.1335"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madigan</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromatium tepidum sp. nov., a thermophilic photosynthetic bacterium of the family Chromatiaceae.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>222</fpage><lpage>227</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-222</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chromatium tepidum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chromatium tepidum</i> (tepí.dum. L. neut adj. <i>tepidum</i> lukewarm)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and 1 to 2 μm wide by 2.8 to 3.2 μm long.</s><s>Gram negative, occasionally motile.</s><s>Photosynthetic intracytoplasmic membrane system of the vesicular type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pigments.</s><s>Absorption spectra of intact cells show peaks at 858, 808, and 599 nm, which are typical of bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i>.</s><s>The esterifying alcohol of bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> is phytol.</s><s>Carotenoids of the normal spirilloxanthin series are present; rhodovibrin and spirilloxanthin predominate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Obligately phototrophic.</s><s>Growth occurs photoautotrophically in mineral media supplemented with sulfide as electron donor.</s><s>Sulfur is formed as an intermediate product, which is further oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>Hydrogen and thiosulfate are not utilized as electron donors.</s><s>Acetate and pyruvate are photoassimilated in the presence of sulfide; citric acid cycle intermediates, fatty acids other than acetate, and sugars are not utilized.</s><s>Ammonia, urea, and glutamine serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>No growth factors are required.</s><s>Optimum pH, 7.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 48 to 50°C; no growth below 34°C or above 57°C.</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth and is growth inhibitory at concentrations above 1% (wt/vol).</s><s>Catalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Storage material.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is a storage material.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The DNA contains 61.5 mol% guanine plus cytosine, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>The habitat of <i>C. tepidum</i>: sulfide-containing hot springs of neutral to alkaline pH at temperatures below 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain MC, which was isolated from Stygian Springs, located in the Upper Terraces of Mammoth Hot Springs, Yellowstone National Park.</s><s>This strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 43061<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>