<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3399_nm.6760" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6760" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6760" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora gregorii</organism><reference id="rid.3399"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lacey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Athalye</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Embley</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowen</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora gregorii and Saccharopolyspora hordei: Two new actinomycete species from fodder.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>2125</fpage><lpage>2139</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharopolyspora gregorii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora gregorii</i> (gre.gor'i.i. ML gen.n. <i>gregorii</i> of Gregory; named after P. H. Gregory, a British mycologist and aerobiologist.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies pale yellowish to buff with sparse white aerial mycelium at growth temperatures of about 20 °C.</s><s>Substrate mycelium well developed but fragmenting extensively into coccoid elements.</s><s>Sporulation or fragmentation of the aerial mycelium may sometimes be seen, forming hooks or flexuous chains.</s><s>Transmission electron micrographs show mainly vegetative rods and cocci but occasionally spores with a smooth sheath.</s><s>Degrades aesculin, arbutin, casein, elastin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, Tweens 20 and 80, tyrosine and xanthine ; utilizes adonitol, L-arabinose, fructose, galactose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, mannose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, D- and L-alanine, L-proline, sodium propionate and sodium pyruvate as sole carbon sources but not glycogen, lactose, starch, trehalose or L-serine.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and neither allantoin nor urea is hydrolysed.</s><s>The organism is tolerant to a range of antibiotics and chemical inhibitors (see Table 2).</s><s>Temperature range for growth: 10 to 35 °C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The wall peptidoglycan contains alanine, glutamic acid and glycine with <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid.</s><s>The principal wall sugars are arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The organism is rich in <i>iso</i>- and <i>anteiso</i>- fatty acids, with 14-methylpentadecanoic and 14-methylhexadecanoic acids predominating.</s><s>It also contains tetrahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units as the major isoprenologue and major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and uncharacterized phospho- and glycolipids.</s><s>The mol % G + C content of the DNA of the type strain is 74 (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from grass, hay, straw, barley grain and soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain : <i>Saccharopolyspora gregorii</i> NCIB 12823 (A85).</s></p></content></protolog>