<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6442_nm.8112" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8112" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8112" rank="species">Flavobacterium salegens</organism><reference id="rid.6442"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dobson</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McMeekin</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Direct sequencing of the polymerase chain reaction-amplified 16S rRNA gene of Flavobacterium gondwanense sp. nov. and Flavobacterium salegens sp. nov., two new species from a hypersaline Antarctic lake.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>83</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-1-77</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7678983</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium salegens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium salegens</i> (sal'e. gens. L. n. <i>sal</i>, salt; L. adj. <i>egens</i>, needy; L. adj. <i>salegens</i>, needing salt)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and occur singly, in pairs, and sometimes in chains.</s><s>Cell widths range from 0.5 to 0.8 μm, and cell lengths range from 1.2 to 11.5 μm.</s><s>Cells are gram negative and nonmotile.</s><s>Members of the species are aerobic.</s><s>Colonies on solid media are yellow, circular, entire, and convex.</s><s>Members of this species are moderately halophilic and grow optimally in media containing 5% total salts.</s><s>Growth on Tween 20- containing agar inhibits pigment production.</s><s>All members of this species produce catalase, cytochrome oxidase, phosphatase, DNase, and β-galactosidase, reduce nitrate to nitrite, grow in the presence of 15% NaCl, hydrolyze Tween 20, starch, and esculin, and liquefy gelatin.</s><s>No strain produces ornithine decarboxylase or lysine decarboxylase, utilizes malonate, hydrolyzes chitin, agar, or casein, or produces spreading growth on low-peptone agar.</s><s>No bathochromic shift is observed when 20% KOH is added to colonies.</s><s>The growth of all members of the species is stimulated by arginine, D-gluconic acid, pyruvate, maltose, ornithine, and lactose.</s><s>The growth of all strains is not stimulated by adonitol, L-rhamnose, salicin, glycine, hydroxy- L-proline, D-mannose, D-xylose, serine, D-trehalose, L-asparganine, L-lysine, histidine, L-arabinose, cysteine, threonine, tyrosine, glycerol, inositol, isoleucine, maltose, leucine, and valine.</s><s>All strains produce acid from L-arabinose, maltose, and mannitol and are susceptible to novobiocin (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ampicillin (10 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), and cephalothin (30 μg).</s><s>All strains are resistant to vibriostatic agent OD29 (10 μg) and neomycin (30 μg).</s><s>The G+C contents of this species, determined for three strains, range from 39 to 41 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ACAM 48<sup>T</sup>, which has a G+C content of 41 mol%.</s><s>Distinctive features of the fatty acid profile of strain ACAM 4gT are the presence of 16:1w7c, 3-OH anteiso-15:0, and 3-OH anteiso-17:O.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is menaquinone 6.</s><s>The species is represented by five strains (strains ACAM 2, ACAM 48<sup>T</sup>, ACAM 52, ACAM 53, and ACAM 54).</s><s>Characteristics which vary among strains belonging to this species are shown in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>