<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4056_nm.6275" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6275" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6275" rank="species">Corynebacterium tritici</organism><reference id="rid.4056"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carlson</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of Corynebacterium plant pathogens, including a new pathogen of wheat, based on polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of cellular proteins.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>315</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium tritici</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, pleomorphic rods, with a temperature maximum of 34°C. Colonies are circular (diameter, 2 to 4 mm), convex, and yellow pigmented on NBY medium. Produces acid from xylose, glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, sucrose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, glycerol, and mannitol but not from rhamnose, ribose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, melezitose, adonitol, sorbitol, dulcitol, inositol, salicin, α-methyl glucoside, β-methyl glucoside, or esculin. Utilizes acetate, citrate, fumarate, and succinate but not formate, lactate, or propionate. Does not hydrolyze starch and has a maximum NaCl tolerance of 3 to 4%. Distinguished from other <i>Corynebacterium</i> spp. by the presence of diaminobutyric acid in its peptidolyglycan, its characteristic menaquinones (MK10 and MK8), and its distinct pattern of protein bands in polyacrylamide gels. Isolated from wheat (<i>T. aestivum</i> L.) showing a gumming disease of the leaves, stems, and seedheads. The type strain is ATCC 11403 (=NCPPB 1857), the reference strain of Dye and Kemp (14). The preceding description is based on six strains (including the type strain) characterized by Dye and Kemp (14). As the tests for these six strains were uniform, the species description also serves as a description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>