<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8733_nm.13024" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13024" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7253" rank="species">Streptomyces castelarensis</organism><reference id="rid.8733"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Five new members of the Streptomyces violaceusniger 16S rRNA gene clade: Streptomyces castelarensis sp. nov., comb. nov., Streptomyces himastatinicus sp. nov., Streptomyces mordarskii sp. nov., Streptomyces rapamycinicus sp. nov. and Streptomyces ruanii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1369</fpage><lpage>1378</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65408-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523180</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces castelarensis</em> (Cercós 1954) Kumar and Goodfellow sp. nov., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces castelarensis</em> (cas.tel.ar.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>castelarensis</em> from Castelar, Argentina, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Streptomyces rutgersensis</em> subsp. <em>castelarensis</em> Cercós 1954.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data taken from this and previous studies (Cercós, 1954; Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991).</s><s>Rugose ornamented spores (0.8×1.6 μm) are borne on spiral spore chains with two to six turns on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Grows well on modified Bennett's, glycerol-asparagine, oatmeal and yeast extract-malt extract agars.</s><s>On oatmeal agar the aerial spore mass colour is grey, becoming black and moist when mature, and the substrate mycelium greyish-yellow; diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on either peptone-yeast extract-iron or tyrosine agars. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-glycerol, glycogen, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, trehalose, d-xylitol and d-xylose are used as sole carbon sources, but not sucrose, l-sorbose or d-tagalose.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Produces the antibiotic camphomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 15191<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 40830<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from dust in Castelar, Argentina.</s></p></content></protolog>