<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5149_nm.6339" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6339" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6339" rank="species">Mycobacterium cookii</organism><reference id="rid.5149"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kazda</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minnikin</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daffe</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Parlett</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitulle</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium cookii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>217</fpage><lpage>223</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1697763</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium cookii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium cookii</i> (cook'i.i. L. gen. n. <i>cookii</i>, of Cook, named for Bertram Cook, who discovered the natural reservoirs of this Mycobacterium species in sphagnum vegetation and pond water in New Zealand)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>M. cookii</i> below is based on a study of 17 strains which shared the characteristics shown in Table 2.</s><s>Cells are acid-alcoholfast, polymorphic rods (0.8 by 1.4 to 1.9 μm) which often form clumps but not cords or cross bands.</s><s>Spores, capsules, true branching, and aerial hyphae do not occur.</s><s>Colonies on Lowenstein-Jensen medium and Middlebrook 7H10 agar are smooth, glistening with yellow-orange pigmentation, and 0.5 to 1 mm in diameter; the optimum growth temperature is 31°C.</s><s>These organisms do not grow at 37, 42, or 45°C.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The strains are mycobacteria with limited enzymatic activity.</s><s>They possess catalase, acid phosphatase, and arylsulfatase activities.</s><s>For all strains nitrate reductase activity, amidase activities, and acid production from glucose and mannose are negative.</s><s>These organisms do not tolerate 0.1% NaNO<sub>2</sub> and 0.2% picric acid and do not grow on media containing single carbon sources or single sources of nitrogen plus carbon.</s><s>Most of the strains are susceptible to antituberculosis drugs (Table 2). <i>M. cookii</i> possesses a unique mycolate pattern (Table 6).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content is 63.7 ± 3.0 mol%.</s><s>The phylogenetic position based on an evaluation of the partial 16s rRNA sequences is within the genus Mycobacterium between the slowly growing pathogenic species and the saprophytic rapidly growing species (Fig. 1 and 2).</s><s>The strains which we tested are not pathogenic for guinea pigs, rabbits, or mice.</s><s>They provoke nonspecific skin hypersensitivity reactions to bovine tuberculin.</s><s>The type strain of <i>M. cookii</i> is strain NZ2.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49103 and in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM 43922.</s><s>Strains of <i>M. cookii</i> have been isolated only from intact sphagnum vegetation and the pond water associated with this vegetation in New Zealand.</s></p></content></protolog>