<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6832_nm.4980" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4980" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4980" rank="species">Bacillus simplex</organism><reference id="rid.6832"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Study of mural painting isolates, leading to the transfer of 'Bacillus maroccanus' and 'Bacillus carotarum' to Bacillus simplex, emended description of Bacillus simplex, re-examination of the strains previously attributed to 'Bacillus macroides' and description of Bacillus muralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63221-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Bacillus simplex</em> (<em>ex</em> Meyer and Gottheil 1901) Priest <em>et al.</em> 1989</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus simplex</em> (sim′plex. L. masc. adj. <em>simplex</em> simple).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods are straight, 0·7–0·9 μm in diameter, round-ended or occasionally slightly tapered and occur in chains and sometimes singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile when occurring singly but non-motile when growing in chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, occasionally spherical, lie centrally, paracentrally or subterminally, and do not obviously swell the sporangia.</s><s>Gram reaction is variable amongst cells.</s><s>Colonies, grown for 2 days on nutrient agar at 30 °C, are 3–6 mm in diameter, cream-coloured, glossy, with irregular margins, slightly raised and umbonate.</s><s>Most strains are strictly aerobic, although some strains may grow weakly on nutrient agar under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>They grow at 20 and 30 °C but are not able to grow at 45 °C.</s><s>Strains grow at pH 9 as profusely as at pH 7 and growth at pH 5 is variable.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is variable and a brown tint, of varying strength, diffuses into the medium.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed.</s><s>Tolerance to 5 % NaCl (w/v) is variable and no growth occurs in media supplemented with 7 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Oxidase reaction is negative and catalase is positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, the ONPG, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase reactions are negative, citrate is not utilized, hydrogen sulphide and indole are not produced, urease production and the Voges–Proskauer reaction are negative and gelatin hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>In the API 50 CHB gallery, hydrolysis of aesculin is variable and weak.</s><s>For all strains tested, acid is produced, mostly weakly, without gas from the following carbohydrates: fructose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glucose, inulin, trehalose and sucrose.</s><s>Strains produce acid weakly and variably from salicin.</s><s>Acid production is always negative from adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, glycogen, lactose, d-lyxose, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, rhamnose, starch, sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, l-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>On the basis of reaction patterns for other substrates, two biovars may be recognized: strains belonging to biovar 1 produce acid weakly and variably from l-arabinose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose and sorbitol, while acid production is always negative from cellobiose, glycerol, inositol, maltose and d-xylose; strains of biovar 2 produce acid, weakly, without gas from the following carbohydrates: l-arabinose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol and d-xylose; biovar 2 strains are variable for weak acid production from cellobiose, glycerol, inositol and maltose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, present (means±sd) at 59·03±5·88 and 15·55±2·95 % of total fatty acids, respectively.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present (mean values) at ≥1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (5·94±2·82 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1·56±0·59 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (2·97±0·74 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2·26±1·42 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> (4·80±1·30 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (2·36±1·58 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I and/or anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B (1·12±0·82 %), and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1·82±0·80 %).</s><s>The G+C content is in the range of 39·5–41·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NRS 960<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 49097<sup>T</sup>=DSM 1321<sup>T</sup>=LMG 11160<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>For the variable characters in the API kits, the results for the type strain are as follows: weak or moderate acid production for l-arabinose, mannitol, ribose and sorbitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from raffinose.</s><s>In the Biotype 100 kit, the type strain hydrolyses aesculin very weakly and is able to grow on the following substrates as sole carbon sources: <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, d- and l-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, l-aspartate, benzoate, caprylate, citrate, <em>m</em>-coumarate, ethanolamine, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, fumarate, gentisate, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-glucuronate, l-glutamate, glutarate, dl-glycerate, glycerol, l-histidine, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, 2-keto-d-gluconate, dl-lactate, l-malate, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, mucate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, l-proline, propionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, quinate, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-saccharate, l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinate, l-tartrate, d-trehalose, tricarballylate, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and d-xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>