<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3776_nm.1464" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1464" rank="genus">Afipia</organism><reference id="rid.3776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>English</surname><given-names>C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vincent</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Radosevic</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birkness</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bibb</surname><given-names>W.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quinn</surname><given-names>F.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Afipia gen. nov., with Afipia felis sp. nov. (formerly the cat scratch disease bacillus), Afipia clevelandensis sp. nov. (formerly the Cleveland Clinic Foundation strain), Afipia broomeae sp. nov., and three unnamed genospecies.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>2450</fpage><lpage>2460</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1774249</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Afipia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Afipia</i> (A.fip'i.a. N. L. fem. n. <i>Afipia</i>, derived from the abbreviation AFIP, for Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, where the type strain of the type species was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus are gram-negative, oxidase-positive rods in the α-2 subgroup of the class <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>They are motile by means of a single polar, subpolar, or lateral flagellum.</s><s>They grow on BCYE agar and nutrient broth, but not nutrient broth containing 6% NaCl, and rarely on MacConkey agar at 25 and 30°C; strains grow at least weakly at 35°C, but growth does not occur at 42°.</s><s>Organisms are gray-white, glistening, convex, and opaque colonies and are 1.5 mm wide with entire edges; they are formed after 72 h of incubation at 32°C on blood agar (9) or on BCYE agar, except that the size range is from 0.5 to 1.5 mm.</s><s>They are urease positive and turn litmus milk alkaline. <i>Afipia</i> species are negative in reactions for hemolysis, gas production from nitrate, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production (triple sugar iron method), gelatin hydrolysis, and esculin hydrolysis and are non-fermentative.</s><s>Acid is not produced oxidatively from D-glucose, lactose, maltose, or sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Afipia</i> species contain 11-methyloctadec-12-enoic (C<sub>Br19:1</sub>), <i>cis</i>-octadec-11-enoic (C<sub>18:1</sub>omega7c), and generally, 17- and 19-carbon acids with a cyclopropane ring as major acids, with only trace amounts of hydroxy acids.</s><s>The G+C content is 61.5 to 69 mol%.</s><s>The interrelatedness of species by DNA hybridization is 12 to 69%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Organisms in the genus <i>Afipia</i> contain the etiologic agent of CSD, and other species are presumptively considered to be pathogenic for humans.</s><s>The type species is <i>A. felis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>