<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6422_nm.1136" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1136" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1136" rank="species">Roseobacter algicola</organism><reference id="rid.6422"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lafay</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Traubenberg</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Breittmayer</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gauthier</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseobacter algicola sp. nov., a new marine bacterium isolated from the phycosphere of the toxin-producing dinoflagellate Prorocentrum lima.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>290</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-290</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537061</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Roseobacter algicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Roseobacter algicola</i> (al.gi' co.la L. n. <i>alga</i>, alga; L. subst. <i>cola</i>, dweller; M. L. n. <i>algicola</i>, alga dweller)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of the type strain of <i>Roseobacter algicola</i> (strain FF3) are ovoid (length, 2 to 3 μm; width, 0.8 to 1.6 μm) in the logarithmic growth phase.</s><s>The cells are gram negative, do not form spores, and are motile by means of one or two subpolar flagella.</s><s>Colonies on salt-containing agar media are beige when the cultures are young and pinkish beige after 96 h of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grow at temperatures ranging from 10 to 37°C, and optimal growth occurs at 25 to 30°C.</s><s>The cells have an absolute requirement for sodium ions and can grow in the presence of NaCl concentrations ranging from 0.1 to 2 M.</s><s>The cells are strictly aerobic with a nonfermentative type of metabolism; they do not grow anaerobically on glucose in the presence or absence of nitrate.</s><s>The cells are not able to denitrify.</s><s>They exhibit oxidase, catalase, gelatinase, esculinase, β-galactosidase, and (to a lesser extent) amylase activities.</s><s>They do not accumulate polyhydroxybutyrate.</s><s>They use D-glucose, trehalose, saccharose, D-fructose, maltose, melezitose, acetate, pyruvate, malate, citrate, esculin, 2-ketoglutarate, 5-ketogluconate, L-proline, L-arginine, L-glutamate, and shikimate, but not DL-arabinose, ribose, DL-xylose, galactose, D-mannose, rhamnose, cellobiose, lactose, D-melibiose, rafhose, gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-fucose, glycerol, erythritol, dulcitol, adonitol, inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, xylitol, methanol, amygdalin, inulin, salicin, N-acetylglucosamine, D-gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 2- ketoglutarate, butyrate, DL-β-hydroxybu tyrate, L-histidine, Llysine, and L-tryptophan.</s><s>They do not produce bacteriochlorophyll a.</s><s>FF3<sup>T</sup> cells are resistant to oleandomycin, gentamicin, streptomycin, and neomycin, slightly susceptible to kanamycin and tetracycline, and susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, novobiocin, and penicillin G.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of its small-subunit rRNA sequence, this bacterium belongs to the alpha subdivision of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and is part of a distinct monophyletic group containing <i>Roseobacter denitrificans</i> and <i>Roseobacter litoralis</i>.</s><s>Strain FF3<sup>T</sup> was isolated from a culture of the toxin-producing dinoflagellate <i>Prorocentrum lima</i> PLV2 obtained from Vigo, Spain; this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 51440<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>