<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.62_nm.1098" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1098" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1098" rank="species">Paracoccus aminophilus</organism><reference id="rid.62"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Araki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oyanagi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paracoccus aminophilus sp. nov. and Paracoccus aminovorans sp. nov., which utilize N,N-dimethylformamide.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>291</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-287</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2397196</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paracoccus aminophilus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paracoccus aminophilus</i> (a.mi.no'phi.lus N.L.n. <i>aminum</i> amine; Gr.adj.<i>phila</i>, loving; N.L.adj. <i>aminophilus</i>, amine loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccoid cells (0.5 to 0.9 μm in diameter) or short rods (0.9 to 2.0 μm long).</s><s>Occur singly, in pairs or in clusters.</s><s>Colonies on PYG medium at 30°C for 2 days are white to light yellow.</s><s>Gram-negative, nonmotile.</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid accumulate in the cells.</s><s>Growth in nutrient broth and PYG broth is abundant, but growth in peptone water is weak.</s><s>A water-soluble fluorescent pigment is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The methyl red test and Voges-Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Ammonia is produced.</s><s>Nitrate respiration (anaerobic growth in the presence of potassium nitrate) is not performed.</s><s>Litmus milk is not changed.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively but not fermentatively from L-arabinose, D-glucose, D-galactose, and D-mannitol but not from D-xylose, D-mannose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, D-sorbitol, inositol, glycerol, and soluble starch.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-galactose, glycerol, succinic acid, acetic acid, monomethylamine, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, trimethylamine-N-oxide, formamide, N-methylformamide, and N,N-dimethylformamide are utilized.</s><s>But D-mannose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, inositol, soluble starch, citric acid, formic acid, methanol, ethanol, butanol, methane, and hydrogen are not utilized.</s><s>Thiamine is required as an essential supplement.</s><s>Ammonia and peptone are utilized as a nitrogen source, but urea and nitrate are not utilized.</s><s>Growth is observed between pH 6.0 and pH 9.0.</s><s>No growth at pH 5.0 or pH 10.0.</s><s>Optimum growth pH is 6.5 to 8.0.</s><s>Growth is observed at 30°C but not at 37°C.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 3% sodium chloride is weak.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase are produced.</s><s>Urease is not produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory and not fermentative.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63 mol% G+C.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is straight-chain unsaturated C<sub>18:1</sub> acid.</s><s>The major hydroxy fatty acids are 3-hydroxy C<sub>10:0</sub> and 3-hydroxy C<sub>14:0</sub> acids.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone Q-10, with Q-9 and Q-11 as minor components.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DM-15 isolated from soil by Urakami et al. (in press), deposited at the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (JCM), Institute of Physical and Chemical Research, as JCM 7686.</s></p></content></protolog>