<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8246_nm.13446" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13446" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13446" rank="species">Microlunatus panaciterrae</organism><reference id="rid.8246"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microlunatus panaciterrae sp. nov., a beta-glucosidase-producing bacterium isolated from soil in a ginseng field.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2734</fpage><lpage>2738</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65004-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060049</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microlunatus panaciterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microlunatus panaciterrae</em> (pa.na.ci.ter′rae. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name for ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panaciterrae</em> of soil of a ginseng field).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-motile, coccus-shaped and 0.3–0.7 μm in diameter after 24 h culture on R2A agar plates.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 5 days are smooth, circular, non-glossy, yellowish, convex and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows well at 20–30 °C and at pH 5.0–9.0, but does not grow at temperatures below 15 °C or above 37 °C.</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar, but not on MacConkey agar or trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Growth on R2A agar occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 5.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not with 6.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase reactions are positive.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced under aerobic conditions, but nitrite is not reduced.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur; nitrate is not reduced under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>In API 20E tests, negative results are obtained for urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase; positive results are obtained for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, gelatinase and in the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-glucose, melibiose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: d-arabinose, citrate, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-glucose, lactate, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol and sucrose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, d-adonitol, alanine, starch, amygdalin, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, caprate, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, galactose, glycogen, glycerol, gluconate, histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, inulin, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, malate, malonate, d-mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, phenylacetate, proline, propionate, raffinose, serine, sodium acetate, l-sorbose, suberate, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, valerate, xylitol and l-xylose.</s><s>Xylan, chitin, cellulose, casein, olive oil and DNA are not degraded, but starch is degraded.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) is the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The polar lipids detected are phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 954<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13058<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18662<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.1 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>