<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11784_nm.19891" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19891" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19891" rank="species">Shewanella xiamenensis</organism><reference id="rid.11784"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella xiamenensis sp. nov., isolated from coastal sea sediment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1585</fpage><lpage>1589</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013300-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684319</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella xiamenensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella xiamenensis</em> (xia.me.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xiamenensis</em> from Xiamen, China, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.7–0.8×2.5–4.0 μm, motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic chemoheterotroph.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar 2216 are smooth, circular, slightly brown in colour and convex with clear edges.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 37 °C, but not above 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0, with optimum growth around pH 7.0.</s><s>Sodium ions are not required for growth; growth occurs in the presence of 0–4 % NaCl and optimal growth occurs in 1–2 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells are positive for oxidase, catalase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, acid and alkaline phosphatase, leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphoamidase activities.</s><s>Cells are able to reduce nitrate, nitrite, TMAO, selenite, fumarate, ferric citrate and ferric oxide with lactate as electron donor.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin, DNA and Tween 80 is positive; negative for starch hydrolysis.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is formed anaerobically from thiosulfate.</s><s>Fermentation is observed on d-glucose.</s><s>Utilizes a limited range of carbon sources according to Biolog: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, Tweens 40 and 80, l-arabinose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, inosine, uridine and thymidine.</s><s>Glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, monomethyl succinate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-leucine and l-threonine are utilized weakly.</s><s>Both menaquinones and ubiquinones are present, with Q-7 and Q-8 as the predominant ubiquinones and MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone.</s><s>The main fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, S4<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC M 209017<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16212<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal sediment collected off Xiamen, China.</s></p></content></protolog>