<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2838_nm.4278" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4278" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4278" rank="species">Eubacterium uniforme</organism><reference id="rid.2838"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Gylswyk</surname><given-names>N.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van der Toorn</surname><given-names>J.J.T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium uniforme sp. nov. and Eubacterium xylanophilum sp. nov., fiber-digesting bacteria from the rumina of sheep fed corn stover.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>323</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-323</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> (u.ni.for'me. L. neut. adj. <i>uniforme</i> uniform, denoting unusual uniformity among strains)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic and nonmotile.</s><s>The majority of cells from 16-h cultures on xylan agar stain gram positive.</s><s>Most cells are short rods (coccoid forms are present) and have rounded or somewhat blunt ends (Fig. 1).</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, and sometimes in short chains.</s><s>The cells are usually about 0.4 μm wide, but some are wider (up to 0.6 μm), and the length varies from 0.6 to 1.5 μm.</s><s>No differences in cell size occur on xylan or cellobiose agar medium.</s><s>No spores are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation for 3 days on films of xylan (3%) agar medium in roll bottles, surface colonies appear mucoid and round with smooth to wavy or irregular edges.</s><s>Colony diameters vary from 2 to 8 mm.</s><s>The colonies are white and show a strong bluish-green irridescence when they are viewed obliquely in transmitted light.</s><s>Clearings surrounding the colonies and resulting from xylan solubilization in the opaque medium vary from 15 to 25 mm in diameter.</s><s>The degradation of xylan within the clearings is complete in the vicinity of the colonies.</s><s>Submerged colonies are lens shaped.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of seven strains tested (strains X3C39<sup>T</sup> [T = type strain], X3C56, X10C60, X3D34, X4D63, X5E38, and X2E39) requires rumen fluid or carbon dioxide-bicarbonate for growth.</s><s>All strains grow well in medium which lacks added reducing agent (sulfide and cysteine) but which is nevertheless reduced with respect to resazurin.</s><s>Injection of 5 ml of sterile air into 30-ml bottles containing either 4 or 10 ml of medium results in at least partial oxidation of the medium, as indicated by the color of the resazurin indicator, and causes complete inhibition of growth.</s><s>Although six of the seven strains grow at 45°C (strain X2E39 does not grow at this temperature), the pH of the cultures is lowered less at 45°C than at 38°C.</s><s>No strain grows at 22°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions of <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> are listed in Table 2.</s><s>In addition, the type strain and the six other isolates tested liquefy gelatin.</s><s>None produces indole, amethylindole, hydrogen sulfide, or catalase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Despite the fact that all strains produce acid from starch (weakly in the case of one strain), in all cases at least some starch remains unhydrolyzed, as indicated by reaction with iodine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major products of xylan fermentation are formic, acetic, and L-lactic acids and ethanol; some propionate is utilized (Table 3).</s><s>The type strain and the six other strains all produce gas and acetylmethylcarbinol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35.2 ± 2.04 mol% for type strain X3C39 and 34.9 ± 2.00 mol% for strain X10C60.</s><s>The type strain is strain X3C39 (= ATCC 35992), which was isolated from the rumen of a sheep.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The end products of fermentation of <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> (formic, acetic, and lactic acids and ethanol) are similar to those of several other eubacteria. <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> differs from <i>Eubacterium formicigenerans</i> (6) in the G+C content of the DNA (which is 40 to 44 mol% for the latter species), the ability to ferment cellobiose, fructose (some strains of <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> ferment fructose weakly), salicin, starch, and xylose, the production of acetylmethylcarbinol, and cell dimensions.</s><s>It differs from <i>Eubacterium eligens</i> (6), which has a similar G+C content (36 mol%), in the ability to ferment L-arabinose, fructose (see above), and galactose, the production of acetylmethylcarbinol, motility, and cell dimensions. <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i> differs from <i>Eubacterium aerofaciens</i> (4) in cell morphology and in that the latter species ferments fructose (see above) and mannose and does not ferment arabinose and starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bryant et al. (1, 2) described bacteria (groups +R-2 and +SR-gGXC) which they placed in the genus <i>Eubacterium</i>.</s><s>No specific epithet was assigned.</s><s>The characteristics that were determined conformed in many respects with those of <i>Eubacterium uniforme</i>, except that ethanol production was not detected and the strains of Bryant et al. did not ferment a xylan which was easily degraded by other species of rumen bacteria.</s></p></content></protolog>