<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12614_nm.22141" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22141" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22141" rank="species">Hymenobacter yonginensis</organism><reference id="rid.12614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Joung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hymenobacter yonginensis sp. nov., isolated from a mesotrophic artificial lake</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1511</fpage><lpage>1514</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024588-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656807</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hymenobacter yonginensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hymenobacter yonginensis</em> (yon.gi.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>yonginensis</em> of or belonging to Yongin, Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, non-motile, aerobic rods.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are convex, circular and smooth with entire margins, reddish pink and approximately 5 mm in diameter after 2 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs on R2A, blood agar and TSA.</s><s>No growth occurs on MA, DNA test agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0.5 %), at pH 7–8 (optimum, pH 7) and at 10–30 °C (optimum, 25 °C).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>Casein and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production and acetylmethylcarbinol production are not observed.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following Biolog GN3 microplate compounds are utilized: dextrin, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylneuraminic acid, d-mannose, d- and l-fucose, l-rhamnose, d- and l-serine, d-mannitol, d-arabitol, d-glucose 6-phosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, d-aspartic acid, gelatin, glycyl l-proline, l-alanine, pectin, d-galacturonic acid, l-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, glucuronamide, methyl pyruvate, l-lactic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, l-malic acid, bromosuccinic acid, Tween 40, aminobutyric acid, β-hydroxy-dl-butyric acid, propionic acid, acetic acid and formic acid.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, gentiobiose, turanose, stachyose, raffinose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-salicin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, α-d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, 3-methyl glucose, inosine, d-sorbitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-glucuronic acid, mucic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, citric acid, d-malic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid and acetoacetic acid.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω5<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and summed feature 4 (anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> B and/or iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> I).</s><s>The complete fatty acid profile of the type strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HMD1010<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22745<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7546<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a mesotrophic freshwater pond in Yongin, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>