<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1604_nm.11322" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11322" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11322" rank="species">Clostridium nitrophenolicum</organism><reference id="rid.1604"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suresh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rastogi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium nitrophenolicum sp. nov., a novel anaerobic p-nitrophenol-degrading bacterium, isolated from a subsurface soil sample.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1886</fpage><lpage>1890</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64604-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684276</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium nitrophenolicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium nitrophenolicum</em> (ni.tro.phen.o′li.cum. N.L. n. <em>nitrophenol</em>; L. suff. <em>-icus -a -um</em> suffix used with the sense of belonging to; N.L. neut. adj. <em>nitrophenolicum</em> referring to the substrate nitrophenol that can be utilized by the species).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped measuring 3.5–5.0 μm in length and 0.6–0.9 μm in width and strictly anaerobic.</s><s>They form spores that are oval and central in position.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA are circular, smooth and convex with wavy margin.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 6.5 and 8.0 and no growth is observed below pH 6.5 and above 8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 45 °C and does not grow at 15 or 50 °C.</s><s>Optimum growth is observed at pH 7.2 and temperature 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between 0 and 1 % NaCl and does not grow with 2.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Strain 1D<sup>T</sup> is negative for catalase and oxidase, and positive for indole and methyl red test.</s><s>Starch and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite and is negative for Voges–Proskauer test, citrate utilization and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Using Biolog MicroPlates (AN), the strain showed a positive reaction for the assimilation of d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, palatinose and l-rhamnose and a negative reaction for acetic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine adonitol, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl l-glutamine, l-alanyl l-histidine, l-alanyl l-threonine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, l-asparagine, d-cellobiose, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, dulcitol, <em>i</em>-erythritol, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, glycerol, glyoxylic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, inosine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>β</em>-ketobutyric acid, lactic acid, lactulose, malic acid, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, mannose, d-melibiose, l-methionine, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, 3-methyl-d-glucose, l-phenylalanine, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-saccharic acid, salicin, l-serine, d-sorbitol, stachylose, succinic acid, sucrose, <em>m</em>-tartaric acid, l-threonine, thymidine, trehalose, turanose, uridine, urocanic acid and l-valine.</s><s>It produced acid from glucose, dulicitol, fructose, galactose, maltose, mannose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, salicin or sorbitol.</s><s>Fermentation end products from glucose include acetate, formate and pyruvate.</s><s>Menaquinone present is MK-7 and the cell wall amino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Polar lipids present are DPG, PG, PE and two unknown phospholipids (UKP1 and UKP2).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are (%); C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (28.02), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>I/anteiso B (23.05), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (10.82) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (10.02).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 35.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 1D<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 7832<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14030<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a subsurface soil sample from a depth of about 3–4 m.</s></p></content></protolog>