<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6313_nm.9380" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9380" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9380" rank="species">Flavobacterium psychrolimnae</organism><reference id="rid.6313"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandecandelaere</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium fryxellicola sp. nov. and Flavobacterium psychrolimnae sp. nov., novel psychrophilic bacteria isolated from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>769</fpage><lpage>772</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03056-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774660</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium psychrolimnae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium psychrolimnae</em> (psy.chro′lim.nae. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; Gr. fem. n. <em>limna</em> lake; N.L. gen. n. <em>psychrolimnae</em> of the cold lake).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0·5×2·0 μm).</s><s>Gliding motility is not observed.</s><s>Grows at 5–25 °C, with optimal growth at 20 °C; weak growth is observed at 30 °C and no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Yellow, convex, translucent colonies with entire margins and a diameter of 1–3 mm are formed on R2A plates after 6 days incubation.</s><s>Colonies on agar of Anacker &#x0026; Ordal (1955) are flat, round with entire margins and 0·5–1·0 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on trypticase soy agar and nutrient agar; no growth is detected on marine agar.</s><s>Colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in 0–2 % NaCl, but not in 5–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and starch are degraded.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Growth is observed (API 20NE) on glucose, mannose and maltose, whereas no growth is detected on arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, carboxymethyl–cellulose, DNA, gelatin, tyrosine and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed and no flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>Brown diffusible pigment is not produced on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction, Voges–Proskauer reaction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains has arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E) and lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM) activities.</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, medium activity is observed for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, and strong activity is observed for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Cells contain the fatty acids C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso and summed feature 3 (C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) as the main constituents.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 33·8–34·5 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from the freshwater lakes Fryxell (fresh/brackish) and Hoare in the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 22018<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108326<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>