<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4402_nm.915" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.915" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.915" rank="species">Gluconacetobacter entanii</organism><reference id="rid.4402"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schüller</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hertel</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hammes</surname><given-names>W.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gluconacetobacter entanii sp. nov., isolated from submerged high-acid industrial vinegar fermentations.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2013</fpage><lpage>2020</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155975</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gluconacetobacter entanii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gluconacetobacter entanii</i> (en.ta'.ni.i. L. gen. <i>entanii</i> of Entani, in honour of Etsuzo Entani, a Japanese microbiologist who performed the crucial experiments on isolation and propagation of spirit vinegar bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, ellipsoidal to rod-shaped, straight or slightly curved, 0.8-1.2 μm by 1.3-1.6 μm, non-motile, occurring singly, in chains and mainly in pairs.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, never fermentative.</s><s>Colonies are round, regular, umbonate, soft, glossy and with a diameter of 1-2 mm on AE agar; catalase-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth only in the presence of acetic acid, ethanol and glucose; the total concentration (sum of acetic acid and ethanol) has to exceed 6.0%.Oxidizes ethanol to acetic acid and does not over-oxidize acetic acid.</s><s>Growth on 3% (v/v) ethanol in the presence of up to 11%acetic acid (v/v).</s><s>Gluconate, glycerol and lactate are not assimilated.</s><s>No formation of ketogluconic acids from glucose.</s><s>Good growth on glucose, fructose and sucrose in AE broth (4a/3e).</s><s>Cellulose formation was not detected on solid media or in bouillon.</s><s>The type strain is <i>Gluconacetobacter entanii</i> LTH 4560<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13536<sup>T</sup>), which has a DNA G+C content of 58 mol% and has been isolated from a submerged spirit vinegar fermentation in a factory in the Southern part of Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>