<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4661_nm.5669" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5669" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5669" rank="species">Streptococcus parauberis</organism><reference id="rid.4661"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Molecular taxonomic studies on Streptococcus uberis types I and II. Description of Streptococcus parauberis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>68</volume><fpage>485</fpage><lpage>490</lpage><source id="176">The Journal of Applied Bacteriology</source><abbrev>J Appl Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0021-8847</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1695217</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus parauberis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus parauberis</i> (para.u'ber.is.Gr. pref. <i>para</i> alongside of or near; L. gen. n. <i>uberis</i> of an udder; M. L. f. n. <i>parauberis</i> alongside of uberis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the studies of Garvie &#x0026; Bramley (1979) and Collins et al. (1984).</s><s>Cells are coccoid, occurring in pairs to chains of moderate length.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>On blood agar there may be a weak α-haemolysis or none.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature ca 35 to 37°C.</s><s>May or may not survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Grows in 4% NaCl but not 6.5% NaCl or at pH 9.6.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, β-gentiobiose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from amidon, dulcitol, inulin, melezitose, rafinose and D-tagatose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fuose, glycerol, glycogen, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, inositol, lyxose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-xyloside, rhamnose, sorbose, turanose, xylitol, D-xylose and L-xylose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Hippurate hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Tyrosine is not decarboxylated.</s><s>Voges Proskauer positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine dehydrolase, leucine arylamidase and pyrrolidonylarylamidase produced.</s><s>Some strains produce α-galactosidase.</s><s>β-Glucuronidase is not produced. heterogeneous.</s><s>The G plus C content of DNA isSerologically 34.8 to 36.5%.</s><s>The V2 region of 16s rRNA of <i>Strep. uberis</i> contains the sequence UAAGUACACAUGUACUNAAUUUAAAAGGAGCAAU (positions 187 to 220), which serves to distinguish it from <i>Strep. uberis</i>.</s><s>Found on lips and skin of cows, in raw milk and on udder tissue.</s><s>Causes mastitis.</s><s>The type strain is NCDO 2020.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>In most respects the characteristics of the type strain corresponds to that of the species.</s><s>Acid is produced from amidon, inulin, D-raffinose, and D-tagatose.</s><s>α-Galactosidase is produced and hippurate is hydrolysed.</s></p></content></protolog>