<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9935_nm.14908" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14908" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14908" rank="species">Ponticaulis koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.9935"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ponticaulis koreensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Hyphomonadaceae isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2951</fpage><lpage>2955</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011114-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19628598</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ponticaulis koreensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ponticaulis koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>koreensis</em> pertaining to Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those described in the genus.</s><s>Cells are 3.1–6.6 μm long and 0.4–0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Colonies are colourless, circular, smooth, convex and 0.3–0.5 mm in diameter after 5 days of incubation.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–42 °C (optimum 30–37 °C), at pH 6.1–10.1 (optimum pH 7.1) and with up to 6 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA but not casein or starch.</s><s>Degrades dl-tyrosine but not elastin, chitin, cellulose, hypoxanthine or xanthine.</s><s>Positive for gelatin hydrolysis but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, aesculin degradation and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API 20NE).</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) (weak), esterase lipase (C8) (weak), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>In GN2 MicroPlates, metabolizes Tweens 40 and 80, raffinose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline and l-pyroglutamic acid as sole carbon and energy sources, but not <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d- or l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GSW-23<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22146<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19734<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14975<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater taken from Kymnyeong Beach on the island of Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>