<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1468_nm.1898" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1898" rank="genus">Methylophilus</organism><reference id="rid.1468"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jenkins</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Byrom</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylophilus: a new genus of methanol-utilizing bacteria.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>446</fpage><lpage>448</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-446</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylophilus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylophilus</i> (Me.thyl.o.phil'us. M. L. n. <i>methyl</i>, the methyl radical; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M. L. masc. n. <i>Methylophilus</i>, methyl radical loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The salient characters of the genus, based on the literature descriptions (2, 10-15; Jenkins, Ph.D. thesis; D.</s><s>G.</s><s>MacLennan, J.</s><s>C.</s><s>Ousby, T.</s><s>R.</s><s>Owen, and D.</s><s>C.</s><s>Steer, British patent 1370892, October, 1974) and on our own observations, are as follows.</s><s>When grown on methanol-mineral salts agar or in methanolmineral salts liquid medium, straight or slightly curved rods usually 0.3 to 0.6 μm in diameter and 0.8 to 1.5 μm in length occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Gram negative, but the stain is often not taken up well.</s><s>Motile by polar flagella or nonmotile.</s><s>Endospores are absent.</s><s>No cellular inclusions.</s><s>No sheath or prosthecae detected.</s><s>No capsules formed, but slime may be produced by some strains.</s><s>Colonies on methanol-mineral salts agar plates incubated for 2 days at 30 or 37°C are circular, 1 to 2 mm in diameter, with entire edge, convex, translucent to opaque.</s><s>Pyocyanin and fluorescein are not produced.</s><s>No, or extremely poor, growth on nutrient agar and in nutrient broth incubated at 30 or 37°C for 2 days.</s><s>No, or extremely poor, growth on blood agar; no hemolysis.</s><s>Optimum temperature, 30 to 37°C; no growth occurs at 4 or 45°C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth, 6.5 to 7.2 Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism respiratory; very little or no acid is produced from glucose.</s><s>Methanol is utilized as the sole carbon and energy source by all strains.</s><s>In addition, a limited range of other carbon compounds such as methylamines, formate, glucose, and fructose may be utilized as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Nutritionally nonexacting; nitrate and ammonium salts serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Catalase positive and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty acid composition is primarily of the nonhydroxylated straight-chain saturated and monounsaturated types with C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>16:0</sub> predominating (2, 10, 14, 16).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone components are ubiquinones with eight isoprene units (Q-8) (11, 12, 14, 16; Jenkins, Ph.D. thesis).</s><s>DNA base composition is 50 to 53 mol% guanine plus cytosine as determined by estimation of the melting point (11, 12; Jenkins, Ph.D. thesis).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bacteria of this kind have been isolated from activated sludge, mud, and river and pond water (MacLennan et al., British patent 1370892).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Methylophilus methylotrophus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>