<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8456_nm.13354" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13354" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13354" rank="species">Halomonas lutea</organism><reference id="rid.8456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas lutea sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a salt lake.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2065</fpage><lpage>2069</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65436-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768605</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas lutea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas lutea</em> (lu′te.a. L. fem. adj. <em>lutea</em> orange-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, short rods and are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>The type strain is unable to grow on modified ISP 5 medium supplemented with salts containing only K<sup>+</sup>, Mg<sup>2+</sup> and Ca<sup>2+</sup> cations.</s><s>Growth ranges for temperature, pH and NaCl are 4–45 °C, pH 5–9 and 1–20 % (w/v) NaCl, with optimal growth at 37 °C, pH 7.5 and 5–10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>DNase, aesculin, casein, starch and Tweens 40 and 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate production and in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>In the API 20E system, the following enzyme activities are recorded as negative: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, urease, gelatinase, indole production from tryptophan, H<sub>2</sub>S production from sodium thiosulfate and acetoin production from sodium pyruvate.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources (Biolog GN2 system): dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, dl-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, sucrose, trehalose, methyl pyruvate, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, dl-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine, inosine, uridine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized.</s><s>In the API 50 CH system, acid is produced from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, aesculin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, starch, trehalose, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not from erythritol, inositol, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, arbutin, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, salicin, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, potassium gluconate or l-arabitol.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase give positive results.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless indicated otherwise): amoxicillin (10), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), neomycin (30), netilmicin sulfate (30), norfloxacin (10), novobiocin (30), penicillin G (10), rifampicin (5), streptomycin sulfate (10), tetracycline (30), tobramycin (10), trimethoprim/sulfonamides (23.7/1.25) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Resistance is exhibited only to amikacin (30 μg) and lincomycin (2 μg).</s><s>Q-9 is the predominant ubiquinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 91125<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12847<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AB 206093<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>