<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5646_nm.5444" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5444" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5444" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus yamanashiensis yamanashiensis</organism><reference id="rid.5646"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nonomura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus yamanashiensis subsp. yamanashiensis and Lactobacillus yamanashiensis subsp. mali sp. and subsp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>406</fpage><lpage>407</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-406</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus yamanashiensis</i> subsp. <i>yamanashiensis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus yamanashiensis</i> subsp. <i>yamanashiensis</i> (ya.ma.na.shi.en'sis. N . L. adj. <i>yamanashiensis</i> belonging to Yamanashi Prefecture, Japan, the source of the wine must from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of <i>L. yamanashiensis</i> are gram positive, catalase negative, facultatively anaerobic rods 0.5 to 0.8 by 1.2 to 2.3 μm and occur singly, in pairs, and in short chains.</s><s>Nonmotile, or weakly motile with a few peritrichous flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, smooth, and glistening after a few days.</s><s>Liquid cultures are turbid after a few days, with subsequent clearing and sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Homofermentative, producing L(+)- and DL-lactic acids.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, mannose, sucrose, and salicin.</s><s>No acid is produced from ribose, arabinose , xylose , maltose, melibiose, lactose, raffinose or rhamnose.</s><s>Little or no acid is produced from galactose, melezitose, mannitol, or sorbitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth in 4% taurocholate or 5% NaCl.</s><s>No change in litmus milk.</s><s>Dextran is produced from sucrose.</s><s>Mannitol is not produced from fructose.</s><s>Ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>Nitrite is not produced from nitrate.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acetoin is produced.</s><s>Malic acid is decomposed to lactic acid and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Pseudocatalase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15°C but not at 45°C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is 5 to 7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Very good growth occurs in medium containing peptone, tryptose, yeast extract, liver extract, Tween 80, MnCl<sub>2</sub>, glucose, and fructose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glutamate, and glycine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content of deoxyribonucleic acid is 32.9 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method (1).</s><s>Source: wine must.</s><s>Type strain: 239 (=ATCC 27340).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species is differentiated from all other species in the genus <i>Lactobacillus</i> most decisively by its low guanine-plus-cytosine content, in addition to the presence of diaminopimelic acid in its cell wall peptidoglycan (1, 5).</s><s>It is distinguished also by the following key characteristics: homofermentation, growth at 15°C, inability to ferment ribose, and production of L(+)- and DL-lactic acids.</s></p></content></protolog>