<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4823_nm.5470" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5470" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5470" rank="species">Abiotrophia elegans</organism><reference id="rid.4823"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roggenkamp</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abele-Horn</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trebesius</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tretter</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Autenrieth</surname><given-names>I.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heesemann</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Abiotrophia elegans sp. nov., a possible pathogen in patients with culture-negative endocarditis.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>100</fpage><lpage>104</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9431929</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Abiotrophia elegans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Abiotrophia elegans</i> (e'le.gans. L. adj. <i>elegans</i>, fastidious, referring to the fastidious growth requirements)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Abiotrophia elegans</i> is a gram-positive microorganism.</s><s>The shape is dependent on the nutritional state.</s><s>In sufficiently supplemented nutritional broth the bacterium appears coccoid in short chains.</s><s>Lack of appropriate growth factors results in pleomorphism and the appearance of elongated, swollen forms.</s><s>The microorganism is nonmotile, nonsporulating, and catalase and oxidase negative and grows as a facultative anaerobe with complex growth requirements.</s><s>It grows as satellite colonies adjacent to <i>S. epidermidis</i> on trypticase- soy-sheep blood agar plates with α-hemolysis.</s><s>Tiny colonies up to 0.2 mm in diameter are formed on Schaedler-sheep blood agar plates after 48 h, but only minimal growth is visible on chocolate agar plates.</s><s>Growth occurs at 27 and 37°C but not at 20 or 42°C.</s><s>It grows in THB or casein-soy peptone bouillon supplemented with 0.01% L-cysteine hydrochloride.</s><s>It does not grow in THB or casein-soy peptone bouillon supplemented with 0.001% pyridoxal hydrochloride.</s><s>It produces a red chromophore visualized by boiling the microorganism at pH 2 for 5 min.</s><s>It produces pyrrolidonyl-arylamidase and leucine aminopeptidase but not alkaline phosphatase, α- or β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, or β-glucosidase.</s><s>It hydrolyzes hippurate.</s><s>It ferments raffinose but not trehalose, inulin, lactose, starch, or glycogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain B1333 has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 11693.</s></p></content></protolog>