<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5992_nm.4978" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4978" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4978" rank="species">Bacillus shackletonii</organism><reference id="rid.5992"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhelst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus shackletonii sp. nov., from volcanic soil on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>373</fpage><lpage>376</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02661-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023945</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus shackletonii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus shackletonii</em> (sha.ckle.ton′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>shackletonii</em> of Shackleton, referring to RRS <em>Shackleton</em>, the ship used by the first British scientific expedition to visit Candlemas Island, the vessel being named in honour of the celebrated Anglo-Irish Antarctic explorer Sir Ernest Shackleton).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from unheated volcanic soil taken from the east lava flow of Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago.</s><s>Cells are motile, round-ended rods (0·7–0·9×2·5–4·5 μm) occurring singly.</s><s>Gram-variable; Gram-positive reactions are only seen in cultures at 18 h or at temperatures below 30 °C.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, lie subterminally and occasionally paracentrally, and usually cause the sporangia to swell (Fig. 1).</s><s>After 2 days on trypticase soy agar, colonies are 2–5 mm in diameter, have a granular appearance and butyrous texture, have opaque, cream-coloured centres and have translucent, irregular margins.</s><s>The minimum temperature for growth lies between 15 and 20 °C, the optimum temperature for growth is 35–40 °C and the maximum growth temperature is 50–55 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 4·5 and 5·0, the optimum pH for growth is 7·0 and the maximum pH for growth lies between 8·5 and 9·0.</s><s>Organisms are strictly aerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>They do not grow readily on casein agar but, when they do grow on it, they may hydrolyse the casein.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip (bioMérieux) incubated at 30 °C, ONPG is hydrolysed slowly; reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, the Voges–Proskauer reaction, gelatin hydrolysis and nitrate reduction are negative (in the API 20E strip incubated at 40 °C, citrate may be utilized slowly, gelatin may be hydrolysed slowly and the Voges–Proskauer reaction may be positive).</s><s>In the API 50 CH gallery (bioMérieux), hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium (bioMérieux): amygdalin, cellobiose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and salicin; weak acid reactions were detected for arbutin, d-fructose, galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, ribose, d-tagatose and d-trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, d- and l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, <em>meso</em>-inositol, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, d-melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, d-raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-turanose, xylitol and d- and l-xylose.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to filter-paper disks containing the following antibiotics: ampicillin (25 μg), chloramphenicol (50 μg), colistin sulphate (100 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (50 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and tetracycline (100 μg).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 35, 31, 6 and 18 % of total fatty acids).</s><s>The following fatty acids were present in smaller amounts (between about 1 and 3 %): C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso C<sub>16 : 1<em>ω</em>11<em>c</em></sub>, summed feature 4 (C<sub>17 : 1</sub> iso I and/or C<sub>17 : 1</sub> anteiso B) and iso C<sub>17 : 1ω10<em>c</em></sub>.</s><s>Details of the fatty acid methyl ester composition are available as supplementary data in IJSEM Online.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA varies between 35·4 mol% (type strain) and 36·8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 18435<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 107762<sup>T</sup>=Logan collection number B1724<sup>T</sup>=isolate SSI024<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>