<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8739_nm.13403" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13403" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13403" rank="species">Marinobacter guineae</organism><reference id="rid.8739"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mercadé</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter guineae sp. nov., a novel moderately halophilic bacterium from an Antarctic environment.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1346</fpage><lpage>1349</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65298-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523176</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter guineae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter guineae</em> (gui.ne′ae. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>guineae</em> in honour of the late Professor Jesús Guinea, a prominent Spanish microbiologist, who isolated this strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.4 μm wide and 1.4–4.0 μm long), Gram-negative and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>After 72 h incubation at 30 °C on MA, colonies are 1.5–2.0 mm in diameter, smooth, round, convex and white.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 42 °C and at pH 5.0–9.5.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 1–15 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of Na<sup>+</sup>.</s><s>Growth is observed under anaerobic conditions in the presence of KNO<sub>3</sub>.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed, but DNA, lecithin, casein and starch are not.</s><s>Using the API 20NE test, aesculin hydrolysis is positive, but gelatin hydrolysis, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease are negative.</s><s>Assimilates <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and phenylacetic acid, but not d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid or trisodium citrate.</s><s>Using the API 50CH test, only glycerol, d-glucose and d-fructose are fermented; none of the other organic substrates included in the API 50CH test are fermented.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>The main fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Ubiquinone-9 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 57.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M3B<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24048<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7243<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sediment collected from Deception Island (South Shetland Islands, Antarctica).</s></p></content></protolog>