<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1198_nm.4012" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4012" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4012" rank="species">Clostridium saccharolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.1198"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>A.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van den Berg</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium saccharolyticum sp. nov., a saccharolytic species from sewage sludge.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>132</fpage><lpage>135</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-1-132</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium saccharolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium saccharolyticum</i>sp. nov. (Gr. noun <i>sacchar</i> sugar; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i> dissolving; M.L. adj. <i>saccharolyticum</i> sugar-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology: Straight, spindle-shaped rods, 0.5 to 0.7 μm by 3.0 μm.</s><s>Spores are round and terminal and cause cell swelling.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Colony characteristics.</s><s>White, circular, convex, smooth margins, 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutrition: Saccharolytic, capable of fermenting adonitol, amygdalin, cellobiose, esculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose , raffinose , rhamnose , ribose, salicin, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>It cannot use arabinose, cellulose, dulcitol, erythritol, inulin, sorbitol, or starch.</s><s>Requires a growth factor provided by 0.1% yeast extract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation products: Produces acetic acid, hydrogen, carbon dioxide, ethanol, and traces of pyruvic and lactic acids from cellobiose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions: Gelatin not liquefied; sulfate and nitrate not reduced; produces acetylmethylcarbinol, ammonia, and indole; catalase and urease negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature relationships: Temperature for optimal growth is 37°C; growth range, 17 to 43°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH relationship: pH for optimal growth is 7.4; growth range, pH 6.0 to 8.8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition: 28 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Methanogenic cellulose-enrichment culture from sewage sludge.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: WM1.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the National Research Council of Canada culture collection under the accession number NRC 2533.</s></p></content></protolog>