<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3614_nm.10231" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10231" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10231" rank="species">Rhodanobacter spathiphylli</organism><reference id="rid.3614"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Clercq</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ceustermans</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coosemans</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ryckeboer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodanobacter spathiphylli sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium isolated from the roots of Spathiphyllum plants grown in a compost-amended potting mix.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1755</fpage><lpage>1759</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64131-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902003</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodanobacter spathiphylli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodanobacter spathiphylli</em> (spa.thi.phyl′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>spathiphylli</em> of <em>Spathiphyllum</em>, referring to the isolation source of the first strains, the rhizosphere of <em>Spathiphyllum</em> plants).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, 0.8×1.5–4.0 μm in size and non-motile.</s><s>They form smooth, circular, yellow colonies as large as 2–3 mm in diameter on nutrient agar and TSA after 48 h incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>The strains grow well on nutrient agar, TSA and other common bacteriological media at ≥25 °C and ≤35 °C for all strains.</s><s>Strains B35 and B39<sup>T</sup> are unable to grow at ≤7 °C or ≥45 °C.</s><s>Strain B42 is unable to grow at ≤20 °C or ≥40 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C for strains B35 and B42 and 35 °C for strain B39<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>All strains give positive results in tests for the following: oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, C<sub>4</sub> esterase, C<sub>8</sub> esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, aesculin, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase, growth on sorbitol and growth on glycogen; weak acid production from aesculin, citrate, salicin and potassium 5-ketogluconate is observed.</s><s>All strains give negative results in tests for the following: C<sub>14</sub> lipase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-d-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-d-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-d-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-d-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-d-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, fermentation of d-glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, growth on d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosamine, d-maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, salicin, d-melibiose, l-fucose, propionate, valerate, histidine, 2- and 5-ketogluconate, 3- and 4-hydroxybutyrate, l-proline, rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, d-sucrose, itaconate, suberate, malonate, acetate, d- and l-lactate, l-alanine, 3-hydroxybenzoate and l-serine and acid production from glycerol, erythritol, d- and l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- and l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose (bovine origin), d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate and potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The three strains respond differently in tests for some biochemical characteristics.</s><s>Strain B42 gives a positive response for <em>β</em>-d-glucosidase activity and for the degradation of gelatin, whereas strains B35 and B39<sup>T</sup> give negative responses.</s><s>Strains B35 and B39<sup>T</sup> give positive results for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase activity whereas strain B42 gives a negative response.</s><s>The reactions for the production of acids from d-maltose and starch are negative for strain B42 and weakly positive for strains B35 and B39<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The cells contain the fatty acids 15 : 0 iso and 17 : 1 iso <em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> as the main constituents.</s><s>The mean DNA G+C content is 67.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B39<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23181<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17631<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizospheres of <em>Spathiphyllum</em> plants grown in a compost-amended potting mix.</s></p></content></protolog>