<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1217_nm.5104" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5104" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5104" rank="species">Listeria welshimeri</organism><reference id="rid.1217"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rocourt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Listeria welshimeri sp. nov. and Listeria seeligeri sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>866</fpage><lpage>869</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-866</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Listeria welshimeri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Listeria welshimeri</i>(wel.shi'mer.i. M. L. gen. n. <i>welshimeri</i> of Welshimer, honoring Herbert J. Welshimer, American bacteriologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small (0.4 to 0.5 by 0.5 to 2.0 μm), asporogenous, gram-positive rods which are motile at 28°C by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on tryptose agar (Difco Laboratories) are small (1 to 2 mm in diameter after 1 or 2 days of incubation at 37°C), regular, and smooth with a blue-green color when they are examined with obliquely transmitted light.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4°C within 5 days.</s><s>Metabolism is facultatively anaerobic, catalase is produced, the oxidase test is negative, and nitrates are not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid, but no gas, is produced from D-glucose, D-xylose, and α-methyl-D-mannoside.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from L-rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-mannitol.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests are positive.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed in 1 day.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolyzed, and indole is not produced.</s><s>Sheep erythrocytes are not hemolyzed, and CAMP tests with <i>S. aureus</i> CIP 5710 and <i>R. equip</i> CIP 5869 are negative.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolyzed, and H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>The strains presently assigned to <i>L. welshimeri</i> belong to servers 6a and 6b (these servers also occur in <i>L. innocua</i>) and are nonpathogenic are holoxenic pathogen-free mice (50% lethal dose, more than 10<sup>8</sup> colony-forming units per ml).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 36%.</s><s>Isolated from decaying plants and soil in the United States.</s><s>The type strain, strain SLCC 5334 (= CIP 8149 = Welshimer V8), was isolated in the United States by H.</s><s>J.</s><s>Welshimer from decaying vegetation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the type strain is the same as the description for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain does not produce acid from L-rhamnose and belongs to serovar 6b.</s></p></content></protolog>