<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1584_nm.10967" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10967" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10967" rank="species">Pseudolabrys taiwanensis</organism><reference id="rid.1584"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jäckel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudolabrys taiwanensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an alphaproteobacterium isolated from soil</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2469</fpage><lpage>2472</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64124-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012581</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudolabrys taiwanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudolabrys taiwanensis</em> (tai.wan.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>taiwanensis</em> of Taiwan, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain comprises iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (0.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (4.8 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (2.0 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (0.8 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (6.1 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (2.9 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (24.1 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2.9 %), 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (1.2 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (51.2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub> 2-OH (1.0 %) and C<sub>20 : 2</sub><em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em> (0.8 %).</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Flexirubin-like pigments and fluorescence are absent.</s><s>Acid production is negative from glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, rhamnose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, d-arabitol, d-mannose, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, d-xylose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol and melibiose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (method according to Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991 and Biolog GN2): acetate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate (weakly), mesaconate (weakly), 3-hydroxybenzoate, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester and succinic acid monomethyl ester.</s><s>The following tests are negative (Biolog GN2): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate, salicin, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-xylose, maltitol, adipate, pyruvate, azelate, suberate, l-tryptophan, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA).</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl d-galactopyranoside (ONPG), pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pna and l-proline pNA (method according to Kämpfer <em>et al.</em>, 1991).</s><s>Positive results (API ZYM) are seen for activities of esterase, esterase lipase, lipase (weak), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, while results are negative for alkaline phosphatase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Additional physiological features are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CC-BB4<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 51779<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108932<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from Sinshe in Taichung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>