<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1054_nm.73" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.73" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.73" rank="species">Sulfolobus tokodaii</organism><reference id="rid.1054"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwasaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uzawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nemoto</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kon</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamagishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oshima</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sulfolobus tokodaii sp. nov. (f. Sulfolobus sp. strain 7), a new member of the genus Sulfolobus isolated from Beppu Hot Springs, Japan.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>39</fpage><lpage>44</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11878560</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sulfolobus tokodaii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sulfolobus tokodaii</i> (tou.kou.dye. M. L. gen. adj. <i>tokodaii</i>, pertaining to the Japanese name of the Tokyo Institute of Technology, where this isolate was initially characterized).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular cocci and variable in size (usually 0.5-0.8 μm in diameter) and have some flattened and uneven surfaces.</s><s>The cell envelope consists of a hexagonal S-layer lattice (spacing approximately 20 nm).</s><s>Colonies are pale tan, translucent, smooth, and convex, with entire margins.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grow chemoheterotrophically on a modified Brock’s basal salts mixture supplied with trypton, yeast extract, casaminoic acid, or amino acids under obligatory aerobic conditions.</s><s>Best growth occurs on a modified Brock’s basal salts mixture supplied with yeast extract (1 g/l), casaminoic acid (1 g/l), and glucose (1 g/l).</s><s>Supplements of elemental sulfur are not required for the chemoheterotrophic growth.</s><s>Poor growth occurs under facultatively chemolithotrophic conditions in the presence of elemental sulfur when supplied with alanine (10 mg/l) or polypeptone (0.1 g/l).</s><s>No growth occurs in minimal medium amended with a H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> (90:10) headspace.</s><s>Growth occurs at 70° to 85°C; optimal growth is at 80°C under aerobic and chemoheterotrophic growth conditions.</s><s>No growth was detected at 65° and 90°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 2 to 5; optimal growth is at pH 2.5–3.</s><s>No growth was detected at pH 1 or pH 6.</s><s>It is an obligately aerobic and facultatively chemoheterotrophic thermoacidophile that grows by aerobic respiration rather than by simple fermentation.</s><s>Cells contain membrane-bound cytochromes <i>b<sub>562</sub>, a<sub>583</sub>, and aa<sub>3</sub></i>, with the α bands at 562 nm, 583 nm, and 603 nm, respectively, as constituents of its aerobic respiratory terminal oxidase supercomplex and a soluble zinc-containing ferredoxin as a major cytosolic electron transport protein.</s><s>No <i>c</i>- and <i>d</i>-type cytochromes are detected spectrophotometrically.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The complete genomic DNA sequence of <i>Sulfolobus tokodaii</i> strain 7<sup>T</sup> has been analyzed by Kawarabayasi et al. (2001).</s><s>The G + C content of the genomic DNA is 32.8 mol%, as calculated from its whole genomic DNA sequence.</s><s>The phylogenetic analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence and the DNA–DNA homologies with similar species distinguish it as a new species belonging to the genus <i>Sulfolobus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>Sulfolobus tokodaii</i> sp. strain 7<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from the Beppu Hot Springs in the continental acidic geothermal area of Kyushu Island, Japan, and it has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as strain JCM 10545.</s></p></content></protolog>