<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11792_nm.19902" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19902" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19902" rank="species">Rhodocytophaga aerolata</organism><reference id="rid.11792"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Anandham</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodocytophaga aerolata gen. nov., sp. nov., a new
member of the family Cytophagaceae isolated from air</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1554</fpage><lpage>1558</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015305-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684325</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodocytophaga aerolata</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodocytophaga aerolata</em> (ae.ro.la′ta. Gr. n. <em>aer</em> air; L. fem. part. adj. <em>lata</em> carried; N.L. fem. part. adj. <em>aerolata</em> airborne).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following characteristics in addition to those listed in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped to filamentous (0.3–0.9×2.5–25.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are reddish pink and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>The temperature and pH ranges for growth are 10–35 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Hydrolyses CM-cellulose, DNA, starch and Tween 80, but not agar, casein, chitin, hypoxanthine, pectin or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, d-mannose, <em>N-</em>acetylglucosamine, maltose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, salicin and melibiose, but not d-ribose, d-mannitol, l-arabinose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, phenylacetic acid or l-proline.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities, but negative for esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>The detailed fatty acid composition of the type strain is given in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 45.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5416T-29<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12507<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22190<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an air sample from Suwon city, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>