<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1947_nm.8451" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8451" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8451" rank="species">Algoriphagus antarcticus</organism><reference id="rid.1947"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandecandelaere</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Algoriphagus antarcticus sp. nov., a novel psychrophile from microbial mats in Antarctic lakes</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1969</fpage><lpage>1973</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02973-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545419</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Algoriphagus antarcticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Algoriphagus antarcticus</em> (ant.arc′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>antarcticus</em> of the Antarctic, the environment from where the strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The rod-shaped cells range from 2 to 3 μm in length and up to 0·5 μm in width; motility not detected.</s><s>The strains grow at 5–20 °C, with weak growth at 25 °C and an optimal growth temperature of 20 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 30 °C.</s><s>Orange–red-pigmented, convex, opaque colonies with a diameter of 0·5–3 mm with entire margins are formed on marine agar plates after 6 days incubation.</s><s>Colonies on Anacker &#x0026; Ordal's agar are flat, round with entire margins and 0·5–0·7 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on nutrient agar and R2A and colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>No growth on trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Gram-negative and catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Degrades aesculin.</s><s>Growth is not observed (API 20NE) on glucose, mannose, maltose, l-arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, casein, CM-cellulose, DNA, starch, gelatin, tyrosine and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed.</s><s>There is no production of a brown diffusible pigment on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains shows activity for the enzymes arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase (except strain LMG 21983), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, medium activity for valine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, and strong activity for alkaline and acid phophatases, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Variable results are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Growth occurs in up to 5 % NaCl but not in 10 % NaCl, indicating that the strains are not halophilic but are moderately halotolerant.</s><s>The G+C content of the strains is 39·9–41·0 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from lakes Reid, Fryxell and Ace, Antarctica.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21980<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15986<sup>T</sup>=R-10710<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>