<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1434_nm.4875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4875" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3927" rank="species">Bacillus azotofixans</organism><reference id="rid.1434"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Seldin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Elsas</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Penido</surname><given-names>E.G.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus azotofixans sp. nov. a nitrogen-fixing species from Brazilian soil and grass roots.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>451</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus azotofixans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus azotofixans</i> (a. zo. to. fix´ans. Gr. n. <i>azote</i> nitrogen; M.L. part. adj.<i>fixans</i> fixing, to hold in place; N.L. adj. <i>azotofixans</i> nitrogen fixing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods.</s><s>After 24 to 48 h in GB broth, they occur singly and are weakly motile.</s><s>The cells are 3 to 6 by 1 μm.</s><s>In older GB broth cultures, long forms are produced.</s><s>Strains sporulate well after 5 days on aerobic GB agar; in growth obtained from agar slants, the bulk of the organisms occur as spores.</s><s>The spores are oval to ellipsoidal and predominantly central to subterminal and distend the sporangium to spindle shape (Fig. 1).</s><s>Capsules with discrete boundaries are produced.</s><s>Aerobic cultures in medium supplemented with 0.1% (NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub> HPO<sub>4</sub> contain inclusions of polyphosphate.</s><s>Young (24-h) GB broth cultures are gram variable, containing both gram-positive and gram-negative cells.</s><s>On GB agar under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions, colonies develop after 48 h at 32°C.</s><s>Colonies are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, whitish, circular to slightly irregular, and convex, with entire to undulate margins.</s><s>They are mucoid and opaque, with a butyrous texture, and do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>Colonies gradually become flatter and duller, and after 2 weeks reveal three to five concentric rings when viewed by transmitted light.</s><s>Strains produce moderate growth after 48 h of anaerobic incubation on nitrogen-free thiamine-biotin agar (20).</s><s>Under aerobic conditions, little or no growth is produced in nutrient broth or on the agar of Gordon et al. (6).</s><s>TY broth and agar (22) permit moderate growth.</s><s>Abundant growth is produced after 24 to 48 h in GB broth.</s><s>Visible growth occurs in a pellet on the bottom.</s><s>The minimum and maximum temperatures for growth are 15 to 20 and 37 to 40°C respectively.</s><s>No growth occurs at 10 or 42°C.</s><s>Moderate growth is produced at pH 5.7.</s><s>Strains grow in the presence of 1% NaCl.</s><s>At 2 and 3% NaCl, variable growth occurs.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 5% NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 0.001% lysozyme.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Aerobic growth is catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer positive.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer broth acidified to pH 4.5 to 5.1.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from glucose, sucrose, galactose, maltose, raffinose, cellobiose, inulin, and mannitol.</s><s>Acid and gas are not produced from xylose, arabinose, lactose, ribose, sorbose, and glycerol.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized as a carbon source.</s><s>Casein and pectin are not decomposed.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Tyrosine is not decomposed.</s><s>Starch hydrolysis is negative, but slight clearing of the medium occurs beneath colonies.</s><s>Dihydroxyacetone is not produced from glycerol.</s><s>No crystalline dextrins are formed in rolled oat medium.</s><s>Nitrogen is fixed under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Not susceptible to <i>B . polymyxa</i> typing phages EPy-1, SPy-1, and SPy-2.</s><s>The base composition of the DNA ranges from 47.9 to 52.5 mol% G + C (average, 50.7 mol%) (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 35681 (= P3L-5).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species; the base composition of the DNA is 51.6 ± 1.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>