<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12624_nm.22158" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22158" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22158" rank="species">Litorimonas taeanensis</organism><reference id="rid.12624"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Litorimonas taeanensis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a sandy beach</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1534</fpage><lpage>1538</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022129-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Litorimonas taeanensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Litorimonas taeanensis</em> (tae.an.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>taeanensis</em> of or belonging to Taean, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics described for the genus, the species is characterized by the following properties.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.6×1.6–2.0 µm, strictly aerobic, chemoheterotrophic and moderately halophilic.</s><s>Colonies on MA are yellow–orange, convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C (optimum 25–30 °C), at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 7–8) and in 1–6 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2–3  %).</s><s>Positive for assimilation of d-glucose but negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannose, maltose, d-mannitol, malic acid, potassium gluconate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20 NE).</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and α-glucosidase activities but negative for lipase (C14), α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for esterase (C4), β-glucosidase and naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for (Biolog GN2) utilization of Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid mono-methyl ester, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, β- and γ-hydroxybutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, l-asparagine, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, γ-amino butyric acid, inosine, uridine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, α-dl-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose-1-phosphate and d-glucose-6-phosphate.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>Resistant to polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, lincomycin, ampicillin, tetracycline, penicillin G and carbenicillin but sensitive to chloramphenicol.</s><s>PG, MGDG, GUDG and two unidentified glycolipids are the polar lipids detected.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub> ω6<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, G5<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 13701<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22008<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from beach sand in Taean, South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>