<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1791_nm.11105" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11105" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11105" rank="species">Thalassospira xiamenensis</organism><reference id="rid.1791"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassospira xiamenensis sp. nov. and Thalassospira profundimaris sp. nov.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>316</fpage><lpage>320</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64544-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267971</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassospira xiamenensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassospira xiamenensis</em> (xi.a.me.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xiamenensis</em> pertaining to Xiamen, the city where the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.8–2.3 μm long and 0.3–0.8 μm wide, non-spore-forming, Gram-negative curved rods that are motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on HLB agar are circular, convex, glistening, viscid, translucent and yellowish.</s><s>Mesophilic; growth temperature ranges from 4 to 40 °C (optimum 22 °C).</s><s>NaCl is required for growth, cells grow at 0.5–10 % NaCl (optimum at 2–4 %).</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase activities, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, amylase and gelatinase activity.</s><s>Cannot hydrolyse Tween 40, Tween 80 or agar.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic; can grow in anaerobic conditions by reducing nitrate.</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (10 μg per 6 mm disc): chloramphenicol, norfloxacin, furazolidone, co-trimoxazole, ofloxacin, midecamycin, ceftriaxone, polymyxin B, doxycycline, tetracycline, neomycin, kanamycin, gentamicin, amikacin, erythromycin, minocycline, carbenicillin, cefalexin, cephradine, ciprofloxacin and cefuroxime, but resistant to: cefoperazone, clindamycin, vancomycin, ceftazidime, cefazolin, penicillin, oxacillin, ampicillin and piperacillin.</s><s>Among the 95 carbon sources in the Biolog system, the following are utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, monomethyl succinate, methyl pyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine, l-pyroglutamic acid, urocanic acid, thymidine and glycerol.</s><s>Principal fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, with minor amounts of C<sub>13 : 1</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo and small amounts of 11 methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>G+C content of the genomic DNA is 52.6 mol%.</s><s>Table 1 shows characteristics used to distinguish strain M-5<sup>T</sup> from other members of the genus <em>Thalassospira</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M-5<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17429<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.3998<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface water collected from a waste-oil pool at an oil storage dock in the city of Xiamen on the Eastern coast of China.</s></p></content></protolog>