<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4675_nm.11724" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11724" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8425" rank="species">Dictyoglomus turgidus</organism><reference id="rid.4675"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Svetlichny</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Svetlichnayá</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dictyoglomus turgidus sp. nov., a new extremly thermophilic eubacterium isolated from hot springs of the Uzon volcano caldera</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>435</fpage><lpage>441</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dictyoglomus turgidus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dictyoglomus turgidus</i> (tur'gi. dus-from Lat. adj. <i>turgidus</i> - bulbous, inflated; turgidus - forming spherical aggregates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells (10 to 30 μm long by 0.3-0.4 μm wide) occur as single cells or in spherical aggregates, that contain from two to several hundreds of cells and are surrounded by a common outer membrane.</s><s>The cells are gram-negative, nonmotile, non-sporeforming, multiplicate by binar fision.</s><s>The cell envelope is of gram-negative type, threelayered, with easily exfoliating outer membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Obtains energy from fermentation.</s><s>As carbon and energy sources uses cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, raffinose, sucrose, rhamnose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, pyruvate, starch, glycogen, pectin, microcrystalline cellulose, carboxymethyl cellulose, lignin, humic acids, yeast extract, peptone, casein hydrolysate, casamino acids.</s><s>Arabinose, fucose, galactose, xylose, mannose, glycerol are not fermented.</s><s>The products of starch fermentation are lactate, CO<sub>2</sub>, acetate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict anaerobe, thermophilic.</s><s>Growth occures between 48 and 86° C with an optimum at 72° C and pH between 5,2 and 9,0 with an optimum at 7.0-7.1.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by streptomycin (100 μg/ml), chloramphenicol (5.0 μg/ml), benzylpenicillin (50 μg/ml), NaCl (2.0%) and sodium dodecyl sulfate (100 μg/ml), but not inhibited by 100 μg/ml of vancomycin or rifampicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA is 32.5 mol.%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Belongs to eubacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat; hot springs of the Uzon volcano caldera (Kamchatka).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Z-1310.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Stored in the Laboratory of lithotrophic microorganisms, Institute of Microbiology, the USSR Academy of Sciences, Moscow.</s></p></content></protolog>