<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11762_nm.19865" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19865" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19865" rank="species">Actinomyces timonensis</organism><reference id="rid.11762"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Renvoise</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces timonensis sp. nov., isolated from a
human clinical osteo-articular sample</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1516</fpage><lpage>1521</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012914-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomyces timonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomyces timonensis</em> (ti.mo.nen′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>timonensis</em> pertaining to la Timone, named after Hôpital de la Timone, the hospital in Marseilles, France, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are anaerobic, Gram-positive, straight rods, catalase-negative and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>After 48 h growth on blood sheep agar, surface colonies are pin-point.</s><s>The rod size, estimated by electron microscopy, is 1.0–3.2 μm in length and 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Using API ZYM, leucine arylamidase activity is detected, but valine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Using API 50CH strips after an incubation time of 24 h, acid is produced from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose and raffinose.</s><s>After an incubation time of 24 h, acid is produced weakly from glycerol, d-ribose, d-mannose and glycogen.</s><s>After an incubation time of 48 h, acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-mannose and glycogen and acid is produced weakly from d-arabitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, cellobiose, inulin, starch, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>After 24 h incubation, acid production is variable from arbutin.</s><s>After 48 h incubation, acid production is variable from d-adonitol and arbutin.</s><s>Using API Rapid ID32A: positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase; variable for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, mannose fermentation and raffinose fermentation; and negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 7400942<sup>T</sup> (=CSUR P35<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 55928<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a human clinical osteo-articular sample.</s></p></content></protolog>