<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2233_nm.6496" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6496" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6496" rank="species">Rhodococcus roseus</organism><reference id="rid.2233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyama</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodococcus roseus sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>389</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodococcus roseus</i> sp. nov., nom. rev. Tsukamura, Yano, Kudo, and Miyama.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodococcus roseus</i> (ro'se. us. L. adj. <i>roseus</i>, of rose; strains ATCC 271<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 4004 were previously placed in the taxon <i>Bacterium mycoides roseum</i> Grotenfelt 1889 [21]; the specific epithet was taken from this name)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 271.</s><s>The description below is based on the type strain (among the distinguishing characteristics shown in Table 2, strain ATCC 4004 differs only in its ability to utilize trehalose as a sole carbon source).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slightly acid-fast rods that are 3 to 7 μm long and 0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Mycelium is not formed.</s><s>Colonies are rough, dry, and pinkish in egg media and on modified Sauton agar medium (glutamate substituted for asparagine).</s><s>Grow occurs after 3 days.</s><s>Grow occurs at 28, 37, and 42°C but not at 45°C.</s><s>Resistant to 0.2% sodium <i>para</i>-aminosalicylate in Ogawa egg medium.</s><s>Resistant to the following compounds (tests conducted in Ogawa egg medium): hydroxylamine hydrochloride (0.25 mg/ml), sodium salicylate (0.5 mg/ml), paranitrobenzoic acid (0.5 mg/ml), and ethambutol (5 μg/ml).</s><s>Susceptible to the following compounds: rifampin (25 μg/ ml), 5-fluorouracil (20 μg/ml), mitomycin C (5 μg/ml), and hydroxylamine hydrochloride (0.5 mg/ml).</s><s>Tolerates 0.2% picric acid and 0.2% sodium nitrite in modified Sauton agar medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arylsulfatase activity is negative after 14 days; niacin is not formed; <i>para</i>-aminosalicylate and salicylate are not degraded to catechol.</s><s>Tween 80 is not hydrolyzed after 14 days; catalase activity is semiquantitively positive (foam height, &#x003E;45 mm).</s><s>α-Esterase and β-esterase activities are negative.</s><s>P-Galactosidase activity is negative.</s><s>Acid phosphatase activity is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetamidase and urease activities are positive, but benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, salicylamidase, allantoinase, and succinamidase activities are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-Glutamate, glucosamine, and acetamide are utilized as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources, but L-serine, benzamide , monoethanolamine , and trimethylene diamine are not.</s><s>Acetate, succinate, malate, pyruvate, benzoate, fumarate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, propylene glycol, 2,3-butylene glycol, <i>n</i>-butanol, and iso-butanol are utilized as sole sources of carbon in the presence of an ammoniacal nitrogen source.</s><s>Citrate, malonate, 1,3-butylene glycol, and 1,4- butylene glycol are not utilized as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, sucrose, mannose, mannitol, and sorbitol are utilized as sole carbon sources, but L-galactose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, trehalose, and inositol are not.</s><s>Acetamide, urea, pyrazinamide, nicotinamide, and nitrate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources in the presence of a glycerol carbon source, but benzamide and nitrite are not utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only one α-mycolic acid spot is present on thin-layer chromatograms.</s><s>The numbers of carbon atoms present in the mycolic acids are 36,38,40,42,44, and 46 (center, 42 carbon atoms).</s><s>The number of double bonds in the mycolic acids is zero or one.</s><s>The number of carbon atoms in the α-unit is 14 or 16, and the number of carbon atoms in the β-unit is 20 to 32.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 67.5 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall type is type IVA.</s><s>The menaquinone type is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) (&#x003E;80%).</s></p></content></protolog>