<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3591_nm.3045" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3045" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3045" rank="subspecies">Aeromonas hydrophila hydrophila</organism><reference id="rid.3591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Albert</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kühn</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denys</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas hydrophila subsp. dhakensis subsp. nov., isolated from children with diarrhoea in Bangladesh, and extended description of Aeromonas hydrophila subsp. hydrophila (Chester 1901) Stanier 1943 (approved lists 1980).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>705</fpage><lpage>712</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01844-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054229</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>hydrophila</i> (Chester 1901) Stanier 1943 (Approved Lists 1980)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>As mentioned above, the name <i>A. hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>hydrophila</i> was included in the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names (Skerman et al., 1980) but was assigned species rank as <i>A. hydrophila</i> by Popoff (1984). As a result of the taxonomic allocation of the biochemically distinct BD-2 group to <i>A. hydrophila</i>, the description of <i>A. hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>hydrophila</i> (Chester 1901) Stanier 1943 (Approved Lists 1980) needs to be extended somewhat. The following description of the latter taxon is based on phenotypic data determined from the three HG1 strains included in this study and on data reported previously for <i>A. hydrophila</i> HG1 by Abbott et al. (1992), Kämpfer &#x0026; Altwegg (1992) and Hänninen (1994), which all included the type strain, ATCC 7966<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 2844<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains display the following characteristics typical of the genus <i>Aeromonas</i>: Gram-negative, straight, motile rods, chemo-organotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism, cytochrome oxidase- and catalase-positive, reduction of nitrate to nitrite without the production of gas and resistant to the vibriostatic agent O/129.</s><s>Glucose is fermented with production of acid and gas.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 24 h at 28 °C on TSA medium, but all strains also grow at 41 °C after 24±48 h.</s><s>No brown, water-soluble pigment is produced on TSA medium.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-, lysine decarboxylase-, indole-, aesculin hydrolysis- and Voges-Proskauer-positive.</s><s>No production of urease, tryptophan deaminase, ornithine decarboxylase or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole carbon and energy sources: N-acetyl β-D-galactosamine, L-alanine, L-arabinose, <i>p</i>-arbutin, DL-lactate, D-mannitol, putrescine, D-serine, salicin and D-sucrose.</s><s>Strains do not use D-cellobiose, DL-isocitrate, β-alanine, 4-aminobutyrate or urocanic acid.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-mannitol, salicin, and D-sucrose, but not from D-cellobiose, lactose, D-rhamnose or D-sorbitol.</s><s>See Table 3 for additional phenotypic markers for differentiation from <i>A. hydrophila</i> subsp. <i>dhakensis</i>.</s><s>Isolated from humans, animals, fish and fresh water.</s><s>Strong β-haemolytic activity on TSA supplemented with 5% sheep blood.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 7966<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 2844<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>