<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.782_nm.1364" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1364" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1364" rank="species">Bartonella clarridgeiae</organism><reference id="rid.782"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Bartonella clarridgeiae sp. nov. isolated from the cat of a patient with Bartonella henselae septicemia.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>64</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="158">Medical Microbiology Letters : an international journal for rapid communications on all aspects of medical and clinical microbiology</source><abbrev>Med Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>1018-4627</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bartonella clarridgeiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bartonella clarridgeiae</i> (The name is to honour the American microbiologist Jill E. Clarridge, III who first isolated the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>By gram-stain the Houston-2 cat strain fits the description of the genus <i>Bartollella</i> in being small (about 0.5 x 1.2 μ) pleomorphic gram-negative coccobacilli or slightly curved rods similar in size to <i>B. quintana</i> and <i>B. henselae</i> but somewhat smaller than <i>B. elizabethae</i> and <i>B. vinsonii</i>.</s><s>When grown at 35°C with added humidity and CO<sub>2</sub>, colonies form slowly (visible at 5 days) on initial isolation; on subculture the colonies are about 0.5 mm at 10 days and appear white, raised, indurant (cauliflower-like) and cohesive.</s><s>Growth of the Houston-2 cat strain is supported on many blood containing media such as brain heart infusion (BBL) or trypticase soy agar (BEL) with 5 to 10% sheep blood.</s><s>After subculture, the Houston-2 cat strain colonies can become smooth and round.</s><s>Compared to the Houston-2 cat strain, <i>B. elizabethae</i> and <i>B. vinsonii</i> strains grew faster and formed larger colonies while <i>B. henselae</i> and <i>B. quintana</i> grew slower and formed smaller colonies.</s><s>Cells of the Houston-2 cat strain possess flagella which are polar and number about 3 per bacteria (Fig. 1).</s><s>With the exception of <i>B. bacilliformis</i>, all other <i>Bartonella</i> spp. lack flagella (1, 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Houston-2 cat strain gave negative reactions for catalase, urease, esculin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, oxidase and carbohydrate utilization.</s><s>By measuring preformed enzymes (RapID Ana II) the strain was found to be biochemically inert except for the production of peptidases; the profile number was 000671 indicating negative reactions to carbohydrates and positive reactions for the cleavage of leucyl-glycine, glycine, proline, phenylalanine, arginine, and serine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The determined 165 rRNA gene sequence of the Houston-2 cat strain consisted of 1466 nucleotides.</s><s>Comparative sequence searches of EMBL and GenBank data libraries showed <i>Bartonella</i> to be the closest genealogical relatives of the Houstoncat strain.</s><s>The 165 rRNA gene sequence of the cat strain showed 97.4 to 98.5% similarity with the sequences of other <i>Bartonella</i> spp. (1,2).</s><s>Although this degree of relatedness is high, it is lower than the levels of similarities exhibited between several other genotypically distinct (as shown by DNA-DNA pairing) <i>Bartonella</i> spp.</s><s>A tree depicting the phylogenetic position of the Houston-2 strain amongst the <i>Bartonellaceae</i> and relatives is shown in Fig 2.</s><s>Consistent with pairwise sequence values (Table 1), the treeing analysis showed the cat strain to be genealogically distinct and having no particularly close genotypic affinity with any other recognized <i>Bartonella</i> spp.</s><s>Although the cat strain clustered near the periphery of <i>Bartonella</i>, its inclusion does not alter the monophyletic nature of the genus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is evident from the phylogenetic analysis that the Houston-2 strain from the cat of a patient with <i>B. henselae</i> septicemia (3) represented a new subline within the genus <i>Bartonella</i>.</s><s>Although a precise correlation between percent 165 rRNA sequence relatedness and speciation is not possible, the levels of sequence divergence (approx. 1.5 to 2.6%) between the Houston-2 cat strain and other <i>Bartonella</i> spp. are substantially higher than observed divergence values between other <i>Bartonella</i> spp. known to be genotypically distinct using DNA-DNA pairing (1).</s><s>These considerations together with the distinct line formed by the Houston-2 strain within the <i>Bartonella</i> tree clearly indicate this organism constitutes a new species.</s><s>It is pertinent to note that the Houston-2 strain is also readily distinguished from other <i>Bartonella</i> species by citrate synthase gene sequence homology and in possessing a unique REP-peR pattern (3).</s><s>Within the <i>Bartonellaceae</i>, these two genetic approaches are known to distinguish between all described species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The two Bartonella spp. which possess flagella (viz: <i>B. bacilliformis</i>, Houston2 cat strain) may be separated by RapID AnaII results, rate of growth, colony type and most definitely by CFA composition analysis (3).</s><s>Other species with RapID Ana code 000671 do not have 'flagella and usually grow more slowly.</s><s>Therefore based on the phenotypic distinctiveness of the organism and genotypic criteria we consider the Houston-2 cat strain to represent a new species, for which the name <i>Bartonella clarridgeiae</i> sp. nov. is proposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Bartonella clarridgeiae</i> is as described above and the type strain is Houston-2 cat (ATCC 51734).</s><s>The determined 16S rRNA gene sequence of <i>Bartonella clarridgeiae</i> strain Houston-2 car has been deposited in EMBL data library under accession number X89208.</s></p></content></protolog>