<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2678_nm.955" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.955" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.955" rank="species">Rickettsia africae</organism><reference id="rid.2678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beati</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matthewman</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia africae sp. nov., the etiological agent of African tick bite fever.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>611</fpage><lpage>614</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-611</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934912</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia africae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia africae</i> (a' fri. cae. L. gen. n. <i>africae</i>, from Africa, the continent where the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Rickettsia africae</i> is an obligately intracellular gram-negative bacterium.</s><s>This organism can be grown in the yolk sacs of developing chicken embryos, which die 5 to 7 days following inoculation, and in L929, Vero, and human embryonic lung fibroblast cells.</s><s>Plaque formation does not occur in infected Vero cells.</s><s>Gimenez-stained (15) infected cells contain intracellular, rod-shaped organisms that are 0.3 to 0.5 by 0.9 to 1.6 μm.</s><s>Electron microscopy shows that the organisms occur free in the cytoplasm and have an outer slime layer and a trilaminar cell wall (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. africae</i> can be isolated from humans with a history of tick bites and clinical signs consistent with African tick bite fever and from <i>A. hebraeum</i> and <i>A. variegatum</i>.</s><s>Stage-to-stage and transovarial transmission of the organism has been demonstrated in <i>A. hebraeum</i>, and all feeding stages of this tick can transmit the organism to rabbits.</s><s>Adults can transmit the organism to goats.</s><s>In these species and in Swiss Webster and BALB/c mice, infections are subclinical, although antibodies to the organism are produced.</s><s>At 4 to 6 days after intraperitoneal inoculation, guinea pigs may develop a mild fever (&#x003E;39.5°C for 1 to 2 days), but they do not develop scrota1 edema.</s><s>In microimmunofluorescence tests the SPDs between <i>R. africae</i> and the other SFG rickettsiae are &#x003E;3 (the SPD between <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. parkeri</i> is 7, and the SPD between <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. sibirica</i> is 5.5).</s><s>As determined by SDS-PAGE, <i>R. africae</i> produces three distinct high-molecular-weight protein bands, at 11 7, 135, and 138 kDa; the most prominent band is the 117-kDa band.</s><s>Sera from mice inoculated with <i>R. africae</i> have antibodies that react with these bands. <i>R. africae</i> can be differentiated from all other SFG rickettsiae, except <i>R. parkeri</i> by the results of PCR restriction fragment length polymorphism analysis.</s><s>When amplified rickettsial DNA derived from PCRs with primers Rr190.70p and Rr190.602n is digested with restriction endonuclease <i>RsaI</i>, 343- and 220-bp fragments are obtained (a 107-bp fragment and a double 223-bp band are obtained with <i>R. sibirica</i> [7]); restriction endonuclease <i>PstI</i> digests the DNA into of 267-, 124-, and 81-bp fragments. <i>RsaI</i> digestion of the products obtained from PCRs performed with primers BG 1-21 and BG 2-20 yields 163-, 133-, 102-, 88-, and 60-bp fragments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As determined by PFGE, the estimated genome size of <i>R. africae</i> is 1,248 kDa.</s><s>The PFGE profiles of the DNA of the organism obtained following digestion with <i>EagI</i>, <i>SmaI</i>, and <i>BssHII</i> are distinct from those of the other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>After digestion with <i>BssHII</i>, the profile of <i>R. africae</i> is characterized by five fragments, the <i>R. parkeri</i> profile contains four bands (one in common with <i>R. africae</i>), and the <i>R. sibirica</i> profile contains four bands (two in common with <i>R. africae</i>); after restriction with <i>EagI</i> the profiles of these three organisms contain 16 bands, 7 of which are shared by <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. sibirica</i> and 8 of which are shared by <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. parkeri</i>; after digestion with SmaI 8 of 25 fragments are shared by <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. parkeri</i> and 18 fragments of 26 are shared by <i>R. africae</i> and <i>R. sibirica</i> (34).</s><s>The bands on which the citrate synthase and 190- and 120-kDa surface protein genes are located are distinct from the bands on which these genes are located in the other SFG rickettsiae following PFGE of the digestion products of endonucleases <i>BssHII</i> and <i>SmaI</i>. <i>R. africae</i> has a 16s rRNA gene sequence which differs from the 16s rRNA gene sequences of the other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>Compared with <i>R. rickettsii</i>, <i>R. africae</i> has a TTT insertion at position 85/6 and an A mutation at position 78.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The illness.</s><s>Previously, tick bite fever and fievre boutonneuse have been considered different names for a single disease resulting from <i>R. conorii</i> infection.</s><s>Therefore, the clinical features of these diseases have been considered to be the same (12).</s><s>There is now strong evidence, however, that tick bite fever has a different etiological agent, and additional studies will be needed to determine more precisely the clinical features, prognosis, and therapy for the disease.</s><s>The data available and our unpublished findings suggest that tick bite fever results from bites of infected <i>Amblyomma</i> spp. encountered during travel into rural areas.</s><s>An eschar develops at the bite site, and regional lymphadenopathy, mild fever, and severe headache follow.</s><s>The absence of a skin rash appears to be a characteristic feature of the disease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>R. africae</i> is strain Z9-Hu, an isolate obtained from a person with tick bite fever; this strain has been deposited in the Collection of the World Health Organization Collaborative Center for Rickettsial Reference, Marseille, France.</s><s>Nucleotide sequence accession number.</s><s>The 16s rRNA gene sequence of <i>R. africae</i> Z9-Hu<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Gen-Bank data library under accession number L36098</s></p></content></protolog>