<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6213_nm.9354" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9354" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9354" rank="species">Jannaschia rubra</organism><reference id="rid.6213"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jannaschia rubra sp. nov., a red-pigmented bacterium isolated from sea water</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>653</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63412-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774638</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jannaschia rubra</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jannaschia rubra</em> (ru′bra. L. fem. adj. <em>rubra</em> red).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, rod-shaped cells, about 1·0–2·0×0·5 μm.</s><s>Divides by binary division.</s><s>Motile by means of three to five monopolar flagella.</s><s>Growth on MA after 7 days of incubation leads to irregular, red colonies adhering to the agar.</s><s>It does not swarm or luminesce.</s><s>Requires at least 0·34 % (w/v) marine salts and tolerates up to 9 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>Sodium and magnesium are required.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–25 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 37 °C or above.</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>Strict aerobic chemo-organotrophic bacterium.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, gelatin, starch, Tween 80, alginate or lecithin, but shows DNase activity on DNase agar supplemented with half-strength ASW.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase activities.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production from thiosulfate, indole production from tryptophan and sulfite oxidation.</s><s>Able to grow on BMA with the following compounds as carbon and energy sources: d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, malate, lactate, acetate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-leucine, l-serine, l-glutamate, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-ornithine, citrulline, l-aspartate, sarcosine and putrescine, provided that the medium is supplemented with a small amount of yeast extract (an indication that undetermined growth factors are required).</s><s>Under the same conditions, the following carbon sources are weakly positive: maltose, d-gluconate, <em>meso</em>-inositol, glycerate, citrate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, l-arginine and l-histidine.</s><s>Pigmentation is absent or delayed when using pyruvate, l-glutamate, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, l-ornithine, citrulline, l-aspartate and glycerate.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: d-ribose, l-arabinose, d-trehalose, l-rhamnose, cellobiose, sucrose, lactose, d-melibiose, amygdalin, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, saccharate, propionate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, glycine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine and l-alanine.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain 4SM3<sup>T</sup> is 64·6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 4SM3<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5088<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16279<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Mediterranean sea water.</s></p></content></protolog>