<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5012_nm.5879" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5879" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5879" rank="species">Arthrobacter uratoxydans</organism><reference id="rid.5012"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fowler</surname><given-names>V.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seiler</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on Arthrobacter nicotianae and related taxa: description of Arthrobacter uratoxydans sp. nov. and Arthrobacter sulfureus sp. nov. and reclassification of Brevibacterium protophormiae as Arthrobacter protophormiae comb. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter uratoxydans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter uratoxydans</i> (U.ra.to'xy.dans M.L. n. <i>uratum</i> salt of uric acid; M.L. part. <i>oxydans</i> oxidizing; M.L. part. <i>uratoxydans</i> uric acid oxidizing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is taken from the original description of <i>Sugisaki</i> et. al., 1973; US patent No. 3.767.533 of "<i>Corynebacterium uratoxydans</i>".</s><s>Data are supplemented with our own results on the peptidoglycan, DNA G+C content and some metabolic properties.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In young cultures, straight to slightly curved or ellipsoidal rods with metachromic granules to pleomorphic rods which are club shaped swellings; angular or palisade rods formed by snapping divisions are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive; 0.8 to 1.2 by 1.0 to 5 μm; non motile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No capsula; no endospores.</s><s>Colonies circular, flat, smooth, entire margines, slightly glistening and opaque, 3-4 mm in diameter; creamy white in young cultures to pale yellow in old cultures.</s><s>Water soluble, pale yellowish brown pigment produced In nutrient broth scanty surface growth; no sediments.</s><s>In gelatine stab best growth at top and filiform; liquification stratiform.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In litmus milk no reaction slightly alkaline; no coagulation.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test negative, Indole production negative; hydrogen sulfide production positive; hydrolrsis of starch negative; utilization of sodium citrate (Koser's and Christen's medium) positive; utilization of a great variety of organic nitrogen compounds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Uricase strongly positive; haemolysis negative; pathology negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilization of a great variety of organic compounds: besides those listed (see footnote to Table 5), 5-amino valerate, glyoxylate, L-leucine, L-xylose, and uric acid are utilized in addition.</s><s>Hydrolysis of xanthine and casein; no acid from sugars; cellulose is not decomposed.</s><s>Aerobic to slightly facultative anaerobic; optimal tpetature for growth between 27 and 35 °C; optimal pH for growth between 7 and 8; thermal death time 10' at 52°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptide subunit of the peptidoglycan consistes of alanine, D-glutamic acid and lysine.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge contains alanine and glutamic acid (Lys-Ala-Glu type, variation A4α, according to <i>Schleifer</i> and <i>Kandler</i>, 1972).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 61.2 and 61.5 for the strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitar: Humus soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Arthrobacter uratoxydans</i> ATCC 21749.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Comments: Contradicting results have been found for the acid production.</s><s>While strong acid formation from glucose, fructose, and maltose have been reported by <i>Suisaki</i> et al. (1973), no acid production from any sugar tested could be detected in out study. <i>A. uratoxydans</i> can be distinguished from <i>A. nicotianae</i> and <i>A. protophormiae</i> by the strong activity of oxydative decomposition of uric acid and by the lack of ability to utilize L-asparagine, L-arginine, L-histidine, D-xylose, D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-galactose, and glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species are used for the production of uricase (US patent 3.767.533).</s></p></content></protolog>