<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1763_nm.9524" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9524" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9524" rank="species">Shewanella sediminis</organism><reference id="rid.1763"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manno</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaulieu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paquet</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hawari</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shewanella sediminis sp. nov., a novel Na+-requiring and hexahydro-1,3,5-trinitro-1,3,5-triazine-degrading bacterium from marine sediment.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1511</fpage><lpage>1520</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63604-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014474</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shewanella sediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shewanella sediminis</em> (se.di.mi′nis. L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of sediment, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, motile, non-spore-forming rods with mean length of 1·7 μm and mean diameter of 0·7 μm.</s><s>Single flagellum is found at polar position.</s><s>Biomass is slightly pinkish and non-bioluminescent.</s><s>Growth at temperatures ranging from 4 to 25 °C, with 10 °C as optimum.</s><s>No growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> is required for growth.</s><s>Growth at 1–4 % NaCl, with 2 % NaCl as optimum, but no growth at 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth on Brewer's anaerobic agar supplemented with 2 % NaCl.</s><s>TMAO, MnO<sub>2</sub>, nitrate, nitrite, thiosulfate and RDX are reduced.</s><s>Negative for reduction of Fe(III) and elemental sulfur.</s><s>Casein, chitin and DNA are hydrolysed, but not gelatin, alginate, starch and agar.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitroreductase, arginine dehydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, alkaline phosphatase, proline arylamidase, leucine glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase.</s><s>Weakly positive for urease.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>p</em>-nitrophenylalanine deaminase by API rapid test, and for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, mannose and raffinose fermentation, indole production, argine arylamidase, phenyl arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase and glycine arylamidase by Rapid ID32 A test.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>By Biolog GN2 microplate test, positive for utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, acetate, methyl pyruvate, propionate, dl-lactate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycine-l-glutamic acid, l-alanine-glycine, inosine, uridine and thymidine; weakly positive for Tween 80, <em>β</em>-hydroxy butyrate, l-leucine and l-proline; negative for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fucose, m-inositol, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid mono methyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>- or <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxy phenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-keto glutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerolphosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate. <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine is oxidized and fermented to acid.</s><s>Galactose, lactose, fructose, sucrose, mannose and glucose are not oxidized or fermented to acids. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, Tween 40, Tween 80, acetate, succinate, butyrate, valerate, pyruvate, serine, proline, peptone and yeast extract are sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Tween 20, malate, propionate and glutamic acid are weak carbon sources.</s><s>Galactose, lactose, fructose, sucrose, mannose, glucose, citrate, lactate, formate, phenol, glycine, leucine and threonine are not utilized.</s><s>Fatty acids C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (7 %), C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH (8 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (4 %), C<sub>i15 : 0</sub> (8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (17 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 (33 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7 (7 %) and C<sub>20 : 5</sub><em>ω</em>3 (3 %) are produced.</s><s>Quinone composition is Q-7 (33 %), Q-8 (13 %), MK-7 (49 %) and MMK-7 (4 %).</s><s>The G+C content is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HAW-EB3<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14036<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17055<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a site 215 m deep and 50 nautical miles from Halifax Harbour, in the Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>