<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3460_nm.1785" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1785" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1785" rank="species">Acidovorax anthurii</organism><reference id="rid.3460"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dauga</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prior</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saddler</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidovorax anthurii sp. nov., a new phytopathogenic bacterium which causes bacterial leaf-spot of anthurium.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>246</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826809</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidovorax anthurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidovorax anthurii</i> (an.thu.rii. L. fem. n. <i>Anthurium</i> anthurium; L. gen. n. <i>anthurii</i> of anthurium, referring to the plant from which this phytopathogenic bacterium was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On YBGA, colonies are circular, raised with an entire margin and white-creamy and brown diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight rods, 0.2-0.7x1.0-5.0 μm, motile by a long polar flagellum.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and urease are positive.</s><s>Strictly aerobic, poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is accumulated in the cell, arginine is used as sole source of carbon.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from cysteine and cellulose is hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole, levane and acetoin are not produced.</s><s>Casein and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, arabinose and glycerol.</s><s>Acetate, formiate, glycerol, DL-5-aminobutyrate, D(-)tartrate and azelate are utilized.</s><s>Trehalose, caprylate, D-ribose, D-glucose, N-acetylglucosamine, L-arginine, saccharose, inositol, sarcosine, itaconate, D-xylose, L-tryptophan, aesculin and mannitol are not utilized.</s><s>The sole hydroxylated fatty acid present is 3-hydroxy-decanoic acid.</s><s>The G+­C content of the strain CFBP 3232<sup>T</sup> determined by thermal denaturation method is 63.5 mol%.</s><s>All strains elicit a hypersensitive reaction on tobacco leaves (HR) and are pathogenic on anthurium, producing typical leaf-spot symptoms.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the CFBP, Angers, France, as CFBP 3232<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>