<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8454_nm.13723" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13723" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13723" rank="species">Haloactinospora alba</organism><reference id="rid.8454"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>X.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloactinospora alba gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic filamentous actinomycete of the family Nocardiopsaceae.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2075</fpage><lpage>2080</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65531-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18768607</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloactinospora alba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloactinospora alba</em> (al′ba. L. fem. adj. <em>alba</em> white).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Growth is good on Czapek's agar, yeast extract-malt extract agar and potato agar, moderate on inorganic salts-starch agar, glycerol-asparagine agar and nutrient agar and poor on oatmeal agar.</s><s>The colour of the aerial mycelium is white to yellow–white and the substrate mycelium is pale yellow to light yellow or deep yellow.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>The aerial and substrate mycelia are well developed, but not fragmented, on most media tested.</s><s>Spores are straight and cylindrical with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Tests for gelatin liquefaction, production of H<sub>2</sub>S and melanin, hydrolysis of cellulose and starch and urease production are negative, whereas tests for milk peptonization and coagulation are positive.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-tagatose and d-xylose are utilized as carbon sources, but d-adonitol, d-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, xylitol and l-xylose are not.</s><s>Temperature, pH and NaCl tolerance ranges are 20–45 °C, pH 6–9 and 9–21 % (w/v) NaCl; good growth occurs at 37 °C, pH 7.0–8.0 and 15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 90648<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45015<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AA 206008<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a salt lake in Xinjiang Province, north-west China.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 68 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>