<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1186_nm.10553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1737" rank="species">Achromobacter xylosoxidans</organism><reference id="rid.1186"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Achromobacter gen. nov. and Achromobacter xylosoxidans (ex Yabuuchi and Ohyama 1971) nom. rev.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>477</fpage><lpage>478</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-4-477</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Achromobacter xylosoxidans</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Achromobacter xylosoxidans</i> (ex Yabuuchi and Ohyama 1971) nom. rev. (xylos ox'idans. M.L. <i>xylos</i> xylose; M.L.v. <i>oxido</i> make acid, oxidize; M.L. part.adj. <i>xylosoxidans</i> oxidizing xylose).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming, straight rods 0.8 to 1.2 by 2.5 to 3.0 μm, with rounded ends.</s><s>Motile and peritrichous.</s><s>The number of flagella is one to nine per cell.</s><s>Strictly aerobic and nonfermentative.</s><s>Definite acidity is produced promptly at the top of OF xylose medium without a paraffin seal.</s><s>Oxidative acid production from glucose, galactose, mannose, and D-arabinose is usually slow and weak.</s><s>Indophenol oxidase and catalase positive; urease, gelatinase and deoxyribonuclease negative; 3- ketolactose is not produced from lactose.</s><s>The guanine-pluscytosine content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is in the range of 65 to 70 mol%.</s><s>A detailed study and description of 75 phenotypic characters of 55 strains, the guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the deoxyribonucleic acids of 20 strains of this species, and a set of characters useful in the identification of <i>A. xylosoxiduns</i> have been published previously.</s><s>The major fatty acid components of cell-bound lipids are 2-hydroxydodecanoic acid (25.6 to 33.6%), 2-hydroxytetradecanoic acid (16.4 to 22.4%), and 3-hydroxytetradecanoic acid (31.1 to 37.6%).</s><s>The respiratory quinone of <i>A. xylosoxzduns</i> was reported to be ubiquinone 8 (K.</s><s>Miyazaki, H.</s><s>Kurose, Y.</s><s>Fujimura, H.</s><s>Kuraishi, M.</s><s>Akagawa, and K.</s><s>Yamasato, Abstr.</s><s>Annu.</s><s>Meet.</s><s>Jpn.</s><s>SOCF. erment.</s><s>Technol. 1980, p. 155).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>A. xylosoxiduns</i> has been isolated from various kinds of pathological specimens, including blood, spinal fluid, pleural fluid, peritoneal fluid, pus, urine, stools, and swabs of eyes, ears, and pharynxes.</s><s>Although its natural habitat is not known, this organism is frequently found in unsterilized “distilled” water and in chlorhexidine solutions in hospitals.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 27061.</s><s>The description of the type strain is identical to that of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>