<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7621_nm.14047" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14047" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14047" rank="species">Jiangella alkaliphila</organism><reference id="rid.7621"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jiangella alkaliphila sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from a cave.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1176</fpage><lpage>1179</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65479-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jiangella alkaliphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jiangella alkaliphila</em> (al.kal.i.phil′a. Arabic article <em>al</em> the; Arabic n. <em>qaliy</em> ashes of saltwort; N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>alkaliphila</em> loving alkaline conditions).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid–alcohol-fast.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Forms well-developed aerial and vegetative mycelia that fragment into short or elongated rods.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white or greyish yellow–brown.</s><s>The reverse colour of colonies is variable depending on growth medium.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>The temperature for growth is in the range 20–37 °C, with good growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The initial pH range for growth is 6.1–10.1, with good growth at pH 8.1–10.1.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Casein, DNA, elastin, aesculin and hypoxanthine are degraded, but chitin, starch, dl-tyrosine, urea and xanthine are not.</s><s>d-Arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextran, d-fructose, d-glucose, inulin, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-xylose, adonitol (weak), glycerol and d-mannitol are assimilated as sole carbon and energy sources for growth.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: d-galactose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, 2,3-butanediol, <em>myo</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, 1,2-propanediol, d-sorbitol and d-xylitol.</s><s>Assimilation of organic acids (acetate, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, succinate, dl-tartrate) is not observed.</s><s>Cell wall contains ll-DAP as the diagnostic diamino acid and glucose as the major sugar.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipid profile comprises diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside and an unknown phospholipid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (20.4 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (18.0 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8.9 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 71.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, D8-87<sup>T</sup> (=JBRI 2008<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19222<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45079<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a natural cave in Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>