<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8755_nm.13804" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13804" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7698" rank="subspecies">Bifidobacterium longum longum</organism><reference id="rid.8755"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mattarelli</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonaparte</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal to reclassify the three biotypes of Bifidobacterium longum as three subspecies: Bifidobacterium longum subsp. longum subsp. nov., Bifidobacterium longum subsp. infantis comb. nov. and Bifidobacterium longum subsp. suis comb. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>767</fpage><lpage>772</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65319-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398167</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium longum</em> subsp. <em>longum</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bifidobacterium longum</em> subsp. <em>longum</em> (long′um. L. neut. adj. <em>longum</em> long) (Reuter 1963).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On TPY agar, strains of this species show mostly very elongated and relatively thin cellular elements with slightly irregular contours and rare branchings.</s><s>In TPY broth, most strains develop with uniform turbidity, clearing is slow and the sediment is viscous. <em>B. longum</em> is apparently the only species among those usually found in human faeces which possesses a large variety of plasmids (Sgorbati <em>et al.</em>, 1982).</s><s>Concerning DNA–DNA relatedness (63–81 %), this subspecies is most closely related to <em>B. longum</em> subsp. <em>infantis</em> and <em>B. longum</em> subsp. <em>suis</em> (Scardovi <em>et al.</em> 1979; Lauer &#x0026; Kandler, 1983; Bahaka <em>et al.</em>, 1993; Sakata <em>et al.</em>, 2002).</s><s>The genome of <em>B. longum</em> NCC 2705 (GenBank accession no. AE014295) was the first to be completely sequenced among the genus <em>Bifidobacterium</em>.</s><s>Sequencing the DNA of this strain has revealed much about its metabolic diversity and generated insights into other members of the genus (Schell <em>et al.</em>, 2002).</s><s>Bioinformatic analysis revealed several physiological traits that could partially explain the successful adaptation of this bacterium to the colon.</s><s>An unexpectedly large number of the predicted proteins appeared to be specialized for catabolism of a variety of oligosaccharides, some possibly released by rare or novel glycosyl hydrolases acting on ‘non-digestible’ plant polymers or host-derived glycoproteins and glycoconjugates. <em>B. longum</em> DJ010A is presently available as a partly assembled genome (GenBank accession no. AABM00000000) (Leahy <em>et al.</em>, 2005).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from infant and adult human faeces, from faeces of suckling calf, from human vagina and from sewage.</s><s>For the original description, see Reuter (1963).</s><s>The genomic G+C content is 61 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: E194b (variant a)<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 15707<sup>T</sup>=DSM 20219<sup>T</sup>), from faeces of human adult (Reuter, 1963).</s></p></content></protolog>