<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5713_nm.6813" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6813" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6813" rank="species">Saccharothrix violacea</organism><reference id="rid.5713"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roe</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharothrix violacea sp. nov., isolated from a gold mine cave, and Saccharothrix albidocapillata comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1315</fpage><lpage>1323</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843077</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharothrix violacea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharothrix violacea</i> (vi.o.la.ce'a. L. adj. <i>violaceus</i> violet ; M.L. adj. <i>violacea</i> violet-coloured)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms a violet substrate mycelium and a white aerial mycelium.</s><s>Reddish-brown pigment is produced.</s><s>Melanin pigment is not produced.</s><s>Aerial mycelium fragments into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Aerobic, catalaseand urease-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10-37°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 42°C.</s><s>Utilizes L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, meso-inositol, D-mannitol, acetate, fumarate, α-ketoglutarate, lactate, malonate, propionate, pyruvate and succinate as carbon sources.</s><s>Gelatin liquefaction occurs.</s><s>Arbutin, DNA, aesculin, hypoxanthine and tyrosine are decomposed.</s><s>Casein, hippurate and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-lactose and L-ribose.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 4% NaCl and 0.01% lysozyme.</s><s>Does not utilize inulin, D-melezitose, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-mannoside, D-raffinose, dulcitol, 2,3-butanediol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, 1,2-propanediol, D-sorbitol, D-xylitol, benzoate, citrate, formate, malate, maleate, oxalate or tartarate as carbon sources.</s><s>Adenine, guanine and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 0.01% thallium acetate.</s><s>No acid is produced from D-cellobiose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, methyl α-D-mannoside, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol or D-mannitol.</s><s>Susceptible to erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, novobiocin, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and tobramycin, but resistant to ampicillin, lincomycin and vancomycin.</s><s>Type III cell wall (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, galactose, mannose and rhamnose in whole-cell hydrolysates).</s><s>Phospholipid profiles contain phosphatidylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidyl-glycerol and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is i-C<sub>16:0</sub> (42.5% of total).</s><s>A considerable amount of C<sub>16:1</sub> (9.6%), i-C<sub>15:0</sub> (7.0%) and 10Me-C<sub>16:0</sub> (8.0%) are also present.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 69.6 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from soils inside a gold mine cave in Kongju, Korea.</s><s>The type strain is strain LM 036<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 50388<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>