<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4506_nm.2939" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2939" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2939" rank="species">Thalassomonas viridans</organism><reference id="rid.4506"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassomonas viridans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel marine gamma-proteobacterium.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1283</fpage><lpage>1289</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491324</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thalassomonas viridans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thalassomonas viridans</i> (vi.ri'dans. L. adj. <i>viridans</i> green)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, it has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Strains grow on MA as regular, opaque colonies that produce a green/blue-green, unstable, diffusible pigment.</s><s>They grow in MB with 2-4% NaCl but not with 6% or more.</s><s>No growth is observed in STB 2-4% NaCl, in STB 2-4% NaCl plus MgCl<sub>2</sub>, in STB 2% NaCl plus CaCl<sub>2</sub> or in STB 2% NaCl plus MgCl<sub>2</sub> and CaCl<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Strains hydrolyse Tween 80 only after prolonged incubation (more than 7 d).</s><s>Organic growth factors are required.</s><s>Strains are able to grow on basal medium supplemented with 0.1 g yeast extract l<sub>-1</sub>, using the following compounds as sole carbon and energy sources: cellobiose, amygdalin, propionate, L-tyrosine, L-citrulline, glutamine and histidine.</s><s>Growth is weak on D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, fumarate and L-leucine.</s><s>Neither of the strains utilizes the following substrates: L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, salicin, arbutin, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, saccharate, glycerate, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, citrate, aconitate, α-ketoglutarate, DL-malate, acetate, DL-lactate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, glycine, L-serine, L-glutamate, L-alanine, caminobutyrate, sarcosine and putrescine.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 15:0, 16:0 and 17:1<i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>.</s><s>Isolated from oysters harvested on the Mediterranean coast of Vinaroz, Spain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, XOM25<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5083<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13754<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from oyster homogenate.</s><s>The species also includes strain XOM5 (=CECT 5082=DSM 13753).</s><s>The type strain XOM25<sup>T</sup> differs from XOM5 by the following traits : it is able to use D-ribose, succinate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, L-threonine, L-arginine and L-ornithine as sole carbon and energy sources.</s></p></content></protolog>