<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5806_nm.5133" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5133" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5133" rank="species">Paenibacillus graminis</organism><reference id="rid.5806"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Berge</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinebretière</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus graminis sp. nov. and Paenibacillus odorifer sp. nov., isolated from plant roots, soil and food.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>607</fpage><lpage>616</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01883-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus graminis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus graminis</i> (gra'mi.nis. L. gen. neut. n. <i>graminis</i> of grass)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile vegetative cells are rods, 0.5-1.0x3.0-4.0 μm (as determined by phase-contrast microscopy), and occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Cells produce oval spores, located terminally in swelling sporangia, and are Gram-positive (aminopeptidase assay).</s><s>Nutrient agar colonies are cream coloured, smooth with regular entire margins and measure 1.0-2.0 mm in diameter after 3 d at 30 °C on TSA medium.</s><s>Colonies are mucous on media containing 2% glucose or sucrose.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Maximum and minimum growth temperatures are 5-10 °C and 35-40 °C, respectively.</s><s>With API systems, acid is produced from glycerol, L-arabinose, D-xylose, methyl β-D-xyloside, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, methyl α-dglucoside, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentibiose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, D-arabinose, ribose, L-xylose, adonitol, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from inulin, D-fucose and gluconate.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetylene is reduced to ethylene by all strains and the <i>nifH</i> gene is present at least in the type strain.</s><s>Isolated from maize rhizosphere, wheat roots and soil.</s><s>G­C content of the type strain is 52.1 mol%.</s><s>Type strain is RSA19<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 19080<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-95<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>