<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12745_nm.22526" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22526" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22526" rank="species">Flindersiella endophytica</organism><reference id="rid.12745"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kaewkla</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franco</surname><given-names>C.M.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flindersiella endophytica gen. nov., sp. nov., an endophytic actinobacterium isolated from the root of Grey Box, an endemic eucalyptus tree</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2140</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026757-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20889769</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flindersiella endophytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flindersiella endophytica</em> (en.do.phy′ti.ca. Gr. <em>endo</em> within; Gr. <em>phyton</em> plant; L. fem. suff. -<em>ica</em> adjectival suffix used with the sense of belonging to; N.L. fem. adj. <em>endophytica</em> within plant, endophytic, pertaining to the original isolation from plant tissue).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid–alcohol-fast, catalase-positive actinobacterium.</s><s>Colony morphology ranges from smooth to rugose.</s><s>Colonies are white on ISP 4 and yellowish white on ISP 5, Bennett’s agar and NA.</s><s>They are greyish yellow on ISP 3 and ISP 7 and pale yellow on ISP 2.</s><s>Colonies are olive green on HPDA and change to a bluish purple colour after 30 days growth.</s><s>The type strain produces a greyish orange pigment on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Substrate mycelium develops well on most media, but aerial mycelium is rarely formed.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is branched with irregular thickness and fragments into short chains or aggregates.</s><s>Spores are tiny rods on short chains that develop from aerial mycelium.</s><s>White spores are produced on ISP 3, ISP 4, ISP 7 and HPDA.</s><s>Grows between 15 and 37 °C, between pH 5.0 and 10.0 and in the presence of up to 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth is achieved at a temperature of 27–37 °C, between pH 6 and 10 and in the presence of &#x003C;3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Acid production from carbon sources is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EUM 378<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 45355<sup>T</sup> = ACM 5289<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface-sterilized root tissue of a <em>Eucalyptus microcarpa</em> tree that grows on the campus of Flinders University, Adelaide, South Australia.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>