<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3132_nm.4044" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4044" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4044" rank="species">Clostridium thermosuccinogenes</organism><reference id="rid.3132"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Drent</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lahpor</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegant</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschal</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentation of Inulin by Clostridium thermosuccinogenes sp. nov., a Thermophilic Anaerobic Bacterium Isolated from Various Habitats.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>455</fpage><lpage>462</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16348411</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium thermosuccinogenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium thermosuccinogenes</i> (ther.mo'suc.ci.no'ge.nes. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; M.L. n. <i>acidum succinicum</i>, succinic acid; Gr. v. <i>gennaio</i>, produce; M.L. adj. <i>thermosuccinogenes</i>, succinic acid producing in heat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of the G+C content of strain IC (35.9 mol%) and the formation of succinic acid as a major fermentation product by all of the newly isolated thermophilic, inulin-hydrolyzing strains, we propose to create a new species within the genus <i>Clostridium</i>, namely <i>Clostridium thermosuccinogenes</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Cellular characteristics.</s><s>Straight rods 2 to 4 μm in length and 0.3 to 0.4 μm in width; peritrichously inserted flagella are present.</s><s>Surface layer consists of hexagonally arranged particles; terminal spores encountered frequently towards the end of the growth phase in batch culture; cells stained negative in Gram stain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Colony characteristics.</s><s>Small (1 to 2 mm in diameter), white, round colonies are formed within a few days of incubation in an anaerobic jar, on both nutrient broth and basal medium agar plates supplied with inulin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Physiological characteristics.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic growth was possible on a range of sugars.</s><s>These include fructose, glucose, galactose, inulin, xylose, ribose, sucrose, lactose, maltose, cellobiose, raffinose, and starch.</s><s>No growth was observed with methanol, glutamate, glycerol, pyruvate, citrate, arabinose, Casamino Acids, xylan, pectin, cellulose, or H<sub>2</sub>-CO<i>2</i> (80:20, vol/vol).</s><s>Some strains fermented galactose, mannitol, yeast extract, and sorbitol.</s><s>Formate, acetate, lactate, succinate, and H<sub>2</sub> were the fermentation products when inulin was used as the growth substrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the type strain, IC, is 35.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Habitats.</s><s>Apparently widespread, as the organism could be enriched from different sources, including fresh cow manure, beet pulp from a sugar refinery, soil around a Jerusalem artichoke, and mud from a tropical pond of a botanical garden.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain availability.</s><s>The type strain, IC, has been deposited as DSM 5807<sup>T</sup> in the DSM.</s><s>The other strains, IA, ID, and IE, have also been deposited in the DSM as DSM 5806 (strain IA), DSM 5808 (strain ID), and DSM 5809 (strain IE).</s></p></content></protolog>