<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4047_nm.1621" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1621" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1621" rank="species">Burkholderia ambifaria</organism><reference id="rid.4047"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahenthiralingam</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Henry</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>LiPuma</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laevens</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Speert</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia ambifaria sp. nov., a novel member of the Burkholderia cepacia complex including biocontrol and cystic fibrosis-related isolates.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1481</fpage><lpage>1490</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491349</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia ambifaria</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia ambifaria</i> (am.bi.fa'ria. M.L. adj. <i>ambifarius</i> that has two sides, of double meaning, ambiguous; referring to the fact that isolates of this species can be used for biological control purposes but also cause infections in humans)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, straight rods.</s><s>All strains grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Oxidase, β-galactosidase and lysine decarboxylase activities are present.</s><s>No ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophanase, arginine dihydrolase or urease activity.</s><s>Growth is observed at 30 and 37 °C.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, D-gluconate, caprate, adipate, L-malate, citrate and phenylacetate, but not maltose.</s><s>Positive for acidification of glucose, maltose, lactose, xylose and adonitol.</s><s>The G+­C content is 65.5-66.8 mol%.</s><s>The small relative amounts of fatty acids 16:0 and 17:0 cyclo and the large relative amounts of summed feature 3 and summed feature 7 present in all strains investigated are good characteristics for identification (see Table 3).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from the environment and from the respiratory tract of CF patients.</s><s>The finding that this new taxon includes both strains isolated from CF patients and potentially useful biocontrol strains supports the general consensus that the large-scale use of biocontrol strains belonging to this taxon is ill-advised until more is known about their potential pathogenic mechanisms.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 19182<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 44356<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the type strain are the same as those described above for the species.</s><s>In addition, the type strain is characterized by the presence of nitrate reduction, gelatinase activity, growth at 42 °C and acidification of sucrose and the absence of aesculin hydrolysis and pigment production.</s><s>Its G+­C content is 66.8 mol% and its 16S rDNA and recA gene sequences are available in GenBank under accession nos AF043302 and AF323985, respectively.</s><s>Strain LMG 19182T was isolated from the rhizosphere of pea plants in Wisconsin, USA, in 1985.</s><s>Strains LMG 19182<sup>T</sup>, LMG 6991, LMG 19465, LMG 19466, LMG 19467, LMG 11351, LMG 17828 and LMG 17829 have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection, Universiteit Gent, Ghent, Belgium.</s></p></content></protolog>