<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1197_nm.8223" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8223" rank="genus">Sphingobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.1197"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyoshi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium gen. nov., Sphingobacterium spiritivorum comb. nov., Sphingobacterium multivorum comb. nov., Sphingobacterium mizutae sp. nov., and Flavobacterium indologenes sp. nov.: glucose-nonfermenting Gram-negative rods in CDC groups IIK-2 and IIb.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>580</fpage><lpage>598</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sphingobacterium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sphingobacterium</i> (sphin.go.bac.te'rium. Gr. adj. <i>sphingos</i> of sphinx; Gr. neut. n. <i>bakterion</i> a small rod; N.L. neut. n. <i>Sphingobacterium</i> a sphingosine-containing bacterium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells of species in this genus are gram negative, nonsporeforming, straight rods that have no flagella but may exhibit sliding motility.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>These organisms are chemoorganotrophs without specialized growth factor requirements.</s><s>Colonies usually become yellowish after several days at room temperature.</s><s>Indole and acetylmethylcarbinol are not produced.</s><s>The cells are nonproteolytic, and gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from carbohydrates oxidatively but not fermentatively .</s><s>The major characteristics for generic differentiation of <i>Sphingobacterium</i> from <i>Cytophaga</i> and <i>Flavobacterium</i> are shown in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Sphingobacterium</i> cellular lipids contain sphingophospholipids whose ceramide moieties are chiefly branched-chain dihydrosaturated C<sub>17:0</sub> sphingosin, and the major acid is i-2-OH-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antisera against <i>F . meningosepticum</i> serogroups A through F do not agglutinate cells of strains of the <i>Sphingobacterium</i> species described here.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA nucleotide base ratios (G+C contents) of described species range from 39 to 42 mol%.</s><s>The type species if <i>Sphingobacterium</i> spiritivorum (Holmes, Owen, and Hollis) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>