<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12559_nm.21793" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21793" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21793" rank="species">Agrococcus carbonis</organism><reference id="rid.12559"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dhanjal</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaur</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korpole</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cameotra</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrococcus carbonis sp. nov., isolated from soil of a coal mine</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1253</fpage><lpage>1258</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024745-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601492</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agrococcus carbonis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agrococcus carbonis</em> (car.bo′nis. L. gen. n. <em>carbonis</em> of coal, of charcoal).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, coccoid (1.0–1.5 µm in diameter) and arranged in pairs, tetrads and clusters.</s><s>Strictly aerobic and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are circular, yellow and 0.4–3.0 mm in diameter on TSA medium.</s><s>Grows at 15–37 °C (optimum 30 °C) and pH 5–11 (optimum 7.5); no growth at 42 °C.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows in the presence of ≤7 % NaCl.</s><s>Negative for starch hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, citrate utilization, indole production, nitrate reduction and the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>Positive for utilization of the following substrates: dextrin, Tween 40, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, α-methyl d-galactoside, palatinose, d-psicose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sedoheptulose, sucrose, d-tagatose, turanose, d-xylose, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine and thymidine 5′-monophosphate.</s><s>Negative for utilization of α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, β-methyl d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, α-methyl d-glucoside, β-methyl d-glucoside, α-methyl d-mannoside, raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol, stachyose, trehalose, xylitol, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, pyruvic acid methyl esters, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Acid is produced aerobically from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, fructose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, xylose, sucrose and trehalose but not from dulcitol, galactose, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, rhamnose or salicin.</s><s>Presence of B-type peptidoglycan containing the amino acids alanine, glycine, threonine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid and the diagnostic diaminobutyric acid.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9, MK-10 and MK-11.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, two unknown glycolipids and six unknown lipids.</s><s>Cell wall sugars include galactose, glucose, ribose and rhamnose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 73.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, G4<sup>T</sup> ( = MTCC 10213<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 22965<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from a coal mine of West Bengal, India.</s></p></content></protolog>