<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6676_nm.9172" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9172" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.268" rank="species">Methanothrix thermophila</organism><reference id="rid.6676"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kamagata</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawasaki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oyaizu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikami</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Endo</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of three thermophilic strains of Methanothrix (Methanosaeta) thermophila sp. nov. and rejection of Methanothrix (Methanosaeta) thermoacetophila.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>463</fpage><lpage>468</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-3-463</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1380291</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> (ther. mo' phi. la. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; Gr. adj. <i>thermophila</i>, heat loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> is a thermophilic (optimum growth occurs at 55 to 60°C), rod-shaped, sheathed, strictly anaerobic, aceticlastic methanogen that belongs to the genus <i>Methanothrix</i> ("<i>Methanosaeta</i>"). <i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> is apparently distinct from <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> ("<i>Methanosaeta concilii</i>") because of its thermophily and 16s rRNA sequence.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile, strictly anaerobic rods with flat ends and are gram negative.</s><s>The mean dimensions of single cells are 0.8 to 1.3 by 2 to 6 μm.</s><s>Cells are enclosed inside an annular, striated sheathed structure and are separated by partitions that have a concentric structure.</s><s>Cells grow in the form of loose sediment, and culture broth exhibits opalescent turbidity after gentle shaking.</s><s>Most of the sheathed filaments are less than 100 μm long, and they do not form bundles or the cottonlike flocs which are common in <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i>.</s><s>Colonies are sometimes observed in acetate agar medium when high cell concentrations are present (11, 28).</s><s>Gas vesicles are often observed inside the cells.</s><s>Cells are not susceptible to lysis by SDS or hypotonic conditions at room temperature, but cells are lysed by SDS at 60°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The intensity of autofluorescence (405-nm excitation) is higher than that for <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> because of a higher content of coenzyme F<sub>420</sub> (11).</s><s>Coenzyme F<sub>420</sub> with four glutamyl residues on the side chain is more abundant than the other coenzyme F<sub>420</sub> types, although the total coenzyme F<sub>420</sub> contents are much lower than the contents in other hydrogenotrophic methanogens (11).</s><s>A tetraether type (dibiphytanediyl-diglycerol tetraether; caldarchaeol) of lipid is found in strain P<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth and methanogenesis is 55 to 60°C, depending on the strain (11, 17, 21, 28).</s><s>The optimum pH is around 7.</s><s>Acetate is the only substrate used for growth and methanogenesis (11, 17, 28).</s><s>Neither methanogenesis nor growth is observed when H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>, formate, methylamines, or methanol is used for the substrate (11, 17, 28).</s><s>Formate is not split into H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> (11,28).</s><s>NaCl is not required for growth (11).</s><s>Coenzyme M (mercaptoethane sulfonate), vitamins, manure extract, or sludge fluid stimulates growth (11, 17, 28).</s><s>Chloramphenicol (5 μg/ml), bacitracin (10 μg/ml), neomycin (10 μg/ml), tetracycline (100 μg/ml), and kanamycin (100 μg/ml) inhibit growth and methanogenesis (1 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 52.7 to 54.3 mol% guanine plus cytosine as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography (Table 1).</s><s>The 16s rRNA sequence is quite distinct from that of <i>Methanothrix soehngenii</i> (level of similarity, less than 95%).</s><s>The type strain of <i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> is strain P<sub>T</sub> (= DSM 6194). <i>Methanothrix thermophila</i> contains two genogroups.</s><s>Genogroup 1 consists of strains P<sub>T</sub><sup>T</sup> (=DSM 6194<sup>T</sup>) and 2-517 (=DSM 4774), and genogroup 2 contains strain CALS-1 (= DSM 3870).</s><s>The partial 16s rRNA sequences described above have been submitted to the National Institute of Genetics, Shizuoka, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>