<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2237_nm.2610" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2610" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2610" rank="species">Pseudomonas fuscovaginae</organism><reference id="rid.2237"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miyajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanii</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akita</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas fuscovaginae sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>656</fpage><lpage>657</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-656</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas fuscovaginae</i> (ex Tanii et al. 1976) nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas fuscovaginae</i> (fus. co. va. gi' nae, L. adj. <i>fuscus</i> fuscous; L. fem. n. <i>vagina</i> vagina, sheath; M. L. fem. n. <i>fuscovaginae</i> of a fuscous vagina)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming, rodshaped cells with round ends, 0.5 to 0.8 by 2.0 to 3.5 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs and are motile by means of one to four polar flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After 4 to 5 days at 28°C on nutrient agar moderate growth consisting of white to light brown, smooth, glistening, raised, translucent, circular, butyrous colonies 3 to 5 mm in diameter is produced.</s><s>A green fluorescent, diffusible pigment is produced on King's medium B.</s><s>No slime is produced on nutrient agar containing 5% sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolism of glucose is oxidative in Hugh-Leifson oxidation-fermentation medium.</s><s>Catalase and Kovacs oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Denitrification is negative; nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Lipolysis of margarine and Tween 80 is positive.</s><s>No growth occurs in nutrient broth supplemented with 5% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptonization and reduction of litmus milk without coagulation are positive.</s><s>Pits are not produced on polypectate gels at pH 8.5.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are hydrolyzed, but esculin and arbutin are not.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and ammonia are produced, but cytochrome oxidase, phenylalanine deaminase, urease, 2-ketogluconate, H<sub>2</sub>S, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Levan is not produced</s></p><p class="description"><s>from sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No organic growth factors are required.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, arabinose, rhamnose, and mannitol but not from maltose, sucrose, raffinose, inulin, salicin, dextrin, adonitol, erythritol, inositol, dulcitol, or α-methylglucoside.</s><s>Citrate, malonate, succinate, urate, acetate, β-alanine, L-valine, and L-lysine are utilized, but tartrate, hippurate, 2-ketogluconate, and polygalacturonic acid are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is approximately 28°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>Characteristics that vary among strains of <i>P. fuscovaginae</i> are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A hypersensitive reaction is produced when cells are inoculated into tobacco leaves, but potato soft rot is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity was demonstrated on <i>Oryza sativa</i>, <i>Hordeum vulgare</i>, <i>Triticum aestivum</i>, <i>Avena sativa</i>, <i>Zea mays</i>, <i>Lolium perenne</i>, <i>Bromus marginatus</i>, <i>Phleum pratense</i>, and <i>Phalaris arundinacea</i> but was not apparent on two species of the <i>Solanaceae</i>, six species of the <i>Leguminosae</i>, <i>Petroselinum crispum</i>, <i>Brassica oleracea</i>, <i>Lactuca sativa</i>, or <i>Citrus limon</i>.</s><s>On <i>O. sativa</i>, water-soaked dark green spots appear first; then these spots become brown to dark brown blotches on the flag leaf sheaths.</s><s>Infected young panicles show a brown to dark brown discoloration.</s><s>On the other eight species of the Gramineae tested, water-soaked lesions appear and then become greyish white or reddish brown spots on the leaves.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. fuscovaginae</i> is similar to other fluorescent pseudomonads that are positive for arginine dihydrolase and oxidase (1, 3, 4, 6).</s><s>Table 2 lists the characters which have diagnostic value for differentiating <i>P . fuscovaginae</i> from other species of this group.</s><s>Table 2 shows that <i>P. fuscovaginae</i> is most similar to the saprophytes <i>Pseudomonas putida</i> and <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> biotype G (6).</s><s>There are consistent differences between <i>P. fuscovaginae</i> and <i>P. putida</i> in six characters (gelatin liquefaction; utilization of trehalose, 2-ketogluconate, and hippurate; starch hydrolysis; and hypersensitive reaction). <i>P. fluorescens</i> biotype G also differs in six characters (utilization of arabinose, 2-ketogluconate, inositol, sorbitol, and adonitol; and hypersensitive reaction).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains were isolated from diseased leaf sheaths of <i>O. sativa</i> in Japan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species is 6801 (= NCPPB 3085 [National Collection of Plant Pathogenic Bacteria, Harpenden, England] = PDDCC 5940 [Plant Diseases Division Culture Collection, Auckland, New Zealand]).</s></p></content></protolog>