<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5274_nm.258" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.258" rank="genus">Methanomethylovorans</organism><reference id="rid.5274"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lomans</surname><given-names>B.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luderer</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Op den Camp</surname><given-names>H.J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pol</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van der Drift</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vogels</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Methanomethylovorans hollandica gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from freshwater sediment, a methylotrophic methanogen able to grow on dimethyl sulfide and methanethiol.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>65</volume><fpage>3641</fpage><lpage>3650</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10427061</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanomethylovorans</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanomethylovorans</i> (Me.tha.no.me.thy.lo'vo.rans. M. L. n. <i>methanum</i>, methane; M. L. n. <i>methylum</i>, methyl; L. adj. <i>vorans</i>, devouring; M. L. n. <i>Methanomethylovorans</i>, methane producing, methyl group consuming)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are irregular, nonmotile, coccoid (diameter, 1 to 1.5 μm), and gram negative.</s><s>Cells normally occur in clusters consisting of two to four cells which form large aggregates.</s><s>Cells are not sensitive to lysis by 1.0 g of SDS per liter.</s><s>Trimethylamine, dimethylamine, monomethylamine, methanol, DMS, and MT are catabolic substrates, but H<sup>2</sup>-CO<sup>2</sup> and acetate are not.</s><s>Growth is most rapid in the presence of 0 to 0.04 M NaCl, and no growth occurs at NaCl concentrations higher than 0.4 M.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at pH 6.5 to 7.0, and no growth occurs at pH values lower than 6.0 and higher than 8.0.</s><s>Growth is most rapid at 34 to 37°C, and very slow or no growth occurs at temperatures below 12°C and above 40°C.</s><s>Type strain DMS1 was isolated from a slurry prepared from a eutrophic pond sediment (Campus of Dekkerswald Institute, Nijmegen, The Netherlands).</s><s>Strain DMS1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the culture collection of the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen (Braunschweig, Germany).</s></p></content></protolog>