<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.737_nm.9434" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9434" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9434" rank="species">Naxibacter alkalitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.737"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Naxibacter alkalitolerans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family 'Oxalobacteraceae' isolated from China</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1149</fpage><lpage>1153</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63407-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879247</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Naxibacter alkalitolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Naxibacter alkalitolerans</em> (al.ka.li.to′le.rans. Arabic article <em>al</em> the; Arabic n. <em>qaliy</em> ashes of saltwort; French n. <em>alcali</em> alkali; N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>alkalitolerans</em> alkali-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics that define the genus, the species has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Colonies are 1·1–1·4 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, glistening, butyraceous, opaque and with pale white–yellow to straw-colour on nutrient agar plates.</s><s>Cells are 0·45–0·8 μm wide and 1·35–2 μm long.</s><s>Endospores are not observed.</s><s>Polyhydroxyalkanoates are not formed.</s><s>The isolate cannot grow in the presence of sodium chloride at 3 %.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–55 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 28–37 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6·5–12·0, with optimum growth occurring between pH 7·0 and 9·0.</s><s>Dextrin, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, ribose, salicin and xylitol are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but not adonitol, arabitol, galacturonate, inositol, oxalate, sorbitol or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Nitrate, l-threonine, l-valine, l-hydroxyproline, l-lysine, l-tryptophan, l-proline, l-tyrosine, phenylalanine, l-histidine and l-asparagine (weak) are used as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-methionine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-arginine or l-cysteine.</s><s>Urea, acetamide, xanthine, hypoxanthine, aesculin, keratin, chitin and DNA are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 20 and 80 are degraded, but not cellulose, starch, allantoin, glucosamine, amygdalin or adenine.</s><s>Tests for gelatin, melanin production and H<sub>2</sub>S production are positive; however, those for nitrate reduction, indole production, resistance to KCN, milk coagulation and peptonization are negative.</s><s>Tests for lipase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase are positive.</s><s>Tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are negative.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme, penicillin G, vancomycin, polymyxin B, tobramycin sulfate, gentamicin sulfate, netilmicin, oleandomycin and ciprofloxacin (weak), but sensitive to erythromycin, terramycin, aureomycin, tetracycline, streptomycin sulfate, amikacin, novobiocin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profiles are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (42·4 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (28·1 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (6·8 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (6·1 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (4·3 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4·2 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (3·4 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1·2 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0·5 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (0·4 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH (0·3 %) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (0·2 %).</s><s>The isoprenoid quinones are Q-8 (93·4 %) and Q-7 (6·6 %).</s><s>The phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA is 62·4±0·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 31775<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 204003<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 12194<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from soil in Lijiang, Yunnan Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>