<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10348_nm.16862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.16862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.16862" rank="species">Clostridium cavendishii</organism><reference id="rid.10348"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dupré</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moe</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium hydrogeniformans sp. nov. and Clostridium cavendishii sp. nov., hydrogen-producing bacteria from chlorinated solvent-contaminated groundwater</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>363</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013169-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19651721</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium cavendishii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium cavendishii</em> [ca.ven.di′shi.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>cavendishii</em> of Cavendish, named after Henry Cavendish (1731–1810), the British chemist who has been credited with the discovery of hydrogen].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining rods (0.4–1.0×2.2–10.0 μm) that form terminal spores.</s><s>Colonies grown on anaerobic CSBA are irregular with undulate to lobate margins, convex, creamy white and semi-opaque to translucent.</s><s>Aerotolerant anaerobe.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 15–46 °C, with optimum growth at 37–46 °C.</s><s>In PYG medium, grows in the presence of up to 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The pH range for growth at 25 °C is pH 6.0–8.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.9–8.0.</s><s>Ferments cellobiose, dextran, fructose (weak), glucose, maltose, salicin and trehalose but not adonitol, arabinose, cellulose, galactose, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not gelatin or starch.</s><s>Does not produce hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Positive for lecithinase but not catalase.</s><s>No reaction in milk.</s><s>In the Rapid ID 32A test system, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase (weak), <em>α</em>-glucosidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase activity, but negative results are observed for nitrate reduction, indole production, fermentation of mannose and raffinose, activity of alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase 6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and urease and activities of the following arylamidases: alanine, arginine, glutamyl glutamic acid, glycine, histidine, leucine, leucyl glycine, phenylalanine, proline, serine and tyrosine.</s><s>End products of fermentation in PYG medium include acetate, butyrate, pyruvate, hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</s><s>Dominant cellular fatty acids from cells growing exponentially in PYG medium at 30 °C are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> dimethyl aldehyde, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Produces hydrogen when grown in the presence of near-saturation concentrations of PCE (1.1 mM) and high concentrations of 1,2-dichloroethane (19.8 mM) and 1,1,2-trichloroethane (7.4 mM).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BL-28<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21758<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-51352<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from groundwater.</s><s>The DNA G+C content for the type strain is 28.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>