<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9578_nm.14761" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14761" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11383" rank="species">Piscinibacter aquaticus</organism><reference id="rid.9578"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbarg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frühling</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dissection of the genus Methylibium: reclassification of Methylibium fulvum as Rhizobacter fulvus comb. nov., Methylibium aquaticum as Piscinibacter aquaticus gen. nov., comb. nov. and Methylibium subsaxonicum as Rivibacter subsaxonicus gen. nov., comb. nov. and emended descriptions of the genera Rhizobacter and Methylibium</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2552</fpage><lpage>2560</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008383-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622640</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Piscinibacter aquaticus</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Piscinibacter aquaticus</em> (a.qua′ti.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>aquaticus</em> living, growing or found in or by the water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Methylibium aquaticum</em> Song and Cho 2007.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on that given for <em>Methylibium aquaticum</em> (Song &#x0026; Cho, 2007), supplemented with our own data.</s><s>In addition to characters that define the genus, it has the following characteristics.</s><s>Cells are short rods (0.8–1.9×0.4–0.7 μm).</s><s>After 4 days of incubation, colonies on R2A agar are circular, umbonate, beige–milkish and smooth with entire margins, 0.5–2.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Contains poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Using the API 20NE system, maltose assimilation is positive, gelatinase and urease activity and aesculin hydrolysis are weakly positive and indole production, d-glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and hydrolysis of adipic acid, gluconate, malic acid, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose and d-mannitol are negative.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase and leucine arylamidase activities are positive; esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are negative.</s><s>Of 47 different carbon sources included in a custom-made 48-well plate assay, the following are utilized: methanol, glycerol, d-ribose, d-galactose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, rhamnose, adonitol, d-xylitol, gluconic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-histidine, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>Methylamine, ethanol, dl-glyceraldehyde, d-arabinose, d-xylose, d-fructose, d-glucosamine, d-glucose, d-mannose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, arabitol, d-mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, citric acid, glucuronic acid, itaconic acid, pyruvic acid, succinic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-glycine, l-leucine, l-lysine and l-ornithine are not utilized.</s><s>Using Biolog GN microplates, utilizes dextrin, d-glucose, d-fructose, glycogen, dl-lactic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, l-proline, succinamic acid, methylpyruvate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid and <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid (see Table 1 for negative reactions).</s><s>Assimilation of methanol depends on the test system used.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid composition of the type strain is listed in Supplementary Table S1.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg) chloramphenicol (25), erythromycin (15), streptomycin (10), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), penicillin G (10) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>Resistant to (μg) ampicillin (10), rifampicin (50) and tetracycline (30).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1728<sup>T</sup> =KCCM 42364<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102349<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19915<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from an artificial freshwater pond located inside Inha University, Incheon, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>