<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4540_nm.2526" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2526" rank="genus">Chromohalobacter</organism><reference id="rid.4540"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Halomonas canadensis and Halomonas israelensis to the genus Chromohalobacter as Chromohalobacter canadensis comb. nov. and Chromohalobacter israelensis comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1443</fpage><lpage>1448</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491344</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus Chromohalobacter (Ventosa et al. 1989) Arahal et al.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight or sometimes slightly curved, motile rods that are 0.6-1.2x1.5-4.2 μm and occur singly, in pairs and in short chains. Non-sporeforming. Colonies are pigmented cream to brown-yellow. Moderate halophiles. Salt is required for growth. Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 8-10%(w/v) salt. May grow at salt concentrations up to 30%(w/v). The broader ranges of temperature and pH observed for growth are 5-45 °C and pH 5.0-10.0. Chemo-organotrophs. Aerobic. Catalase-positive. Most strains reduce nitrate, but H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced. Negative for urease and phenylalanine deaminase. Casein, DNA, aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed. Acid is produced from arabinose, glucose, glycerol, lactose and xylose. Habitat: the Dead Sea and marine salterns. The DNA base composition ranges from 62 to 65 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method. The type species is <i>Chromohalobacter marismortui</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>