<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12472_nm.21302" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21302" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21302" rank="species">Altererythrobacter namhicola</organism><reference id="rid.12472"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choe</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ka</surname><given-names>J.-O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Altererythrobacter namhicola sp. nov. and Altererythrobacter aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>709</fpage><lpage>715</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021196-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20418413</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Altererythrobacter namhicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Altererythrobacter namhicola</em> (nam.hi′co.la. N.L. n. <em>namhae</em> Namhae, the Korean name of the South Sea; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> from L. n. <em>incola</em> a dweller, inhabitant; N.L. masc. n. <em>namhicola</em> a dweller of the South Sea, referring to the isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-motile, ovoid rods, 1 µm wide and 1.4 µm long (Supplementary Fig. S2a).</s><s>Colonies on MA are orange-pigmented, circular, smooth and convex with entire margins, approximately 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 7 days at 30 °C (pH 7).</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C (optimum, 30 °C) and at pH 5–11 (optimum, pH 6–7).</s><s>Growth occurs in 1–2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Does not contain BChl <em>a</em> as a photosynthetic pigment.</s><s>Methanol-soluble pigment is characterized by an absorption maximum at 460 nm.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for acid production from d-glucose and maltose, production of indole and H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipate, arabinose, caprate, citrate, gluconate, glucose, malate, maltose, mannitol, mannose and phenylacetate.</s><s>Aesculin, starch, l-tyrosine and Tweens 20 and 80 are degraded, but casein, CM-cellulose, DNA, egg yolk, gelatin, urea and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, acid and alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities are present, but <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and α-mannosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In the GN2 microplate (Biolog), acetic acid, γ-aminobutyric acid, dl-carnitine, α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, glycyl l-glutamic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-alanine (weak), l-alaninamide (weak), l-alanyl glycine (weak), α-ketoglutaric acid (weak), phenylethylamine (weak), l-proline (weak), l-pyroglutamic acid (weak) and d-serine (weak) are utilized.</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized (Supplementary Table S1).</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (µg per disc, unless indicated) ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), penicillin (10 IU), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30), but resistant to amikacin (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300 IU) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>DPG, PE, SGL and unknown phospholipid PL3 are the major polar lipids (Supplementary Fig. S1).</s><s>The predominant whole-cell fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KYW48<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22736<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16345<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample collected from the South Sea, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>