<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5908_nm.9775" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5850" rank="species">Tetrasphaera duodecadis</organism><reference id="rid.5908"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Arthrobacter duodecadis Lochhead 1958 as Tetrasphaera duodecadis comb. nov. and emended description of the genus Tetrasphaera</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1369</fpage><lpage>1373</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02984-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738116</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tetrasphaera duodecadis</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tetrasphaera duodecadis</em> (du.o.de′ca.dis. L. n. <em>duodecas</em> -<em>adis</em> the number twelve; L. gen. n. <em>duodecadis</em> of twelve, referring to the requirement of the organism for vitamin B<sub>12</sub>).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Arthrobacter duodecadis</em> Lochhead 1958.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological and basic growth descriptions are taken from the original study by Lochhead (1958) and the description of peptidoglycan structure is based on data from Schleifer &#x0026; Kandler (1972).</s><s>Cells are Gram-variable and exhibit rod to coccus morphological change; rods vary in length from 1.5 to 4 μm and are 0.5–0.6 μm wide.</s><s>Many V- and T-shaped formations occur; coccoid cells are 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter.</s><s>Exhibits slow growth.</s><s>For regrowth from an L-drying ampoule on the medium of Lochhead (1958), visible colonies may not appear for a week or more.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> and thiamine are required for growth.</s><s>Grows well at 20–32 °C; growth occurs at 10 °C but not at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies on agar are circular, entire and convex, with a smooth surface, and cream-coloured to pale-brown and somewhat translucent, and may reach a diameter of 1.5 to 2 mm.</s><s>Aminopeptidase, oxidase, indole test, Voges–Proskauer test and production of H<sub>2</sub>S are negative, but catalase reaction, nitrate reduction and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are positive.</s><s>O/F test is positive.</s><s>Fructose, glucose, mannitol and sucrose are assimilated, but not xylose, mannose, arabinose, maltose or rhamnose.</s><s>Gelatin, acetoamide and aesculin are hydrolysed, but not urea or arginine.</s><s>Citrate and malonic acid are not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content is 73 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains alanine, glutamic acid, aspartic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>A large amount of 3-hydroxy <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid is present instead of <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Peptidoglycan structure is A4<em>γ</em>-type.</s><s>The acyl type of the cell wall is acetyl.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are 10-methyl-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>In addition, 10-methyl-C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (tuberculostearic acid) and 10-methyl-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IAM 14868<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 13347<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 9222<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 12959<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from soil.</s></p></content></protolog>