<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3435_nm.7655" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7655" rank="genus">Kineosporia</organism><reference id="rid.3435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsushima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of four new species of the genus Kineosporia: Kineosporia succinea sp. nov., Kineosporia rhizophila sp. nov., Kineosporia mikuniensis sp. nov. and Kineosporia rhamnosa sp. nov., isolated from plant samples, and amended description of the genus Kineosporia.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1245</fpage><lpage>1255</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1245</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828426</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Kineosporia</i> Pagani and Parenti 1978</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The amended description below is based on the previous amended description (Itoh et al., 1989) except for compositions of A,pm isomers and whole-cell sugars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive and non-acid-fast.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium lack aerial mycelia, form central projections with radiating vegetative hyphae, and are occasionally accompanied by bunches of spore clusters in the agar.</s><s>Mature colonies have a gelatinous matrix which confers a glossy appearance.</s><s>Spores, which are spherical to ovoid or pyriform with a long axis of 1-2 μm, are catenated around the central projection or are located singly or in aggregates at the tips of hyphae.</s><s>The spores are motile with polar tufts of flagella.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains almost equivalent LL- and <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>pm, or mainly LL- or <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>pm.</s><s>The spores contain predominantly <i>meso</i>-A<sub>2</sub>pm accompanied by glycine.</s><s>The whole-cultured organism contains galactose, glucose, mannose and ribose.</s><s>In addition to these sugars, rhamnose and 3-O-methylrhamnose may be present.</s><s>Phosphatidylcholine is a diagnostic phospholipid, and MK-9(II,III-H<sub>4</sub>) is present as a major component.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile is composed mainly of n-hexadecanoic acid and n-octadecenoic acid, and lacks iso- and anteisobranched fatty acids.</s><s>10-Methyl octadecanoic acid and 2-hydroxy hexadecanoic acids are also present in some strains.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA ranges from 69 to 7 1 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>K. aurantiaca</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>