<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3436_nm.3446" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3446" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3446" rank="species">Mannheimia glucosida</organism><reference id="rid.3436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Angen</surname><given-names>Ø.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caugant</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic relationships of the [Pasteurella] haemolytica complex as evaluated by DNA-DNA hybridizations and 16S rRNA sequencing with proposal of Mannheimia haemolytica gen. nov., comb. nov., Mannheimia granulomatis comb. nov., Mannheimia glucosida sp. nov., Mannheimia ruminalis sp. nov. and Mannheimia varigena sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>67</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-67</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028248</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mannheimia glucosida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mannheimia glucosida</i> (glu.co'si.da. Gr. adj. <i>glukus</i> sweet; L. adj.-forming suff. -<i>os</i> rich in; L. adj.-forming suff. -<i>id</i>(<i>us</i>), fem. -<i>ida</i>; M.L. adj. <i>glucosida</i> pertaining to glucosides, which are fermented by almost all biovars)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Corresponds to Frederiksen’s third taxon of [<i>P.</i>] <i>haemolytica</i> (Frederiksen, 1973), classified as [<i>P.</i>] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroups 3 and 5 by Bisgaard &#x0026; Mutters (1986) and reclassified as [<i>P.</i>] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroups 3A-3H by Angen <i>et al</i>. (1997a).</s><s>The species also includes NPG and <i>meso</i>-inositol-positive strains of [<i>P.</i>] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroup 9 (Bisgaard &#x0026; Mutters, 1986). <i>M. glucosida</i> is correspondingly listed as biovars A-I in Table 9.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile small rods.</s><s>Colonies are smooth and greyish on blood agar and are 1-2 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation.</s><s>All strains are haemolytic on bovine blood agar.</s><s>All strains ferment D-sorbitol, D-xylose, maltose and dextrin.</s><s>ONPG and NPG tests are positive for all biovars.</s><s>The biovars are separated by differences in ornithine decarboxylase, ONPX, ONPF and fermentation of L-arabinose and glucosides.</s><s>Further biochemical characteristics are listed in Table 9 and under the description of the genus <i>Mannheimia</i>.</s><s>Typable strains within <i>M. glucosida</i> all belong to serotype 11 (Angen <i>et al</i>., 1999).</s><s>All strains investigated have been isolated from sheep, although isolates of serotype 11 have been reported from cattle (Quirie et al., 1986).</s><s>This group of bacteria is normally not associated with disease conditions and probably represents part of the resident microflora in the upper respiratory tract (Biberstein &#x0026; Gills, 1962).</s><s>The type strain is P925<sup>T</sup> (numbering according to SSI Strain Collection = CCUG 38457<sup>T</sup>), originally received as B558 from Moredun Research Institute.</s><s>It was isolated from ovine lung in UK, and belongs to biovar B and serotype 11 (Angen <i>et al</i>., 1997a).</s><s>The G+ C content of the type strain is 41.v6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>