<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1200_nm.7807" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7807" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7807" rank="species">Spirochaeta isovalerica</organism><reference id="rid.1200"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Harwood</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta isovalerica sp. nov., a marine anaerobe that forms branched-chain fatty acids as fermentation products</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>573</fpage><lpage>579</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirochaeta isovalerica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirochaeta isovalerica</i> (i.so.val.er'ic.a. M.L. fem. adj. <i>isovalerica</i> of isovaleric acid, the major acid formed as a fermentation product from branched-chain amino aids)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are helical and 0.4 by 10 to 15 μm.</s><s>Shorter (6 μm) and longer (up to 50 μm) cells occur in cultures.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Two subterminally inserted periplasmic (axial) fibrils are present in a 1-2-1 arrangement.</s><s>The protoplasmic cylinder and periplasmic fibrils are enclosed in an outer sheath.</s><s>Gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Grows (final yield, 6x10<sup>8</sup> to 9x10<sup>8</sup> cells per ml) in medium containing yeast extract, Trypticase, peptone, a carbohydrate, and inorganic salts under anaerobic conditions (in an N<sub>2</sub> atmosphere).</s><s>No growth occurs aerobically.</s><s>Subsurface colonies in medium containing 0.8% agar (Difco) are spherical and white, resembling cotton balls in appearance.</s><s>Growth (final yield, 3x10<sup>8</sup> to 6x10<sup>8</sup> cells per ml) occurs in a chemically defined medium containing glucose, cysteine or sulfide, asparagine, vitamins, 0.3 M NaCl, 0.05 M MgSO<sub>4</sub>, 0.01 M KCl, 0.01 M CaCl<sub>2</sub>, and trace elements.</s><s>Exogenously supplied vitamins are not required for growth, but a mixture of vitamins stimulates growth.</s><s>Fails to grow when NaCl is omitted from the medium.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by MgSO<sub>4</sub> and CaCl<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Inorganic ammonium salts or amino acids serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Carbohydrates, but not amino acids, serve as carbon and energy sources for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major products of glucose fermentation are H<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, acetate, and ethanol.</s><s>Cells have the ability to generate adenosine 5'-triphosphate by catabolizing L-leucine, L-isoleucine, and L-valine to form isovalerate, 2-methylbutyrate, and isobutyrate, respectively, as end products.</s><s>Adenosine 5'-triphosphate formed in this way is utilized by cells to prolong survival during periods of growth substrate starvation.</s><s>Smaller amounts of isobutanol and isoamyl alcohol are also formed by cells from valine, isoleucine, and leucine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase negative; nitrate not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Optimum temperature range, 15 to 35°C.</s><s>Poor growth at 5 and 39°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 63.6 to 65.6 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s><s>Isolated from anoxic marine marsh mud.</s><s>The type strain is MA-2; this strain has been deposited with the German Collection of Microorganisms, Gottingen, Federal Repubic of Germany, under the number DSM 2461.</s></p></content></protolog>