<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5328_nm.10194" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10194" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10194" rank="species">Herminiimonas aquatilis</organism><reference id="rid.5328"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Herminiimonas aquatilis sp. nov., a new species from drinking water.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>291</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.12.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16436326</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>H. aquatilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>H. aquatilis</em> (a.qua.ti′lis, L. masc. adj. aquatilis, living, growing, or found, in or near water, aquatic).</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>H. aquatilis</em> forms short rod-shaped cells 0.8–1.2 μm in length and 1.0–1.2 μm in width.</s><s>Gram stain is negative.</s><s>The cells are motile.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are yellowish, 2–3 mm in diameter and mucoid.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is about 25 °C, Cytochrome oxidase positive.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>High amounts of the fatty acids (16:1 <em>ω</em>7c and 16:0) are present. 10:0 3-OH is present.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8, is the major respiratory quinone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the predominant compounds phosphatidyl ethanolamine, diphosphatidyl glycerol, moderate amounts of phosphatidyl glycerol, and small amounts of three unknown aminophospholipid and one unknown phospholipid.</s><s>Major polyamines are 2-hydroxyputrescine and putrescine; moderate amounts of cadaverine and spermidine are present as well.</s><s>Traces of diaminopropane, spermine, and homospermidine are also found.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sugars are not utilized, very few organic acids can serve as single carbon sources.</s><s>No acid production could be detected from the following sugars: glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl-d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol, and d-mannose.</s><s>Utilization of pyruvate and dl-lactate was positive.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicine, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>i</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, glycerol, d-mannitol, maltitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, dl-3 hydroxybutyrate, mesaconate, adipate, azelate, glutarate, itaconate, acetate, propionate, suberate, l-aspartate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-tryptophane, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, and phenylacetate.</s><s>Hydrolysis of l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide was positive.</s><s>The following compounds were not hydrolyzed: bis-pNP-phosphate, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside (pNPG), ONPG, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-pNA 2-deoxythymidine-5′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain CCUG 36956<sup>T</sup> has been deposited at the Culture Collection of the University Göteborg and in the Culture Collection of the Institut Pasteur, Paris, France as strain CIP 108933<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The EMBL data base accession number of the partial 16S rRNA gene for strain CCUG 36956<sup>T</sup> is <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=search&#x0026;db=nucleotide&#x0026;doptcmdl=genbank&#x0026;term=AM085762[accn]" target="externObjLink">AM085762</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>