<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6885_nm.7263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7263" rank="species">Streptomyces seoulensis</organism><reference id="rid.6885"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Youn</surname><given-names>H.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yim</surname><given-names>Y.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces seoulensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>492</fpage><lpage>498</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-492</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103639</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces seoulensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces seoulensis</i> (seo.ul.en’sis, M. L. masc. adj. seoulensis, indicating Seoul, Republic of Korea, the geographical origin of the species)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Streptomyces seoulensis</i> is an aerobic, gram-positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile actinomycete which forms a yellow substrate mycelium on glycerol- asparagine agar and a gray aerial mycelium and spores on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Verticils are not present.</s><s>Long-chain rectiflexible spores with smooth surfaces are produced.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced on ISP 5 medium.</s><s>Melanin is not produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar and tyrosine agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains LL-diaminopimelic acid, and no diagnostic sugars are present in the cell wall fraction (chemotype I).</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidyl glycerol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides are present in the polar lipid fraction (phospholipid type II).</s><s>The fatty acids are mainly saturated straight-chain as well as isoand anteiso-branched fatty acids (fatty acid type 2c).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Activity is not exhibited against <i>Aspergillus niger</i>, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>, <i>Candida albicans</i>, <i>Micrococcus luteus</i>, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i>, or <i>Streptomyces murinus</i>.</s><s>The strain grows in the presence of potassium tellurite, rifampin, and penicillin G but not at 45°C or in the presence of sodium chloride, sodium azide, thallous acetate, neomycin, or oleandomycin.</s><s>It utilizes L-histidine as a sole nitrogen source but not m-α-amino-nbutyric acid, L-cysteine, L-valine, L-phenylalanine, L-hydroxyproline, or potassium nitrate.</s><s>It uses D-fructose, lactose, mannitol, D-melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sodium pyruvate, sucrose, and D-xylose as sole sources of carbon but not adonitol, L-arabinose, dextran, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-melezitose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium propionate, or xylitol.</s><s>Tests for lecithinase, lipolysis, pectin hydrolysis, and H<sub>2</sub>S production are positive but not those for hippurate hydrolysis or nitrate reduction.</s><s>The organism degrades allantoin, arbutin, and elastin but not guanine, xanthine, or xylan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine ratio of the DNA is 68 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>Streptomyces seoulensis</i> IMSNU 21266<sup>T</sup></s></p></content></protolog>