<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7187_nm.5811" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5811" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5811" rank="species">Actinobaculum schaalii</organism><reference id="rid.7187"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Åkervall</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of some Actinomyces-like isolates from human clinical specimens: reclassification of Actinomyces suis (Soltys and Spratling) as Actinobaculum suis comb. nov. and description of Actinobaculum schaalii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>899</fpage><lpage>903</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-899</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226926</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinobaculum schaalii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinobaculum schaalii</i> (N. L. gen. n. <i>schaalii</i>, of Schaal, to honor Klaus P. Schaal, contemporary German microbiologist, for his contributions to actinomycete microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, some of which exhibit branching.</s><s>Cells are gram positive, not acid fast, and nonmotile and do not form spores.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>A weak CAMP reaction occurs.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase negative.</s><s>Acetate and succinate are the major end products of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, ribose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from L-arabinose, mannose, starch, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabitol, N-acetyl-β-glucosamine, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, rafiinose, sorbitol, and D-tagatose.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Esculin, gelatin, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>α-Glucosidase, alanine-phenylalanine-proline arylamidase, and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, and β-mannosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase and pyrrolidonylarylamidase activities are shown by some strains.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>The cell wall murein type is type A5a (L-Lys-Lys-D-Glu).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are hexadecanoic, octadecanoic, and cis-deltα-9-octadecenoic acids.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 57 mol% G+C.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from human blood and urine.</s><s>The habitat is unknown but is probably the genital or urinary tract.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Actinobaculum schaalii</i> is CCUG 27420.</s><s>The source of CCUG 27420<sup>T</sup> was human blood (chronic pyelonephritis, 64- year-old male).</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nucleotide sequence accession number.</s><s>The 16s rRNA gene sequence of strain CCUG 27420<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the GenBank database under accession number Y 12329.</s></p></content></protolog>