<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12619_nm.22148" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22148" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22148" rank="species">Flavobacterium banpakuense</organism><reference id="rid.12619"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanaya</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kanaya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium banpakuense sp. nov., isolated from leaf-and-branch compost</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1595</fpage><lpage>1600</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022467-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20693364</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium banpakuense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium banpakuense</em> [ban.pa.ku.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>banpakuense</em> of or belonging to banpaku, the short name of ‘Bankoku Hakurankai Koen’ (the Japanese name of EXPO Park), where the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative rods, 0.4–0.8 µm in diameter and 1.6–3.2 µm in length, motile by gliding, strictly aerobic, chemoheterotrophic, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on LB gellan gum are circular with entire margins, convex, smooth, slightly raised and yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed by colonies.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on LB gellan gum at 10–34 °C (optimum, 30 °C), at pH 6–8 (optimum, pH 7) and in the presence of 0–1.5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 1 %).</s><s>Weak growth occurs at 4 °C, but no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs in 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows on LB agar, NA, TSA and R2A agar at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar show irregular spreading shapes.</s><s>Skim milk, CM-cellulose and starch are degraded, but not agar, chitin, tributyrin or filter paper.</s><s>In the API 20NE strip: nitrate is reduced to nitrogen; indole is produced; glucose is not fermented; β-galactosidase activity is present; arginine dihydrolase and urease activities are absent; aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed; and glucose, arabinose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose are assimilated, but mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate are not.</s><s>In the API ZYM strip, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but esterase (C4), lipase (C14), α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Weak activities are observed for esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase and β-glucuronidase.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 15F3<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14225<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16466<sup>T</sup>), isolated from leaf-and-branch compost at EXPO Park, Osaka, Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 31.1 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>