<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.302_nm.7689" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7689" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7689" rank="species">Bifidobacterium denticolens</organism><reference id="rid.302"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Crociani</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alessandrini</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiarini</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium inopinatum sp. nov. and Bifidobacterium denticolens sp. nov., two new species isolated from human dental caries.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>564</fpage><lpage>571</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-564</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934909</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium denticolens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium denticolens</i> (den.ti.co' lens. L. masc. n. <i>dens</i>, <i>dentis</i>, tooth; L. v. <i>colere</i>, to dwell; L. pres. part. <i>colens</i>, dwelling; M.L. adj. <i>denticolens</i>, tooth dwelling)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, nonmotile, non-spore-forming, small, slender rods that occasionally are arranged in a V shape are 0.8 to 1.5 μm long.</s><s>Morphology is variable depending on the cultural conditions.</s><s>In the presence of lactose, the cells of arabinose-negative strains are very long (4 to 5 μm), sometimes branched, and have wide ends; the cells of arabinose-positive strains are smaller and coccoid (length, 0.4 to 0.6 μm).</s><s>At an initial pH of 7.7 or 8.0 the cells are very small (length, 0.4 to 0.6 μm); at an initial pH of 4.9 or 5.5 the cells are longer and branched or short (length, 0.8 to 2.5 μm) and frequently club shaped.</s><s>In liquid cultures incubated in air-CO<sub>2</sub> (1:10) at 37°C the cells are much longer rods with swollen ends; however, the cells become very long (length, 3 to 10 μm) and branched when cultures are incubated at 30°C, whereas the cells are unbranched and flexuous with protuberances if they are grown at 42°C.</s><s>Liquid cultures of this species always have clear supernatants with compact sediment in clumps that cannot be dispersed with vigorous swirling.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on TPY agar are soft, smooth, circular, convex with irregular margins, glistening, and cream to white.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>CO<sub>2</sub> enhances anaerobic growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 36.5 to 38.5°C, the minimum temperature is 27.0 to 30.5°C, and the maximum temperature is 42 to 44°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25 or 46°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum initial pH is 6.7 to 7.3, growth is delayed at pH 4.9 or 8.0, and no growth occurs at pH 4.4 or 8.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>D-Ribose, galactose, glucose, fructose, lactose, cellobiose, sucrose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, dextrin, starch, amylose, amylopectin, inulin, and salicin are fermented.</s><s>D-Xylose, D-glucuronate, L-rhamnose, mannose, α-D-galacturonate, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-galactosamine, melezitose, gluconate, lactate, xylan, polygalacturonate, alginate, arabinogalactan, pectin, laminarin, D-mannitol, D-glucitol, glycerol, hyaluronate, heparin, chondroitin sulfate, ovomucoid, bovine submaxillary mucin, porcine gastric mucin, gum arabic, gum ghatti, gum guar, gum locust bean, gum karaya, and gum tragacanth are not fermented.</s><s>Fermentation of L-arabinose, D-glucosamine, and trehalose is variable.</s><s>Dextran is fermented by 75% of the strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces acetylmethylcarbinol and hydrolyzes asparagine.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole, hydrogen sulfide, and catalase or pseudocatalase (hemin) production negative.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied; ammonia is not produced from urea or arginine.</s><s>Litmus milk is always acidified and coagulated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation products from glucose are L-(+)-lactic acid and acetic acid at a molar ratio of 1:2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA of this species is not related to the DNA of <i>B. inopinatum</i> or the DNA of any other species of the genus <i>Bifidobacterium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 55±1 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in human dental caries.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain B3028 (= DSM 1010.5).</s></p></content></protolog>