<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1557_nm.11664" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11664" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8076" rank="species">Flavobacterium branchiophila</organism><reference id="rid.1557"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wakabayashi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huh</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kimura</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium branchiophila sp. nov., a causative agent of bacterial gill disease of freshwater fishes.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>213</fpage><lpage>216</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-213</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium branchiophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium branchiophila</i> (bran.chi.o'phi.la. Gr. <i>branchia</i>, gill; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i>, loving; M.L. adj. <i>branchiophila</i>, gill loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain BGD-7721; this strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strain ATCC 35035.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, nonsporeforming, rod-shaped cells approximately 0.5 by 5 to 8 μm with parallel sides and rounded ends.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intracellular granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Does not glide or spread.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on CA are light yellow, smooth, round, raised, entire, and 0.5 to 1 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days at 18°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in CB are uniformly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic; metabolism is oxidative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 25°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0 to 0.075% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin, casein, and starch are degraded, but esculin, chitin, agar, and cellulose are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, melibiose, raffinose, and inulin, but not from galactose, lactose, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, adonitol, mannitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, inositol, or salicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzymes are produced (determined by using API ZYM galleries): alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase-lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, and phosphoamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzymes are not produced (determined by using API ZYM galleries): lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), trypsin, chymotrypsin, a-galactosidase , β-galactosidase , β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-6-glucosominidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 29 to 31 mol%; for the type strain, the G+C content is 30 mol% (as determined by thermal denaturation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain was isolated in 1977 from a diseased fingerling Yamame (<i>Oncorhynchus masou</i>) from a fish hatchery in Gumma Prefecture, Japan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>One additional strain of <i>Flavobucterium branchiophila</i>, strain BV-1, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 35036</s></p></content></protolog>