<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7773" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7773" rank="genus">Chlamydophila</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Chlamydophila</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chlamydophila</i> (Chla.my.do'phil .a. Gr . fem. n. <i>chlamys</i>, <i>chlamydis</i> a cloak; L. fem. n. <i>phila</i> dear, beloved; M.L. fem. n. <i>Chlamydophila</i> dear to the cloak)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Chlamydophila</i> is one of two genera in the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> and is composed of the current species <i>Chlamydia pecorum</i>, <i>Chlamydia pneumoniae</i> and <i>Chlamydia psittaci</i>.</s><s>These taxa, therefore, are renamed <i>Chlamydophila pecorum</i>, <i>Chlamydophila pneumoniae</i> and <i>Chlamydophila psittaci</i>.</s><s>The complete 16s rRNA and 23s rRNA genes of <i>Chlamydophila</i> species are ≥95 % identical. <i>Chlamydophila</i> species are readily identified and distinguished from other species by ribosomal signature sequences (Figs 3 and 4), or by inspection of the ribosomal intergenic spacer (Everett &#x0026; Andersen, 1997).</s><s>Any of several other genes may also be used to identify <i>Chlamydophila</i> species on the basis of DNA homology.</s><s>The <i>Chlamydophila</i> genome is approximately 1.2 Mbp. <i>Chlamydophila</i> species do not produce detectable quantities of glycogen.</s><s>The <i>Chlamydophila</i> genome is slightly larger than the <i>Chlamydia</i> genome and contains a single ribosomal operon (Fig. 5) (Fukushi &#x0026; Hirai, 1993; Scieux et al., 1992). <i>Chlamydophila</i> strains have varying morphology and varying resistance to sulfadiazine.</s><s>Extrachromosomal plasmid is present in many <i>Chlamydophila</i> species (Table 4).</s><s>The type species for the genus <i>Chlamydophila</i> is <i>Chlamydophila psittaci</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>