<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.457_nm.2992" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2992" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2992" rank="species">Vibrio orientalis</organism><reference id="rid.457"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yeh</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beaman</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of marine luminous bacteria isolated off the coast of China and description of Vibrio orientalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>95</fpage><lpage>100</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio orientalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio orientalis</i> (L. adj. <i>orientalis</i>, of or belonging to the Orient)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The phenotypic properties of strains 715-719 (Table 1) as well as those of strains representative of all of the species of <i>Vibrio</i> and <i>Photobacterium</i> listed by Baumann et al. [7] were submitted to a numerical analysis.</s><s>The results (not shown) indicated that these isolates were distinct and differed from the species of these two genera by 9-32 phenotypic properties.</s><s>Four additional species of <i>Vibrio</i> have recently been described [13,16,17,20].</s><s>Although characterized by a different and somewhat more limited methodology than the one used in our studies, the results, nevertheless, clearly indicate that the species are phenotypically distinct from <i>V. orientalis</i>.</s><s>An electron microscopic examination of strain 717, grown on liquid or solid medium, revealed the presence of a single, sheathed polar flagellum (Fig. 2).</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNA of strain 715, 717, and 719 were 45.8, 45.4, and 45.3 moles %, respectively.</s><s>All of these results indicate that the cluster consisting of strains 715-719 was a new species of <i>Vibrio</i>, which we have designated as <i>V. orientalis</i> sp. nov.</s><s>Strain 717 has been designated as the type strain and deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 33934.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>V. orientalis</i> is the only described luminous species of Vibrio that is able to accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product and to utilize DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, putrescine, and spermine as sole or principal sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>Additional diagnostic traits are the presence of an amylase, an arginine dihydrolase system, growth at 4 °C but not at 40 °C and the ability to utilize sucrose and cellobiose but not glucuronate, α-ketoglutarate, and γ-aminobutyrate as sole or principal sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>This combination of properties distinguishes <i>V. orientalis</i> from species of <i>Vibrio</i> and <i>Photobacterium</i> by 6-I0 traits.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Using the antiserum to the SOD from <i>V. alginolyticus</i> 90, <i>V. splendidus</i> biotype II 2, <i>V. fischeri</i> 61, and <i>V. cholerae</i> M13 [1], we have determined the ImDs of strains 715, 716, and 717.</s><s>The combined results for all three strains (expressed as the mean ± standard deviation) are 6.4 ± 0.1, 23.5 ± 0.2, 26.0 ± 0.8, and 59 ± 0.4 ImD units, respectively.</s><s>A three-dimensional representation of the results, which includes only those species and strains of <i>Vibrio</i> with an SOD similar to the enzyme from <i>V. orientalis</i>, is presented in Fig. 3. (This figure is a portion of the larger Fig. 3 in reference [1], which includes many additional strains of <i>Vibrio</i>.) On the basis of its SOD, <i>V. orientalis</i> is related to the relatively large group of primarily marine species of <i>Vibrio</i>, which includes such common species as <i>V. harveyi</i>, <i>V. alginolyticus</i>, and <i>V. parahaemolyticus</i>.</s><s>Its nearest neighbor is strain 77; both <i>V. orientalis</i> and strain 77 have an arginine dihydrolase system.</s></p></content></protolog>