<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11909_nm.19996" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19996" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19996" rank="species">Marinobacterium lutimaris</organism><reference id="rid.11909"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeo</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacterium lutimaris sp. nov., isolated from a tidal-flat of the Yellow Sea</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1828</fpage><lpage>1831</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016246-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19767363</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacterium lutimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacterium lutimaris</em> (L. n. <em>lutum</em> mud; L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>lutimaris</em> of sea mud).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, motile rods, 0.6–0.8 μm wide and 1.2–1.4 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on MA are creamy white, convex and round with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and at pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum, pH 6.5–7.5).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase activities but negative for lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>- glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannose and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzyme activities are observed for esterase (C4), <em>β</em>-glucosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase (API ZYM).</s><s>Positive for Biolog GN2 MicroPlate system substrates glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine and putrescine.</s><s>Other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 microplates are not utilized.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Resistant to carbenicillin, but sensitive to penicillin G, polymyxin B, streptomycin, gentamicin, tetracycline, neomycin, kanamycin, ampicillin, lincomycin, chloramphenicol and oleandomycin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58.0 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AN9<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 13703<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22012<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat of the Taean coast in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>