<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5806_nm.5149" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5149" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5149" rank="species">Paenibacillus odorifer</organism><reference id="rid.5806"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Berge</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinebretière</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Achouak</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus graminis sp. nov. and Paenibacillus odorifer sp. nov., isolated from plant roots, soil and food.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>607</fpage><lpage>616</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01883-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paenibacillus odorifer</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paenibacillus odorifer</i> (o.do'ri.fer. L. n. <i>odor</i> smell; L. suff. n. -<i>fer</i> carrier ; L. n. <i>odorifer</i> carrier of smell)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile vegetative cells are rods, 0.5-1.0x2.0-4.0 μm (as determined by phase-contrast microscopy) and occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Cells produce oval spores, located terminally in swelling sporangia, and are Gram-positive (aminopeptidase assay).</s><s>Nutrient agar colonies are cream coloured, smooth with regular entire margins and measure 1.5-3.0 mm in diameter after 3 d at 30 °C on TSA medium.</s><s>Colonies are not mucous on media containing 2% glucose or sucrose.</s><s>Catalase is produced, but not oxidase.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Maximum and minimum growth temperatures are 5 and 35 °C, respectively.</s><s>With API systems, acid is produced from L-arabinose, ribose, D-xylose, methyl β-D-xyloside, galactose, glucose, fructose, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentibiose and D-turanose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, D-arabinose, L-xylose, adonitol, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, melezitose, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from glycerol, mannose and L-fucose.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acetylene is weakly reduced to ethylene by all strains and the <i>nifH</i> gene is present at least in the type strain.</s><s>A typical fruity volatile aroma is produced on nutrient media.</s><s>Isolated from wheat roots and pasteurized and chilled leek and courgette pure!es.</s><s>G­C content of the type strain is 44.0 mol%.</s><s>Type strain is TOD45<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 19079<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-93<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>