<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2203_nm.3153" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3153" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3153" rank="species">Enterobacter asburiae</organism><reference id="rid.2203"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McWhorter</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kai</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farmer</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter asburiae sp. nov., a new species found in clinical specimens, and reassignment of Erwinia dissolvens and Erwinia nimipressuralis to the genus Enterobacter as Enterobacter dissolvens comb. nov. and Enterobacter nimipressuralis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>1114</fpage><lpage>1120</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3711302</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. (as.ber'ry.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>asburiae</i>) is named in honor of Mary Alyce Fife-Asbury, an American bacteriologist who made many important contributions to the classification of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>, particularly in describing new <i>Klebsiella</i> and <i>Salmonella</i> serotypes (9, 10, 16), new genera, and new species (3, 11-13, 18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. are gram-negative, oxidasenegative, nonmotile, fermentative, nonpigmented rods with the general characteristics of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Enterobacter</i> (Table 5).</s><s>They gave positive reactions in tests for methyl red, citrate utilization (Simmons and Christensen's), urea hydrolysis (may be delayed; see footnote to Table 5), L-ornithine decarboxylase (Moeller's), growth in KCN, hydrolysis of esculin, reduction of nitrate to nitrite, O-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, acid and gas from the fermentation of D-glucose, and fermentation of L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-galactose, glycerol (delayed), lactose (may be delayed), D-mannitol, D-mannose, a-methyl-glucoside, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>They gave negative reactions in tests for indole production, in the Voges-Proskauer test (see footnote to Table 5), in tests for H<sub>2</sub>S production, phenylalanine deaminase, L-lysine decarboxylase (Moeller's), gelatin hydrolysis, malonate utilization, lipase (corn oil), DNase, tyrosine clearing, and fermentation of adonitol, D-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, i(<i>myo</i>)-inositol, melibiose, and L-rhamnose.</s><s>Variable reactions were obtained in tests for L-arginine dihydrolase (Moeller's), acid from mucate, L-tartrate fermentation (Jordan's), acetate utilization, and fermentation of raffinose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A number of biogroups were identified among <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. strains.</s><s>Strains in these biogroups gave one or more of the following atypical test reactions: negative for urea hydrolysis, ornithine, growth in KCN, gas from glucose, fermentation of L-arabinose, D-mannitol, alphamethyl-glucoside, raffinose, and D-xylose, and positive in the Voges-Proskauer test, tests for motility, and tests for utilization of malonate and fermentation of melibiose and L-rhamnose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Several <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. strains were received at the CDC as suspected <i>Yersinia</i> or <i>Citrobacter</i> species.</s><s>Tests that differentiate <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. from species in these genera are shown in Table 6.</s><s>Its positive methyl red test and negative Voges-Proskauer test and tests for motility, utilization of malonate, and fermentation of melibiose and L-rhamnose serve to differentiate <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. from all named Enterobacter species (Table 5).</s><s>Tests of differential value in separating <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. from species of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> are described elsewhere (14, 15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. strains were susceptible to gentamicin and sulfadiazine and resistant to ampicillin, cephalothin, and penicillin.</s><s>Variable susceptibility was seen to the other antimicrobial agents tested (Table 3).</s><s>The sources of <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. strains and accompanying clinical information are given in Table 1.</s><s>The strains came from 24 states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and Canada.</s><s>Where the sex of the patient was identified, 27 of 50 isolates were from males.</s><s>Where age was given, 24% of strains were isolated from people aged 0 to 2 years, 26% of strains were isolated from people aged 16 to 44 years, and 50% of strains were isolated from people aged 59 to 90 years.</s><s>Sixteen of the strains were from urine, 15 were from respiratory sources, 12 were from stools, 11 were from wounds or exudates, 7 were from blood, and 1 each was from the endometrium, gall bladder, lochia, penis, peritoneal fluid, synovial fluid, and environment. <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. is widely distributed geographically in the United States and is frequently encountered, at least with respect to the more recently described species of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (14, 15).</s><s>Its presence in seven blood cultures (mentioned above) at least suggests clinical significance.</s><s>When isolated from other sources, however, its clinical significance is uncertain and requires further study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Enterobacter asburiae</i> sp. nov. is 1497-78 (=ATCC 35953).</s><s>It was isolated from a lochia exudate from a 22-year-old woman in R.I.</s><s>Its biochemical characteristics are those of the species as shown in Table 3.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 55 ± 1.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>