<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9261_nm.14539" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14539" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14539" rank="species">Microbacterium invictum</organism><reference id="rid.9261"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faria</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium invictum sp. nov., isolated from homemade compost</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2036</fpage><lpage>2041</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005561-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567581</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium invictum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium invictum</em> (in.vic′tum. L. neut. adj. <em>invictum</em> invincible, powerful, that survives composting, also an ancient and popular designation attributed to Oporto city).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On PCA, colonies are white after 2 days of incubation and yellow after 5 days.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive motile short rods (0.74±0.07 μm long and 0.54±0.08 μm wide) and do not form spores.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, pH 6.0–9.5 and with up to 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Citrate is not used and H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Anaerobic growth is observed in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, aesculin, starch (weakly) and ϵ-poly-caprolactone (weakly).</s><s>Oxidizes (API 20E) and assimilates l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose and d-sorbitol; additionally, assimilates <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, maltose, d-mannose, turanose, xylitol (weakly) and d-xylose, but not phenyl acetate, d-adonitol, adipate, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, caprate, citrate, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, d-galactose, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, d-lyxose, malate, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, l-xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside or methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside.</s><s>Glucose fermentation is weak and slow.</s><s>Acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose and salicin, with weak reactions observed for d-galactose, d-sorbitol and d-xylose, but not from d-adonitol, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate or 2- and 5-ketogluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, l-xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside or methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl <em>β</em>-glucosamidase, but not arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of (μg l<sup>−1</sup>) sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25), meropenem (10) and ceftazidime (30).</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the type B1 alpha, with lysine as the diamino acid, and muramic acid residues are glycolylated.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-11 and MK-12, in similar proportions.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.1±0.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DC-200<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19600<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24557<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from homemade compost.</s></p></content></protolog>