<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4819_nm.3384" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3384" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3384" rank="species">Pasteurella granulomatis</organism><reference id="rid.4819"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ribeiro</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carter</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frederiksen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riet-Correa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pasteurella haemolytica-like bacterium from a progressive granuloma of cattle in Brazil.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>1401</fpage><lpage>1402</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2754010</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella granulomatis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella granulomatis</i> (gran.u.lo'matis. L. dim. n. <i>granulum</i>, a small grain; Gr. suff. -<i>oma</i>, a swelling or tumor; M.L. n. <i>granuloma</i>, a granuloma; M.L. n. <i>granulomatis</i>, of a granuloma)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Three strains of the <i>P. haemolytica</i>-like organism which has been given the name "<i>Pasteurella granulomatis</i>" were isolated from three cattle with typical cases of lechiguana after culture of tissue obtained by deep biopsy of the tumors.</s><s>Fourteen isolates were obtained but only three were retained for further study.</s><s>Efforts at reproducing the disease with the <i>P. granulomatis</i> isolates were successful and will be described separately.</s><s>The purpose of this report is to describe the characteristics of three strains of <i>P. granulomatis</i> and to present evidence that they constitute a new taxon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All three strains, 26, 115, and 294, appeared as small coccobacilli or short rods after culture on 5% bovine blood agar or Trypticase soy agar for 24 h.</s><s>They were indistinguishable in shape from strains of <i>Pasteurella multocida</i> and <i>P. haemolytica</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the three strains, only strain 115 had capsules when organisms from colonies on blood agar were stained by Maneval stain (4).</s><s>None of the strains was motile.</s><s>Although all strains grew on Trypticase soy agar, growth was better on blood agar.</s><s>After 24 h on blood agar at 37°C, colonies were round, grayish, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Their appearance resembled that of colonies of <i>P. haemolytica</i> and nonmucoid <i>P. multocida</i>.</s><s>After initial isolation, all grew equally well in air or with reduced oxygen partial pressure (10% CO<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Although the three strains grew anaerobically on blood agar, colonies were smaller.</s><s>After incubation for 24 h in broth, the three strains settled to the bottom of the tube, producing a sediment.</s><s>All strains grew on MacConkey agar (no. 2; GIBCO Laboratories).</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains caused hemolysis on bovine blood agar of the kind seen with <i>P. haemolytica</i>; however, beta-hemolysis was obtained with the three cultures on sheep blood agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three strains were examined serologically by counter-immunoelectrophoresis (M.</s><s>M.</s><s>Chengappa, College of Veterinary Medicine, Kansas State University, Manhattan) and slide agglutination (G.</s><s>F.</s><s>Frank, National Animal Disease Center, Ames, Iowa) to determine if they were known serotypes of <i>P. haemolytica</i>.</s><s>Results indicated that they were not serotypes of this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Some of the important biochemical characteristics of the three strains are listed below.</s><s>The nitrophenyl test was used for the glucosidases, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside (ONPG), 4-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucopyranosiduronic acid (PGUA), and <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-xylopyranoside (PNPX) (3), and the amino acid decarboxylase tests were performed as described previously (3).</s><s>Other biochemical tests were performed in three different laboratories by using standard procedures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive reactions were obtained for oxidase, catalase (weak), NO<sub>3</sub> reduction, β-glucuronidase (PGUA), and Igalactosidase (ONPG).</s><s>Acid but no gas was obtained from glucose, galactose, sucrose, lactose (7 days), maltose (7 days), cellobiose (7 days), sorbitol, mannitol (7 days), salicin, and esculin.</s><s>No acid or gas was obtained from arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, mannose, trehalose, melibiose, adonitol, dulcitol, and inositol.</s><s>Negative reactions were obtained for indole, NO<sub>2</sub> reduction, urease, H<sub>2</sub>S (triple sugar iron), gelatinase, β-xylosidase (PNPX), phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, arginine decarboxylase and dihydrolase, and ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Some important characteristics which differentiate <i>P. granulomatis</i> from closely related varieties and species are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>From the characteristics described, the three strains studied o not conform to the <i>P. haemolytica</i> biotypes described previously (1-3).</s><s>Although they resemble "<i>P. haemolytica</i> 3rd type" (3), they differ from this variety in being xylose negative and β-glucuronidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three strains of <i>P. granulomatis</i> have been deposited in the collection of W.</s><s>Frederiksen at the State Serum Institute, Copenhagen, Denmark, and in the American Type Culture Collection.</s><s>The type strain is strain 26.</s></p></content></protolog>