<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12647_nm.22187" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22187" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22187" rank="species">Zhihengliuella aestuarii</organism><reference id="rid.12647"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baik</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choe</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zhihengliuella aestuarii sp. nov., isolated from tidal flat sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1671</fpage><lpage>1676</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026245-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20729314</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Zhihengliuella aestuarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Zhihengliuella aestuarii</em> (aes.tu.a′ri.i. L. gen. n. <em>aestuarii</em> of a tidal flat, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, ovoids to short rods, approximately 0.7–0.9×0.8–1.1 µm after 3 days at 30 °C on TSA.</s><s>No rod–coccus life cycle.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA plates for 3 days at 30 °C are yellow, circular, opaque and convex with entire margins, approximately 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA at 4–37 °C; optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–10; optimum pH 8–9.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–7 % (w/v) NaCl; no growth in the presence of 8 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed, but CM-cellulose, DNA, egg yolk, Tweens 20 and 80, starch, l-tyrosine and xylan are not.</s><s>In the API 20NE system (bioMérieux), gives positive results for assimilation of d-glucose and maltose and negative results for nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis (β-glucosidase), arginine dihydrolase, β-galactosidase, gelatin hydrolysis, urease and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, l-arabinose, capric acid, malic acid, d-mannitol, d-mannose, phenylacetic acid, potassium gluconate and trisodium citrate.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, α-glucosidase and leucine arylamidase activities are present and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin activities are weakly positive; <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase and valine arylamidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (positive with the Biolog GP2 system): l-alanine, l-asparagine, dextrin, d-fructose, α-d-glucose, l-glutamic acid, l-malic acid, d-mannose, d-ribose (weak), l-pyroglutamic acid (weak), l-serine and d-sorbitol (weak).</s><s>The remaining substrates of the Biolog GN2 system are not utilized.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): ampicillin (10), penicillin (10 IU) and vancomycin (30) but resistant to amikacin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), polymyxin B (300 IU), streptomycin (10) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Peptidoglycan type is A4α, l-Lys←l-Ala←d-Glu.</s><s>The glycan moiety of the peptidoglycan contains acetyl residues.</s><s>Major cell-wall sugars are tyvelose and glucose; a minor amount of galactose is also detected.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is MK-10; a minor amount of MK-9 is also detected.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, an unknown aminophospholipid and three unknown aminolipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DY66<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 19557<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16364<sup>T</sup>), isolated from tidal flat sediment collected from Deukryang Bay, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>