<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7342_nm.3392" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3392" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3392" rank="species">Pasteurella testudinis</organism><reference id="rid.7342"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Snipes</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biberstein</surname><given-names>E.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pasteurella testudinis sp. nov.: a parasite of desert tortoises (Gopherus agassizi).</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>210</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-2-201</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella testudinis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella testudinis</i> (tes.tu.di.nis. L.noun <i>testudo</i> tortoise; L. gen. noun <i>testudinis</i> of the tortoise)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell characteristics: gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, pleomorphic rods, 0.2 by 1.5 to 2.0 μm; the majority of the strains appear to possess capsule-like surface layers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on sheep blood agar are white, mucoid, and approximately 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter after 24 to 48 h of incubation at 37 or 20°C; colonies on sheep blood agar regularly produce a beta-hemolytic zone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Atmospheric requirements: facultatively anaerobic; extra CO<sub>2</sub> not required for growth in air.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactivity: chemoorganotrophic; the various carbohydrates fermented are listed in Tables 3 and 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation end products from glucose: acetic, propionic, lactic, and succinic acids are produced; gas is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content of DNA: 46.7 ± 0.2 mol% (CsCl gradient separation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serology: possibility of serovars, as evidenced by the close serological relatedness of 5 of 13 strains in direct tube agglutination tests.</s><s>The similarity among these five strains appears to be a result of related somatic antigens.</s><s>Heat-extractable surface antigens are suggested by agglutination and IHA reactions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sources: so far, isolated from pneumonic lesions, abscesses, and gastrointestinal tracts of California desert tortoises.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pathogenicity: associated with multifocal bronchopneumonia in California desert tortoises.</s><s>The disease is not highly contagious under experimental conditions, and the bacterium appears to be commensal in healthy free-ranging tortoises.</s><s>Some strains are pathogenic for mice when inoculated intraperitoneally or intranasally.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: 90-23-79n (= ATCC 33688).</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>