<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6165_nm.10289" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10289" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10289" rank="species">Burkholderia oklahomensis</organism><reference id="rid.6165"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Glass</surname><given-names>M.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jordan</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilkins</surname><given-names>P.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gee</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia oklahomensis sp. nov., a Burkholderia pseudomallei-like species formerly known as the Oklahoma strain of Pseudomonas pseudomallei.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2171</fpage><lpage>2176</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63991-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957116</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia oklahomensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia oklahomensis</em> (ok.la.hom.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>oklahomensis</em> pertaining to Oklahoma, of Oklahoma).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the results of studies of four isolates.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, bipolar-staining rods.</s><s>The cells are aerobic and motile and grow well at 25 and 37 °C, but slowly at 42 °C.</s><s>Colonies on 5 % sheep blood agar are irregular, white, smooth and show a diffuse lysis of red cells extending out from heavy growth with no action by individual colonies.</s><s>They may become wrinkled or mucoid after 72 h incubation.</s><s>Cells grow well on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Cells are oxidase-, catalase-, arginine decarboxylase (dihydrolase)- and nitrate reduction-positive.</s><s>Cells grow in nutrient broth with 0 % NaCl.</s><s>The three Oklahoma strains (C6786<sup>T</sup>, C7532 and C7533) produce variable results for gas from nitrate.</s><s>Both production of gas and of little to no gas have been observed (McCormick <em>et al.</em>, 1977; Yabuuchi <em>et al.</em>, 1992a).</s><s>The Georgia strain (E0147) is negative for production of gas from nitrate.</s><s>Tests for indole, urease, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and hydrogen sulfide are negative.</s><s>Cells show oxidative metabolism and, on triple-sugar iron agar, produce an acid reaction on the slant and no change in the butt of the medium.</s><s>All strains are positive for assimilation of glucose, d-xylose, mannitol, lactose, sucrose and maltose.</s><s>All are negative on minimal salts agar with 10 % arabinose (Wuthiekanun <em>et al.</em>, 1995).</s><s>Purple, wrinkled colonies are seen on Ashdown's agar after 1 week incubation at 37 °C (Ashdown, 1979).</s><s>Differential tests are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the four strains of <em>Burkholderia oklahomensis</em> and comparison with similar <em>Burkholderia</em> species</s></p><p class="description"><s>v, Results are variable from strain to strain; (v), results vary within strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>First isolated from human wound infection in Oklahoma, USA.</s><s>Type strain is C6786<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23618<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13387<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 51349<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>