<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8552_nm.13537" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13537" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13537" rank="species">Prevotella amnii</organism><reference id="rid.8552"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella amnii sp. nov., isolated from human amniotic fluid.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>92</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65118-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175689</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella amnii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella amnii</em> (am′ni.i. Gr. n. <em>amnion</em>, inner membrane surrounding the fetus; N.L. gen. n. <em>amnii</em>, of the amnion, pertaining to the amniotic fluid from which the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of Gram-negative rods that are anaerobic, non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Typical cells are 0.8–3.0×0.5–1.5 μm.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar plates after 48 h of incubation at 37 °C under anaerobic conditions are white, smooth, glistening with an entire edge and less then 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are still viable after 6 h when left in air.</s><s>Using the API Rapid ID32AN test system, positive reactions are produced with <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, phospho-6-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, glutamyl-glutamic acid arylamidase and leucyl glycine arylamidase.</s><s>Using the API ZYM test kit, positive reactions are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, <em>N</em>-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but gelatin is not.</s><s>Glucose, lactose and maltose are fermented, but cellobiose, fructose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose are not.</s><s>The major end products of glucose metabolism are acetic and succinic acids.</s><s>The major long-chain cellular fatty acids consist of iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-3OH-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CCUG 53648<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14753<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human amniotic fluid.</s></p></content></protolog>