<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12748_nm.22529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22529" rank="species">Dietzia alimentaria</organism><reference id="rid.12748"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>K.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dietzia alimentaria sp. nov., isolated from a traditional Korean food</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2254</fpage><lpage>2258</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021501-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20952550</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dietzia alimentaria</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dietzia alimentaria</em> (a.li.men.ta′ri.a. L. fem. adj. <em>alimentaria</em> pertaining to food).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are opaque, smooth, circular, convex, entire and shiny in appearance, with a coral-red pigment and approximately 1–2 mm in diameter after 5 days on marine agar at 30 °C.</s><s>Cells are rods (1–1.5 µm wide), Gram-reaction-positive, non-motile, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7–10 (optimum pH 7.0), with 0–10 % NaCl (optimum 2 % NaCl) and at 15–37 °C (optimum 30 °C).</s><s>No growth at 45 °C.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 but negative for hydrolysis of casein and starch.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for esterase (C4), alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β- and α-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase; acid phosphatase reaction is weak.</s><s>With API 20NE, positive for reduction of nitrates to nitrogen, fermentation of d-glucose and assimilation of adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate and weakly positive for assimilation of d-mannose; negative for production of indole, assimilation of potassium gluconate, urease and β-galactosidase activity (4-nitrophenyl β<em>-</em>d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis) and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>With API 50 CH, assimilates methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, starch and glycogen, assimilates d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate weakly, but does not assimilate glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, d-adonitol, d-galactose, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, cellobiose, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates show the main cell-wall components to be <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside, an unknown phospholipid, six unknown glycolipids, an unknown aminolipid and an unknown lipid.</s><s>The major isoprenoid menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 72<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16360<sup>T</sup>  = KACC 21126<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a traditional salt-fermented seafood made of clam jeotgal from Sokcho, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>