<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11783_nm.19890" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19890" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19890" rank="species">Luteimonas terricola</organism><reference id="rid.11783"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xin</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Luteimonas terricola sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1581</fpage><lpage>1584</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015537-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684321</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Luteimonas terricola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Luteimonas terricola</em> (ter.ri′co.la. L. n. <em>terra</em> earth, soil; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>terricola</em> a dweller upon earth, soil-dweller, referring to the isolation of the type strain from soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped (0.6–0.8×1.8–2.2 μm in R2A medium).</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are light yellow, round, convex, opaque and smooth with entire margins, approx. 1–1.5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs in R2A medium at 1–25 °C, with the highest cell yields at 10–15 °C and the fastest growth at 25 °C; growth on R2A agar at 1 °C is very weak.</s><s>Growth on R2A agar occurs at pH 7–8 and with 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces catalase and cytochrome oxidase but not indole, H<sub>2</sub>S or urease.</s><s>Reduces nitrate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse aesculin or gelatin.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, weakly positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, trypsin and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, but negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase, ornithine dihydrolase, tryptophan deaminase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Does not utilize l-arabinose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, citrate, adipic acid, capric acid, malic acid or phenylacetic acid as carbon sources.</s><s>Does not ferment glucose or other carbon sources in the API 50CH B/E system.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin and penicillin G, but sensitive to chloramphenicol, kanamycin, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline (all at 30 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Ubiquinone-8 is the major ubiquinone.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>11 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is BZ92r<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22344<sup>T</sup> =CGMCC 1.8985<sup>T</sup>), isolated from hydrocarbon-contaminated soil in Bozen, South Tyrol, Italy.</s></p></content></protolog>