<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7161_nm.6511" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6511" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6511" rank="species">Tsukamurella tyrosinosolvens</organism><reference id="rid.7161"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brzezinka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmitt</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seifert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zimmermann</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mauch</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gierth</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lux</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schaal</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella tyrosinosolvens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>607</fpage><lpage>614</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-607</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226890</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella tyrosinosolvens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella tyrosinosolvens</i> (ty. ro. si. no. sol' vens. Gr. masc. n. <i>tyros</i>, cheese; <i>tyrosine</i>, an amino acid; L. pres. part. <i>sohens</i>, dissolving; M. L. adj. <i>tyrosinosolvens</i>, tyrosine dissolving, referring to the hydrolysis of tyrosine which is characteristic of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, gram-positive, and slightly acid-alcohol-fast bacilli.</s><s>Most cells are long rods that, at a late stage of growth, fragment into three parts which then separate and grow as independent rods.</s><s>The cells do not form spores, capsules, or aerial hyphae.</s><s>Visible growth from dilute inocula occurs within 2 days; colonies on BHI agar are yellowish, dry, and rough.</s><s>Growth occurs at 24, 31, and 37°C but not at 45°C.</s><s>The organism contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid as the wall diamino acid in addition to galactose and arabinose in whole-cell hydrolysates (i.e., the cell wall chemotype is chemotype IV).</s><s>It has a type α, α' mycolate pattern and a type PII phospholipid pattern with significant amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Menaquinone MK-9 is the major menaquinone, and minor amounts of menaquinones MK-8 and MK-10 are also present.</s><s>Melanoid pigments are not produced on either ISP medium 6 or ISP medium 7.</s><s>Produces acetamidase, allantoinase, catalase, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, urease, and phosphatase but not arylsulfatase (after 3 days), benzamidase, nitrate reductase, and succinamidase.</s><s>Grows on MacConkey agar without crystal violet and tolerates 5% NaCl and <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoic acid.</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>D-Glucose, galactose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, D-melezitose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, acetate, benzoate, citrate, gluconate, adipate, isoamyl alcohol, 2,3-butandiol, 1,2-propandiol, and paraffin are utilized as sole carbon sources, but L-arabinose, D-xylose, Lrhamnose, lactose, raffinose, cellobiose, adonitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, lactate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, and <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate are not utilized.</s><s>Acetamide, L-alanine, and proline are utilized as nitrogen and carbon sources, but gelatin and serine are not utilized.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, tyrosine, xanthine, urea, esculin, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed, but adenine, casein, gelatin, elastin, guanine, keratin, and testosterone are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-galactose, maltose, trehalose, sucrose, mmnose, D-melezitose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, and fructose, but not from L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, lactose, raffinose, cellobiose, adonitol, and inulin.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin, isoniazid, ethambutol, ripampin, <i>p</i>-aminosalicylic acid, protionamide, capreomycin, and cycloserine.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 73.6 ± 0.03 mol%, and the G+C contents of the species range from 69 to 74 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain IMMIB D-1397 (= DSM 44234).</s></p></content></protolog>