<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5984_nm.10119" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10119" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10119" rank="species">Cloacibacterium normanense</organism><reference id="rid.5984"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cloacibacterium normanense gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel bacterium in the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from municipal wastewater</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1311</fpage><lpage>1316</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64218-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738108</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cloacibacterium normanense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cloacibacterium normanense</em> (nor.man.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>normanense</em> pertaining to the city of Norman, OK, USA, where the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following features in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>In broth cultures, cells are long (up to 27 μm); cells from agar plate cultures are much shorter (5–9 μm).</s><s>After 48 h, colonies grown on tryptic soy agar are 1.0–1.5 mm in diameter, round, entire and very waxy.</s><s>Growth occurs between 18 and 36 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 4 °C or at 40 °C or above.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>All strains grow at pH 7 and 8; some strains also grow at pH 6 and 9.</s><s>The pH optimum for all strains is 7.</s><s>Indole-positive.</s><s>Starch, aesculin, gelatin and casein are hydrolysed and DNA is hydrolysed weakly.</s><s>Urea, chitin, pectin, alginate, uric acid, xanthine and hypoxanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Methyl red- and Voges–Proskauer-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Cellulose and agar are not degraded.</s><s>Most isolates tested are resistant to erythromycin (15 μg) and kanamycin (30 μg).</s><s>All isolates tested are sensitive to carbenicillin (100 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), sulfathiazole (0.25 mg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>With the API kits, acid is produced with <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin and mannose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from alanine, ribose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, hippurate, glycogen, melibiose, melezitose, sucrose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, tagatose or raffinose.</s><s>Enzyme activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase (weak reaction), arginine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, esterase C-4 (weak reaction), ester lipase C8, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, maltose, phenylalanine arylamidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Enzyme activity is not detected for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, lipase C14 or trypsin.</s><s>Fatty acids iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (8–9 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (40–46 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> (7–10 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5–9 %) predominate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 31 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NRS1<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46293<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108613<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-825<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15886<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from untreated human wastewater.</s><s>Additional strains of the species, strains NRS30 (=CCUG 48043) and NRS32 (=CCUG 48044), were also isolated from wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>