<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2228_nm.9467" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9467" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9467" rank="species">Chryseobacterium taichungense</organism><reference id="rid.2228"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium taichungense sp. nov., isolated from contaminated soil</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1301</fpage><lpage>1304</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63514-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15879271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium taichungense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium taichungense</em> (tai.chung′en.se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>taichungense</em> pertaining to Taichung, a province in Taiwan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (approx. 2 μm in length).</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-positive, shows good growth after 48 h on nutrient agar, brain heart infusion agar and trypticase soy agar at 11–36 °C, but unable to grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges, becoming mucoid and unidentifiable as single entities after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The yellow pigmentation is non-diffusible and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Unable to grow at 4 and 45 °C.</s><s>Positive for gelatinase activity.</s><s>Grows well over a broad range of pH values (6·0–9·0) but grows better in neutral or weakly alkaline conditions (pH 7·0–8·0).</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 15 : 0 iso and 17 : 0 iso 3OH.</s><s>Positive reactions observed for alkaline phosphatase, butyrate esterase, carprylate esterase, myristate lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-Bl-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>No enzymic activities found for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weakly positive for indole production, cytochrome oxidase activity and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG test), but negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Strain CC-TWGS1-8<sup>T</sup> shows weak production of acid from adonitol, d-glucose, i-inositol, d-maltose, l-rhamnose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-trehalose, acetate, propionate, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-fructose, d-mannitol, maltitol, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, i-inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis(<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl) phosphate, bis(<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl) phenylphosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenylphosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine 2′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide are hydrolysed.</s><s><em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide is not hydrolysed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-TWGS1-8<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50001<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108519<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from tar-contaminated soil in Taichung, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>