<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.579_nm.4879" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4879" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4879" rank="species">Bacillus bataviensis</organism><reference id="rid.579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanparys</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Felske</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus novalis sp. nov., Bacillus vireti sp. nov., Bacillus soli sp. nov., Bacillus bataviensis sp. nov. and Bacillus drentensis sp. nov., from the Drentse A grasslands.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02723-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus bataviensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus bataviensis</em> (ba.ta.vi.en′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>bataviensis</em> pertaining to <em>Batavia</em>, the name Julius Caesar gave to The Netherlands).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive or variable (at 24 h), facultatively anaerobic, motile, slightly tapered rods (0·7–1·2 μm in diameter) occurring singly, in pairs and in short chains.</s><s>Endospores are mainly ellipsoidal but may be spherical, and lie centrally, paracentrally and occasionally subterminally, in slightly swollen sporangia (Fig. 3d).</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA are butyrous, cream-coloured and produce a light-brown pigment that diffuses into the agar; they are slightly raised and umbonate, have regular margins and have smooth or rough, eggshell-textured surfaces.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 30 °C and the maximum growth temperature lies between 50 and 55 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 4·0 and 6·0, the optimum pH is 7·0–8·0 and the maximum pH lies between 9·5 and 10·0.</s><s>Casein is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, ONPG hydrolysis is positive, gelatin is hydrolysed by most strains and nitrate reduction is positive; the Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative and reactions for arginine dihydrolase (one strain positive), lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and indole production are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive in the API 50CH gallery.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50CH gallery, using CHB suspension medium: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, galactose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol (weak), lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, raffinose, ribose (weak), salicin (weak), d-trehalose and d-turanose.</s><s>The following reactions are variable between strains and, when positive, are usually weak: amygdalin, arbutin, l-fucose, inulin, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, starch and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, gluconate, glycogen, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, <em>meso-</em>inositol, methyl d-xyloside, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, xylitol, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, respectively present at about 37 and 21 %, while C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> accounts for about 11 % of the total fatty acids.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present to at least 1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>10<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>For the strains tested (Table 4), the G+C content is 39·6–40·1 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil (Drentse A agricultural research area, The Netherlands).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the variable reactions, the type strain, LMG 21833<sup>T</sup> (=R-16315<sup>T</sup>=IDA1115<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15601<sup>T</sup>), was positive but weak for arbutin, l-fucose, inulin, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside and sucrose and negative for amygdalin and starch.</s><s>The G+C content for the type strain is 40·1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>