<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1517_nm.2533" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2533" rank="genus">Deleya</organism><reference id="rid.1517"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowditch</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Deleya gen. nov. created to accomodate the marine species Alcaligenes aestus, A. pacificus, A. cupidus, A. venustus, and Pseudomonas marina.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>793</fpage><lpage>802</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-793</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Deleya</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Deleya</i> (De.ley'a. M. L. fem. n. <i>Deleya</i> named for Jozef De Ley, a Belgian microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods 0.8 to 1.1 μm wide and 1.5 to 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product.</s><s>Involution forms are usually present in old cultures or under adverse conditions of cultivation.</s><s>Do not form endospores or microcysts.</s><s>Most species are motile by 4 to 12 peritrichous flagella; one species is motile by 2 to 5 polar flagella.</s><s>Strict aerobes; molecular oxygen is a universal electron acceptor.</s><s>Do not denitrify or fix molecular nitrogen.</s><s>All species are chemoorganotrophs that are able to grow on a mineral medium containing a seawater base, D-glucose, and NH<sub>4</sub>Cl.</s><s>Na<sup>+</sup> is an absolute requirement for all species; the minimal concentration necessary for optimal growth ranges from 75 to 200 mM.</s><s>All species utilize D-glucose, acetate, succinate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, lactate, glycerol, and L-α-alanine.</s><s>All species grow at 35°C.</s><s>No species has an extracellular lipase, gelatinase, or chitinase.</s><s>No species is able to utilize H<sub>2</sub> as the sole source of energy and CO<sub>2</sub> as the sole source of carbon.</s><s>All species lack an arginine dihydrolase system.</s><s>Found in marine habitats.</s><s>The G+C contents of the DNAs range from 52 to 68 mol%, as determined by buoyant density.</s><s>The type species is <i>Deleya aesta</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Further descriptive information.</s><s>Light and electron micrographs showing the general cell morphology and flagellation of representative strains of species of <i>Deleya</i> have been published previously (4, 6).</s><s>There may be difficulty in determining the type of flagellar arrangement in <i>Deleya</i> marina since this species has multitrichous flagella which tend to bend backward toward the cell, giving arrangements which may be interpreted as lateral or peritrichous flagellation.</s><s>References 4 and 6 should be consulted for a discussion of this problem.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The appearance of the colonies of species of <i>Deleya</i> is not distinctive.</s><s>All are cream colored and convex with entire edges.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Species of <i>Deleya</i> are able to utilize 47 to 85 different organic compounds as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>These include pentoses, hexoses, disaccharides, sugar acids, sugar alcohols, fatty acids, dicarboxylic acids, tricarboxylic acid cycle intermediates, amines, and a number of simple aromatic compounds (see above; Table 1).</s><s>Aromatic compounds are utilized via the β-ketoadipate pathway, which involves the <i>o</i> cleavage of diphenolic compounds (4, 21).</s><s>D-Glucose and D-fructose are utilized via the Entner-Doudoroff pathway (1,17).</s><s>In the case of the latter sugar, the initial reactions appear to involve the conversion of D-fructose to fructose 1- phosphate via a D-fructose:phosphotransferase system, 1-phosphofructokinase, and a pyrophosphate-dependent 6-phosphofructokinase (17).</s></p></content></protolog>