<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1885_nm.10928" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10928" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10928" rank="species">Parabacteroides johnsonii</organism><reference id="rid.1885"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kitahara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parabacteroides johnsonii sp. nov., isolated from human faeces.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>293</fpage><lpage>296</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64588-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267966</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parabacteroides johnsonii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parabacteroides johnsonii</em> (john.so′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>johnsonii</em> of Johnson, named after the American molecular taxonomist John L. Johnson, who was the first to describe <em>P. merdae</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods (0.8×1.7–2.5 μm).</s><s>On EG agar plates, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey to off-white in colour, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth.</s><s>Indole and urease are not produced.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is not digested.</s><s>Grows on medium containing 20 % bile.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose but not from d-cellobiose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, salicin or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Positive Rapid ID 32A reactions are obtained for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s><s>Mannose and raffinose are fermented.</s><s>All of the other tests (for urease, arginine dihydrolase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, proline arylamidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase) are negative.</s><s>The major end products from PYG broth cultures (1 % peptone, 1 % yeast extract, 1 % glucose) are succinic and acetic acids; small amounts of isovaleric acid and propionic acid are also produced.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-15 : 0 and iso-17 : 0 3-OH.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinones are menaquinones MK-9 and MK-10.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, M-165<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13406<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18315<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s></p></content></protolog>