<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12449_nm.21276" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21276" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21276" rank="species">Halomarina oriensis</organism><reference id="rid.12449"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Inoue</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohkuma</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kogure</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomarina oriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from a seawater aquarium</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>942</fpage><lpage>946</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.020677-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495022</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomarina oriensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomarina oriensis</em> [o.ri.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>oriensis</em> pertaining to ORI, an arbitrary adjective formed from the acronym for the Ocean Research Institute (University of Tokyo), where the organism was originally isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.6–2.0 µm in size.</s><s>Colonies are about 0.5 mm in diameter after 15 days of incubation at 37 °C on 1.5 % agar plates containing 2.7 M (16 %) NaCl; they are circular, entire, smooth, convex and pink.</s><s>Cells are irregular cocci or discs, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1.7–5.0 M NaCl (optimum, 2.6 M), in 0.01–1.0 M Mg<sup>2+</sup> (optimum, 0.2–0.5 M), at pH 7.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0–8.0) and at 20–42 °C (optimum, 37 °C).</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Gelatin and Tween 40 are hydrolysed, whereas starch and casein are not.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur in the presence of nitrate, arginine, DMSO or TMAO.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from elemental sulfur.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: glucose, mannose, galactose, fructose, d-ribose, d-xylose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, starch, glycerol, pyruvate and l-aspartate.</s><s>No growth occurs on mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, dl-lactate, succinate, l-malate, fumarate, citrate, glycine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-glutamate or l-lysine.</s><s>Acid is produced when grown on utilizable carbohydrates.</s><s>The polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> and C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>25</sub> diether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, a glycolipid chromatographically identical to the glycosyl-mannosyl-glucosyl diether (TGD-2) and at least one unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>Resistant to novobiocin, erythromycin, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol and neomycin.</s><s>Sensitive to bacitracin, anisomycin, aphidicolin and rifampicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KeC-11<sup>T</sup> ( = JCM 16495<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 4074<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a seawater aquarium located at the Ocean Research Institute, University of Tokyo, Japan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>