<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1792_nm.964" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.964" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.964" rank="species">Rickettsia japonica</organism><reference id="rid.1792"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Uchida</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchiyama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kumano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia japonica sp. nov., the etiological agent of spotted fever group rickettsiosis in Japan.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>303</fpage><lpage>305</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-2-303</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1581190</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia japonica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia japonica</i> (ja. po' ni. ca. N.L. adj. <i>japonica</i>, pertaining to Japan, the country in which the organism was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In smears from cell cultures, the intracellular organisms are visualized by Gimenez staining or by indirect immunofluorescence with immune sera (20).</s><s>Gram-negative rods that are 0.4 to 0.5 by 0.8 to 1.5 μm.</s><s>The organisms possess an outer slime layer and a trilaminar cell wall with thin outer and thick inner leaflets (24).</s><s>Obligate intracellular parasite.</s><s>The organisms carry species-specific epitopes on the surface (25).</s><s>The organisms also possess an SFG-common antigen that is detectable by monoclonal antibody 3Y8-B3 (to <i>R. japonica</i> YHT) that reacts with all of the strains of SFG rickettsiae tested but not with <i>Rickettsia typhi</i> Wilmington (= ATCC VR144).</s><s>Polyclonal antibodies produced in mice against <i>R. japonica</i> react with <i>R. typhi</i> only at low titers.</s><s>On the other hand, sera from some patients infected with <i>R. japonica</i> react with <i>R. typhi</i> at high dilutions (22).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth of <i>R. japonica</i> occurs in Vero cells without cytopathic effects, and a carrier state that persists for 20 subcultures of infected cells develops.</s><s>Carrier Vero cells divide until a monolayer is formed after subculturing in minimal essential medium containing 10% fetal calf serum and no antibiotics in a 5% CO<sup>2</sup>-air incubator at 34°C.</s><s>After cocultivation with uninfected Vero cells, all cells enter the carrier state.</s><s>The organisms in carrier cells are viable after storage at -80°C or in liquid nitrogen when the carrier cells are stored in minimal essential medium containing 5% dimethyl sulfoxide, 20% fetal calf serum, and no antibiotics. <i>R. japonica</i> differs from other SFG rickettsiae with respect to growth in Vero cells; the strains which we tested have been described previously (23). <i>Rickettsia australis</i> Cutlack, <i>Rickettsia conorii</i> Malish 7, <i>Rickettsia rickettsii</i> R (= ATCC VR891), and Thai tick typhus rickettsia TT-118 produce cytopathic effects 3 to 6 days after inoculation.</s><s>Although <i>Rickettsia akari</i> Kaplan (= ATCC VR148) and <i>Rickettsia sibirica</i> 232 cause few cytopathic effects, the infected cells do not grow continuously after subculturing.</s><s>The growth properties are the same in Vero C1008 (= ATCC CRL1586) cells.</s><s>Chicken embryo fibroblast primary culture, BHK 21/13, and L929 cells allow <i>R. japonica</i> to grow with cytopathic effects.</s><s>Replication in Vero and BHK 21/13 cells occurs primarily in the cytoplasm and rarely in nuclei.</s><s>Figure 1 shows ultrathin sections of heavily infected Vero C1008 cells, which were examined with a Hitachi model HU-12 electron microscope as described previously (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The plaque morphology produced by <i>R. japonica</i> is different from that produced by most other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>Infected Vero cells centrifuged at 250 x g for 5 min were diluted in sucrose-phosphate-glutamate buffer (1) and plated onto Vero cell monolayers and then overlaid with Leibovitz medium L-15 containing 0.5% methylcellulose and 5% fetal calf serum.</s><s>At intervals during incubation at 34°C in an air incubator, the monolayers were simultaneously fixed and stained with a 10% formalin solution containing 0.5% crystal violet and washed with water to identify plaques (infectious centers).</s><s>After 9 to 11 days of incubation, <i>R. japonica</i> formed plaques with a targetlike appearance (a dye-stained inner spot surrounded by a clear zone).</s><s>The diameter of the targetlike plaques increased to 2.0 mm on day 13.</s><s>Other SFG rickettsiae produced clear plaques on day 6; <i>R. rickettsii</i> produced plaques with diameters of 1.6 and 2.0 mm on days 8 and 11, respectively, while other rickettsiae formed smaller plaques. <i>R. akari</i> produced very tiny plaques.</s><s>When monolayers were overlaid with 0.8% agarose and stained with neutral red as described previously (2), no plaques were formed by <i>R. japonica</i> even after 13 days, while clear plaques with a diameter of 2.5 mm were produced by <i>R. rickettsii</i> after 8 days of incubation.</s><s>A plaque type variant isolated from a guinea pig after inoculation with <i>R. japonica</i> (see below) formed a clear plaque.</s><s>About 0.01 to 0.001% of the carrier cells with strain YHT produced clear plaques on Vero cell monolayers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms are pathogenic for guinea pigs.</s><s>Specific-pathogen-free male guinea pigs (strain Hartley, 13 weeks old) were obtained from the SLC Farm, Shizuoka, Japan, and were inoculated intraperitoneally with 10 to 10<sup>6</sup> carrier cells that had been subcultured 9 to 11 times and contained an average of 50 rickettsial particles per cell, which were counted after smears were stained by using the immunofluorescence technique.</s><s>The rectal temperatures abruptly increased to more than 40°C; this reaction was accompanied by scrotal swelling 2 to 3 days after inoculation, even if a small dose (10 carrier cells) was inoculated.</s><s>The fever continued for 2 to 3 days and was followed by defervescence to around 38°C.</s><s>Most of the rickettsiae recovered by tissue culturing from the blood during the febrile stage produced targetlike plaques; the one exception was a clear-plaque variant that was isolated from a guinea pig which was inoculated with 10<sup>6</sup> carrier cells.</s><s>Specific-pathogen-free strain C3H/HeSlc mice and conventional strain ddY mice (males that were 8 to 12 weeks old) developed inapparent infections after intraperitoneal inoculation; C3H/He mouse strains have been reported to be susceptible to <i>R. conorii</i> (3).</s><s>The mice produced antibodies (titers, 1:20 to 1:160) on day 7, and the titers increased to 1:320 to 1:2,560 on day 21 after inoculation with 10<sup>2</sup> to 10<sup>3</sup> carrier cells.</s><s>Chicken embryos died 5 to 7 days after yolk sac inoculation with organisms propagated in chicken embryo fibroblasts (10<sup>3</sup> infected cells) when they were incubated at 33°C; the maximum yield occurred on day 2 after the death of the chicken embryos.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. japonica</i> exhibited no hemolytic activity when it was assayed with 0.26 mg of protein by using the method of Snyder et al. (14); the organisms which we used were propagated in BHK 21/13 cells and banded at a density of 1.080 g/cm<sup>3</sup> in a Percoll gradient.</s><s>A control reaction mixture containing the same quantity of <i>R. typhi</i> protein resulted in hemolysis, giving an A<sub>545</sub> of 0.240.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The buoyant density of <i>R. japonica</i> DNA was estimated to be 1.692 g/cm<sup>3</sup>.</s><s>Rickettsial DNA extracted from Percoll density gradient-purified organisms by using the standard phenol-chloroform method (12) was centrifuged with CsCl in 10 mM Tris HCl (pH 8.0) at 290,000 x g for 7 h at 20°C in a type RP55VF2 vertical rotor in a Hitachi model CP56G Himac preparative ultracentrifuge, resulting in a single peak of DNA in a CsCl gradient.</s><s>The CsCl density of the peak fraction, obtained from the refractory index (5), was determined on the basis of a value of 1.710 g/cm<sup>3</sup> for the density of the reference DNA from <i>Escherichia coli</i> B (13).</s><s>Both strain YH<sup>T</sup> and clear-plaque variant DNAs banded at the same density.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The thermal denaturation temperature (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>) of DNA from <i>R. japonica</i> was 82.1 ± 0.3°C (n = 5).</s><s>A Hitachi model U-3210 spectrophotometer equipped with a thermoelectric cell holder connected to a model SPR-10 temperature controller and a digital thermometer was used to measure the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> as described by Marmur and Doty (9).</s><s>In this study we used clear-plaque variant DNA.</s><s>As Table 1 shows, reference <i>R. rickettsii</i> R DNA, which was extracted and purified as described above, had a <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> identical to the value reported previously (17).</s><s>An <i>E. coli</i> B standard DNA also had the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> reported previously (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine (G+C) content of <i>R. japonica</i> DNA calculated from the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> by using the previously described formula (9) was 31.2 2 0.7 mol%.</s><s>This value is identical to the values obtained for other SFG rickettsiae (17).</s><s>The G+C value calculated from the estimated buoyant density by using the equation described by Schildkraut et al. (13) was 32.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the illness.</s><s>The illness caused by <i>R. japonica</i> is found mainly in the southwestern part of Japan (4,6-8, 15, 16, 18, 19, 21, 26); a few cases have been reported in the west-northwest portion of Honshu (10). <i>R. japonica</i> causes an illness (Oriental spotted fever) that is similar to boutonneuse fever.</s><s>A similar agent has been isolated in another laboratory (11) and remains to be identified as <i>R. japonica</i>.</s><s>The vector has not been determined.</s><s>The full geographic distribution of the organisms remains to be established.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>Type strain YH (= ATCC VR-1363) of <i>R. japonica</i> is the first strain of <i>R. japonica</i> that was isolated and has been distributed to the National Institute of Health, Tokyo, Japan, and to prefectural public health laboratories in Japan.</s><s>All of the strains have the same properties.</s></p></content></protolog>