<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9256_nm.14534" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14534" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14534" rank="species">Brevibacterium massiliense</organism><reference id="rid.9256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevibacterium massiliense sp. nov., isolated from a human ankle discharge</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1960</fpage><lpage>1964</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.007864-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19567570</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevibacterium massiliense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevibacterium massiliense</em> (mas.si.li.en′se. L. neut. adj. <em>massiliense</em> of Massilia, the old Roman name for Marseille, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>They are short, irregular, straight rods, 0.4–1.4 μm in length and 0.3–0.5 μm in diameter, as determined by electron microscopy.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Grows between 25 and 45 °C, with optimal growth at 30–37 °C.</s><s>After 24 h growth in 5 % CO<sub>2</sub> on sheep blood agar, surface colonies are beige, shiny, smooth, circular and 0.2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl, with good growth in 1–10 % NaCl; no growth is observed in 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, esterase (C4) and leucine arylamidase activities are detected.</s><s>Esterase lipase (C8) activity is weakly positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Using API Coryne, pyrazinamidase activity is weakly positive.</s><s>Reduction of nitrates and hydrolysis of gelatin are negative.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and urease activities are negative.</s><s>Negative for fermentation of all carbohydrates tested.</s><s>Using API 32A, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase and serine arylamidase activities are detected.</s><s>Histidine arylamidase activity is weakly positive.</s><s>Urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Mannose fermentation, raffinose fermentation, reduction of nitrates and indole production are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive biochemical traits recovered when using the Biolog system are as follows: Tween 40, Tween 80, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>The following traits are weakly positive: lactamide and TMP.</s><s>The following traits are negative: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>β</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, AMP, UMP, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The following traits are not reproducible: <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine and d-ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by the predominance of anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5401308<sup>T</sup> (=CSUR P26<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109422<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53855<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human ankle discharge sample.</s></p></content></protolog>