<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5268_nm.1213" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1213" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1213" rank="species">Erythromicrobium ramosum</organism><reference id="rid.5268"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yurkov</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuerst</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hugenholtz</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Golecki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gad'on</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gorlenko</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kompantseva</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Drews</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic positions of novel aerobic, bacteriochlorophyll a-containing bacteria and description of Roseococcus thiosulfatophilus gen. nov., sp. nov., Erythromicrobium ramosum gen. nov., sp. nov., and Erythrobacter litoralis sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>427</fpage><lpage>434</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-427</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520734</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erythromicrobium ramosum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erythromicrobium ramosum</i> (ra.mo'sum. L. adj. <i>ramosum</i>, ramifying, referring to the morphology of the cells)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, orange rods that are 0.6 to 1.0 by 1.3 to 2.5 μm.</s><s>Cells may branch.</s><s>Multiplication occurs by binary or ternary fission.</s><s>Motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Bchl <i>a</i> and carotenoids are present.</s><s>The cytoplasmic membrane contains a reaction center and two light-harvesting complexes, one with an absorption maximum at 870 nm and one with absorption maxima at 798 and 832 nm.</s><s>The major carotenoids are the very polar compound erythroxanthin sulfate and bacteriorubixanthinal.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at temperatures between 25 and 30°C and at pH values between 7.0 and 8.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum substrates for growth are glucose, sucrose, maltose, acetate, pyruvate, butyrate, malate, succinate, fumarate, propionate, glutamate, casein hydrolysate, and yeast extract.</s><s>Growth also occurs on fructose, citrate, lactate, tartrate, and ethanol.</s><s>No growth occurs on ribose, arabinose, formate, benzoate, methanol, mannitol, glycerol, and glycolate.</s><s>Methanol is not utilized.</s><s>Starch, gelatin, and Tween 80 are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive, The tricarboxylic acid cycle operates.</s><s>The glyoxalate shunt has been observed in strain E4 (2), but not in strain E5<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to the following antibiotics: tetracycline, polymyxin B, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, amikacin, gentamicin, nystatin, bacitracin, kanamycin, neomycin, aureomycin, vancomycin, novobiocin, chloramphenicol, and fusidic acid.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, ampicillin, streptomycin, and nystatin.</s><s>The storage compounds are polysaccharides, poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid, and polyphosphates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 63.6 to 64.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: cyanobacterial mat from an alkaline spring (pH 9.5; 25°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is E5 (= DSM 8510).</s></p></content></protolog>