<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3914_nm.11494" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11494" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11494" rank="species">Burkholderia rhizoxinica</organism><reference id="rid.3914"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Partida-Martinez</surname><given-names>L.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schmitt</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richter</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roth</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hertweck</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Burkholderia rhizoxinica sp. nov. and Burkholderia endofungorum sp. nov., bacterial endosymbionts of the plant-pathogenic fungus Rhizopus microsporus.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2583</fpage><lpage>2590</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64660-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978222</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia rhizoxinica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia rhizoxinica</em> (rhi.zo.xi′ni.ca. N.L. n. <em>rhizoxinum</em> rhizoxin; L. f. suff. -<em>ica</em> suffix used with various meanings; N.L. fem. adj. <em>rhizoxinica</em> referring to the ability of this organism to produce the antimitotic agent rhizoxin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Irregularly cultured, Gram-negative, motile, short or coccoid rods that occur singly, in pairs or irregular clusters.</s><s>Cell size varies from 1.2 to 2.0 μm in length and from 0.6 to 1.2 μm in width.</s><s>Cells are positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Single colonies are tiny, circular, flat, glistening and of cream colour (about 1 mm in diameter).</s><s>Growth is poor on agar plates and typically occurs as a very thin lawn.</s><s>Production of diffusible pigments is not observed.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated well up to a concentration of 2 % (w/v).</s><s>Growth is negative or weak at a concentration of 3 % (w/v) NaCl and is inhibited completely at 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>The type strain is able to grow at temperatures between 16 and 45 °C and at a pH range of 5.0–7.4.</s><s>Optimum pH is 6.0–6.5.</s><s>Cells are not viable at pH values below 4.5 or above 7.5.</s><s>In cultures without pH control, growth stops at pH 7.5.</s><s>Glucose is not metabolized, but glycerol is utilized.</s><s>Able to grow under aerobic and microaerophilic conditions, but not in an anaerobic atmosphere containing CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phylogenetic distinctiveness is supported by the fatty acid profile, which is characterized by major amounts of hexadecanoic acid (C16 : 0), cyclo-heptadecanoic acid (C17 : 0 cyclo), <em>ω</em>-7-<em>cis</em>-octadecenoic acid (C18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) and cyclo-<em>ω</em>-8-nanodecanoic acid (C19 : 0<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>).</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, l-mannosidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, imipenem, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, norfloxacin, oxytetracycline, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, lincomycin, meticillin, novobiocin, penicillin G, sulfonamide and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HKI 454<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19002<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109453<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from the fungus <em>Rhizopus microsporus</em> van Tieghem var. <em>chinensis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>