<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2449_nm.11350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11350" rank="species">Rhodobacter vinaykumarii</organism><reference id="rid.2449"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>T.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anil Kumar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>Ch.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>Ch.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodobacter vinaykumarii sp. nov., a marine phototrophic alphaproteobacterium from tidal waters, and emended description of the genus Rhodobacter</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1984</fpage><lpage>1987</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65077-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766859</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodobacter vinaykumarii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodobacter vinaykumarii</em> (vi′nay.ku.ma′ri.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>vinaykumarii</em> of Vinaykumar, named after the late Dr M. Vinaykumar, an Indian microbiologist and research supervisor of Ch. V. R. and Ch. S, who initiated work on anoxygenic phototrophic bacteria in India).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.8–1.2×1.5–3.0 μm, non-motile and divide by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The colour of photosynthetically grown cultures is yellowish brown.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 377, 452, 479, 512, 590, 803 and 851 nm, thus confirming the presence of bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and probably carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>Mesophilic (30 °C), with optimum growth at pH 6.0–7.5.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth (optimum 1–4 %, w/v).</s><s>Photoheterotrophy with organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Good growth is obtained on pyruvate, fumarate, oxoglutarate and malate.</s><s>Growth on acetate, succinate, lactate, glucose, glycerol, sorbitol, cysteine, peptone and Casamino acids also occurs.</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic and chemolithoautotrophic growth is not possible in the presence of thiosulfate/hydrogen as electron donor and NaHCO<sub>3</sub> as carbon source.</s><s>Fermentative growth is not possible in the presence of pyruvate as the fermentable carbon source.</s><s>Biotin is required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JA123<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18714<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14544<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 54311<sup>T</sup>), isolated from marine tidal waters on the east coast of India.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.8 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>An additional strain of this species, JA249, has been isolated from marine water in Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>