<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9211_nm.14463" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14463" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14463" rank="species">Sphaerisporangium album</organism><reference id="rid.9211"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphaerisporangium flaviroseum sp. nov. and Sphaerisporangium album sp. nov., isolated from forest soil in China</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1679</fpage><lpage>1684</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006130-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542141</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphaerisporangium album</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphaerisporangium album</em> (al′bum. L. neut. adj. <em>album</em> white).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Forms pale-grey substrate mycelia and white aerial mycelia.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced on any of the media tested.</s><s>Spherical and pyriform spore vesicles are borne on aerial mycelia.</s><s>Grows in 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are positive.</s><s>Cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and nitrate reduction are positive, but gelatin liquification, milk coagulation and peptonization, H<sub>2</sub>S production and hydrolysis of cellulose are negative.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, arabinose, xylose, ribose, rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, cellobiose, starch, dextrin, fucose, inositol, mannitol, aesculin, galactose are utilized, but sorbin, xylitol, erythritol or amygdalin are not.</s><s>Hydrolyses urea, proline, serine, ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-arginine, l-valine, histidine and lysine, but not glycine, l-tryptophan, methionine or xanthine.</s><s>Major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) (32.5 %), MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) (31.3 %) and MK-9 (29.0 %).</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (4.8 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (56.2 %), and 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (15.8 %).</s><s>Diagnostic amino acid of peptidoglycan is <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain ribose, madurose, galactose, glucose and mannose.</s><s>Phospholipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannoside, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphoglycolipids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 71 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 48782<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45172<sup>T</sup>=CCTCC AA 208026<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of Hunan, China.</s></p></content></protolog>