<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9179_nm.14383" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14383" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14383" rank="species">Winogradskyella arenosi</organism><reference id="rid.9179"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Winogradskyella arenosi sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from marine sediments from the Sea of Japan.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1443</fpage><lpage>1446</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006809-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502331</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Winogradskyella arenosi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Winogradskyella arenosi</em> (a.re.no′si. L. gen. n. <em>arenosi</em> of a sandy place, dwelling in marine sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>An aerobic, Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive, yellow-pigmented, gliding, rod-shaped bacterium (0.2–0.3 μm in diameter and 1.7–2.5 μm in length) (Fig. 1).</s><s>Cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>On MA, yellow-pigmented, shiny, smooth, slimy colonies, 3–5 mm in diameter, are formed.</s><s>Flexirubin and diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Sodium ions are required for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.5–9.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth temperature range is 4–35 °C, with optimum growth at 25–28 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Casein, chitin, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper), agar and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed slowly over 3–5 days in both routine and API 20NE tests.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production is positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, maltose, mannose and d-mannitol, but not from sucrose, d-cellobiose, arabinose, rhamnose, galactose or xylose.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for hydrolysis of aesculin, but negative for reduction of nitrate, production of indole, production of acid from glucose and assimilation of arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API 50CH tests, positive for utilization of aesculin, but negative for utilization of glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, d-arabitol, gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, weakly positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>; smaller amounts of anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH are present; and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6 and C<sub>18 : 1</sub> occur as minor components.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R60<sup>T</sup> (=KMM 3968<sup>T</sup>=NRIC 0748<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15527<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sediment sample collected from Peter the Great Bay of the Sea of Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>