<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9487_nm.14631" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14631" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14631" rank="species">Hirschia maritima</organism><reference id="rid.9487"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Hirschia maritima sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2264</fpage><lpage>2268</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008326-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620361</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Hirschia maritima</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Hirschia maritima</em> (ma.ri′ti. ma. L. fem. adj. <em>maritima</em> of the marine environment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, oxidase-positive and catalase-positive.</s><s>Vegetative cells produce a prostheca (0.06–0.1 μm in diameter) and reproduce by budding.</s><s>Mature cells are spherical, oval- or rod-shaped and measure about 0.6–1.1×1.2–1.3 μm.</s><s>At maturity, both the vegetative cell and the bud produce one or more flagella.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, entire, orange and measure 0.5–0.8 mm in diameter after 5 days incubation.</s><s>Growth does not occur on any medium supplemented with natural seawater or artificial sea salts except for MA.</s><s>Grows at 10–30 °C (optimum, 30 °C), at pH 6.1–10.1 (optimum, pH 8.1–9.1) and on MA supplemented with 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces a non-diffusible carotenoid pigment [<em>λ</em><sub>max</sub>=460 nm in methanol/acetone (1 : 1, v/v)], but bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is absent.</s><s>Degrades DNA and starch but not casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, elastin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Positive for aesculin degradation and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease (API 20NE).</s><s>Enzyme activities for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are positive, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative (API ZYM).</s><s>In the Biolog GN2 system, l-arabinose, d-fructose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, methyl pyruvate, methyl succinate, acetic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, Tween 40, Tween 80, l-alanine, l-proline, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannitol (weak), <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid (weak), phenylethylamine (weak), putrescine (weak) and 2,3-butanediol (weak) are oxidized.</s><s>The following carbon substrates are not oxidized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, malonic acid, citric acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-alaninamide, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, l-serine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose <em>α</em>-6-phosphate.</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic diamino acid of the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The predominant quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The only polar lipid detected is phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are components included in summed feature 7 and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GSW-2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19733<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14974<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater taken from the seashore of Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>