<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6318_nm.11205" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11205" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11205" rank="species">Chitinophaga ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.6318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Na</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>C.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chitinophaga ginsengisegetis sp. nov. and Chitinophaga ginsengisoli sp. nov., isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1396</fpage><lpage>1401</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64688-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625164</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chitinophaga ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chitinophaga ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil of a ginseng field, the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Cells are 0.6–0.8 μm in diameter and 1.2–1.6 μm in length after 3 days culture on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar for 3 days are smooth, circular, convex, transparent and yellowish.</s><s>Grows well at temperatures of 15–42 °C and at pH 5.5–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of &#x003C;1.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur.</s><s>Able to degrade chitin, but not DNA or xylan.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>In addition to the data in Table 1, can also utilize <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, arabinose, glucose, maltose, mannose, d-melibiose, l-proline, salicin, d-sorbitol and sucrose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Positive results are also found for gluconate, inositol and rhamnose after 7 days incubation.</s><s>After 14 days incubation, gives a positive result for l-fucose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Does not utilize acetate, adipate, l-alanine, caprate, citrate, glycogen, histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, l-lactate, malate, malonate, mannitol, phenylacetate, propionate, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, suberate or valerate.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, gives positive results for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase and is weakly positive for chymotrypsin and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>According to the API 20NE gallery, gives positive results for arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatin hydrolysis, glucose fermentation and urease, but is negative for nitrate reduction and tryptophan degradation.</s><s>Flexirubin pigmentation is positive.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> are the predominant cellular fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 48.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 052<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12592<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18017<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>