<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11910_nm.19998" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19998" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19998" rank="species">Arenicella xantha</organism><reference id="rid.11910"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenicella xantha gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel gammaproteobacterium isolated from a marine sandy sediment from the Sea of Japan</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1832</fpage><lpage>1836</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.017194-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19767361</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenicella xantha</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenicella xantha</em> (xan′tha. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xantha</em> from Gr. adj. <em>xanthos</em> yellow-coloured).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.6 μm in diameter and 3.0–4.0 μm long.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Produces deep-yellow-pigmented, smooth, shiny colonies with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter, on MA.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs at 1–5 % (w/v) NaCl and is optimal with 2–3 %.</s><s>Grows well in/on peptone medium containing NaCl alone without the addition of any of the components of sea salts (MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub>, NaNO<sub>3</sub>, K<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>, KCl, NaSO<sub>4</sub>, NaHCO<sub>3</sub>, NaF and FeSO<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>No growth on basal medium supplemented with 0.1 % glycerol, 0.1 % potassium acetate or 0.1 % potassium succinate or on basal medium when the Na<sup>+</sup> salts are replaced by equimolar amounts of K<sup>+</sup> salts.</s><s>Shows weak growth on d-glucose, melibiose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose and l-alanine and no growth on maltose, sucrose, d-galactose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, lactose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-mannose, cellobiose, glycerol, acetate, glutamic acid, dl-methionine, d-mannitol, citrate, l-asparagine, l-arginine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine, l-lysine, l-leucine and l-histidine.</s><s>Psychrotolerant; the temperature range for growth is 5–35 °C, with optimum growth at 25–28 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed at 4 °C or above 35 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–11.0 with an optimum at pH 8.5–9.5.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed in 3–5 days.</s><s>Does not degrade CM-cellulose, agar, chitin or DNA.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, does not produce melanin-like pigments and/or clearance zones.</s><s>No acid production is observed from d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or d-mannitol.</s><s>According to API 20 NE tests, positive for aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and the PNPG test (<em>β</em>-glucosidase) and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose acidification under anaerobic conditions, production of arginine dihydrolase and urease and assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>According to API 20 E tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis and the PNPG test and negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production under anaerobic conditions, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, acetoin production (Voges–Proskauer reaction) and oxidation or fermentation of d-glucose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin and <em>β</em>-glucosidase and negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The fatty acid profile includes (in decreasing order of abundance) C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5 and iso-C<sub>18 : 1</sub>.</s><s>Susceptible to (content per disc) ampicillin (10 μg), benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), oleandomycin (15 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), ofloxacin (5 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), cephazolin (30 μg), cephalexin (30 μg) and chloramphenicol (30 μg) and resistant to vancomycin (30 μg), lincomycin (15 μg), oxacillin (10 μg), polymyxin (300 U) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.1 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3895<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0759<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16153<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sandy sediment sample collected offshore from the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>