<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2085_nm.6701" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6701" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6701" rank="species">Actinopolyspora mortivallis</organism><reference id="rid.2085"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsubara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Horikoshi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinopolyspora mortivallis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic actinomycete.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinopolyspora mortivallis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinopolyspora mortivallis</i> (mor. ti. val'lis. N.L. gen. n. <i>mortivallis</i>, of Death Valley, the source of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The aerial mycelium is branched monopodially and forms spore chains with more than 10 spores per chain.</s><s>The spores are oval to cylindrical with smooth surfaces (0.5 to 0.7 by 0.8 to 1.3 μm).</s><s>Fragmentation of hyphae has not been observed.</s><s>Colonies on oatmeal agar (ISP medium no. 3) are yellowish white.</s><s>Casein and xanthine are decomposed.</s><s>Urease is not produced.</s><s>Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Xylose, fructose, sucrose, raffinose, and glucose are utilized as carbon sources, but rhamnose, mannitol, inositol, and arabinose are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from xylose, sucrose, and glucose.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Milk is peptonized.</s><s>The organism is susceptible to penicillin at a concentration of 10 mg/ml.</s><s>The growth temperature range is 10 to 50°C, with optimum growth occurring at 45°C.</s><s>The NaCl tolerance range is 5 to 30%, with optimum growth occurring at NaCl concentrations between 10 and 15% at 45°C.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 68 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Our isolate is distinguished from <i>Actinopolyspora halophila</i> by the following characteristics: decomposition of xanthine, carbon source utilization profile, nitrate reduction, milk peptonization, temperature range (Fig. 3A) and pH range (Fig. 3C) for growth, NaCl concentration range which permits growth (Fig. 3B), and antibiotic susceptibility (especially against β-lactam antibiotics) (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain is strain HS-1 (= JCM 7550).</s><s>Monotypic.</s></p></content></protolog>