<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12307_nm.20320" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20320" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20320" rank="species">Breoghania corrubedonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12307"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vila</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nieto</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Urdiain</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Móra</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grifoll</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Breoghania corrubedonensis gen. nov. sp. nov., a novel alphaproteobacterium isolated from a Galician beach (NW Spain) after the Prestige fuel oil spill, and emended description of the family Cohaesibacteraceae and the species Cohaesibacter gelatinilyticus.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>316</fpage><lpage>321</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.06.005</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Breoghania corrubedonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0070"&#x003E;<em>Breoghania corrubedonensis</em> (Co.ru.be.do.nen'sis N.L. fem. adj. corrubedonensis, of or belonging to Corrubedo, northwest Spain, isolated from the beach of Corrubedo, the location where the sand sample used to inoculate the enrichment cultures from which strain UBF-P1<sup>T</sup> was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0075"&#x003E;In addition to the characteristics reported for the genus, cells are regular, irregular or bulbous rods, motile by one or two subpolar flagella, and approximately 0.6–0.7 μm wide and 2–3.5 μm long.</s><s>They reproduce by asymmetric division.</s><s>On LB ASW, LB 3% NaCl, or Marine Agar, colonies are circular, entire, convex, mucoid, and creamy white in colour.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days at optimal growth conditions, colonies are approximately 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>The strain grows at temperatures in the range of 15–40 °C (optimum 30 °C) and at pH 5–8.5.</s><s>Growth occurs with NaCl concentrations of 1–10%.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatine or aesculin does not occur.</s><s>Aminopeptidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease activities are present.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for nitrite reduction, indole production, and H<sub>2</sub>S formation.</s><s>β-Glucosidase and β-galactosidase are not produced.</s><s>Starch, DNA or Tween 80 are not degraded.</s><s>Acid is only weakly produced from l-arabinose.</s><s>Growth occurs on glucose, arabinose, mannitol, d-sorbitol, adipate, gluconate (w), phenyl acetate, acetate, succinate, malate, pyruvate, casaminoacids (Difco), acetone, and Tween 20.</s><s>No growth occurs on d-xylose, mannose, maltose, starch, caprate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosamine, citrate, lactate, oxalacetate, propionate or methanol.</s><s>The fatty acids are C<sub>18:1</sub><em>ω</em>7c (75.3%), C<sub>19:0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8c (6.4%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (4.4%), C<sub>16:1</sub><em>ω</em>7c and/or C<sub>15:0</sub> iso 2-OH (summed feature 3, 2.5%), C<sub>18:0</sub> 3-OH (2.4%), C<sub>18:0</sub> (2.2%), and C<sub>20:1</sub><em>ω</em>9c (1.3%).</s><s>Other minor (&#x003C;1%) fatty acids are C<sub>14:0</sub> 3-OH or C<sub>16:1</sub> iso I (summed feature 2), C<sub>17:1</sub><em>ω</em>8c, C<sub>17:1</sub><em>ω</em>6c, and C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol (DPG), phosphatidylglycerol (PG), phosphatidylethanolamine (PE), phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine (PME), and phosphatidylcholine (PC).</s><s>The DNA content is 63.9 mol%.</s><s>The discriminative traits of the species are listed in diagnostic <a href="#tbl0005">Table 1</a> and <a href="#sec0030">Supplementary Material Table S2</a>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0080"&#x003E;The type strain of the species UBF-P1<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in three culture collections under the following numbers: CECT 7622, LMG 25482, and DSM 23382.</s></p></content></protolog>