<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2423_nm.11302" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11302" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11302" rank="species">Litoricola lipolytica</organism><reference id="rid.2423"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choo</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Litoricolaceae fam. nov., to include Litoricola lipolytica gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium belonging to the order Oceanospirillales</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1793</fpage><lpage>1798</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65059-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684259</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Litoricola lipolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Litoricola lipolytica</em> [li.po.ly′ti.ca. Gr. n. <em>lipos</em> fat; Gr. adj. <em>lytikos</em> dissolving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lipolytica</em> fat-dissolving, pertaining to esterase lipase (C8) activity of the species].</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to having the properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.5–0.7 μm wide and 0.8–1.3 μm long, dividing by binary fission (see Supplementary Fig. S1, available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, opaque, cream-coloured and 0.05 mm in diameter, after 1 week of incubation.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 1 mm in diameter after 3 weeks incubation.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–30 °C (optimum, 25 °C), pH 5–10 (optimum, pH 7.0) and 1.5–10.0 % NaCl (optimum, 3.0–3.5 % NaCl).</s><s>No growth is observed at 10 or 35 °C, at pH 4 or 10 or at 1.0 or 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity is present.</s><s>Negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase and urease.</s><s>Only esterase lipase (C8) activity is detected in API ZYM tests; alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>In tests for the utilization of sole carbon sources, positive results are obtained for the following carbon substrates: glycerol, dl-glyceraldehyde, d-ribose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, d-raffinose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-xylitol, citric acid, d-glucuronic acid, pyruvic acid, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-ornithine and l-serine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized weakly: methylamine, ethanol, d-galactose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-melezitose, d-mannitol, gluconic acid, itaconic acid, propionic acid and dl-proline.</s><s>Methanol, d-xylose, d-fructose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucosamine hydrochloride, d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, maltose, l-arabitol, d-sorbitol, malonic acid, succinic acid, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-glycine and l-leucine are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin, but resistant to ampicillin and penicillin G.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are composed of C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (42.8 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (20.6 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (14.1 %), an unknown fatty acid (equivalent chain-length 11.799) (6.8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (6.5 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (5.6 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0.9 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.7 %), C<sub>19 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (0.8 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> 11-methyl (0.6 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (0.4 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (0.1 %) and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0.1 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IMCC1097<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42360<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 102074<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface seawater off the coast at Goseong, East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>