<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.987_nm.8256" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8256" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8256" rank="species">Flexibacter japonensis</organism><reference id="rid.987"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kosako</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okuhara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flexibacter japonensis sp. nov., a new species that produces a novel inhibitor of human leukocyte elastase isolated from soil</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8662178</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flexibacter japonensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flexibacter japonensis</i> (ja. po. nen’sis. M. L. adj. <i>japonen- sis</i>, referring to Japan, source of the soil from which the organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram- negative, long, slender rods or sometimes filaments, motile by gliding.</s><s>Colonies are translucent, orange yellow, flat with irregular edges on nutrient agar.</s><s>Microcysts are not formed.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic condition on nutrient agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures ranging from 17° to 44°C.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction; hydrolysis of gelatin, esculin, and DNA; growth in the presence of 2.0% NaCl; acid production from D-glucose, D-xylose, D- galactose, sucrose, lactose, and maltose; and utilization of glycerol, D-xylose, adonitol, D-fructose, rhamnose, salicin, and inulin.</s><s>Negative for the Voges-Proskauer reaction; hydrolysis of casein, chitin and starch; acid production from D-fructose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, inositol, and salicin; and utilization of D-mannitol, gentibiose, and D-turanose.</s><s>MK-7 is the major menaquinone, and MK-6 is minor menaquinone.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of strain 758 DNA is 49.8 mol % (as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Flexibacter japonensis</i> is strain 758.</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics described above.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited at the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as JCM9735.</s></p></content></protolog>