<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12512_nm.21361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4967" rank="species">Psychrobacillus psychrodurans</organism><reference id="rid.12512"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Krishnamurthi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruckmani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacillus gen. nov. and proposal for reclassification of Bacillus insolitus Larkin &#x0026; Stokes, 1967, B. psychrotolerans Abd-El Rahman et al., 2002 and B. psychrodurans Abd-El Rahman et al., 2002 as Psychrobacillus insolitus comb. nov., Psychrobacillus psychrotolerans comb. nov. and Psychrobacillus psychrodurans comb. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>33</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>367</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2010.06.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20650590</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>
Description of 
<em>Psychrobacillus psychrodurans
</em> (Abd El-Rahman et al., 2002) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>psy.chro.dur’ans. Gr. adj. <em>psychros</em> cold; L. pres. part. <em>durans</em> enduring; N.L. part. adj. <em>psychrodurans</em> cold-enduring)</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Bacillus psychrodurans</em> Abd El-Rahman et al. (2002).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on three strains, 68E3<sup>T</sup> (DSM 11713<sup>T</sup>), 67E1 (DSM 11712) and 61E1 (DSM22889).</s><s>In addition to the characteristics of the genus, the species has the following characteristics.</s><s>Positive for oxidation of l-glutamic acid and α-ketovaleric acid (strain 61E1 is weakly positive), the type strain is negative for oxidation of other substrates of the Biolog system (strain 67E1 is positive for oxidation of acetic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, 2,3 butanediol, weakly positive for inosine; strain 61E1 shows positive or weak oxidation of arbutin, D-fructose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, pyruvic acid methylester, succinic acid mono-methylester, pyruvic acid, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, 2-deoxyadenosine, inosin, thymidine, and uridine; <a href="#app1">Supplementary Table S3</a>) The type strain is positive for alkaline phosphatase, weak production of leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin and α-chymotrypsin but negative for esterase production.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, starch hydrolysis and nitrate reduction <a href="#bib1">[1]</a>.</s><s>Negative for gelatin, esculin and PNPG hydrolysis and citrate utilization.</s><s>Positive or weak acid production from d-glucose, d-fructose, esculin, mannitol and cellobiose (strain 61E1 is negative for acid production).</s><s>Other characteristics are given in <a href="#tbl2">Table 2</a>, <a href="#app1">Supplementary Tables S3 and S4</a>.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids mentioned in the genus description, the type strain also contains one phospholipid (PL 3), an aminophospholipid (APL) and three unknown lipids (UL 3, 4, 5).</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>In addition, the species also contains iso-C<sub>14:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>16:1</sub>ω7c alcohol in moderate amounts.</s><s>The genomic DNA G + C content 35.8–36.5 mol% (36.5 mol% for the type strain).</s><s>The type strain is 68E3<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11713<sup>T</sup> = (NCIMB 13837<sup>T</sup> = ATCC BAA796<sup>T</sup> = CIP 107791<sup>T</sup>) and was isolated from garden soil, El-kanater, Egypt <a href="#bib1">[1]</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>