<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6862_nm.9551" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9551" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9551" rank="species">Gelidibacter gilvus</organism><reference id="rid.6862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Novel members of the family Flavobacteriaceae from Antarctic maritime habitats including Subsaximicrobium wynnwilliamsii gen. nov., sp. nov., Subsaximicrobium saxinquilinus sp. nov., Subsaxibacter broadyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Lacinutrix copepodicola gen. nov., sp. nov., and novel species of the genera Bizionia, Gelidibacter and Gillisia</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63527-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014468</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gelidibacter gilvus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gelidibacter gilvus</em> (gil′vus. L. masc. adj. <em>gilvus</em> pale yellow).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, approximately 0·4–0·6×2–8 μm.</s><s>Large coccoid bodies (2–3 μm in diameter) form in older cultures.</s><s>Motile by gliding.</s><s>Cell mass is yellow.</s><s>Flexirubin pigments are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are circular and convex, with a thin spreading margin and a viscid consistency on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs at −2 °C in marine broth.</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA at 1–25 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 30 °C or higher.</s><s>Halophilic.</s><s>Grows in 0·1–1·5 M NaCl, with optimal growth occurring in approximately 0·3–0·4 M NaCl.</s><s>Grows in media prepared with 2× strength sea salts, whereas no growth occurs in 4× strength sea salts.</s><s>Grows well on TSA containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl, and weakly on TSA and NA.</s><s>Requires yeast extract or peptone for growth, and cannot use inorganic nitrogen sources such as sodium nitrate or ammonium chloride.</s><s>In minimal growth media can utilize d-glucose, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, dl-arabinose, maltose, sucrose, sodium acetate, sodium propionate and l-proline as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acid production from carbohydrates on Leifson's O–F medium is positive for d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-rhamnose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, lactose, cellobiose, trehalose, maltose, d-melibiose, inositol and glycerol.</s><s>Acid is not formed from melezitose, raffinose, dextran, adonitol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80 and aesculin, but not gelatin, casein, elastin, l-tyrosine, starch, DNA or urea.</s><s>Produces lecithinase.</s><s>Produces 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminidase, but not alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase or reduce nitrate.</s><s>Other phenotypic data are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Mean DNA G+C content is 39 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IC158<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 1054<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108531<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from sea-ice algae, collected from fast sea-ice cores obtained from the coastal areas of the Vestfold Hills, an ice-free region of East Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>