<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1950_nm.8477" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8477" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8477" rank="species">Arthrobacter bergerei</organism><reference id="rid.1950"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Irlinger</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bimet</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Delettre</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefèvre</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter bergerei sp. nov. and Arthrobacter arilaitensis sp. nov., novel coryneform species isolated from the surfaces of cheeses.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>457</fpage><lpage>462</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63125-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653918</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter bergerei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter bergerei</em> (ber.ge′re.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>bergerei</em> of Bergère, to honour Jean-Louis Bergère, a French microbiologist).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below was based on the results of studies of five strains.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile and exhibit a rod–coccus growth cycle.</s><s>Colonies on BHI agar medium are yellow, round, smooth, convex and 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows between 10 and 30 °C and tolerates up to 7·5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase, pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are produced.</s><s>Urease, phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and gelatinase are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>d-Glucose, ribose, xylose, mannitol, maltose, lactose, sucrose and glycogen are not fermented.</s><s>In Biotype 100 strips using biotype 2 medium, all strains (100 %) are able to use the following substrates as sole carbon sources: d-glucose, fructose, d-galactose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, ribose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glycerol, d-gluconate, quinate, protocatechuate, lactate, aspartate and glutamate.</s><s>Other substrates are used less frequently (20–80 %): lactulose, d-cellobiose, l-rhamnose, d-melezitose, d-mannitol, turanose, d-trehalose, d-mannose, maltotriose, arabitol, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, aconitate, citrate, 2-keto-d-gluconate, l-tryptophan, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, phenylacetate, malate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, betaine, 5-aminovalerate, ethanolamine, malonate, 3-phenylpropionate, coumarate, 4-aminobutyrate, benzoate, putrescine, glucosamine, 3-hydroxybutyrate, histidine, l-alanine, serine, propionate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, proline, d-alanine and tyrosine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: sorbose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, methyl <em>β</em>-glucopyranoside, aesculin, palatinose, fucose, l-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, tagatose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-sorbitol, adonitol, lyxose, erythritol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl d-glucopyranose, saccharate, mucate, d-, l- and <em>meso</em>-tartrate, tricarballylate, d-glucuronate, d-galacturonate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, gentisate, trigonelline, histamine, caprate, caprylate, glutarate, glycerate, tryptamine and itaconate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Ca106<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108036<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16367<sup>T</sup>), utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon sources: d-glucose, fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, sucrose, lactulose, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, maltotriose, maltose, lactose, d-cellobiose, ribose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-arabitol, glycerol, d-gluconate, aconitate, citrate, phenylacetate, quinate, protocatechuate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, putrescine, 4-aminobutyrate, lactate, histidine, glucosamine, aspartate, glutamate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, proline, d-alanine, l-alanine, serine, propionate and tyrosine.</s><s>The cell wall contains lysine, alanine and glutamic acid.</s><s>The whole cell sugars are glucose, ribose and mannose.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the surface of Camembert cheese.</s></p></content></protolog>