<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3130_nm.7873" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7873" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7873" rank="species">Treponema saccharophilum</organism><reference id="rid.3130"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema saccharophilum sp. nov., a large pectinolytic spirochete from the bovine rumen</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>212</fpage><lpage>219</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">4051480</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema saccharophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema saccharophilum</i> (sac.cha.ro.phi'lum. Gr.n. <i>sacchar</i> sugar; Gr.adj. <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>saccharophilum</i> sugar-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells, 0.6 to 0.7 μm to 12 to 20 μm.</s><s>Cell coiling is regular except when cells are in contact with solid surfaces.</s><s>A bundle of periplasmic flagella is wrapped around the cell body.</s><s>Approximately 16 periplasmic flagella are inserted near each end of the protoplasmic cylinder and overlap in the central region of the cell.</s><s>An outer sheath surrounds both the flagellar bundle and the protoplasmic cylinder.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In liquids, at 37°C, cells swim at velocities in excess of 60 μm/s. but no translational motility is observed at 23°C.</s><s>Translational motility ceases 1 to 2 min after the cells are exposed to air.</s><s>Cells in contact with solid surfaces exhibit creeping motility.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Optimum growth is at 37 to 39°C.</s><s>At these temperatures, the final growth yield in rumen fluidglucose- sodium bicarbonate-salts broth is 7 x 10<sup>8</sup> cells per ml and the population doubling time is 90 min.</s><s>No growth at 23°C or 45°C.</s><s>Subsurface colonies in agar media are spherical and opaque with diffuse edges.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilizes as fermentable substrates for growth: L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucuronic acid, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, D-raffinose, dextrin, inulin, starch, pectin, polygalacturonic acid, and arabinogalactan.</s><s>Do not serve as fermentable growth substrates: L-rhamnose, D-xylose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, cellulose, dextran, amino acids, D-arabitol, dulcitol, mannitol, ribitol, sorbitol, xylitol, glycerol, potassium galactonate, potassium gluconate, sodium acetate, sodium formate, sodium lactate, sodium succinate, potassium fumarate, Tween 80, glucosamine, and xylan.</s><s>Exogenous isobutyric acid is required for growth, valeric acid is stimulatory.</s><s>Neither NaHCO<sub>3</sub> in media nor a CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere is required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fermentation end products of growing cells (micromoles per 100 μmol of glucose utilized): formate, 150; acetate, 91.2; ethanol, 79.4.</s><s>Approximately 15% of the glucose carbon consumed by growing cells is assimilated in cell material.</s><s>Acetate and formate are major end products of pectin or glucuronic acid fermentation.</s><s>Pyruvate is metabolized via a coliform-type clastic reaction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from bovine rumen fluid by using an agar medium that contained rifampin as a selective agent and pectin as a fermentable substrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 54 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: PB; deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, DSM collection no. 2985.</s></p></content></protolog>