<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.795" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.795" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.795" rank="species">Chlorobaculum limnaeum</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chlorobaculum limnaeum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chlorobaculum limnaeum</em> (lim.nae′um. Gr. adj. <em>limnaios</em> pertaining to or living in lakes; M.L. neut. adj. <em>limnaeum</em> living in lakes).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0·6–0·8 μm wide and non-motile.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is brown or green, and photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>e</em> with isorenieratene as the major carotenoid in brown strains and BChl <em>c</em> with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid in green strains.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and sulfur as photosynthetic electron donors; molecular hydrogen may also be used.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria without a requirement for sodium chloride.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> may be required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 1677<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is AJ290831.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two strains that were known as <em>Chlorobium phaeobacteroides</em>, 1549 and DSM 1677, have almost-identical 16S rRNA and <em>fmo</em> gene sequences and are closely related to <em>Chlorobaculum tepidum</em>.</s><s>They are phylogenetically distant from the type strain of <em>Chlorobium phaeobacteroides</em> and are assigned to <em>Chlorobaculum limnaeum</em> sp. nov.</s><s>The strains known as <em>Chlorobium limicola</em> UdG 6038, UdG 6040, UdG 6042 and UdG 6045 have highly similar 16S rDNA sequences to the two strains of <em>Chlorobaculum limnaeum</em>, and may be considered as strains of this species.</s><s>The assignment of strain UdG 6041 requires further study.</s></p></content></protolog>