<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1214_nm.6245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6245" rank="species">Corynebacterium minutissimum</organism><reference id="rid.1214"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium minutissimum sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>870</fpage><lpage>871</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-870</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium minutissimum</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The following description is based on a number of studies (1-9, 11) and our own observations on strains NCTC 10288<sup>T</sup>, NCTC 10284, and NCTC 10285.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on blood agar are circular, about 1 mm in diameter, low convex with entire margins, and not pigmented; the surfaces are shiny and moist.</s><s>When grown on certain rich media (e.g., media supplemented with 20% [vol/vol] fetal bovine serum), colonies show a coral red to orange fluorescence under Wood light (365 nm).</s><s>Gram strains of exponential-phase cultures show straight to slightly curved rods which exhibit some pleomorphism.</s><s>Cells occur singly or are arranged at right angles to give V formations; palisading occurs.</s><s>The lengths of the rods range from 1 to 2 μm, and the diameters range from 0.3 to 0.6 μm.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>No endospores are produced.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 35 to 37°C.</s><s>Not heat resistant.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase and cytochromes are produced.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from glucose, fructose, mannose, and maltose.</s><s>Some strains (including strain NCTC10288<sup>T</sup>) produce acid from sucrose.</s><s>No acid is produced from lactose, raffinose, or xylose.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer negative.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Sodium hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase and deoxyribonuclease are produced.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase positive.</s><s>Urease is not produced.</s><s>Gelatin and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>mess</i>-diaminopimelic acid; alanine and glutamic acid are also present.</s><s>Arabinose and galactose are the wall sugars.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids (28 to 36 carbon atoms) are present.</s><s>Long-chain nonhydroxylated fatty acids are primarily of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated (oleic acid series), and 10-methyl branched types.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are hexadecanoic, octadecenoic, and 10-methyl octadecanoic acids.</s><s>Major menaquinone components are MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol dimannoside, and some glycolipids.</s><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid base composition ranges 56 to 58 mol% guanine plus cytosine, as determined by the thermal denaturation method (NCTC 10288<sub>T</sub>, 58.0 mol%; NCTC 10284, 57.5 mol%; NCTC 10285, 56.4 mol%).</s><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 10288.</s></p></content></protolog>