<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5717_nm.5250" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5250" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5250" rank="species">Staphylococcus fleurettii</organism><reference id="rid.5717"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vernozy-Rozand</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mazuy</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meugnier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lasne</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Etienne</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freney</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus fleurettii sp. nov., isolated from goat's milk cheeses.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1521</fpage><lpage>1527</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939659</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus fleurettii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus fleurettii</i> (fleu.rett'i.i. L. gen. n. in honour of the French microbiologist Jean Fleurette for his contribution to the taxonomy of staphylococci)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. fleurettii</i> is based on the results of a study of six strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and biochemical characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism has Gram-positive spherical cells, 0-8 to 1-4 μm in diameter, that occur singly, in short chains and in irregular clumps.</s><s>The organism is non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are less than 3 mm in diameter when the organisms are grown aerobically on P agar at 37 °C.</s><s>Colonies on P agar are usually raised, with ulcerated, irregular centres, opaque and often have sectored or irregular edges; five of the six strains studied produce unpigmented colonies and one strain produces cream pigmentation.</s><s>Colonies grown on tryptic soy agar are much larger (8-12 mm in diameter) and not as irregular as colonies grown on P agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains are negative for staphylocoagulase, thermonuclease, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, arginine arylamydase, β-glucuronidase and β-galactosidase activities.</s><s>All strains are negative for aerobic production of acid from the following substrates: D-raffinose, D-galactose, L-fucose, α-lactose, D-melezitose, D-cellobiose, salicine and D-xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains are positive for catalase and nitrate reductase activities, modified oxidase activity and aerobic production of acid from the following substrates, D-fructose, maltose, D-mannose, D-trehalose, sucrose and turanose.</s><s>The variable characteristics of <i>S. fleurettii</i> are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Enterotoxin production and detection</s></p><p class="description"><s>The six strains of <i>S. fleurettii</i> do not produce the seven different enterotoxins that were investigated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities</s></p><p class="description"><s>In disk diffusion tests, resistance to novobiocin, bacitracin and vibriostatic compound O/129 is noted.</s><s>In contrast, all of the strains are sensitive to lysostaphin.</s><s>All strains are resistant to 1000 μg lysozyme ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As shown by the following MIC values (mg l<sup>-1</sup>), all of the strains are susceptible to penicillin G (0.06-0.1), gentamicin (0.06-0.1), kanamycin (0.5), tobramycin (0.06), neomycin (0.06), minocycline (0.06), chloramphenicol (4.0), erythromycin (0.06-0.5), lincomycin (0.06-0.5), clindamycin (0.06-0.1), pristinamycin (0.25-10), rifampicin (0.1), teicoplanin (0.5-20), vancomycin (0.5-1.0) and tetracycline (0.25).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two strains (90 and CIP 106114<sup>T</sup>) are resistant to oxacillin and chloramphenicol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall analysis</s></p><p class="description"><s>The composition of peptidoglycans is given in Table 3.</s><s>The molar ratios of the amino acids and amino sugars occurring in the peptidoglycans of strains 193 and CIP 106114<sup>T</sup> are based on lysine.</s><s>The peptidoglycans tested appear to have tetraglycine interpeptide bridges that also contain alanine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lysostaphin is able to hydrolyse the cell walls, whereas lysozyme has only weak hydrolysis activity, suggesting acetylation of muramic acid (as is the case for S. aureus peptidoglycan).</s><s>The composition of the cell walls of strains 193 and CIP 106114T was 0.7 and 0.9 μmol phosphorus (mg cell wall)<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Glycerol and glucose were found both in cell walls and in isolated teichoic acids.</s><s>As a product obtained by HF-hydrolysis of cell walls, isolated teichoic acid α-glucosyl-glycerol was recognized by GLC (Fiedler et al., 1981).</s><s>This indicated that glucose is linked α-glycosidically to glycerol phosphate units of poly-(glycerolphosphate) teichoic acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lipoteichoic acids were found and their structure corresponds to that described for staphylococci (Ruhland &#x0026; Fiedler, 1990).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA–DNA hybridization</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA relationships among the six <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains and between strain CIP 106114<sup>T</sup> and other <i>Staphylococcus</i> species are shown in Table 1.</s><s>In DNA-DNA hybridization reactions performed under optimal conditions (55 °C), <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains exhibited high levels of DNA similarity (86-100%).</s><s>However, the level of DNA relatedness between the new species and the <i>Staphylococcus</i> species were significantly low (8-37%).</s><s>Under stringent conditions (70 °C), the levels of DNA similarity were 20% for <i>S. vitulinus</i>, 10% for <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>sciuri</i>, 10% for <i>S. sciur</i> subsp. <i>carnaticus</i> and 12% for <i>S. sciuri</i> subsp. <i>rodentium</i>.</s><s>The Δ<i>T<sup>m</sup></i> between strain CIP 106114<sup>T</sup> and <i>S. vitulinus</i> was greater than 5°C (56°C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+­C content of the DNA of all strains tested varied over a narrow range between 30.9 and 32 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ribotyping</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ribotypes determined for the six isolates were entered into our database, which contains information on staphylococcal strains (32 species and 4 subspecies).</s><s>The six <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains shared very close rDNA restriction profiles and a core of 10-18 common hybridizing bands (Fig. 1).</s><s>A similar pattern was observed for three <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains (81, 193 and 241<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The three other <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains presented unique patterns.</s><s>The ribotypes of the six <i>S. fleurettii</i> strains were different from those of the <i>S. sciuri</i> and S. vitulinus type strains and are distinguishable by the presence of an <i>S. fleurettii</i>-specific core of 10 common hybridizing bands (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intergenic transcribed spacer 16S–23S PCR (ITS-PCR)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The <i>S. fleurettii</i> patterns shared a core of common fragments and were different from those of the <i>S. sciuri</i> and <i>S. vitulinus</i> type strains (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. fleurettii</i> can be phenotypically distinguished from the other novobiocin-resistant and oxidase-positive <i>Staphylococcus</i> species on the basis of the lack of acid production from cellobiose and raffinose and the acid production from trehalose, mannose, turanose and maltose (Table 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain 241<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106114<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13212<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a cheese made from raw goat's milk, has the following characteristics.</s><s>Colonies are 3 mm in diameter, unpigmented and raised with ulcerated centres.The type strain produces catalase and is resistant to bacitracin, vibriostatic agent O/129 and lysozyme but is sensitive to lysostaphin.</s><s>The type strain is novobiocin-resistantandnegative for staphylocoagulase, clumping factor, thermonuclease, alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, β-glucuronidase and β-galactosidase activities, arginine utilization and acetoin production.</s><s>It is negative for aerobic production of acid from the following substrates: D-raffinose, D-galactose, L-fucose, α-lactose, D-melezitose, D-cellobiose, salicine and D-xylitol.The type strain is positive for modified oxidase activity, aesculin hydrolysis and aerobic production of acid from the following substrates, D-fructose, maltose, D-mannose, D-trehalose, L-arabinose and D-turanose.</s><s>The G­+C content of its DNA is 30.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>