<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5773_nm.3994" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3994" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3994" rank="species">Clostridium piliforme</organism><reference id="rid.5773"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Duncan</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carman</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of the agent of Tyzzer's disease to Clostridium piliforme comb. nov. on the basis of 16S rRNA sequence analysis.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>314</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-314</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7684241</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium piliforme</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The levels of 16s rRNA similarity (fractions of sequence identity) between Tyzzer's bacillus and the bacterial sequences in the Ribosomal Database Project alignment (19) were calculated and sorted. All of the highest levels of similarity were with members of the low-G+C-content gram-positive group (28). A representative collection of levels of sequence similarity and corresponding evolutionary distance estimates is presented in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>More detailed phylogenetic analyses were performed on the 16s rRNA sequence from Tyzzer's bacillus, the sequences most similar to it, and a diverse collection of other sequences from the same general region of the phylogenetic tree available from the Ribosomal Database Project (19).</s><s>These sequences were subjected to analysis by the maximum- likelihood method (Fig. 1) and the parsimony method (data not shown).</s><s>A smaller group of sequences were analyzed by the least-squares painvise distance analysis method (data not shown).</s><s>In all cases, the sequences from Tyzzer's bacillus, <i>Clostridium coccoides</i>, <i>Clostridium oroticum</i>, <i>Clostridium clostridiiforme</i>, <i>Clostridium symbiosum</i>, <i>Streptococcus hansenii</i>, <i>Clostridium aminovalericum</i>, and "<i>Acetitomaculum ruminis</i>" formed a distinct group.</s><s>Although the maximum-likelihood tree (Fig. 1) suggests that <i>C. aminovalericum</i> and "<i>A. ruminis</i>" might be viewed as peripheral to the group, other methods of analysis or changes in the collection of sequences included can move Tyzzer's bacillus to a branch point deeper than that of these two organisms.</s><s>The tree shown is the best estimate given by the maximum-likelihood analysis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The statistical reliability of this group as a whole was examined by using the bootstrap method (8), which estimates the uncertainty in a measurement due to a finite sample size (in this case, the limited length of the sequences).</s><s>When parsimony was used, 92% of the 100 bootstrap resamplings retained all eight organisms of the proposed group, whereas when maximum-likelihood analysis was used, 99% (119 of 120) of the bootstrap resamplings retained this group.</s><s>Our inclination is to accept the support offered by the maximum-likelihood analysis as a reflection of additional statistical power of the method and therefore to interpret the inferred grouping of Tyzzer's bacillus as strongly supported.</s><s>Neither parsimony nor maximum-likelihood analyses indicated a significant resolution of the order in which Tyzzer's bacillus, <i>C. aminovalericum</i>, and "<i>A. ruminis</i>" separate from the remaining group of five sequences (data not shown) .</s><s>There are two oligonucleotides which when used together are a signature of this phylogenetic group.</s><s>These are GAAGTATYTCGGTATGTAAA at positions 413 to 432 and TCCACCTGGGGAGTA at positions 878 to 892 on the <i>E. coli</i> numbering system (3, 4).</s></p></content></protolog>