<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7306_nm.4429" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4429" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4429" rank="species">Selenomonas lipolytica</organism><reference id="rid.7306"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dighe</surname><given-names>A.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shouche</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ranade</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Selenomonas lipolytica sp. nov., an obligately anaerobic bacterium possessing lipolytic activity.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>783</fpage><lpage>791</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-783</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734032</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Selenomonas lipolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Selenornonas lipolytica</i> (li.po.ly'ti.ca. Gr. n. <i>lipos</i> fat; Gr. adj. <i>lytikos</i> dissolving; M.L. adj. <i>lipolytica</i> fat-dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved rods, 0.55-0.77 by 3.3-4.5 µm in size and actively motile.</s><s>Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, obligately anaerobic, catalase-negative, indole-negative.</s><s>Strain CFIB<sup>T</sup> cannot hydrolyse gelatin.</s><s>The habitat is tropical anaerobic lagoon.</s><s>The type strain is CFIB<sup>T</sup>,which was isolated from a tropical anaerobic lagoon of an edible oil mill near Pune, India.</s><s>Flagella (4-5) are arranged linearly as a single tuft near the centre of the concave side.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of 30-47 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 40 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 6.8.</s><s>The strain could tolerate NaCl concentration up to 40 g l<sup>-1</sup> with optimum growth occurring in the absence of NaCl in PYG broth.</s><s>The organism is sensitive to many antibiotics affecting cell-wall synthesis.</s><s>It shows considerable resistance to antibacterial compounds affecting protein synthesis.</s><s>It shows luxurious growth on glucose without any supplementation of n-valerate.</s><s>Acetate and propionate are the only volatile fatty acids produced after fermentation of glucose, with propionate as the major end product.</s><s>The strain shows strong and true lipolytic activity.</s><s>It shows degradation zones on tributyrin, triolein and groundnut oil in qualitative plate clearance assays.</s><s>The strain utilizes glycerol but not lactate.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 40 mol %.</s><s>The strain has maximum similarity with the genus <i>Selenornonas</i> with respect to a 16s rDNA sequence with a similarity of 91% and S<sub>ab</sub> value of 0.674 for <i>S. ruminantium</i> strain GA 192.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CF1B<sup>T</sup>,has been deposited as MCMB 505<sup>T</sup>, in the MCM culture collection centre (Maharashtra Association for Cultivation of Science Culture Collection of Microorganisms) established at Agharkar Research Institute, Pune, India.</s></p></content></protolog>