<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8503_nm.13317" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13317" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13317" rank="species">Dyadobacter alkalitolerans</organism><reference id="rid.8503"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mo</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dyadobacter alkalitolerans sp. nov., isolated from desert sand</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>60</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001404-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126724</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Dyadobacter alkalitolerans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Dyadobacter alkalitolerans</em> (al.ka.li.to′le.rans. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> alkali; L. part. adj. <em>tolerans</em> tolerating; N.L. part. adj. <em>alkalitolerans</em> alkali-tolerating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, aerobic rods.</s><s>Colonies on 0.1× TSB agar are circular, mucoid, smooth and yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–12 (optimally at pH 7), at 4–30 °C (optimally at 18–25 °C) and in the presence of up to 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of aesculin and in the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Negative for urease, gelatinase, lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, tryptophan deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrolysis of casein, cellulose, chitin, DNA, starch, gelatin, H<sub>2</sub>S production and indole production.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), cystine arylamidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are weakly positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, turanose and d-lyxose, but not from glycerol, erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilizes d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose, maltose, d-glucose, salicin and melibiose as sole carbon resources, but not l-alanine, glycogen, l-arabinose, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, l-proline, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, lactic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, d-mannitol, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, capric acid, valeric acid, trisodium citrate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or 4-hydroxybenzoic acid.</s><s>Sensitive to (μg per disc) tetracycline (30), rifampicin (25), kanamycin (30) and tobramycin (10), but resistant to ampicillin (25), erythromycin (15), vancomycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), furazolidone (300), amoxicillin (10) and cephamezine VI (30).</s><s>The pigment present is a flexirubin type with absorption maxima at 428, 452 and 478 nm.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content for the type strain is 46.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 12116<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207176<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-51268<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from desert sand in Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>