<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2858_nm.11202" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11202" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11202" rank="species">Rheinheimera aquimaris</organism><reference id="rid.2858"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rheinheimera aquimaris sp. nov., isolated from seawater of the East Sea in Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1386</fpage><lpage>1390</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64898-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625162</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rheinheimera aquimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rheinheimera aquimaris</em> (a.qui.ma′ris. L. n. <em>aqua</em> water; L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>aquimaris</em> of the water of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods or cocci (0.4–0.7×0.5–2.5 μm) on MA and rods (0.3–0.5×1.0–5.0 μm) on trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming and motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>After incubation for 2 days at 37 °C, colonies on MA are circular, raised, slightly wrinkled, yellowish-white in colour and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter; colonies on trypticase soy agar (Difco) are circular, slightly convex, glistening, smooth, greyish-yellow in colour and 3.0–4.0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 43 °C, but not at 44 °C; optimal growth occurs at 30–37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5, but not at pH 5; optimal growth occurs at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 8 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of more than 9 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions on MA or on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Casein, l-tyrosine, urea and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are absent.</s><s>Tryptophan deaminase is present.</s><s>d-Xylose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-trehalose, starch, glycogen, acetate, succinate and pyruvate are utilized, but glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, fructose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, benzoate, formate and l-glutamate are not utilized.</s><s>Utilization of sucrose is variable (positive for the type strain).</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following substrates: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, polymyxin B and streptomycin, but not to ampicillin, cephalothin, penicillin G, novobiocin, tetracycline, lincomycin or oleandomycin.</s><s>Susceptibility to carbenicillin is variable (negative for type strain).</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 50.1–50.5 mol% (HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1 and Supplementary Table S1 (available in IJSEM Online).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SW-353<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12840<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14331<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater collected at Hwajinpo (East Sea, Korea).</s></p></content></protolog>