<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12681_nm.22420" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22420" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22420" rank="species">Pontibacillus yanchengensis</organism><reference id="rid.12681"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pontibacillus yanchengensis sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from salt field soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1906</fpage><lpage>1911</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023911-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pontibacillus yanchengensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pontibacillus yanchengensis</em> (yan.chen.gen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>yanchengensis</em> of or belonging to Yancheng, as the type strain was isolated from a salt field in Yancheng).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive–staining, rod-shaped (0.5–0.9×1.9–2.5 µm), motile with flagella and are unable to grow in anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Spherical endospores are formed at the terminal position in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, smooth and have circular/slightly irregular margins after incubation on MA plus 5 % NaCl (w/v) at 37 °C for 48 h.</s><s>Grows in media containing 3–20 % (w/v) NaCl; optimum growth occurs on media containing 6–8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Growth is observed at pH 6.0–9.5 and optimum growth occurs at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–45 °C (optimum, 35–40 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and starch, but not casein, l-tyrosine, Tween 80, hypoxanthine, xanthine, gelatin or urea.</s><s>Negative result in tests for the production of H<sub>2</sub>S or indole, for the fermentation of glucose and for nitrite reduction.</s><s>Negative result in methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannitol, maltose, trehalose and starch, but not from d-ribose, d-xylose, d-mannose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, α-lactose, d-galactose, raffinose, d-salicin, melibiose, adonitol or sucrose.</s><s>Enzyme activities are positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, α-glucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>Weak or negative activity for α-chymotrypsin.</s><s>Negative for lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, lysine decarboxylase, α-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids on MA plus 3 % (w/v) NaCl are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> alcohol.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan type is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The menaquinone is menaquinone-7 (MK-7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Y32<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.10680<sup>T</sup> = CCTCC AB209311<sup>T</sup> = NRRL B-59408<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from subsurface soil of Sanwei salt field, Yancheng, Jiangsu province, South-east China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.3 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>