<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3940_nm.3177" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3177" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3177" rank="subspecies">Erwinia carotovora odorifera</organism><reference id="rid.3940"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallois</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Samson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ageron</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Erwinia carotovora subsp. odorifera subsp. nov., associated with odorous soft rot of chicory (Cichorium intybus L.).</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>582</fpage><lpage>588</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-582</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eewinia carotovora</i> subsp. <i>odorifera</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eewinia carotovora</i> subsp. <i>odorifera</i> (o.dor.if'er.a. L.fem.adj. <i>odorifera</i>, bringing odors, fragrant)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporeforming, peritrichous, straight rods.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grow on nutrient agar, producing colonies that are about 2.5 mm in diameter after 48 h at 25°C on YPDA medium.</s><s>Colonies are circular, greyish (to yellowish on media containing sucrose or gelatin), slightly domed, and semitranslucent.</s><s>All strains grow at 37°C.</s><s>Aminopeptidase is produced.</s><s>Dextrose is fermented without gas production.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test positive.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Polypectate gel is acidified and liquefied (Sutton medium).</s><s>Cellulase is produced (carboxymethyl cellulose).</s><s>Lecithinase and phosphatase are not produced.</s><s>Indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s>Reducing substances are produced from sucrose (Benedict reagent).</s><s>Acid is not produced from inulin in peptone-water.</s><s>Acid is produced in minimal mineral medium from lactose (2 to 3 days), trehalose (5 to 10 days), α-methylglucoside (3 to 7 days), palatinose (2 to 3 days), melibiose (2 to 3 days), D-arabitol (2 to 4 days), and D-sorbitol (2 to 4 days).</s><s>Alkalinization of mineral medium containing citrate occurs, but there is no alkalinization of mineral medium containing malonate.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>β-Glucuronidase is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy on Biotype strips by at least 10 of the 11 strains: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, sucrose, D-raffinose, lactose, lactulose, D-cellobiose, gentiobiose, 1-O-methyl-β-D-glucoside, D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, palatinose, L-rhamnose, D-arabitol, glycerol, myo-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, 1-O-methyla-D-glucoside, D-saccharate, mucate, L-malate, citrate, D-galacturonate, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, gluconate, DL-glycerate, D-glucosamine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, and L-serine (in 3 or 4 days at 30°C).</s><s>Maltose, 1-O-methyl-α-galactoside, maltitol, D-turanose, D-glucuronate, 2-ketogluconate, succinate, fumarate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, and L-serine are utilized by some strains but not by all strains.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized within 4 days: L-sorbose, maltotriose, L-fucose, D-melezitose, L-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, D-tagatose, adonitol, D-lyxose, <i>i</i>-erythritol, 3-O-methyl-~-glucose, L-tartrate, D-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, D-malate, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, tricarballylate, 5-ketogluconate, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, gentisate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, benzoate, 3-phenylpropionate, <i>m</i>-coumarate, trigonelline, betaine, putrescine, 4-aminobutyrate, histamine, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, glutarate, 5-aminovalerate, ethanolamine, tryptamine, itaconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, D-alanine, L-alanine, malonate, propionate, L-tyrosine, and 2-ketoglutarate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains produce flavoring volatile compounds, such as propyl acetate, isobutyl acetate, isoamyl acetate, and actamyl acetate, when they are inoculated onto witloof leaves.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soft rots of various plants, including <i>C. intybus</i> (cultivated for witloof production).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CFBP 1878.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain CFBP 187g<sup>T</sup> was isolated from soft rot of <i>C. intybus</i> in Britanny (France) by R.</s><s>Samson.</s><s>This strain and five other strains (strains CFBP 1879, CFBP 1880, CFBP 1892, CFBP 1893, and CFBP 1959) have been deposited in the National Collection of Plant Pathogenic Bacteria, Harpenden, Great Britain, the International Collection of Microorganisms from Plants, Auckland, New Zealand, and the Laboratorium Microbiologie Rijksuniversiteit Culture Collection, Rijksuniversiteit, Gent, Belgium.</s><s>The type strain has all of the properties given above for the subspecies.</s><s>In addition, it utilizes as sole sources of carbon and energy succinate and fumarate in 2 days and 1-O-methyl-α-galactoside and proline in 4 days.</s><s>It does not utilize trehalose, maltose, D-glucuronate, and 2-ketogluconate in 4 days.</s></p></content></protolog>