<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2403_nm.11236" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11236" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11236" rank="species">Pseudosphingobacterium domesticum</organism><reference id="rid.2403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudosphingobacterium domesticum gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from home-made compost</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1535</fpage><lpage>1538</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64950-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625189</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudosphingobacterium domesticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudosphingobacterium domesticum</em> (dom.es.ti.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>domesticum</em> of or belonging to the house).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>On nutritive non-selective medium, colonies are yellowish, smooth and mucilaginous.</s><s>Cells are short rods (1.2–1.5×0.5–0.6 μm).</s><s>Growth occurs on EMB and m-FC agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–36 °C and pH 5.5–8.0, but not at 40 °C or pH 9.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3 % NaCl, but not in 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth may occur in the presence of the following antibiotics: cephalothin, ceftazidime, gentamicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and colistin sulphate.</s><s>No growth in the presence of ciprofloxacin, sulfamethoxazole or meropenem.</s><s>Gelatin and starch are hydrolysed, but Tween 80 is not hydrolysed.</s><s>No specific nutritional growth factors such as vitamins or amino acids are required.</s><s>Assimilation and acid production is positive for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>d-Arabinose, arbutin and methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside support acid production, whereas salicin, starch and d-turanose are assimilated.</s><s>Acid production or assimilation is negative for other API 50 CH and API 20NE carbon sources.</s><s>The major fatty acid is summed feature C<sub>16 : 1</sub>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of strain DC-186<sup>T</sup> is 42 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DC-186<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 54353<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23837<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from home-made compost.</s></p></content></protolog>