<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12650_nm.22191" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22191" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22191" rank="species">Modestobacter marinus</organism><reference id="rid.12650"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Modestobacter marinus sp. nov., a psychrotolerant actinobacterium from deep-sea sediment, and emended description of the genus Modestobacter</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1710</fpage><lpage>1714</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023085-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20802061</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Modestobacter marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Modestobacter marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> pertaining to the sea, where the type strain was found).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, Gram-stain-positive, short rods (straight, lightly curved, about 0.5–0.8×1.5–2.5 µm; Supplementary Fig. S4), motile by means of flagella.</s><s>Colonies are orange to red on copiotrophic medium at the initial stage of growth and turn black after 14 days.</s><s>Colonies are dark throughout growth on oligotrophic medium.</s><s>Psychrotolerant, growing at 4–35 °C (but not at 37 °C), with optimal growth at 28 °C.</s><s>Tolerant of only narrow variations in pH, with fast growth occurring at pH 6–8 and very slow growth at pH 9.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl at concentrations less than 5 % (w/v).</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, cellulose and starch.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S and cannot grow on DNase test plates.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for aesculin hydrolysis, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl β-d-galactopyranosidase and assimilation of l-arabinose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, malic acid and phenylacetate.</s><s>Negative for indole production, acid from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease and gelatinase.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is weakly positive.</s><s>Tested by the API ZYM enzyme assay, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and β-glucosidase; weakly positive for cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin and β-galactosidase; negative for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>In the API 50 CH test system, acids are produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, aesculin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and l-fucose.</s><s>Weakly positive for acid production from l-rhamnose, salicin, cellobiose, lactose and d-lyxose.</s><s>All the other API 50 CH test results are negative.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em>; the major respiratory quinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The diagnostic phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown aminophospholipid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 72.3±1 mol%.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to a wide variety of antibiotics, but are resistant to discs containing ceftazidime (30 µg), trimethoprim (5 µg) and monobactam (30 µg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 42H12-1<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 45201<sup>T</sup>  = CGMCC 4.5581<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from deep-sea sediment collected from the Atlantic Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>