<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1456_nm.7437" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7437" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7437" rank="species">Streptosporangium fragile</organism><reference id="rid.1456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shearer</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colman</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptosporangium fragile sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>364</fpage><lpage>367</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Streptosporangium fragile sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Morphology. Strain SK&#x0026;F-BC2496<sup>T</sup> has the general morphological features that were described by Couch (4) for the genus <i>Streptosporangium</i>. It is a gram-positive, non-acid-fast organism that forms a substrate mycelium with hyphae about 0.5 to 1.0 μm in diameter and an aerial mycelium that bears sporangia. The sporangia are usually 6 to 12 μm in diameter and may be formed apically on main threads or on very short to relatively long lateral branches; a few appear to be sessile. The immature sporangiospores are arranged in coils within the sporangia. Mature sporangiospores are spherical to ovoid and nonmotile. The sporangial membranes are unusually fragile and could be demonstrated clearly only by electron microscopy (Fig. 1 and 2). This fragility of the sporangial membranes results in the coalescence of the sporangiospores into large irregular masses as the cultures age (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell chemistry.</s><s>Purified cell wall preparations of strain SK&#x0026;F-BC249<sup>T</sup> contained <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glutamic acid, alanine, glucosamine, and muramic acid; no characteristic sugars were present.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contained madurose.</s><s>Phospholipid preparations contained phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, cardiolipin, and unknown glucosamine containing phospholipids.</s><s>Therefore, strain SK&#x0026;F-BC249<sup>T</sup> has a type III cell wall (19) with a type B whole-cell sugar pattern (19) and a type PIV phospholipid composition  (18), which are characteristic of the genus <i>Streptosporangium</i> (18, 19).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Soluble pigment.</s><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-BC2496<i>T</i> produced a brown soluble pigment on nearly all media.</s><s>The exact nature of this pigment was not determined.</s><s>However, based on the chromatographic columns used to isolate the antibiotic and perform the phospholipid analyses, we determined that this pigment is a mixture of a number of colored pigments which, when combined, give the brown color.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Appearance on various media.</s><s>In this study all cultures were observed for 3 weeks.</s><s>The colors of the cultures were determined by comparison with chips from either the ISCC-NBS Centroid Color Charts (15, 21) or the Munsell Book of Color (20).</s><s>The characteristics of the culture on the media tested are given below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yeast extract-malt extract agar: growth excellent, black; aerial mycelium scant to moderate, white, turning light pink; sporangia abundant; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Oatmeal agar: growth good, black (ISCC-NBS 267, black); aerial mycelium moderate, white, turning light pink (ISCC-NBS 8, grayish pink); sporangia abundant; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Inorganic salts-starch agar: growth good, brownish black; aerial mycelium moderate, white, turning light pink (Munsell 5R 9/2); sporangia abundant; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glycerol-asparagine agar: growth fair, flat, brown; aerial mycelium sparse, white; sporangia none to sparse; soluble pigment light brown.</s><s>Potato dextrose agar: growth fair to good, black; aerial mycelium abundant, white, turning pink (Munsell 2.5YR 9/2); sporangia abundant; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Thin potato-carrot agar: growth fair, flat, black; aerial mycelium sparse, white, turning light pink; sporangia abundant; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Czapek-sucrose agar: growth poor, flat, brown; aerial mycelium scant, white; no sporangia; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bennett agar: growth good, black; no aerial mycelium; soluble pigment brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Czapek-peptone agar: growth fair, brown; no aerial mycelium; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Emerson YpSs agar: growth good, black; aerial mycelium scant, white; no sporangia; soluble pigment brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Medium 172: growth excellent, black; aerial mycelium none to sparse, white; sporangia none to moderate; soluble pigment brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tyrosine agar: growth fair, brown; aerial mycelium sparse, white; no sporangia; soluble pigment light brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Defined agar: no growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-BC249<sup>T</sup> did not grow under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The temperature range for growth was 15 to 45°C; no growth occurred at 10 or 50°C.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide was produced.</s><s>Milk was peptonized.</s><s>Gelatin was hydrolyzed but not liquefied.</s><s>Nitrate was reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Starch, casein, L-tyrosine, and hypoxanthine were hydrolyzed, but urea, adenine, and xanthine were not.</s><s>Esculin was decomposed, but allantoin and hippurate were not.</s><s>No growth was produced in lysozyme broth.</s><s>Catalase was produced.</s><s>No violet crystals of iodinin were produced in any medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid was produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, dextrose, i-erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, glycogen, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, starch, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>No acid was produced from adonitol, dulcitol, inulin, melibiose, raffinose, or α-methyl-D-mannoside.</s><s>Acid production during an initial culture in medium containing glycerol, iinositol, D-melezitose, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, or sucrose was variable, but when the organism was subcultured in media containing these carbohydrates the results were consistently negative.</s><s>Citrate, malate, succinate, lactate, and pyruvate were utilized; utilization of mucate was weakly positive.</s><s>During an initial culture in media containing acetate and propionate, these organic acids were utilized, but when the organism was subcultured, the results were variable.</s><s>Benzoate and tartrate were not utilized.</s><s>During an initial culture in media containing oxalate and formate, utilization was variable; when the organism was subcultured, the results were consistently negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain SK&#x0026;F-C2496<sup>T</sup> not require vitamins for growth in the synthetic medium used.</s><s>Either ammonium sulfate or the combination of ammonium sulfate and L-asparagine was a satisfactory nitrogen source; L-asparagine or sodium nitrate permitted little, if any, growth.</s></p></content></protolog>