<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.19_nm.6124" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6124" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6124" rank="species">Curtobacterium plantarum</organism><reference id="rid.19"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dunleavy</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Curtobacterium plantarum sp. nov. is ubiquitous in plant leaves and is seed transmitted in soybean and corn</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>240</fpage><lpage>249</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Curtobacterium plantarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Curtobacterium plantarum</i> (plan.ta'rum. L. fem. n. <i>planta</i>, a sprout; M.L. n. <i>planta</i>, a plant; M.L. gen. pl. n. <i>plantarum</i>, of plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-endospore- forming, motile rods (0.3 to 0.5 by 0.6 to 3.0 μm) that become shorter to coccoid in older cultures.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient broth-yeast extract agar are yellow, circular, convex, glistening, and butyrous with entire margins (diameter, 4 to 16 mm).</s><s>All strains are obligate aerobes.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs between 28 and 30°C.</s><s>All strains produce acid from oxidative fermentation of xylose, rhamnose, glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, maltose, and inositol; acid is not produced from sorbose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, cellobiose, raffinose, glycerol, erythritol, or sorbitol.</s><s>Acetic, pyruvic, lactic, succinic, α-ketoglutaric, propionic, glycolic, glyoxylic, and gluconic acids are assimilated.</s><s>Indoxylacetate and gelatin are hydrolyzed, but casein and hippurate are not.</s><s>Pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, phosphatase, N-acetylglucosaminidase, DNase, and β-carotene are produced; urease is not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 10% sodium chloride, and cells of all strains are susceptible to infection by bacteriophage PBY-3.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 76 ± 1 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CL63 (= ATCC 49174).</s><s>The description above is based on 22 strains that are virtually indistinguishable; thus, the species description is also the type strain description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The name <i>C. plantarum</i> does not occur on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names (32) and was not published between 1980 and 1988.</s></p></content></protolog>