<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6962_nm.5253" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5253" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5253" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus hominis hominis</organism><reference id="rid.6962"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olgiate</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Pelt</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McKinnon</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zimmer</surname><given-names>B.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Muller</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weinstein</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mirrett</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus hominis subsp. novobiosepticus subsp. nov., a novel trehalose- and N-acetyl-D-glucosamine-negative, novobiocin- and multiple-antibiotic-resistant subspecies isolated from human blood cultures.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>799</fpage><lpage>812</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-799</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734034</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> is based on the characteristics of 240 strains of <i>S. hominis</i> sp. nov. (Kloos &#x0026; Schleifer, 1975a) isolated from human skin in 1971-1973, 472 strains isolated from human skin in 1974-1988, and 72 strains isolated from clinical specimens in 1989-1993. This subspecies is the type subspecies of <i>S. hominis</i> and contains the type strain according to Rules 40a and 40b of the Bacteriological Code (Lapage et al., 1975). Colonies are either pigmented (cream-yellow to yellow-orange) or unpigmented (grey-white), opaque, entire, butyrous, raised to very slightly umbonate, and grow to a diameter of 4-6 mm on P agar and TSA. Growth in the anaerobic portion of a semi-solid thioglycollate medium is negative within 48 h. Optimum growth temperature is 35°C. Cultures grown on TSA supplemented with either sheep or bovine blood do not exhibit haemolysis. All strains produce acid aerobically from D-glucose, β-D-fructose, maltose, sucrose and glycerol. Acid is not produced from Dxylose, L-arabinose, D-sorbitol, D-cellobiose, salicin and D-raffinose. Most strains (83%) produce acid aerobically from D-trehalose and 86% produce acid from N-acetyl-D-glucosamine. Some strains (57%) produce weak to moderate amounts of acid aerobically from α-lactose and 69% of strains produce weak to moderate amounts of acid from D-melezitose. Only a small percentage of strains produce acid aerobically from D-mannitol(13%) and D-mannose (0.8%). Most strains (99%) are positive for urease activity and 12% of strains are positive for arginine utilization. Some strains (61%) produce acetoin from glucose metabolism. Capsular polysaccharide/adhesin is not produced. Strains may be either susceptible or resistant to penicillin, oxacillin, methicillin, kanamycin, gentamicin, streptomycin, tetracycline, erythromycin, clindamycin, chloramphenicol, trimethoprim/ sulfamethoxazole and ciprofloxacin. Populations subjected to antibiotic pressure often exhibit multiple resistance. Other characteristics of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> that are uniformly positive or negative for the species are listed above in the section on phenotypic characterization and in the original description of <i>S. hominis</i>. The DNA G + C content is 30-36 mol%. <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> is commonly isolated from human skin and occasionally from clinical specimens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>S. hominis</i> subsp. <i>hominis</i> is DM 122<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 27844<sup>T</sup>), which was the type strain of <i>S. hominis</i> (Kloos &#x0026; Schleifer, 1975a).</s><s>It has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies described above, produces acid aerobically from N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, and has other characteristics as indicated in the original description.</s></p></content></protolog>