<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3732_nm.8167" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8167" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8167" rank="species">Gillisia limnaea</organism><reference id="rid.3732"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Van Trappen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandecandelaere</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gillisia limnaea gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from a microbial mat in Lake Fryxell, Antarctica.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>445</fpage><lpage>448</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02922-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023957</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gillisia limnaea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gillisia limnaea</em> (lim.nae′a. Gr. adj. <em>limnaios</em> pertaining to, living in lakes; N.L. fem. adj. <em>limnaea</em> living in the water, referring to the isolation source, microbial mats in Lake Fryxell).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics are the same as given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are 3·0×0·7 μm.</s><s>Grows at 5–25 °C; optimal growth at 20 °C.</s><s>Weak growth is observed at 30 °C and no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Yellow, convex, translucent colonies with diameters of 1–3 mm and entire margins are formed on marine agar plates after 6 days incubation.</s><s>Colonies on Anacker &#x0026; Ordal's agar are flat, round with entire margins and 0·7–0·9 mm in diameter after 14 days incubation.</s><s>Growth also occurs on nutrient agar and R2A and colonies do not adhere to the agar.</s><s>No growth on trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Degrades aesculin and gelatin.</s><s>Growth is not observed (API 20NE) on glucose, mannose, maltose, l-arabinose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Acids are not produced from carbohydrates (API 20E).</s><s>Agar, alginate, pectin, chitin, casein, carboxymethylcellulose, DNA, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed.</s><s>No brown diffusible pigment is produced on l-tyrosine agar and no precipitate is formed on egg-yolk agar.</s><s>Tests for indole production, citrate utilization, nitrate reduction, the Voges–Proskauer reaction and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>None of the strains has the following enzyme activities: arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase (API 20E), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Weak enzymic activity is observed for cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase, medium activity for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and trypsin and strong activity for alkaline and acid phosphatases, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Variable results are observed for <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin activity.</s><s>Growth occurs in up to 5 % NaCl, but not in 10 % NaCl, indicating that strains are moderately halotolerant but not halophilic.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 37·8–38·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21470<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15749<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from microbial mats from Lake Fryxell in the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>