<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1325_nm.6031" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6031" rank="genus">Jonesia</organism><reference id="rid.1325"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rocourt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wehmeyer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Listeria denitrificans to a new genus Jonesia gen. nov., as Jonesia denitrificans comb. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>266</fpage><lpage>270</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Jonesia</i> Rocourt and Stackebrandt gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Jonesia</i> (Jones.' i.a. L. fem. n. <i>Jonesia</i> of Jones, honoring Dorothy Jones, British microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus description is taken mainly from that given in Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology, vol. 2 , by Seeliger and Jones.</s><s>It has to be kept in mind that the description is based upon the characterization of a single isolate only.</s><s>Irregular, nonsporing rods (0.3 by 0.5 μm) showing branched Y- and clublike forms.</s><s>Gram positive, but many cells, especially in older cultures, are readily decolorized.</s><s>Filamentous and coccoid cells may also occur in older cultures.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter (24 to 48 h), convex, smooth, grayish, and translucid to opaque, becoming yellowish in 10 to 20 days.</s><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Cell wall contains murein of the L-lysteinserine-D-glutamic acid type (A4α and teichoic acid of the poly(ribitol phosphate) type (ribitol-galactosamine-galactose, 1:0.2:0.1).</s><s>No lipoteichoic acid.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are <i>anteiso</i>-C<sub>15:0</sub>, <i>anteiso</i>-C<sub>17:0</sub>, and <i>iso</i>-C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>Polar lipids are constituted by diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, two phosphoglycolipids, and small amounts of two unidentified phospholipids.</s><s>No mycolic acid.</s><s>Major isoprenoid type is MK-9.</s><s>Moles percent guanine plus cytosine, 54 to 58 (melting temperature method); 57 (Bd).</s><s>The type species of the genus is phylogenetically related to the genera <i>Promicromonospora</i>, <i>Arthrobacter</i>, <i>Micrococcus</i>, and <i>Cellulomonas</i> and allied taxa.</s><s>The type species is <i>Jonesia denitri</i> Jicans (PrCvot 1961) comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>