<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10557_nm.17795" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17795" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17795" rank="species">Actinoallomurus acaciae</organism><reference id="rid.10557"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Thamchaipenet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Indananda</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bunyoo</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duangmal</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinoallomurus acaciae sp. nov., an endophytic actinomycete isolated from Acacia auriculiformis A. Cunn. ex Benth</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>554</fpage><lpage>559</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012237-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinoallomurus acaciae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinoallomurus acaciae</em> (a.ca.ci′ae. L. n. <em>acacia</em> the acacia tree and also the name of a botanical genus; L. gen. n. <em>acaciae</em> of <em>Acacia</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a root of <em>Acacia auriculiformis</em> A. Cunn. ex Benth.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic and Gram-positive.</s><s>Cells grow well on ISP 2 and MS agar and show moderate growth on ISP 3, oatmeal-nitrate agar and 1/10 yeast-starch agar, forming a well-developed white aerial mycelium that differentiates into short spiral spore chains with smooth surfaces.</s><s>Neither diffusible pigment nor melanin is produced on any of the media tested.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 28–30 °C and optimal pH is pH 6.0–7.0.</s><s>Tolerates up to 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and urease-positive, oxidase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein, milk and gelatin is negative and degradation of starch is weakly positive.</s><s>d-Mannose, l-rhamnose and trehalose are utilized as sole carbon sources but l-arabinose, dulcitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>β</em>-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>With the API ZYM enzyme assay, acid phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine aminopeptidase, lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and phosphoamidase are detected; chymotrypsin, cystine aminopeptidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, lipase (C14), trypsin and valine aminopeptidase are not detected.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acids of the peptidoglycan are <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, lysine, alanine and glutamic acid.</s><s>Whole-cell sugars include galactose, madurose and mannose.</s><s>The glycan moiety of the murein is acetylated.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), with MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) as a minor component.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> and the minor fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, 10-methyl C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern comprises phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 70.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GMKU 931<sup>T</sup> (=BCC 28622<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 104354<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-24610<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a root of <em>Acacia auriculiformis</em> A.</s><s>Cunn. ex Benth. collected in Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</s></p></content></protolog>