<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12525_nm.21380" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21380" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21380" rank="species">Auraticoccus monumenti</organism><reference id="rid.12525"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Alonso-Vega</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Carro</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trujillo</surname><given-names>M.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Auraticoccus monumenti gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinomycete isolated from a deteriorated sandstone monument</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1098</fpage><lpage>1103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024257-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20525813</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Auraticoccus monumenti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Auraticoccus monumenti</em> (mo.nu.men′ti. L. gen. n. <em>monumenti</em> of a monument).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Grows at 15–30 °C, with optimum growth at 28 °C, at pH 6.5–9.0 and in the presence of 1–5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Good growth is observed on <em>Geodermatophilus</em>, ISP 2, Luedemann and <em>Microlunatus</em> agars, but no pigments are produced on these media.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin and activities of alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative for activities of α-naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-glucuronidase and arginine dihydrolase and indole production.</s><s>Positive for the use of the following carbon sources: amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, raffinose, galactose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, methyl α-d-glucoside and methyl α-d-mannoside; negative for use of 5-ketogluconate, 2-ketogluconate, adonitol, citrate, gluconate, glutaric acid, l-proline, propionic acid, quinic acid, l-tyrosine, valine and methyl β-xyloside.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, sucrose and xylose.</s><s>Additional physiological data are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MON 2.2<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7672<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23257<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25551<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sandstone monument in Salamanca, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>