<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1001_nm.7191" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7191" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7191" rank="species">Streptomyces paradoxus</organism><reference id="rid.1001"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Actinosporangium violaceum Krasil'nikov and Yuan, Actinosporangium vitaminophilum Shomura et al. and Actinopycnidium caeruleum Krasil'nikov to the genus Streptomyces, with amended description of the species.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>61</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces paradoxus</i> nom. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces paradoxus</i> (<i>pa. ra. dox'us</i>. Gr. prep. <i>para</i> amiss, contrary to; Gr. n. <i>doxus</i> an opinion; M.L.n. <i>paradoxus</i> contrary to expectation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from several sources (<i>Krasil'nikov</i> and <i>Yuan</i>, 1961; <i>Yamaguichi</i>, 1965; <i>Williams</i> et al., 1983).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic organisms which form extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Spore chains are Reticuli-Aperti; the spore surface is smooth.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is grey; sclerotia are formed.</s><s>Produces melanin pigments.</s><s>Allantoin, adenine, aesculin, arbutin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, testosterone, tyrosine, urea and xanthine are degraded but chitin, elastin, lecithin, pectin and starch are not.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is produced but nitrate is not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>inositol, inulin, D-lactose, mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources but adonitol and xylitol are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grow on L-arginine, L-cysteine, L-histidine, L-hydroxyproline, L-methionine, potassium nitrate, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine, but not on DL-amino-n-butyric acid or L-phenylalanine, as sole nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 10 and 37°C but not at 4 or 45°C.</s><s>Tolerant to phenol (0.1% wlv) and sodium chloride (4%, w/v), but not sodium azide (0.01%, w/v).</s><s>Sensitive to rifampicin and inhibited by sodium chloride at 7%, w/v.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antimicrobial activity not shown against <i>Aspergillus niger</i> LIV 131, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> NCIB 3610, <i>Candida albicans</i> CBS 562, <i>Escherichia coli</i> NCIB 9132, <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> NCIB 196, <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> NCIB 9046, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i> CBS 171 or <i>Streptomyces murinus</i> ISP 5091.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid as the major diamino acid and is of the A3γ type (<i>Stackebrandt</i> et al., 1981).</s><s>The mol % G+C of the DNA has been reported to be 70.4 (<i>Tsyganov</i> et al., 1966), 70.9 (<i>Tsyganov</i> et al., 1970) and 71.6 (<i>Yamaguichi</i>, 1967).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 15813 (= DSM 43350 = KCC 3052 = RIA 655).</s></p></content></protolog>