<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4411_nm.8037" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8037" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8037" rank="species">Dysgonomonas capnocytophagoides</organism><reference id="rid.4411"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hofstad</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eribe</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dysgonomonas gen. nov. to accommodate Dysgonomonas gadei sp. nov., an organism isolated from a human gall bladder, and Dysgonomonas capnocytophagoides (formerly CDC group DF-3).</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2189</fpage><lpage>2195</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155996</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dysgonomonas capnocytophagoides</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dysgonomonas capnocytophagoides</i> (cap.no.cy.to.pha.goi'des. Gr. n. <i>kapnos</i> smoke; Gr. n. <i>kytos</i> hollow vessel ; Gr. v. <i>phagein</i> to eat; Gr. adj. suffix -<i>oides</i> alike ; N.L. adj. <i>capnocytophagoides</i> capnocytophagalike, referring to some properties shared between these organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on results obtained in this study and those obtained by Wallace et al. (1989).</s><s>Cells consist of non-motile, Gram-negative coccobacilli to short rods.</s><s>After 48 h incubation aerobically at 35 °C in a CO<sub>2</sub>-enriched atmosphere (7.5%), the colonies are 1-2 mm in diameter, non-adherent, entire, grey-white, smooth and non-haemolytic and have a slight aromatic odour.</s><s>The organism does not grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>The organism is catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>It does not produce hydrogen sulphide or acetoin.</s><s>Aesculin may or may not be hydrolysed but gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>Indole may or may not be produced.</s><s>Resistant to ox bile.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Major products of glucose fermentation are propionic, lactic and succinic acids.</s><s>Glucose is fermented with production of acid but no gas.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose and D-xylose.</s><s>Adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcitol, inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol and trehalose are not acidified.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, α-arabinosidase, α-galactosidase, bgalactosidase, β-galactosidase 6-phosphate, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>Arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, <i>N</i>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, lysine decarboxylase, leucine arylamidase, α-mannosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, ester lipase C8, lipase C14, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>Esterase C-4 production is variable.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 17996<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 11519<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G­+C content of DNA of the type strain is 38 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>