<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2795_nm.2872" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2872" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2872" rank="species">Moritella profunda</organism><reference id="rid.2795"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rüger</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Kegel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glansdorff</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moritella profunda sp. nov. and Moritella abyssi sp. nov., two psychropiezophilic organisms isolated from deep Atlantic sediments.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>533</fpage><lpage>538</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02228-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710623</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Moritella profunda</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Moritella profunda</em> (pro.fun′da. L. fem. adj. <em>profunda</em> from the deep).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, curved, relatively short to coccoid, non-sporulating rods, single or in pairs, 0·9–1·2 μm wide by 1·5–5·0 μm long, with rounded ends.</s><s>Motile by means of a single, unsheathed, polar flagellum.</s><s>On peptone/yeast extract/sea-water agar, colonies are smooth, colourless, flat and entire with an irregular margin.</s><s>They become creamy-pink and pink on King's media A and B, respectively.</s><s>Moderately halophilic: no growth is observed in the absence of NaCl but normal growth occurs with half-strength sea water.</s><s>Strictly psychrophilic, with a temperature range from 2 (or lower, not tested) to 12 °C under atmospheric pressure in Bacto Marine broth.</s><s>The maximum growth rate is obtained at 2 °C (possibly lower).</s><s>The organism is piezophilic: growth in Bacto Marine broth is stimulated markedly by hydrostatic pressure, with a maximum of 20–24 MPa at 6 °C and slightly higher at 10 °C.</s><s>At 6 °C, the maximum pressure is between 50 and 60 MPa; it is increased considerably by raising the temperature to 10 °C.</s><s>At both extremes of the pressure domain, but mainly under high pressure, elongated forms may be observed.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, prototrophic (possible vitamin dependency, not tested) chemo-organotroph capable of both fermentative and respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Catalase, cytochrome oxidase, DNase and lipase tests are positive.</s><s>Indole is not produced and arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but no gas is produced.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively and fermentatively from glucose (but no gas), d-fructose and d-galactose (weakly).</s><s>No acid is produced from, adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Utilization of the following carbon sources is positive within 4 weeks at 4 °C: d-galactose, gluconate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, ribose, citrate, pyruvate, glycerol, l-alanine, l-arginine and l-glutamate.</s><s>Acetate is utilized after prolonged incubation for up to 6 weeks.</s><s>The following carbon sources give negative results: l-arabinose, cellobiose, maltose, d-mannose, salicin, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylose, propionate, adipate, fumarate, succinate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, lactate, mannitol, sorbitol, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-ornithine, putrescine, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate and quinate.</s><s>Susceptible to disks (Oxoid) containing 10 μg O/129, 2 U penicillin G, 10 μg tetracycline, 10 μg chloramphenicol, 50 μg furazolidone and 300 U polymyxin B.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 41·4 mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are C14 : 0, C14 : 1, C16 : 0, C16 : 1 and C22 : 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain 2674<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21259<sup>T</sup> =JCM 11435<sup>T</sup>), was collected from the upper layer of deep Atlantic sediments at a depth of 2815 m off the West African coast.</s></p></content></protolog>