<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7171_nm.4176" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4176" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4176" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus harei</organism><reference id="rid.7171"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Murdoch</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magee</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of three new species of the genus Peptostreptococcus from human clinical specimens: Peptostreptococcus harei sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus ivorii sp. nov., Peptostreptococcus octavius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>781</fpage><lpage>787</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-781</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Peptostreptococcus harei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Peptostreptococcus harei</i> (ha're.i., M. L. gen. n. <i>harei</i>, of Hare, a British microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly anaerobic, gram-positive cocci that vary considerably in size (diameter, 0.5 to 1.5 μm) and shape (circular, oval, or elliptical).</s><s>Colonies on sheep blood agar are less than 1 mm in diameter after incubation for 48 h; after 5 days, they are approximately 1 mm in diameter, entire, flat, translucent, and nonhemolytic.</s><s>Urease, ALP, coagulase, and ADH are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole and catalase production are variable.</s><s>Acid is not formed from glucose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, raffinose, trehalose, sorbitol, cellobiose, arabinose, ribose, mannose, or mannitol.</s><s>Acid formation from fructose is variable (one of the two strains examined is positive).</s><s>When the ATB 32A preformed enzyme system (API-BioMerieux) is used, the proteolytic enzyme arginine arylamidase (AMD) is present, but saccharolytic enzymes are not detected; production of the enzymes leucine AMD, tyrosine AMD, and histidine AMD is variable.</s><s>The major VFAs produced in Robertson's cooked meat broth are acetic acid and butyric acid, and smaller quantities of propionic, isovaleric, and n-valeric acids are sometimes produced.</s><s>P. harei has been isolated from antral washout specimens, pus from the peritoneal cavity, infected sacral sores, and abscesses of the face, neck, breast, and thigh, occasionally in pure culture (20).</s><s>The type strain, DSM 10020, was isolated from pus from an infected sacral sore of a diabetic patient; it was cocultured with <i>Peptostreptococcus magnus</i>, <i>Enterococcus</i> spp., and <i>Prevotella melaninogenica</i>.</s><s>Strain DSM 10020<sup>T</sup> forms catalase but does not form indole or acid from fructose; the proteolytic enzymes leucine AMD, tyrosine AMD, and histidine AMD are present.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain DSM 10020<sup>T</sup> is 25 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>