<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3855_nm.2263" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2263" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2263" rank="species">Thermomonas brevis</organism><reference id="rid.3855"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermomonas fusca sp. nov. and Thermomonas brevis sp. nov., two mesophilic species isolated from a denitrification reactor with poly(epsilon-caprolactone) plastic granules as fixed bed, and emended description of the genus Thermomonas.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1961</fpage><lpage>1966</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02684-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657130</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thermomonas brevis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thermomonas brevis</em> (bre′vis. L. fem. adj. <em>brevis</em> short).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are non-filamentous rods that are 0·7 μm wide by 3–10 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar monotrichous flagellum.</s><s>Aerobic, but anoxic growth occurs with nitrate as electron acceptor.</s><s>Growth occurs on complex medium at 4–37 °C, but not at 50 °C; optimum growth occurs at 28–37 °C.</s><s>On R2A agar, convex, circular, smooth, translucent colonies of about 2 mm diameter and with entire margins are formed after 5 days incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>Regardless of the incubation temperature, non-pigmented colonies are formed.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>Positive for the following enzymes: oxidase, catalase, alkaline phosphatase, C4-esterase, C8-esterase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Negative for the following enzymes: arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Growth occurs on glucose, mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose, but not on arabinose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Other characteristics are as for the genus.</s><s>Isolated from biofilm grown on poly(<em>ε</em>-caprolactone) plastic granules that were used as a fixed bed in a denitrification reactor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <em>Thermomonas brevis</em> LMG 21746<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15422<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 68·4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>