<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.724_nm.3996" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3996" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3996" rank="species">Clostridium populeti</organism><reference id="rid.724"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sleat</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium populeti sp. nov., a cellulolytic species from a woody-biomass digestor.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>160</fpage><lpage>163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-2-160</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium populeti</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium populeti</i> (po.pu'le.ti. L. n. <i>populetum</i> poplar wood; L. gen. n. <i>populeti</i> of poplar wood)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain gram negative and are L-alanine-4-nitroanilide and KOH negative.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>The slightly curved rod-shaped cells are 1 to 1.5 μm wide and 1.7 to 3.0 μm long and often occur in pairs.</s><s>Oval spores form terminally and cause a marked swelling of the cells (Fig. 1).</s><s>The mature spores are 1.0 to 1.2 μm in diameter.</s><s>Endospores are viable after heating to 80°C for 10 min.</s><s>Vegetative cells are resistant to sodium dodecyl sulfate but are readily lysed by lysozyme and ethylenediaminetetraacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony characteristics.</s><s>In medium solidified with 2% purified agar and containing pebble-milled cellulose, zones of clearing appear within 48 h.</s><s>Deep colonies are irregular, opaque, and yellow.</s><s>The clear zone of cellulolysis can reach a diameter of 20 mm after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The cellulose in agar roll tubes containing high numbers of cellulolytic colonies is completely hydrolyzed within 2 weeks.</s><s>Surface colonies are almost invisible except for a thin opaque edge.</s><s>Colonies in cellobiose-agar medium after 48 h of incubation are 1 mm in diameter, irregular, opaque, and yellow.</s><s>The colonies are smooth and butyrous, becoming rhizoid with age.</s><s>Colonies in pectin-agar medium are yellow; those in xylan-agar medium are orangish brown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutrition and growth conditions.</s><s>Rumen fluid, Trypticase peptone, and added vitamins are not required for growth.</s><s>Nutritional requirements can be met by the addition of 2 g of yeast extract per liter, although yeast extract cannot serve as a primary substrate.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 35°C, and growth occurs over a temperature range of 20 to 40°C (Fig. 2).</s><s>No growth is observed at 15°C after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.0, ahd the pH range is 6.4 to 8.1 (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolic characteristics.</s><s>Obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Sulfate not reduced.</s><s>Arabinose, xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, cellulose, pectin, xylan, and gum arabic are fermented.</s><s>Rhamnose, glycerol, mannose, lactose, trehalose, melezitose, erythritol, arabitol, sorbitol, lactate, and pyruvate are not fermented.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied after prolonged incubation.</s><s>Starch and casein are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in liquid medium containing a soluble carbohydrate is homogeneous.</s><s>Motility and endospore formation are often inhibited during growth on a soluble carbohydrate in liquid medium.</s><s>Cellulose is readily fermented in medium buffered (final concentration, 50 mM) with PIPES [piperazine-N,N'-bis(2-ethanesulfonic acid)] or HEPES organic buffer but is not fermented in the presence of morpholinepropanesulfonic acid, N-2-acetamido-2-aminoethanesulfonic acid, tris(hydroxymethyl)aminomethane, or N,N-methylenebisacrylamide-tris(hydroxymethyl)aminomethane-propane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The products obtained from glucose after fermentation is complete and H<sub>2</sub> production ceases are acetate (16 mol/100 mol of glucose), butyrate (72 mol/100 mol of glucose), lactate (50 mol/100 mol of glucose), H<sub>2</sub> (98 mol/100 mol of glucose), and CO<sub>2</sub> (111 mol/100 mol of glucose).</s><s>These values (the means of five determinations) yield 92.5% recovery of carbon, 101% recovery of hydrogen, and give an oxidation-reduction balance of 0.92 calculated by the method of Gottschalk (8).</s><s>Trace amounts of ethanol and succinate are also detected.</s><s>Pyruvate and formate are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on pebble-milled cellulose in liquid medium is characterized by the production of a yellow pigment which is bound to the substrate.</s><s>The cellulose becomes viscous and tends to clump.</s><s>The maximum rate of cellulose degradation in carbonate-buffered medium (initial pH, 7.0) is 29 mg/liter per h.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub> and butyrate production parallel Avicel degradation during growth in HEPES-buffered medium (Fig. 4).</s><s>Small quantities of reducing sugars (4 mM after 32 days) are produced when excess cellulose is included in the medium.</s><s>The maximum rate of Avicel degradation is 8.7 mg/liter per h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine content.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of <i>C. populeti</i> DNA is 28 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source. <i>C. populeti</i> was isolated from a batch methanogenic fermentation of finely divided hybrid poplar wood.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain of <i>C. populeti</i> is strain 743A (=ATCC 35295).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>C. populeti</i> is distinguished from most mesophilic, cellulolytic clostridia by its production of butyrate as a major fermentation product during cellulose degradation.</s><s>The recently isolated species <i>C. cellulovorans</i> (30) also produces butyrate, but can be distinguished from <i>C. populeti</i> by its production of formate and its endospore morphology. <i>C. cellulovorans</i> produces central or subterminal, oblong endospores, whereas <i>C . populeti</i> produces terminal, oval endospores.</s></p></content></protolog>