<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8658_nm.13400" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13400" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13400" rank="species">Lysobacter capsici</organism><reference id="rid.8658"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aslam</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lysobacter capsici sp. nov., with antimicrobial activity, isolated from the rhizosphere of pepper, and emended description of the genus Lysobacter.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>387</fpage><lpage>392</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65290-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18218936</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Lysobacter capsici</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Lysobacter capsici</em> (cap′si.ci. N.L. gen. n. <em>capsici</em> of <em>Capsicum</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the rhizosphere of <em>Capsicum annuum</em> L.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, rod-shaped, non-spore-forming and non-motile but having gliding activity, 0.3–0.5 μm wide by 2.0–20 μm long.</s><s>Cells occur singly and in pairs and can form irregular filament-like structures.</s><s>Colonies grown on 2 % TSA at 30 °C for 3 days are 2.0–4.0 mm in diameter, creamy white to yellow, smooth and circular.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15–37 °C (very weak growth at 4 °C); no growth occurs at 45 °C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5.5–8.5, with an optimum of pH 7.0–7.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of 1.0–2.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in 3.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Sensitive to 10 μg rifampicin, 50 μg kanamycin and 50 μg tetracycline ml<sup>−1</sup>, but resistant to 100 μg ampicillin ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Uses 5-bromo-3-indoxyl nonanoate, 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and 4-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside as sole carbon sources but not the following: l-arabitol, galacturonic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, sodium pyruvate, d-mannitol, maltose, adonitol, palatinose, l-tryptophan, 5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide, d-glucose, sucrose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, trehalose, d-rhamnose, inositol, cellobiose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is produced from ribose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, glycogen, pullulan, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and tagatose.</s><s>Urea is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Cannot produce acid from sucrose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol or cyclodextrin.</s><s>Tests for <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and <em>β</em>-mannosidase are positive.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Enzyme activities for chitinase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C-4), esterase lipase (C-8), lipase (C-14), leucine arylamidase, trypsinase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are present, but valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Q-8 is the major quinone.</s><s>Has the major polar lipids listed in the amended genus description.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YC5194<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22007<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19286<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of pepper in Jinju, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>