<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5859_nm.6140" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6140" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6140" rank="species">Leucobacter komagatae</organism><reference id="rid.5859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leucobacter komagatae gen. nov., sp. nov., a new aerobic gram-positive, nonsporulating rod with 2,4-diaminobutyric acid in the cell wall.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>967</fpage><lpage>971</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-967</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863425</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leucobacter komagatae</i> sp, nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leucobacter komagatae</i> (koma.ga'tae. N.L. adj. <i>komugatue</i>, of Komagata, in honor of Kazuo Komagata, the Japanese microbiologist who first recognized this strain)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, irregular rods that are 0.2 to 0.3 μm wide and 1.0 to 1.5 μm long.</s><s>The cells are nonsporulating and nonmotile in 2-day-old cultures on PY-BHI agar.</s><s>No mycelium is produced.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, low convex, smooth, opaque, and whitish brown.</s><s>Catalase is produced, but oxidase, arginine dihydrolase, hydrogen sulfide, and urease are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, and esculin are not hydrolyzed, but Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2.0 to 5.0% NaCl and at pH 10.0.</s><s>Acetate, D- and L-lactate, malate, succinate, propionate, oxalate, and hippurate are assimilated, but citrate and formate are not assimilated.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 66 mol%.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains L-DAB, alanine, glycine, γ-aminobutyric acid, and glutamic acid.</s><s>The acyl type of the cell wall is an acetyl type.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is inenaquinone MK-11.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16:0</sub>, and anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub>.</s><s>No diagnostic sugar is present in the cell wall.</s><s>Diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and one unknown glycolipid are present.</s><s>Isolated as a contaminant on an agar plate.</s><s>The type strain is strain IFO 15245 (=IAM 1093).</s></p></content></protolog>