<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5621_nm.9875" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9875" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9875" rank="species">Microbacterium koreense</organism><reference id="rid.5621"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium koreense sp. nov., from sea water in the South Sea of Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>423</fpage><lpage>427</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63854-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium koreense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium koreense</em> (ko.re.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>koreense</em> pertaining to Korea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, non-motile, Gram-positive organism.</s><s>In young cultures, cells are rods about 0·7 μm in width by 3·0–4·0 μm in length.</s><s>In old cultures, rods become shorter or spherical.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex with entire margins, moist, shiny and light yellow in colour.</s><s>Does not grow in an anaerobic chamber at 37 °C.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C, with optimal growth at 30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6·0–8·0, with optimal growth at pH 7·0.</s><s>No growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of more than 10 %; optimal growth occurs without added NaCl.</s><s>Strains give positive results for aesculin hydrolysis, for catalase and for acid production from glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose and starch.</s><s>Weakly positive for acid production from d-xylose, galactoside, trehalose, glycogen and d-turanose.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification, arginine hydrolysis, urease, gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and acid production from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 68 mol%, the major isoprenoid quinones are MK-11 and MK-12, and the major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell-wall sugars are galactose and xylose.</s><s>The diamino acid in the cell-wall hydrolysates is lysine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JS53-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19074<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108696<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 50754<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sea water in the South Sea of Korea (the Korea Strait).</s></p></content></protolog>