<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2625_nm.11583" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11583" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11583" rank="species">Prevotella maculosa</organism><reference id="rid.2625"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sutcliffe</surname><given-names>I.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Booth</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>W.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prevotella maculosa sp. nov., isolated from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2936</fpage><lpage>2939</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65281-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048753</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Prevotella maculosa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Prevotella maculosa</em> (ma.cu.lo′sa. L. fem. adj. <em>maculosa</em> speckled, referring to the internal appearance of colonies of the organism growing on agar media).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on three strains isolated from the human mouth.</s><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, non-pigmenting, Gram-negative bacilli, 0.7 μm wide by 1–3 μm long, with occasional cells up to 6 μm long.</s><s>After 3 days incubation on FAA medium, colonies are 1.4–1.8 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, opaque, shiny and grey, with a slightly mottled internal appearance.</s><s>Growth in broth media produces a moderate turbidity that is enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are saccharolytic and ferment arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and xylose; mannitol, melezitose and sorbitol are not fermented.</s><s>Major amounts of acetic and succinic acids are produced as end products of metabolism in PYG broth.</s><s>The non-hydroxylated fatty acid profile is predominantly anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, with lesser amounts of iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed; arginine, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>There is no growth in 20 % bile.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 48 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, W1609<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19339<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 54766<sup>T</sup>), and strains W2051 and W6974 were isolated from the human oral cavity.</s></p></content></protolog>