<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2627_nm.1125" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1125" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1125" rank="species">Rhodovulum strictum</organism><reference id="rid.2627"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Rhodovulum strictum sp. nov. and some other purple nonsulfur bacteria from colored blooms in tidal and seawater pools.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>319</fpage><lpage>326</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-319</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537066</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodovulum strictum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodovulum strictum</i> (stric'tum. L. part. adj. <i>strictus</i>, strict, accurate, referring to the fact that the cells require strict growth conditions)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid to rod shaped, 0.6 to 1.0 μm wide and 1.0 to 2.5 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Facultative photoheterotrophs that can grow anaerobically in the light or aerobically in the dark in the presence of full atmospheric oxygen tension.</s><s>Photosynthetic cultures are yellow-green to yellow-brown, while aerobic cultures grown in the dark are pink to red.</s><s>Colonies that develop aerobically on agar media in the dark are circular, convex with entire margins, and red; they are 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 7 days of incubation.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cells contain intracytoplasmic membranes of the vesicular type together with bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>Mesophilic, slightly halophilic, and slightly alkaliphilic.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30 to 35°C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of NaCl concentrations ranging from 0.25 to 3.0% (optimum NaCl concentration, 0.8%) and at pH 7.5 to 9.0 (optimum pH, 8.0 to 8.5).</s><s>Biotin, <i>p</i>-aminobenzoic acid, and thiamine are required as growth factors.</s><s>Good carbon sources for phototrophic growth are formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, malate, succinate, glycolate, fructose, alanine, leucine, Casamino Acids, peptone, and yeast extract.</s><s>Weak or slow growth occurs with valerate, caproate, tartrate, citrate, arabinose, and glucose.</s><s>No or little growth occurs with caprylate, pelargonate, malonate, sucrose, galactose, mannose, adonitol, mannitol, sorbitol, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, propanol, asparagine, aspartate, or glutamate.</s><s>Sulfide and thiosulfate are used as electron donors for phototrophic growth, with sulfate as the final oxidation product.</s><s>No reduced sulfur compounds are required as sulfur sources.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone 10.</s><s>Straight-chain unsaturated and monosaturated fatty acids are present, with C<sub>18:1</sub> predominating.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 67.3 to 67.7 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: tidal and seawater pools and similar marine environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: MB-G2, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, RIKEN, Wako, Japan, as <i>Rhodovulum strictum</i> JCM 9220.</s></p></content></protolog>