<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8761_nm.13413" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13413" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13413" rank="species">Massilia brevitalea</organism><reference id="rid.8761"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zul</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wanner</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Overmann</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Massilia brevitalea sp. nov., a novel betaproteobacterium isolated from lysimeter soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1245</fpage><lpage>1251</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65473-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18450722</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Massilia brevitalea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Massilia brevitalea</em> (bre.vi.ta′le.a. L. adj. <em>brevis</em> short; L. fem. n. <em>talea</em> a rod; N.L. fem. n. <em>brevitalea</em> a short-rod, referring to the shape of cells).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods that are 0.7–1.0 μm wide and 1.5–2.0 μm long and motile by means of a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Occasionally, cells with two or three polar or lateral flagella are observed.</s><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, occur singly or in pairs (on 1 : 10-diluted HD medium at 15 °C after 36 h) and are obligately aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, convex, opaque and pale white to yellow.</s><s>Cells grow chemo-organotrophically on diluted HD (1 : 10) agar and on nutrient agar.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and weakly positive for catalase.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–30 °C, with optimum growth occurring at 15 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–10.0, with optimum growth occurring at pH 7.0–7.5.</s><s>Can grow at NaCl concentrations of ≤2 % (w/v).</s><s>Tweens 20 and 80, casein and starch are hydrolysed, but gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for the following enzyme activities: acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease.</s><s>Distinguished from recognized species of the genus <em>Massilia</em> by an inability to hydrolyse gelatin and by the absence of <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities.</s><s>Tests negative for milk coagulation, indole production, hydrogen sulfide production and gives a negative result in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Cellobiose, d-erythrose, l-erythrulose, d-galactose, glucose, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, maltose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetate, adipate, butyrate, crotonate, hexanoate, caproate, caprylate, fumarate, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, isovalerate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, <em>α</em>-ketoisohexanoate, <em>α</em>-ketovalerate, lactate, malate, oxaloacetate, propionate, protocatechuate, pyruvate, succinate, valerate and (slowly) levulinate.</s><s>(+)-l-Alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, (+)-l-asparaginate, (+)-l-cysteine, (+)-l-glutamate, (+)-l-isoleucine, (+)-l-leucine, (+)-l-lysine, (+)-l-phenylalanine, (+)-l-serine, (+)-l-threonine and (+)-l-tyrosine are utilized.</s><s>Growth occurs on Casamino acids, yeast extract and peptone as complex organic substrates.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 65.3 mol%.</s><s>Q-8 is the predominant respiratory quinone and the major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>In addition, the diagnostic fatty acids C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, byr23-80<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18925<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1465<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from lysimeter soil from the Botanical Garden at the University of Bayreuth, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>