<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7448_nm.2631" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2631" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2631" rank="species">Pseudomonas libanensis</organism><reference id="rid.7448"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dabboussi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamze</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elomari</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhille</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baida</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas libanensis sp. nov., a new species isolated from Lebanese spring waters.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1091</fpage><lpage>1101</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1091</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425766</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas libanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas libanensis</i> (li.ba.nen'sis. L. n. <i>Libanus</i> a mountain area in Southern Syria, Lebanon; L. adj. <i>libanensis</i> from or of Lebanon)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motile by a single polar flagellum as observed by transmission electron microscopy of a cell of the type strain.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells produce a fluorescent pigment on King B medium, but not phenazine pigments on King A medium.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 36°C with optimal growth at 30°C.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, circular and non-pigmented.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated as a carbon reserve material.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl but not in the presence of 7% NaCl.</s><s>All strains reduce nitrate to nitrite and grow on cetrimide.</s><s>Non-haemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>Negative for lipase, elastase and tetrathionate reductase.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lecithinase, catalase and cytochrome oxidase are produced.</s><s>Cells are able to form levan from sucrose and can use citrate and malonate.</s><s>Indole and coagulase are not produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>L-Tyrosine is hydrolysed but not aesculin.</s><s>2,3,5-Triphenyltetrazolium chloride is not used.</s><s>Negative Voges-Proskauer reaction and tributyrin test.</s><s>No action against DNA or RNA.</s><s>All strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: D-arabitol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, L-arabitol, xylitol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, adonitol, erythritol, D-mannose, ribose, D-galactose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucosamine, ethanolamine, D-saccharate, mucate, 2-ketogluconate, protocatechuate, β-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, malonate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, itaconate and quinate.</s><s>The following are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: maltitol, sucrose, α-L-fucose, D-turanose, α-D-melibiose, D-raffinose, maltotriose, maltose, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, palatinose, D-tagatose, α-lactose, lactulose, 1-O-methyl-β-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-α-galactopyranoside, 3-O-methyl-D-glycopyranose, 5-keto-D-gluconate, tricarballylate, phenylacetate, gentisate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, 5-aminovalerate, D-tartrate, benzoate, aesculin, trigonelline, histamine, tryptamine and inulin.</s><s>All strains possess the following enzyme activities: alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase C<sub>4</sub> and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>None of the strains possess the following enzyme activities: achymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, pglucoronidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and afucosidase.</s><s>Mean G + C content of the type strain is 58 mol %.</s><s>All strains were isolated from Lebanese spring waters.</s><s>No clinical significance is known.</s><s>Type strain is CFML 96-195<sup>T</sup>, deposited in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur as CIP 105460<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>