<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4820_nm.1600" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1600" rank="genus">Roseomonas</organism><reference id="rid.4820"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rihs</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>V.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Roseomonas, a new genus associated with bacteremia and other human infections.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>3275</fpage><lpage>3283</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8308122</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Roseomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Roseomonas</i> (Roz.e.o.mo'nas M.L. adj. <i>roseus</i>, rosy, rose-colored, or pink; Gr. n. <i>monas</i>, a unit; M.L. n. <i>Roseomonas</i>, a pink-pigmented bacterium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus are gram-negative, nonfermentative, plump coccoid rods, appearing in pairs or short chains, to mainly cocci with only an occasional rod.</s><s>They grow on 5% sheep blood agar, heart infusion agar with 5% rabbit blood, chocolate agar, BCYE agar, Trypticase soy agar, and almost always (91%) on MacConkey agar but do not grow in media containing 6% or more NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25, 30, 35, and, usually, 42°C.</s><s>Pinpoint, pale-pink, shiny, raised, entire, and often mucoid colonies appear on BCYE agar after 2 to 3 days of incubation at 35°C.</s><s>They are catalase and urease positive. <i>Roseomonas</i> species are negative in reactions for beta-hemolysis, indole production, ONPG, hydrogen sulfide production, gelatin liquefaction, phenylalanine deaminase, acetamide assimilation, growth in the presence of cetrimide, L-lysine and L-ornithine decarboxylases, and L-arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>They do not oxidize dulcitol, lactose, maltose, methanol, raffinose, L-rhamnose, or sucrose.</s><s>They do not absorb long-wave UV light.</s><s>The type strains of genomospecies 1 through 4 and 6 are motile and have a single polar flagellum.</s><s>The oxidase test must be considered variable, since many strains were weakly positive in tests at the VAMC and about 20% of strains were oxidase-negative in tests at CDC.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained in tests for citrate utilization, esculin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, and oxidation of L-arabinose, fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-mannose, D-mannitol, salicin, and D-xylose.</s><s>The GC content of DNA is 65 to 71 mol%.</s><s>The interrelatedness of species by DNA hybridization is 7 to 53%. <i>Roseomonas</i> spp. are pathogenic for humans, causing bacteremia and wound, urinary tract, and other infections.</s><s>The type species is <i>Roseomonas gilardii</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>