<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1315_nm.11833" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11833" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5881" rank="species">Corynebacterium variabilis</organism><reference id="rid.1315"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Arthrobacter variabilis, Muller to the genus Corynebacterium, as Corynebacterium variabilis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>288</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-287</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium variables</i> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, nonmotile, rod-shaped cells (0.8 to 1.1 by 1.4 to 3.5 μm). Cells are irregular (club-shaped or tapered) and occur singly, in pairs with typical V forms or clumps; ovoid forms occur in older cultures. Colonies are small (ca. 2 to 4 mm), circular (sometimes irregular), convex, and grey-white (occasionally slight pink) with a dry appearance. Optimum temperature is between 25 and 30°C. Grows in 7% NaCl. Acetate, propionate, capronate, 4-aminobutyrate, caprylate, succinate, DL-malate, levulinate, and some other compounds may be used as sole carbon sources (9). Xanthine, tyrosine, and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase positive, oxidase negative.</s><s>Murein is of the directly cross-linked type based on <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelicacid.</s><s>The glycan moiety of murein contains only acetyl residues.</s><s>The cell wall contains an arabinogalactan polymer.</s><s>Short-chain mycolic acids (30 to 36 carbon atoms) are present.</s><s>Long-chain fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated, mono-unsaturated, and 10-methyl-branched types.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The deoxyribonucleic	acid base composition is 65 mol% guanine plus cytosine (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The type strain is ATCC 15753 (NCIB 9455).</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain correspond to those of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Corynebacterium variabilis</i> can be readily distinguished from other Corynebacterium species in containing high levels of 10- methyloctadecanoic (tuberculostearic) acid.</s><s>The only other authentic <i>Corynebacterium</i> species known to contain this acid is <i>C. minutissirnum</i>. <i>C. variabilis</i>, however, can be readily distinguished from the latter species in being aerobic and in possessing a substantially higher guanine-plus-cytosine content (ca. 56 to 59 mol% for <i>C. minutissimum</i>) (1).</s></p></content></protolog>