<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8399_nm.13622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13622" rank="species">Spirosoma panaciterrae</organism><reference id="rid.8399"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>F.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirosoma panaciterrae sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>331</fpage><lpage>335</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002436-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196773</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Spirosoma panaciterrae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Spirosoma panaciterrae</em> (pa.na.ci.ter′rae. N.L. n. <em>Panax</em> -<em>acis</em> scientific name for ginseng; L. n. <em>terra</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>panaciterrae</em> of soil from a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped and do not form endospores.</s><s>Non-diffusible yellow pigments are produced.</s><s>Grows at 15–42 °C and pH 5.0–9.0; optimum growth occurs at 30 °C and pH 6.5–7.0.</s><s>Does not require NaCl for growth, but can tolerate 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar and TSA.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse gelatin and starch (weakly), but not chitin, xylan, carboxymethylcellulose, casein or DNA.</s><s>Produces <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Does not produce lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: l-arabinose, d-glucose, d-mannose, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and salicin.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-fructose, d-galactose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-fucose, l-sorbose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, inositol, d-mannitol, dulcitol, glycerol, glycogen, acetate, citrate, gluconate, 3- or 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, itaconate, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, malate, propionate, caprate, phenylacetate, adipate, lactate, suberate, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-proline or l-serine.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer reaction and tests for the production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-mannose (weakly), d-sorbitol, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin (weakly), cellobiose, maltose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, d-ribose, d- or l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate, or 2- or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, summed feature 4 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine is the major polar lipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 1519<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22263<sup>T</sup>=DSM 21099<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil of a ginseng field in Pocheon province (South Korea).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 50.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>