<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.227_nm.6361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6361" rank="species">Mycobacterium hodleri</organism><reference id="rid.227"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kleespies</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Webb</surname><given-names>L.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium hodleri sp. nov., a new member of the fast-growing mycobacteria capable of degrading polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>683</fpage><lpage>687</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-683</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782676</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium hodleri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium hodleri</i> (hod' le.ri. L.gen. n. <i>hodleri</i>, of Hodler, referring to Christian Hodler, director of the Ministry of Science and Culture of the State of Lower Saxony, Germany, and a strong supporter of natural sciences)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram positive, acid fast, nonspore forming, nonmotile, and rod shaped (length, 1.8 to 2.3 μm; diameter, 1 μm).</s><s>Some cells occur in V-form and in palisades.</s><s>Scotochromogenic, producing a saffron yellow pigment on Middlebrook agar and a chrome yellow pigment on Trypticase soy broth agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 18 and 28°C.</s><s>Aerobic and chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Utilizes N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-alanine, D-arabitol, L-aspartate, D-galactose, gluconate, D-glucose, inosotol, L-leucine, 2-oxoglutarate, L-proline, putrescine, quinate, D-ribose, L-rhamnose, L-serine, succinate, and L-valine.</s><s>Fluoranthene and rapeseed oil are utilized.</s><s>Capable of cooxidizing fluoranthene with several PAHs, including phenanthrene, fluorene, pyrene, and anthracene.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acetamide, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, caprate, D-sucrose, glucarate, D-glucosaminic acid, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 2-hydroxyvalarate, pimelate, phenylacetate, D-turnanose, and tyramine are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Long-chain mycolic acids present.</s><s>The fatty acids are mainly straight-chain saturated (C<sub>14:0</sub>, C<sub>16:0</sub>) and monounsaturated (C<sub>16:0</sub> <i>cis</i>-10 and C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>cis</i>-9) acids.</s><s>C<sub>18:0</sub>and C<sub>20:0</sub> alcohols and substantial amounts of tuberculostearic acid (10-methylbranched C<sub>18:0</sub>) are present.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 73 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a fluoranthene-contaminated site near Jülich, Germany.</s><s>The type strain is strain EMI2, which has been deposited in the DSMZ-Deutsche Sammlung für Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH as strain DSM 44183.</s></p></content></protolog>