<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.123_nm.3373" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3373" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3373" rank="subspecies">Pasteurella multocida gallicida</organism><reference id="rid.123"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ihm</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pohl</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frederiksen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mannheim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of the genus Pasteurella Trevisan 1887 on the basis of deoxyribonucleic acid homology, with proposals for the new species Pasteurella dagmatis, Pasteurella canis, Pasteurella stomatis, Pasteurella anatis, and Pasteurella langaa.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>309</fpage><lpage>322</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-3-309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella multocida</i> subsp. <i>gallicida</i> supsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>gallicida</i> (gal.li.ci'da. L.fem.n.<i>gallina</i> hen; L.adj.suf. <i>cida</i> kill; M.L.adj. <i>gallicida</i> hen killing, referring to pathogenicity for poultry)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the features consistent with all members of the genus, the biochemical reactions described below are common to the three subspecies.</s><s>Acid is produced from mannitol.</s><s>Positive ornithine decarboxylase reaction.</s><s>Acid is produced from trehalose; production of acid from D-xylose differs in different strains.</s><s>Exceptionally, acid is produced from raffinose, D-lactose, and (exceptionally) maltose.</s><s>No V-factor requirement.</s><s>The G+C contents of all subspecies range from 40.8 to 43.9 mol% (T<sub>m</sub> method).</s><s>The molecular weights of genome DNAs range from 1.5 X 10<sup>9</sup> to 1.9 X 10<sup>9</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The main characteristics used for differentiation of the three subspecies are fermentation of sorbitol and dulcitol. <i>P. multocida</i> subsp. <i>multocida</i> strains ferment sorbitol but do not ferment dulcitol; <i>P. multocida</i> subsp. <i>septica</i> strains exhibit negative reactions for both sorbitol and dulcitol fermentation, whereas the <i>P. multocida</i> subsp. <i>gallicida</i> strains ferment both sorbitol and dulcitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain NCTC 10204 is type strain of <i>P. multocida</i> subsp. <i>gallicida</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>