<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7275_nm.2482" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2482" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2482" rank="species">Alcanivorax borkumensis</organism><reference id="rid.7275"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yakimov</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Golyshin</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Timmis</surname><given-names>K.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alcanivorax borkumensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new, hydrocarbon-degrading and surfactant-producing marine bacterium.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>348</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-339</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731272</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alcanivorax borkumensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alcanivorax borkumensis</i> (bor.kum.en.sis. M.L. adj. <i>borkumensis</i> from the island of Borkum, a small island in Western-Elms harbour in the North Sea, located close to the German-Dutch border)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-motile aerobic rods.</s><s>The cultures grow at 4-35°C with an optimum between 25 and 30°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1.0-12.5% with an optimum between 3 and 10% NaCl.</s><s>Strains exhibit tweenase activity while agarase, amylase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, gelatinase and esculinase activities are not detected.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth is poor on complex bacteriological media and media containing carbohydrates and amino acids.</s><s>Aliphatic hydrocarbons, as well as selected short-chain fatty acids, including formate, acetate, propionate, methylpyruvate and α-ketoglutarate, are used as sole or principal carbon source for growth.</s><s>Strains are able to grow on α-, β- and 𝛾-hydroxybutyrates, although their polymers are not accumulated.</s><s>A mixture of active biosurfactants, glucose lipids, are produced, one of which consists of four 3-hydroxydecanoic acids linked together by ester bonds and coupled glycosidically with the C-1 of glucose.</s><s>The principal fatty acids in PLFA profile are 16:0, 16:1 and 18:1.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 53.4 mol%.</s><s>According to the 16s rRNA sequence, the bacteria belong to the 𝛾-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> and occupy an intermediate position in a distinct, monophyletic cluster between the genera <i>Marinobacter</i> and <i>Halomonas</i>.</s><s>The type strain is SK2<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The type strain SK2<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures (DSMZ) as strain DSM 11573<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>