<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3859_nm.8758" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8758" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8758" rank="species">Paenibacillus cookii</organism><reference id="rid.3859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhelst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus cineris sp. nov. and Paenibacillus cookii sp. nov., from Antarctic volcanic soils and a gelatin-processing plant</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1071</fpage><lpage>1076</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02967-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280271</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus cookii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus cookii</em> [cook′i.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>cookii</em> of Cook, referring to Captain James Cook, of HMS <em>Resolution</em>, who discovered Candlemas Island on Candlemas Day (2 February), 1775].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, round-ended rods (0·6–0·8×3·0–3·5 μm) occurring singly and in pairs.</s><s>Gram-negative or Gram-variable.</s><s>Endospores are formed within 2–3 days incubation on BFA incubated at 30 °C; they are ellipsoidal, lie subterminally and swell the sporangia slightly (Fig. 1, bottom).</s><s>After 2 days at 30 °C, colonies are 1–4 mm in diameter, convex, yellowish and transparent with opaque centres; motile microcolonies are formed and spread across the surface of the agar, rotating clockwise and anticlockwise (Supplementary Fig. A).</s><s>Grows on nutrient agar.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive or weakly positive and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Minimum temperature for growth lies between 15 and 20 °C and the maximum growth temperature is 50 °C.</s><s>Minimum pH for growth lies between 5 and 5·5, the optimum pH for growth is 7·0 and the maximum pH for growth lies between 7·5 and 10.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5 % NaCl, but is inhibited by 7 % NaCl.</s><s>Casein hydrolysis is positive but weak.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, ONPG hydrolysis, Voges–Proskauer reaction and nitrate reduction are positive.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin is variable while reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and indole production are negative.</s><s>In the API 50CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium, hydrolysis of aesculin is positive and acid is produced without gas from the following carbohydrates: amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, lactose, maltose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, methyl xyloside, d-raffinose, ribose, salicin, starch, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-turanose, d-xylose.</s><s>Production of acid without gas is variable for the following carbohydrates: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-fructose (weak), l-fucose, gluconate (weak), 5-keto-d-gluconate (weak), d-mannose and methyl d-mannoside.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, mannitol, rhamnose, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Sensitive to disks of the antibiotics ampicillin (25 μg), chloramphenicol (50 μg), colistin sulphate (100 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (50 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and tetracycline (100 μg).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 36, 20, 13, 11 and 6·5 % of total fatty acids).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller, decreasing amounts (between about 5 and 1 %): iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (Supplementary Table).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 51·6 mol% for the type strain, strain LMG 18419<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108110<sup>T</sup>=Logan collection no. B1718<sup>T</sup>=isolate SSI018); the 16S rDNA sequence of this strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJ250317.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain has a minimum growth temperature of 20 °C and grows in the pH range 5·0–9·5; it does not hydrolyse gelatin; acid production is positive for l-fucose, weak for gluconate and d-mannose and negative for <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-fructose, 5-keto-d-gluconate and methyl d-mannoside.</s><s>Reference strains are LMG 18437, R-11600, R-11662, R-11664, R-11665 and R-11666.</s><s>Isolated from geothermal soil taken from an active fumarole on Lucifer Hill, a volcano on Candlemas Island, South Sandwich archipelago, Antarctica, and from a gelatin extract of bovine bones (strain R-11600).</s></p></content></protolog>