<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9585_nm.14774" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14774" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14774" rank="species">Ferruginibacter alkalilentus</organism><reference id="rid.9585"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ferruginibacter alkalilentus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Ferruginibacter lapsinanis sp. nov., novel members of the family ‘Chitinophagaceae’ in the phylum Bacteroidetes, isolated from freshwater sediment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2394</fpage><lpage>2399</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009480-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620358</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ferruginibacter alkalilentus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ferruginibacter alkalilentus</em> (al.ka.li.len′tus. N.L. n. <em>alkali</em> from the Arabic word <em>al-qaliy</em>, the ashes of saltwort; L. adj. <em>lentus</em>, <em>-a</em>, <em>-um</em> tough, resistant; N.L. masc. adj. <em>alkalilentus</em> resistant to alkaline solution, referring to negative reaction for the flexirubin-KOH test).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-like cells occur as single units, 0.3−0.5 μm in diameter, but vary in length and shape depending on age.</s><s>Cells of young cultures (2 days old) are straight, slender, 3−5 μm long, with slightly tapered ends; cells of 5-day-old cultures are curved or sometimes semicircle-shaped (strain-dependent), 1−3 μm long with rounded or tapered (strain-dependent) ends.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A at 30 °C for 5 days are circular and convex with an entire margin, 0.7−1.2 mm in diameter, translucent, glossy and rusty in colour, and tend to be slimy.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 18−30 °C; growth rate is strain-dependent.</s><s>Cells grow within the pH range 6−8 in the presence of less than 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>No growth on either MacConkey agar or nutrient agar (Difco).</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, nitrite reduction and acetoin production from pyruvate are not observed.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, skim milk and urea are hydrolysed, but hydroxyethylcellulose, DNA, starch and xylan are not.</s><s>No acid is produced from amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose or d-sucrose.</s><s>Activity for arginine dihydrolase is present, but activities for lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are not.</s><s>2-Naphthylphosphate (pH 8.5), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate (weakly) and <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside (weakly) are hydrolysed, but <em>N</em>-benzoyl-dl-arginine 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthylbutyrate, l-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, <em>N</em>-glutarylphenylalanine 2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl-<em>α</em>-l-fucopyranoside, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside and l-valyl-2-naphthylamide are not.</s><s>Hydrolysis of l-naphthyl-<em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-glucosaminide is strain-dependent (negative for type strain).</s><s>All strains can utilize d-raffinose, d-trehalose, xylitol (weakly) and d-xylose as sole carbon sources, but the following compounds are not assimilated: adipate, adonitol, l-alanine, amygdalin, benzoate, caprate, d-cellobiose, dextran, formate, d-fructose, l-fucose, fumarate, d-galactose, glutarate, glycogen, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inulin, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, dl-lactate, d-lactose, d-lyxose, malate, maleate, malonate, d-maltose, oxalate, phenylacetate, l-proline, propionate, pyruvate, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-serine, l-sorbose, suberate, succinate, tartrate, tyrosine, valerate and l-xylose.</s><s>Utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-melibiose and d-sucrose (positive for type strain), acetate, l-arabinose, citrate, gluconate, d-glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose and d-sorbitol (weakly positive for type strain) and d-arabinose (negative for type strain) are strain-dependent.</s><s>Additional characteristics are listed in Tables 1–3 and the genus description, or described elsewhere in the text.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HU1-GD23<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22306<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24312<sup>T</sup>), and four other strains, HU1-GB11 (=KCTC 22307=LMG 24310), HU1-ID41 (=KCTC 22308=LMG 24325), HU1-IH3 (=KCTC 22304=LMG 24326) and HU1-JE21 (=KCTC 22303=LMG 24327), were isolated from freshwater sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>