<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7253_nm.5527" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5527" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5527" rank="species">Enterococcus asini</organism><reference id="rid.7253"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de Vaux</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laguerre</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Diviès</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus asini sp. nov. isolated from the caecum of donkeys (Equus asinus).</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>383</fpage><lpage>387</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-383</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731276</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus asini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus asini</i> (asi'ni. M.L. gen. sing. asini of donkeys, Equus asinus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci, ovoid and occur mostly in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Non-pigmented and nonmotile.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Lancefield group D-antigen-positive.</s><s>Grow at 40°C but growth at 10 and 45 °C is weak.</s><s>No growth in 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Grow in a 40% bile M17 broth.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-xylose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, N-acetyl-glucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, starch and β-gentibiose.</s><s>Weak reactions can occur on rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, D- and L-arabinose, ribose, L-xylose, adonitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, β-methylxyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D- and L-fucose, D- and L-arabitol, gluconate and 2- and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Aesculin and hippurate hydrolysis are positive.</s><s>Strains are positive for leucine arylaminidase, pyrrolidonylarylaminidase and β-glucosidase and negative for agalactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>The reactions of the type strain are the same as the majority of the reactions for <i>E. asini</i> given in Table 1 with the exceptions indicated by the footnotes.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is about 39.4 mol % as determined by the UV absorbancy ratio.</s><s>At the molecular level, this species can be differentiated from other <i>Enterococcus</i> species by the sequence of 16s rRNA gene.</s><s>Strain AS2<sup>T</sup> is the type strain of <i>E. asini</i> and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (DSMZ, Braunschweig, Germany) as strain DSM 11492<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>