<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2808_nm.3910" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3910" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3910" rank="species">Clostridium cellulofermentans</organism><reference id="rid.2808"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Long</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two cellulolytic Clostridium species: Clostridium cellulosi sp. nov. and Clostridium cellulofermentans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>306</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-306</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854643</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium cellulofermentans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium cellulofermentans</i> (cellulofermentans, N.L. adj. cellulose fermenting)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, straight or slightly curved rods which are 0.4 to 0.7 μm wide by 1.5 to 7.0 μm long.</s><s>They occur singly, in pairs, and occasionally in short or long chains.</s><s>Spherical or oval terminal endospores cause marked swelling of the cells (Fig. 3).</s><s>Mature spores are 0.8 to 1.2 μm in diameter.</s><s>They survive 100°C for 10 min.</s><s>Cells are motile with peritrichous flagella (Fig. 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on cellulose agar medium are white, opaque, circular, and flat or slightly convex, with entire or slightly undulate margins.</s><s>Clear zones in cellulose agar are usually observed after 48 or 72 h of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic medium is necessary for initiation of growth.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 37 to 40°C, and the temperature range is 20 to 45°C.</s><s>No growth is produced at 15 or 50°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.0 to 7.2, with a range of 6.0 to 8.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase, gelatinase, acetylmethylcarbinol, and indole are not produced.</s><s>Sulfate is not reduced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced, and milk is curdled.</s><s>Only slight growth occurs in PY medium with no fermentable carbohydrate.</s><s>The other biochemical characteristics are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products of cellulose fermentation are hydrogen, carbon dioxide, ethanol, and acetic acid.</s><s>The ratio of ethanol to acetic acid is about 1:1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil of a dairy farm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA composition is 34 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>C. cellulofermentans</i> is strain AS 1.1775.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Both <i>C. cellulosi</i> AS 1.1777 and <i>C. cellulofermentans</i> AS 1.1775 are deposited in the China Committee for Culture Collection of Microorganisms.</s></p></content></protolog>