<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7384_nm.6636" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6636" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6636" rank="species">Tessaracoccus bendigoensis</organism><reference id="rid.7384"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maszenan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seviour</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rees</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tessaracoccus bendigoensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a gram-positive coccus occurring in regular packages or tetrads, isolated from activated sludge biomass</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>459</fpage><lpage>468</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-459</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319465</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tessaracoccus bendigoensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tessaracoccus bendigoensis</i> (ben.di.go'en. sis. M. L. adj. <i>bendigoensis</i> referring to Bendigo, the place of origin of the isolate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following sugars and sugar derivatives are utilized: L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-fructose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, sucrose, turanose, D-raffinose, D-xylose, stachyose, palatinose, maltotriose, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-galactoside, methyl β-D-galactoside, α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, dextrin, amygladin, arbutin, glycogen, D-mannitol, methylpyruvate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, DL-glycerol phosphate, UMP, glycerol, uridine and salicin, but not cellobiose, L-fucose, D-psicose, L-rhamnose, D-trehalose, D-melezitose, 3-methylglucose, methyl β-D-glucoside, mannan, adonitol, D-arabitol, <i>i</i>-erythritol, <i>m</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, xylitol, monomethylsuccinate, D-galacturonic acid lactone, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, inulin, fructose 6-phosphate, methylsuccinate, adenosine, 2'-deoxyadenosine, AMP, TMP, D-tagatose, methyl α-D-mannoside or sedoheptulosan.</s><s>The following organic acids, amino acids and their derivatives are utilized: acetic acid, D-gluconic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, DL-lactic acid, L-lactic acid and pyruvic acid, but not cis-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galacturonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, Dglucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, 𝛾-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-L-aspartic acid, glycyl-L-glutamic acid, L-pyroglutamic acid, 𝛾-aminobutyric acid, uroconic acid, D-lactic acid methyl ester, D-malic acid, Lmalic acid and N-acetyl-L-glutamic acid.</s><s>The following substrates are metabolized: N-acetyl-D-glucosamine and uridine.</s><s>The following substrates are not metabolized: Tween 40, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetylmannosamine, glucuronamide, alaninamide, lactamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanylglycine, L-asparagine, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, D-serine, Lserine, L-threonine, DL-carnitine, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine and hydroxy-L-proline.</s><s>It possesses the following enzymes: alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, 2-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, pglucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase.</s><s>Cells lack trypsin, chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>It does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S and indole.</s><s>It is Voges-Proskauer-positive and can produce acetoin.</s><s>It can liquefy gelatin.</s><s>The natural habitat is activated sludge.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is between 20 and 37°C; pH range for growth is between 6.0 and 9.0.</s><s>Optimal growth is at 25°C and at pH 7.5.</s><s>The type strain, Ben 106<sup>T</sup>, has been deposited in the Australian Collection of Microorganisms as strain ACM 5119<sup>T</sup></s></p></content></protolog>