<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3903_nm.11347" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11347" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11347" rank="species">Marinobacter segnicrescens</organism><reference id="rid.3903"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>Y.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kida</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter segnicrescens sp. nov., a moderate halophile isolated from benthic sediment of the South China Sea.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1970</fpage><lpage>1974</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65030-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766857</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter segnicrescens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter segnicrescens</em> (seg.ni.cres′cens. L. adj. <em>segnis</em> slow; L. part. adj. <em>crescens</em> growing; N.L. part. adj. <em>segnicrescens</em> slowly growing, referring to the slow growth of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, ellipsoid-shaped (0.6–0.7 μm in width and 0.9–1.2 μm in length) and motile coccobacilli.</s><s>Colonies on MA are smooth, circular, flat, slightly transparent and cream-coloured or light yellow after 3–5 days cultivation at 30 °C.</s><s>Cultivation for 3 days is required to obtain a cell concentration similar to that obtained after 1 day for other <em>Marinobacter</em> species.</s><s>No spores are observed and cells are not heat-resistant.</s><s>Growth occurs in 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 4–8 % NaCl), at temperatures between 15 and 45 °C (optimum, 30–37 °C) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, 7.5–8.0).</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, nitrate reduction, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, but negative for nitrite reduction, Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 80, but not starch, gelatin or urease.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin, tetracycline, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, erythromycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Utilizes d-fructose, d-glucose, trehalose, d-gluconic acid, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, sucrose, acetate, citric acid, succinic acid, propionate, l-sorbose, pyruvate, d-ribose and malic acid, but not dextrin, maltose, d-mannitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-alanine, l-proline, formic acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, l-glutamic acid, d-xylose, ethanol, l-isoleucine, l-arginine, d-melezitose, l-lysine, glycine, toluene, n-tetradecane or crude oil.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is Q9 and the main cellular polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and an unknown glycolipid.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>19 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>10<em>c</em> cyclo, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SS011B1-4<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23928<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6489<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from benthic sediment of the South China Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>