<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3701_nm.9327" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9327" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9327" rank="species">Fastidiosipila sanguinis</organism><reference id="rid.3701"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Welinder-Olsson</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fastidiosipila sanguinis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new Gram-positive, coccus-shaped organism from human blood.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>853</fpage><lpage>858</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63327-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774674</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fastidiosipila sanguinis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fastidiosipila sanguinis</em> (san′gui.nis. L. gen. n. <em>sanguinis</em> of blood, referring to the source of the organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of small cocci (approx. 0·5 μm in diameter) that stain Gram-positive.</s><s>After 48 h anaerobic incubation at 37 °C, colonies are small, pinpoint and grey in colour.</s><s>Grows under anaerobic conditions and also in 2 and 6 % O<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Grows poorly on Fastidious Anaerobe Agar (Oxoid) and Fastidious Anaerobe Broth with meat granules.</s><s>In the latter, small amounts of acetic and butyric acids are detected.</s><s>Lecithinase, lipase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API Rapid ID 32S system, activity is detected for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase and <em>β</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, glycyl trypyophan arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase or urease; <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activity may or may not be detected.</s><s>Hippurate is hydrolysed and acetoin is not produced.</s><s>In the API Rapid ID 32A system, positive reactions are obtained for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase (weak), arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucine arylamidase (weak) and <em>α</em>-fucosidase; reactions for serine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase are either weakly positive or negative.</s><s>Activity is not detected for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenyl alanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Indole is not produced and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Sensitive to kanamycin (1000 μg) and vancomycin (5 μg), but resistant to colistin sulfate (10 μg) and metronidazole (5 μg) identification discs.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 32·9 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from human blood.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 47711<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108292<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>