<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.754_nm.6589" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6589" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6589" rank="species">Dactylosporangium fulvum</organism><reference id="rid.754"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amano</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Dactylosporangium fulvum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>166</fpage><lpage>169</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Dactylosporangium fulvum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Dactylosporangium fulvum</i> (ful'vum. L. neut. adj. <i>fulvum</i> yellowish brown, referring to the color of the vegetative mycelium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The formation of finger-shaped sporangia containing motile spores, the absence of true aerial mycelia, and the presence of type II cell walls place strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> in the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> Thiemann, Pagani, and Beretta (20).</s><s>Five species, <i>D. aurantiacum</i> (20), <i>D. thailandense</i> (19, 20), <i>D. matsuzakiense</i> (16), <i>D. vinaceum</i> (17), and <i>D. ruseum,</i> (14), were described previously as members of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i>.</s><s>We compared strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> directly with type strains of these species.</s><s>The morphology of the finger-shaped sporangia and the spores did not differ significantly from that of any of the known species.</s><s>In addition to finger-shaped sporangia, the formation of globose bodies was proposed as an additional morphological characteristic of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i> (20).</s><s>Sharples and Williams (11) reported that the globose bodies seemed to be products of abnormal development, induced by bacteriophage infection or other factors which cause hyphal lysis.</s><s>Strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> produced globose bodies abundantly.</s><s>Among the known species, <i>D. aurantiacum</i> and <i>D. thailandense</i> produced globose bodies as abundantly as strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup>, whereas the other three species either did not produce them or produced them sparsely (Table 2).</s><s>Furthermore, strains SF-2113<sup>T</sup> formed coremia abundantly.</s><s>The formation of coremia, also called synnemata, have been reported for various genera of the order <i>Actinomycetales</i>.</s><s>Although the taxonomic significance of coremia is not clear, their formation is an important characteristic in the genus <i>Actinosynnema</i> (4).</s><s>Strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> formed abundant coremia regularly on oatmeal agar and inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>None of the other five species formed coremia on these media (Table 2).</s><s>With respect to coremia formation, therefore, strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> differs from the known species.</s><s>Furthermore, strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> differs clearly from the five other species in its cultural and physiological characteristics, as described below. <i>D. vinaceum</i> produced a wine to deep red diffusible pigment on almost all of the media used, whereas strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> did not produce an obvious diffusible pigment on any of the same media. <i>D. roseum</i> showed a distinctive rose reverse color on yeast extract-malt extract agar (ISP medium 2), inorganic salts-starch agar, and especially on sucroseyeast extract agar, whereas the reverse color of strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> was yellowish brown to brown on these media.</s><s>The distinctive reverse color of <i>D. aurantiacum</i>, <i>D. thailandense</i>, and <i>D. matsuzakiense</i> was orange, whereas strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> never showed orange color on any of the media used.</s><s>In addition, strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> differed from these three species in some physiological properties, such as the utilization of L-rhamnose and the production of antibiotic (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In view of the characteristics described above, strain SF-2113<sup>T</sup> should be considered a new species of the genus <i>Dactylosporangium</i>, for which we propose the name <i>Dactylosporangium fulvum</i> sp. nov.</s><s>Strain SF-2113 is the type strain of <i>D. fulvum</i>; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the Institute for Fermentation, Osaka, Japan, as strain IFO 14381.</s></p></content></protolog>