<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7348_nm.6209" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6209" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6209" rank="species">Corynebacterium confusum</organism><reference id="rid.7348"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osorio</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frei</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium confusum sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1291</fpage><lpage>1296</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828429</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium confusum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium confusum</i> (con.fu'sum. L. past part. <i>confusum</i> confusing, to indicate that this bacterium might be phenotypically confused with many other <i>Conynebacaterium</i> species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is based on the results of the studies of three strains.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and non-motile.</s><s>They are typically club-shaped rods that occur as single cells, in pairs or in small clusters.</s><s>Colonies are whitish, glistening, convex, creamy and up to 1.5 mm in diameter after 48 h incubation.</s><s>Weak anaerobic growth.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, ribose, D-fructose, tagatose and 5-ketogluconate, but acid is not produced from maltose, sucrose, mannitol, D-xylose, glycerol, erythritol, arabinose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, galactose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, methyl α-D-mannoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, D-turanose, D-lyxose, fucose, arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from β-gentiobiose is variable.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Urea, aesculin and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is negative.</s><s>Activities of pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>2</sub>) and esterase lipase (C<sub>2</sub>) are detected, whereas pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>Activities of leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase are variable.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acid are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>Minor amounts of tuberculostearic acid are present.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>The type strain DMMZ 2439<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Gothenburg, Sweden, as strain CCUC 38267<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>It has the features described above except that acid production from β-gentiobiose is positive and activities of leucine arylamidase and phosphoa midase are detected.</s></p></content></protolog>