<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.483_nm.2993" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2993" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2993" rank="species">Vibrio pacinii</organism><reference id="rid.483"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gomez-Gil</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>F.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio pacinii sp. nov., from cultured aquatic organisms.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1569</fpage><lpage>1573</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02670-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130050</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio pacinii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio pacinii</em> (pa.ci′ni.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>pacinii</em> of Pacini, named after the Italian anatomist Filipo Pacini, who first discovered the causal agent of cholera).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, motile, with polar flagella.</s><s>Non-luminescent, non-pigmented, translucent colonies on marine agar with no swarming.</s><s>Round, firm, yellow bright colonies on TCBS agar, 1·5–2·8 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 1·5, 2·5, 6·0 and 8·0 % NaCl but not at 0, 10·0 or 12·0 %; can grow at 4, 30 and 35 °C but not at 40 °C in TSB.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive, ferments glucose and lactose; arginine and l-tyrosine dihydrolase-positive, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase-negative.</s><s>Positive for Voges–Proskauer test (except for strain LMG 13245), methyl red, tryptophan deaminase and nitrate reduction; negative for indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S and urease.</s><s>Test for citrate utilization is weakly positive, except for strain LMG 13245, which is strongly positive.</s><s>Positive activity of acid phosphatase (LMG 13245 is weak), <em>α</em>-glucosidase (LMG 21514 is weak), alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) (LMG 13245 is weak), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase (LMG 13245 and LMG 21514 are weak).</s><s>Negative activity of <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin (LMG 19999<sup>T</sup> is weakly positive), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and trypsin.</s><s>All strains utilize <em>α</em>-d-glucose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-mannitol, d-trehalose, gentiobiose, inosine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, sucrose, thymidine and uridine as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>None of the strains utilized 2,3-butanediol, 2-aminoethanol, acetic acid, adonitol, alaninamide, <em>α</em>-d-lactose lactulose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, bromosuccinic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, dl-carnitine, d-alanine, d-arabitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-saccharic acid, d-serine, formic acid, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, glycerol, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy l-proline, i-erythritol, itaconic acid, l-arabinose, l-fucose, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-rhamnose, l-threonine, malonic acid, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, phenylethylamine, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, propionic acid, putrescine, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, turanose, Tween 40, Tween 80, urocanic acid or xylitol.</s><s>The following cellular fatty acids are present in decreasing order (mean percentage of the three strains analysed, minimum and maximum of total fatty acid content): C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (18·7 %, 14·1–25·5), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (11·1 %, 9·9–13·4), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (9·0 %, 8·4–9·7, not detected in LMG 21514), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (6·9 %, 4·7–11·2), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (3·7 %, 1·9–5·2), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3·1 %, 1·5–4·9), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1·9 %, 1·1–2·7, not detected in LMG 21514), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1·4 %, 0·9–2·0, not detected in LMG 21514), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (summed feature 3) (38·7 %, 37·8–39·2) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I (summed feature 2) (2·9 %, 1·5–3·6).</s><s>Eighteen other fatty acids are present in percentages below 1·0, these are: iso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, 11-methyl C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>Antibiotic susceptibility was observed to chloramphenicol (30 μg), oxolinic acid (2 μg), oxytetracycline (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 U), tetracycline (30 μg); resistant to gentamicin (10 μg) (except for LMG 21514, which is intermediate), kanamycin (30 μg), streptomycin (25 μg) and vibriostatic agent O/129 at 10 and 150 μg.</s><s>Additional phenotypic features are listed in Table 2.</s><s>G+C content of the DNA is 44·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 19999<sup>T</sup> (=CAIM 530<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from shrimp larvae (<em>Penaeus chinensis</em>) in the Dahua hatchery in Laizhou (Shandong Province, China).</s><s>Reference strains are LMG 13245 (=CAIM 526) and LMG 21514 (=CAIM 466).</s></p></content></protolog>