<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12788_nm.22577" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22577" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22577" rank="species">Pontirhabdus pectinivorans</organism><reference id="rid.12788"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pontirhabdus pectinivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2475</fpage><lpage>2481</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027441-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21097642</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pontirhabdus pectinivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pontirhabdus pectinivorans</em> (pec.ti.ni.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>pectinum</em> pectin; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>pectinivorans</em> pectin-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following characteristics in addition to those given for the genus.</s><s>Grows under aerobic and microaerobic conditions, but not under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.4–0.6×1.0–2.4 µm.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, convex, translucent, glistening, circular with entire margins.</s><s>Glides on agar plates.</s><s>Does not grow on cetrimide or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5 (optimum, pH 7) and 4–35 °C (optimum, 30 °C).</s><s>Requires sea salts concentration of 1–7 % (w/v) (optimum, 2–3 %) for growth and cannot grow on sea salts-free ZoBell’s medium supplemented with NaCl only.</s><s>Produces acetoin.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite or nitrogen.</s><s>Does not produce indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Does not utilize citrate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Decomposes elastin, aesculin, gelatin, pectin, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 and l-tyrosine, but not agar, adenine, alginic acids, casein, cellulose, chitin, egg yolk, hypoxanthine, starch or xanthine.</s><s>Positive in tests for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, and weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8), but negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>β-Galactosidase activity is negative in API ZYM and API 20E kits, but positive in the API 20NE kit.</s><s>On the basis of the API 50CH system, utilizes the following carbohydrates as sole carbon source: d-xylose, d-galactose, d-mannose, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin) and sucrose, but cannot utilize d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-fructose, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, melibiose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, gentiobiose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, glycogen, turanose, glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>On the basis of the API 50CH system, is able to produce acid from d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, amygdalin, aesculin ferric citrate, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin), sucrose and gentiobiose.</s><s>Produces acid weakly from d-fructose and salicin but no production from d-arabinose, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, melibiose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, glycogen, turanose, glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The fatty acids include iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> G, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub> A, summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 2-OH, iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>15 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>13 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JC2675<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14153<sup>T</sup> = JCM 17107<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample from Jeju Island, Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 30 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>