<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6864_nm.6210" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6210" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6210" rank="species">Corynebacterium coyleae</organism><reference id="rid.6864"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual Ramos</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium coyleae sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>92</fpage><lpage>96</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-92</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995809</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium coyleae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium coyleae</i> (coy'le.ae. N.L. gen. n. <i>coyleae</i>, of Coyle, to honor Marie B. Coyle, a contemporary American microbiologist, for her contributions to the clinical microbiology of coryneform bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of morphological and physiological characteristics below is based on the results of studies of six strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, nonmotile, non-spore-forming diphtheroids.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, and slightly glistening; some colonies have a creamy consistency, and others have a sticky consistency.</s><s>The colony diameter is about 1 mm after 24 h of incubation on sheep blood agar at 37°C.</s><s>Very weak anaerobic growth.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, ribose, D-fructose, D-mannose, and 5-keto-gluconate but not from maltose, sucrose, mannitol, xylose, glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, galactose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fUCOSe, L-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, and 2-keto- gluconate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea, esculin, casein, tyrosine, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is strongly positive.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase-lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, and phosphoamidase activities are detected, but valine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase activity is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 62 to 64 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>Type strain DMMZ 214 has been deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms and cell cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 44184 and in the Culture Collection of the University of Goteborg, Göteborg, Sweden, as strain CCUG 35014.</s><s>Strain DSM44184<sup>T</sup> has the characteristics described above for the species except that it has a negative pyrrolidonyl arylamidase reaction and a G+C content of 62 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>