<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2375_nm.7609" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7609" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7609" rank="species">Actinomadura nitritigenes</organism><reference id="rid.2375"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lipski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Altendorf</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura nitritigenes sp. nov., isolated from experimental biofilters.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>717</fpage><lpage>723</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomadura nitritigenes</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomadura nitritigenes</i> (ni.tri.i’ge.nes. L. n. <i>nitritum</i>, nitrite; Gr. v. suff <i>.-genes</i>, producing; L. adj. <i>nitritigenes</i>, nitrite producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose the name <i>Actinomadura nitritigenes</i> for isolates L20, L34, L46<i>T</i>, and L81.</s><s>The type strain is strain L46. <i>A. nitritigenes</i> forms branching vegetative and aerial mycelia.</s><s>Spores are produced in straight or hooklike chains that are up to seven spores long.</s><s>The spore surface is smooth.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Degrades casein, esculin, Tween 20, Tween 80, hypoxanthine, and testosterone.</s><s>Does not degrade adenine, guanine, xanthine, and xylan and does not form H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite even under aerobic incubation conditions.</s><s>Grows on glucose, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glycerol, mannose, rhamnose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, L-proline, and L-tyrosine.</s><s>Does not grow on lactose, maltose, L-alanine, propionate, pyruvate, and L-serine.</s><s>Grows at 45°C.</s><s>Contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, an acetyl type of peptidoglycan, and madurose.</s><s>Phospholipid type PI.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) is the major menaquinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid and tuberculostearic acid; minor amounts of 2-hydroxyhexadecanoic acid occur.</s><s>Aerobic and mesophilic.</s><s>All strains were isolated from experimental biofilters which were filled with tree bark compost as filter material and supplied with ammonia.</s><s>Isolate L46<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44137<sup>T</sup>) has been deposited in the DSM-Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulicuren GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>