<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7205_nm.6247" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6247" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6247" rank="species">Corynebacterium mucifaciens</organism><reference id="rid.7205"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium mucifaciens sp. nov., an unusual species from human clinical material.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>952</fpage><lpage>957</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336892</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium mucifaciens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium mucifaciens</i> (mu.ci.fa'ci.ens. L. n. <i>mucus</i>, slime; L. part. adj. <i>faciens</i>, producing; L. part. adj. <i>mucifiaciens</i>, slime producing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics given below are based on the results of studies of eight strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and nonmotile and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, glistening, slightly yellowish, and mucoid.</s><s>Colony diameters are about 1 to 1.5 mm after 24 h of incubation on sheep blood agar at 37°C.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, glucose, fructose, and mannose but not from erythritol, arabinose, xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, galactose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl- D-glucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, maltose, lactose, melibiose, trehalose, melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, fucose, arabitol, gluconate, and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid production from ribose and sucrose is variable.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Not lipophilic.</s><s>CAMP reaction negative.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase-lipase, cystine arylamidase, and acid phosphatase are positive, whereas pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and phosphoamidase are variable.</s><s>Lipase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63 to 65 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens.</s><s>Type strain DSM 2278 has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg, Göteborg, Sweden, as CCUG 36878, in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as DSM 44265, and in the Culture Collection of the Institut Pasteur, Paris, France, as CIP 105129.</s><s>Strain CCUG 36878<sup>T</sup> has the characteristics described above for the species, except that it is positive for pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, phosphoamidase, ribose, and sucrose reactions.</s><s>Its G+C content is 64 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>