<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1236_nm.1493" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1493" rank="genus">Rhodopseudomonas</organism><reference id="rid.1236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rearrangements of the species and genera of the phototrophic "purple nonsulfur bacteria."</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>340</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of genus <i>Rhodopseudomuonas</i> Kluyver and van Niel in Czurda and Maresch 1937.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Type species: <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> (Molisch 1907) van Niel 1944. Other species: <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> Drews and Giesbrecht 1966, <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> Pfennig 1969, <i>Rhodopseudomonas sulfoviridis</i> Keppen and Gorlenko 1975, <i>Rhodopseudomonas blastica</i> Eckersley and Dow 1981, <i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> Akiba et al. 1983 (2), and <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> Imhoff 1983. Species removed from this genus: <i>Rhodopseudomonas capsulata</i> (Molisch 1907) van Niel 1944, <i>Rhodopseudomonas sphaeroides</i> van Niel 1944, <i>Rhodopseudomonas gelatinosa</i> (Molisch 1907) van Niel 1944, <i>Rhodopseudomonas sulfidophila</i> Hansen and Veldkamp 1973, <i>Rhodopseudomonas globiformis</i> Pfennig 1974, and <i>Rhodopseudomonas adriatica</i> Neutzling et al. 1984.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped, show polar growth, asymmetrical division, or budding as a mode of reproduction, are motile by means of flagella, and have intracytoplasmic membranes that are adjacent and parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth factor requirements and sensitivity to oxygen are different in the various species. <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> have a small type of cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub>; <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> differs from these species by containing different cytochromes and by the presence of a large type of cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The cytochrome structures of the other species in this genus are not known.</s><s>Studies of lipopolysaccharides have revealed 2,3-diamino-2,3-dideoxyglucose as an unique structural component of <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i>, <i>Rhodopseudomonas sulfoviridis</i>, and <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i>, but not of <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i>.</s><s>Data on the lipopolysaccharide structures of the other species are not available.</s><s>The quinones present in the various species of this genus are also different. <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas blastica</i> have Q-10 as the sole quinone component, whereas <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas marina</i> have MK-10 in addition.</s><s>The quinones of the other species differ in the length of the isoprenoid chain.</s><s>So far four species have been analyzed with respect to the pathway of sulfate assimilation; <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> reduce 3'-phosphate adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate, <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> reduces adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate, and <i>Rhodopseudomonas sulfoviridis</i> is not able to reduce sulfate at all.</s><s>From 16s rRNA studies it is known that <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i> and <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i> have similar oligonucleotide catalogs.</s><s>Hybridization studies of DNA and rRNA have led to the arrangement of <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i>, <i>Rhodopseudomonas viridis</i>, and <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> on one branch of “superfamily IV,” whereas <i>Rhodopseudomonas blastica</i> is placed on another branch of this superfamily together with the species included in the new genus <i>Rhodobacter</i>.</s><s>Because of its morphological properties and since other conflicting results are lacking, <i>Rhodopseudomonas blastica</i> is retained in the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i>.</s><s>The recently described species <i>Rhodopseudomonas rutila</i> is classified with this genus on the basis of its polar growth and budding, as well as its lamellar intracytoplasmic membranes, which are parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell shape, mode of growth, and reproduction, as well as the structure of the intracytoplasmic membranes, are the characteristic properties that allow unequivocal classification of new species in this genus.</s></p></content></protolog>