<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.579_nm.4952" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4952" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4952" rank="species">Bacillus novalis</organism><reference id="rid.579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanparys</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Felske</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus novalis sp. nov., Bacillus vireti sp. nov., Bacillus soli sp. nov., Bacillus bataviensis sp. nov. and Bacillus drentensis sp. nov., from the Drentse A grasslands.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02723-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus novalis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus novalis</em> (no.va′lis. L. gen. n. <em>novalis</em> of fallow land).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, facultatively anaerobic, motile, slightly curved, round-ended rods (0·6–1·2 μm in diameter), occurring singly and in pairs and occasionally in short chains or filaments.</s><s>Endospores are mainly ellipsoidal and lie in subterminal, and occasionally paracentral, positions in slightly swollen sporangia (Fig. 3a).</s><s>When grown on TSA, colonies are raised, with slightly irregular margins and smooth or eggshell-textured surfaces, sometimes with an iridescent centre when viewed by low-powered microscopy; the consistency is butyrous.</s><s>Colonies are cream-coloured and produce a light-brown pigment that diffuses into the agar.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30–40 °C; the maximum growth temperature lies between 50 and 55 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 4·0 and 5·0, the optimum pH is 7·0–9·0 and the maximum pH lies between 9·5 and 10·0.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative, gelatin is hydrolysed by most strains and nitrate reduction is positive (sometimes weakly); reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase and indole production are negative.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is positive in the API 50CH gallery.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced (weakly by some strains) from the following carbohydrates in the API 50CH gallery, using CHB suspension medium (bioMérieux): <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, galactose (always weak), d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose and d-trehalose.</s><s>The following reactions are variable between strains, and, when positive, are usually weak: amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, ribose, sorbitol, d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, glycogen, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, <em>meso-</em>inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl d-xyloside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, l-sorbose, starch, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, respectively present at levels of about 44 and 31 % of the total fatty acid content.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present to at least 1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>For the strains tested (Table 4), the G+C content is 40·0–40·5 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil (Drentse A agricultural research area, The Netherlands).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photomicrographs of sporangia and vegetative cells of (a) <em>B. novalis</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 21837<sup>T</sup>, (b) <em>B. vireti</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 21834<sup>T</sup>, (c) <em>B. soli</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 21838<sup>T</sup>, (d) <em>B. bataviensis</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 21833<sup>T</sup> and (e) <em>B. drentensis</em> sp. nov.</s><s>LMG 21831<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Bars, 3 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain, LMG 21837<sup>T</sup> (=R-15439<sup>T</sup>=IDA3307<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15603<sup>T</sup>), was positive for amygdalin (weak), d-cellobiose (weak), <em>β</em>-gentiobiose (weak), d-mannitol (weak), sorbitol and d-xylose.</s><s>The G+C content for the type strain is 40·5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>