<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12752_nm.22536" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22536" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6333" rank="subspecies">Mycobacterium abscessus abscessus</organism><reference id="rid.12752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leao</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Euzéby</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal that Mycobacterium massiliense and Mycobacterium bolletii be united and reclassified as Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. bolletii comb. nov., designation of Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. abscessus subsp. nov. and emended description of Mycobacterium abscessus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2311</fpage><lpage>2313</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023770-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21037035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> (Moore and Frerichs 1953) Kusunoki and Ezaki 1992, subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> (abs.ces′sus. L. gen. n. <em>abscessus</em> of an abscess).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rule 40d (formerly Rule 46) of the <em>Bacteriological Code</em> (1990 Revision) (Lapage <em>et al.</em>, 1992; De Vos &#x0026; Trüper, 2000) states that ‘the valid publication of a subspecific name which excludes the type of the species automatically creates another subspecies which includes the type and whose name bears the same specific and subspecific epithets as the name of the type’.</s><s>As <em>Mycobacterium</em> <em>bolletii</em> is transferred to the species <em>Mycobacterium</em> <em>abscessus</em> (<em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> comb. nov.), an automatic consequence of this rule is that the subspecies <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> (Moore and Frerichs 1953) Kusunoki and Ezaki 1992 must be created.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At the time of writing, the Judicial Opinion about the request by Tindall &#x0026; Garrity (2008) has not been published.</s><s>Thus, the authorship of the subspecies <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> follows the current Rule 40d.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as that given for <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> by Kubica <em>et al.</em> (1972) and Kusunoki &#x0026; Ezaki (1992). <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> has the properties given in the emended description of <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em>.</s><s>Additional features that distinguish this subspecies are the PRA-<em>hsp65</em> pattern and the <em>rpoB</em> and <em>hsp65</em> gene sequence differences. <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> shows the characteristic PRA-<em>hsp65</em> pattern <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> type 1.</s><s>The trait of 711 bp of the <em>rpoB</em> and the trait of 401 bp of the <em>hsp65</em> nucleotide sequences from <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> show up to 95.6 and 98.5 % similarity, respectively, to <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Hauduroy L948<sup>T</sup> ( = TMC 1543<sup>T</sup>  = ATCC 19977<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 20993<sup>T</sup>  = CIP 104536<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 44196<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 13569<sup>T</sup>  = NCTC 13031<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>