<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4608_nm.8410" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8410" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8410" rank="species">Opitutus terrae</organism><reference id="rid.4608"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chin</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Opitutus terrae gen. nov., sp. nov., to accommodate novel strains of the division 'Verrucomicrobia' isolated from rice paddy soil.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1965</fpage><lpage>1968</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760935</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Opitutus terrae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Opitutus terrae</i> (ter'rae. L. gen. n. <i>terrae</i> of the earth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci, 0.4-0.6 μm in diameter, motile by means of a flagellum.</s><s>No spores are formed.</s><s>The colonies in agar deeps are unpigmented and granular in appearance.</s><s>The G+­C content of the genomic DNA of strain PB90-1<sup>T</sup> is 74 mol%.</s><s>The type strain grows with glucose, fructose, galactose, mannose, galacturonic acid, mannitol, arabinose, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, melibiose, xylan, pectin and starch.</s><s>Xylose, ribose, sorbose, methyl α-glucopyranoside, cellulose, chitin, arabinogalactan, pyruvate, lactate, fumarate, malate, tartrate, citrate, crotonate, glycerol (with or without acetate), aspartate, alanine, serine, leucine, isoleucine, glutamate, proline, lysine and H<sub>2</sub> (with or without acetate) do not support growth of the type strain.</s><s>Propionate and acetate are the major end-products of fermentation.</s><s>Succinate, lactate, formate, ethanol and H<sub>2</sub> are also produced.</s><s>Methanol is also formed from pectin.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Sulfur, sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate and fumarate are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>The type strain grows at pH values of 5.5 to 9.0, with maximum growth rates at pH 7.5-8.0.</s><s>Growth of the type strain is possible at temperatures of 10 to 37 °C, but not at 4 or 40 °C.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>The type strain is PB90-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11246<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>