<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4321_nm.1204" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1204" rank="genus">Blastomonas</organism><reference id="rid.4321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuraishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawahara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the description of Blastomonas natatoria (Sly 1985) Sly and Cahill 1997 as an aerobic photosynthetic bacterium and reclassification of Erythromonas ursincola Yurkov et al. 1997 as Blastomonas ursincola comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1113</fpage><lpage>1118</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843052</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Blastomonas</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of the genus is based on the descriptions reported previously (Sly &#x0026; Cahill, 1997; Yurkov et al., 1997) and in this study. The chemotaxonomic information is derived from the report of Sittig &#x0026; Hirsch (1992) and this study. Cells are ovoid or rod-shaped and reproduce by budding or asymmetric cell division. They occur singly or in pairs and may form rosette-like aggregates. No stalks and prosthecae are found. Gram-negative. Non-sporeforming. Motile by means of polar flagella. Strictly aerobic chemo-organotroph and facultative photoorganotroph. No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light. Produces BChl <i>a</i>. Colonies and cell suspensions are yellow to orange due to the presence of carotenoids. Mesophilic, neutrophilic and freshwater bacterium. Catalase- and oxidase-positive. Nitrate is not reduced. Acid is not produced in Hugh-Leifson's OF medium. The major whole-cell fatty acid is C18:1(d9). The major hydroxy fatty acid is 2-OH C14:0. 2-OH C15:0 and 2-OH C16:0 are present as minor components. 3-OH fatty acids are absent. Monosaccharide-type glycosphingolipids are present. Ubiquinone-10 is the major respiratory quinone. The genomic DNA G+­C content is 64.8-65.2 mol%. The phylogenetic position is in the α-4 group of the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i>. The type species is <i>Blastomonas natatoria</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>