<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9176_nm.14379" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14379" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14379" rank="species">Skermanella xinjiangensis</organism><reference id="rid.9176"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Skermanella xinjiangensis sp. nov., isolated from the desert of Xinjiang, China.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1531</fpage><lpage>1534</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003350-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502348</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Skermanella xinjiangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Skermanella xinjiangensis</em> (xin.jiang.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>xinjiangensis</em> pertaining to Xinjiang, an autonomous region in north-west China).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, rod-shaped and motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.8–0.9 μm×1.1–1.6 μm in size.</s><s>Cells grow best on nutrient-reduced media such as 0.1×TSB agar or R2A.</s><s>Colonies on 0.1×TSB agar are circular, convex and light-pink-coloured.</s><s>Growth occurs on 0.1×TSB agar at 17–37 °C, pH 6–9 and 0–4 % NaCl.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 28–37 °C and the optimum pH is pH 7–8.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are produced.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, chitin, tyrosine, cellulose, starch or Tween 80.</s><s>Positive in tests for urea hydrolysis, aesculin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20 NE).</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, malic acid, propionic acid, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, l-proline, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sodium acetate and lactic acid (API 20NE and API ID 32 GN).</s><s>Does not assimilate <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, valeric acid, l-histidine, potassium 2-ketogluconate, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, inositol, sucrose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, sodium malonate, l-alanine, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid or l-serine (API 20NE and API ID 32 GN).</s><s>Ferments d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, aesculin, cellobiose (weakly), d-lactose (weakly), melibiose, d-lyxose (weakly), d-fucose and l-fucose (weakly), but does not ferment glycerol, erythritol, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-fructose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate (API 50 CH strips).</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 10-1-101<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207153<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-51273<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the surface layer of a desert soil from Xinjiang, China.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 68.8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>