<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12678_nm.22417" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22417" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22417" rank="species">Peptostreptococcus russellii</organism><reference id="rid.12678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whitehead</surname><given-names>T.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cotta</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Peptostreptococcus russellii sp. nov., isolated from a swine-manure storage pit</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1875</fpage><lpage>1879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023762-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Peptostreptococcus russellii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Peptostreptococcus russellii</em> (rus.sel′li.i N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>russellii</em> of Russell, named after the late American microbiologist James B. Russell for his contributions to rumen microbiology and initial isolation of HAP bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on seven strains, isolated from swine faeces and stored manure.</s><s>Cells are obligatory anaerobic, Gram-reaction-positive, non-motile cocci, ~0.8−1.0 µm, occurring in pairs and chains of 3–10 cells.</s><s>After 48 h of growth on BHI agar under anaerobic conditions, colonies are convex, 2–3 mm in diameter, opaque, smooth and whitish in colour.</s><s>Grows in liquid culture at 25–45 °C (optimum 37 °C) but not at 4 or 50 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs after 24 h in static or shaking aerobic BHI broth or on aerobic BHI agar plates.</s><s>Weakly saccharolytic.</s><s>Using the API rapid ID32An system: positive for proline arylamidase and negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphorylase, arginine dihydrolase, α-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α- and β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase-6-phosphate, α- and β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, mannose, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, raffinose, serine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase and urease.</s><s>Using the API ZYM identification system, no positive reactions are obtained.</s><s>The major end-product from glucose metabolism is acetate, with smaller amounts of lactate, formate and citrate and trace amounts of succinate detected.</s><s>Prodigious amounts of ammonia (&#x003E;40 mM) are produced from various nitrogen sources (Tryptone and Casamino acids).</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced and catalase, coagulase and indole are not produced.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is type A4α l-Lys–d-Asp.</s><s>Whole-cell-wall sugars consist of glucose, xylose and traces of mannose.</s><s>The major long-chain fatty acid is iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>No respiratory quinones are detected.</s><s>The polar lipid profile comprises aminoglycolipid, diphosphatidylglycerol, glycolipids, phosphatidylglycerol and phospholipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RT-10B<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 58235<sup>T</sup>  = NRRL B-59380<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23041<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a swine manure storage pit (habitat not known).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 35.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>