<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3517_nm.11770" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11770" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.335" rank="species">Natrialba aegyptiaca</organism><reference id="rid.3517"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hezayen</surname><given-names>F.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rehm</surname><given-names>B.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steinbuchel</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Natrialba asiatica B1T to Natrialba taiwanensis sp. nov. and description of Natrialba aegyptiaca sp. nov., a novel extremely halophilic, aerobic, non-pigmented member of the Archaea from Egypt that produces extracellular poly(glutamic acid).</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1133</fpage><lpage>1142</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Natrialba aegyptiaca</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Natrialba aegyptiaca</i> (ae.gyp'ti.a.ca. L. adj. <i>aegyptiaca</i> from Egypt, referring to the geographical region from which this organism was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Generally non-pigmented, but slightly pigmented under certain conditions, especially when the agar basal medium plus 1%(w/v) sodium acetate is used as carbon and energy sources or after long periods on isolation and maintenance media.</s><s>Cells are either rods, 0.5-1.2x1.5-6 μm, or cocci and tetrads, individual cells measuring 0.5-2.0 μm in diameter; cells are pleomorphic, especially under suboptimal conditions.</s><s>Cocci and coccobacilli dominate when acetate or gluconate is added to the basal medium as carbon and energy source.</s><s>Gram-negative; rods are motile.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 37-42 °C, with a maximum at 60 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 6-9, with an optimum in the range pH 7-8.</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 1.6 M to saturation, with an optimum in the range 2.5-3.0 M.</s><s>NaCl may be replaced to a large extent by KCl (Table 2).</s><s>Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, glucose, sucrose, maltose, lactose (weak) and starch.</s><s>Strongly amylolytic; casein and gelatin are also hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 20, 40 and 80 as well as egg yolk (lecithin) are hydrolysed.</s><s>Produces an exopolymer, which is composed of L-glutamic acid 85% w/w), carbohydrates (12.5% w/w) and unidentified compounds (2.5% w/w).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a salt soil close to Aswan, Egypt.</s><s>The type strain is strain 40<sup>T</sup>, which has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM13077<sup>T</sup> and in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Wako, Saitama, Japan, as JCM 11194<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>