<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12871_nm.22681" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22681" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22681" rank="species">Williamsia phyllosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.12871"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P..</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wellner</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lohse</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lodders</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Williamsia phyllosphaerae sp. nov., isolated from the surface of Trifolium repens leaves</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2702</fpage><lpage>2705</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.029322-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21169464</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Williamsia phyllosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Williamsia phyllosphaerae</em> (phyl.lo.sphae′rae. Gr. neut. n. <em>phyllon</em> leaf; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> ball, sphere; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>phyllosphaerae</em> of the phyllosphere).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive-staining, coccoid–rod-like cells, about 1.0–1.5 µm in diameter.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive and showing an aerobic respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 3 days of incubation on TSA, R2A agar and nutrient agar at 25–30 °C.</s><s>The quinone system consists of MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipid profile is composed of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and three unknown polar lipids.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, d-fructose, sucrose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, propionate, fumarate, pyruvate, 4-hydroxybutyrate and l-malate, but does not utilize <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>p</em>-arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, d-gluconate, d-mannose, maltose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, glutarate, itaconate, dl-lactate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, l-alanine, β-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate or phenylacetate.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, p-nitrophenyl (NP)-α-d-glucopyranoside, pNP-β-d-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP-phosphate, pNP-phenylphosphonate, pNP-phosphorylcholine and l-alanine-p-nitroanilide (NA), but does not hydrolyse oNP-β-d-galactopyranoside, pNP-β-d-glucuronide, pNP-β-d-xylopyranoside or l-glutamate-γ-3-carboxy-pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is C7<sup>T</sup> ( = CCUG 60465<sup>T</sup> = CCM 7855<sup>T</sup>) and was isolated from the surface of leaves of <em>Trifolium repens</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>