<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6436_nm.5361" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5361" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5361" rank="species">Lactobacillus durianis</organism><reference id="rid.6436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leisner</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vilalta</surname><given-names>N.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rusul</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus durianis sp. nov., isolated from an acid-fermented condiment (tempoyak) in Malaysia.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>927</fpage><lpage>931</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02091-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054259</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus durianis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus durianis</i> (du.ri.an'is. N.L. adj. <i>durianis</i> of the durian fruit)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile and non-sporeforming rods occurring singly, as pairs or in chains (fewer than five cells) in APT broth supplemented with glucose, D-xylose or both components.</s><s>Surface colonies on APT agar with D-xylose or glucose after 3 days of micro-aerophilic incubation at 30 °C are 1 mm or less in diameter, round and with smooth surfaces.</s><s>The colonies are smaller with glucose than with D-xylose (growth is enhanced by replacing glucose with D-xylose).</s><s>Catalase-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>NH<sub>3</sub> is not produced from arginine.</s><s>The species is obligately heterofermentative.</s><s>Gas is produced from gluconic acid but not from glucose.</s><s>D(-)- and L-(­+)-lactic acid and acetic acid are produced from both glucose and D-xylose.</s><s>None of the three strains reduces tetrazolium on SBM agar, nor do they grow in Clark &#x0026; Lubbs broth used in the Voges-Proskauer test.</s><s>Able to grow on acetate agar but unable to acidify Lα-broth below pH 4.15.</s><s>Growth occurs for all three strains in APT broth with glucose at temperatures ranging from 15 to 42°C.</s><s>With D-xylose, growth is observed from 10 to 42°C for strains LMG 19195 and LMG 19196 and from 15 to 42°C for strain LMG19193<sup>T</sup>.No growth in the presence of 6.5 or 8% NaCl.</s><s>Resistant towards 30 μg vancomycin g<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>All three strains are able to produce acid from only a few of the carbohydrates in the API 50 CH kit, including L-arabinose, gluconate (weak reaction), 5-ketogluconate (weak reaction), maltose, ribose, D-xylose and methyl β-xyloside.</s><s>Two of the strains (LMG 19193<sup>T</sup> and LMG 19196) are also able to produce acid from D-glucose and D-lyxose and to hydrolyse aesculin or (LMG 19193<sup>T</sup> and LMG 19195) to produce acid from galactose and D-arabinose.</s><s>One strain (LMG 19193<sup>T</sup>) produces acid from starch (weak reaction) and another strain (LMG 19196) produces acid from D-arabitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, arbutin, L-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, fructose, D-fucose, L-fucose, gentiobiose, 2-ketogluconate, N-acetyl glucosamine, methyl α-D-glucoside, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, mannitol, mannose, methyl α-D-mannoside, melibiose, melizitose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-tagatose, trehalose, D-turanose, xylitol or L-xylose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43.2-43.3 mol%.</s><s>Features that differentiate <i>L. durianis</i> from other obligately heterofermentative <i>Lactobacillus</i> species are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from aMalaysian acid-fermented condiment, tempoyak, made from the durian fruit.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 19193<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 45405<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>