<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6_nm.7862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7862" rank="species">Treponema denticola</organism><reference id="rid.6"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chan</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siboo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Keng</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Psarra</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurley</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iugovaz</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema denticola (ex Brumpt 1925) sp. nov., nom. rev., and identification of new spirochete isolates from periodontal pockets</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>196</fpage><lpage>203</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-196</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8494734</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema denticola</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema denticola</i> is a valid and distinct species of the genus <i>Treponema</i> and designate strain ATCC 35405 as the type strain and strains ATCC 33520 (9) and ATCC 35404 as reference strains. Some characteristics which differentiate <i>T. denticola</i> from other Treponema species that are cultivable and do not ferment carbohydrates are shown in Table 5. These characteristics are described in Bergey 's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology (25). Two species that were isolated relatively recently from oral cavities, <i>Treponema pectinovorum</i> and <i>T. socranskii</i>, are not included in Table 5 because they were not included in Belgey 's Manual. Furthermore, <i>Treponema pectinovorum</i> ferments pectin, polygalacturonic acid, galacturonic acid, and glucuronic acid, and <i>T. socranskii</i> ferments glucose. Figure 4 also shows that <i>T. denticola</i> produces a trace of formate and no propionate and that <i>T. vincentii</i> produces acetate plus propionate but no butyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>T. denticola</i> is a small to intermediate spirochete (20).</s><s>Even though a 2-4-2 endoflagellar arrangement is common, <i>T. denticola</i> strains with higher numbers of axial filaments have been found (3, 14).</s><s>The additional description of the species given below is from Bergey's Manual (25).</s><s>The organism moves with a jerky but fairly rapid motion.</s><s>It grows well in peptone-yeast extract-serum medium under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The organism is primarily an amino acid fermenter and does not use the glycolytic pathway as a major source of energy.</s><s>It grows at a pH range of 6.5 to 8.0 and a temperature range of 30 to 42°C.</s><s>The species is found in the oral cavities of humans and chimpanzees, usually in deposits at the junctures between and teeth and gums.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 37-39 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, <i>T. denticola</i> ATCC 35405, was first described by Cheng et al. (4) and was called serovar a before it was deposited in the American Type Culture Collection and acquired an accession number.</s><s>It exhibits 76% DNA homology with <i>T. denticola</i> ATCC 33520 and 82% DNA homology with <i>T. denticola</i> ATCC 35404, both of which we selected as reference strains. <i>T. denticola</i> ATCC 35405<sup>T</sup> is susceptible to the antimicrobial agents spiramycin, metronidazole, tetracycline, penicillin G, and streptomycin but is highly resistant to rifampin (the minimum inhibitory concentration is 50 μg/ml).</s><s>Its cell dimensions are as follows: length, 7.74 ± 0.94 μm; diameter, 0.20 ± 0.02 μm; wavelength, 1.23 ± 0.15 μm; and amplitude, 0.50 ± 0.05 μm.</s><s>It has 10 axial fibrils and therefore has a 5-10-5 endoflagellar arrangement.</s><s>As noted above, <i>T. denticola</i> is the oral spirochete species that is isolated most frequently from subgingival plaque.</s><s>Despite our renewed concerted efforts to isolate new oral spirochete species, the majority of our new isolates were <i>T. denticola</i> strains.</s><s>Unless new isolation and cultivation techniques are developed, it appears that present procedures can yield only isolates belonging to previously described species and that there is little chance of obtaining larger treponemes.</s></p></content></protolog>