<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.337_nm.519" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.519" rank="genus">Thermus</organism><reference id="rid.337"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Thermus ruber (Loginova et al. 1984), Thermus silvanus (Tenreiro et al. 1995), and Thermus chliarophilus (Tenreiro et al. 1995) to Meiothermus gen. nov. as Meiothermus ruber comb. nov., Meiothermus silvanus comb. nov., and Meiothermus chliarophilus comb. nov., respectively, and emendation of the genus Thermus.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>604</fpage><lpage>606</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-604</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Thermus</i> Brock and Freeze 1969</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The cells are 0.5 to 0.8 μm in diameter; the cell length is variable, and short filaments are formed by most strains. Long filaments are produced by a few strains. The cells are gram negative. Colonies are generally yellow pigmented, but nonpigmented strains are also found. Cells are nonmotile. Metabolism is oxidative and aerobic, but the strains of some species grow anaerobically with nitrate and nitrite as terminal electron acceptors. Oxidase positive and catalase positive. The optimum growth temperatures for the species of this genus range from about 65 to 75°C; most species have a maximum growth temperature below 80°C, but some species grow at higher temperatures. The optimum pH is about 7.8. Menaquinone 8 is the major respiratory quinone; ornithine is the principal diamino acid of the peptidoglycan. One major phospholipid and one major glycolipid are the principal polar lipids. Other phospholipids and glycolipids are minor components. The fatty acids are predominantly iso and anteiso branched; iso 3-hydroxy fatty acids are found in some species; and 2-hydroxy fatty acids are vestigial or absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Proteins and peptides are hydrolyzed by all strains.</s><s>Monosaccharides, disaccharides, amino acids, and organic acids are used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Many strains require yeast extract or cofactors for growth.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 60 to 65 mol%.</s><s>Strains of the genus <i>Thermus</i> have been isolated from terrestrial and marine hot springs and artificial hot water systems with neutral to alkaline pH values.</s><s>The type species is <i>T. aquaticus</i>. <i>T. filiformis</i>, <i>T. scotoductus</i>, <i>T. thermophilus</i>, and <i>T. brockianus</i> are also assigned to this genus.</s></p></content></protolog>