<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4859_nm.14103" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14103" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1349" rank="species">Sinorhizobium teranga</organism><reference id="rid.4859"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewettinck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maestrojuan</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neyra</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dreyfus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomy of Rhizobia: emendation of the genus Sinorhizobium and description of Sinorhizobium meliloti comb. nov., Sinorhizobium saheli sp. nov., and Sinorhizobium teranga sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>715</fpage><lpage>733</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Sinorhizobium teranga</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Sinorhizobium teranga</i> (te'ran.ga. local Wolof [a language of the West African Wolof people] n. <i>teranga</i>, hospitality; N. L. n. <i>teranga</i>, hospitality, referring to the fact that this species contains strains isolated from different host plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide by 1.5 to 2 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of one or several polar or subpolar flagella in liquid medium.</s><s>The cells grow on yeast mannitol medium at temperatures as high as 44°C.</s><s>Colonies of most strains on YMA are circular, cream colored, semi-translucent, and mucilaginous and sometimes spread over an entire plate within 2 to 4 days.</s><s>Old colonies turn brown.</s><s>The exceptions are strains ORS 22 and ORS 613, which produce non-mucilaginous colonies.</s><s>In some strains non-mucilaginous mutants arise spontaneously during subculturing.</s><s>A wide range of carbohydrates, organic acids, and amino acids are utilized as sole carbon sources for growth.</s><s>Features that distinguish this species from other species and related genera are shown in Table 2.</s><s>Grows on xylitol but not on L-citrulline and glycolate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains can nodulate <i>Sesbania</i> and <i>Acacia</i> spp., <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>, and <i>N. oleracea</i>.</s><s>At the molecular level this species can be differentiated by the results of DNA-rRNA hybridization experiments, by the SDS-PAGE patterns of proteins, by the results of total DNADNA hybridization experiments, and by the sequence of the 16s ribosomal DNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 60.8 to 61.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Well-studied strain ORS 1009 (= LMG 7854), which was isolated from <i>Acacia laeta</i>, is the type strain, and the characteristics of this strain are shown in Table 2.</s><s>All <i>Sinorhizobium teranga</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Ghent, Ghent, Belgium, and in the Culture Collection of the Laboratory of Soil Microbiology, ORSTOM, Dakar, Senegal.</s></p></content></protolog>