<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2797_nm.4507" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4507" rank="genus">Thermosyntropha</organism><reference id="rid.2797"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Svetlitshnyi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermosyntropha lipolytica gen. nov., sp. nov., a lipolytic, anaerobic, alkalitolerant, thermophilic bacterium utilizing short- and long-chain fatty acids in syntrophic coculture with a methanogenic archaeum.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1131</fpage><lpage>1137</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1131</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863447</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Thermosyntropha</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermosyntropha</i> (Ther.mo.syn.tro'pha. Gr. adj. <i>thermos</i>, hot; Gr. prefix <i>syn</i>, with, together; Gr. verb. <i>trophein</i>, to eat; Gr. masc. n <i>syntrophos</i>, foster brother or sister; M.L. fem. n. <i>thermosyntropha</i> [“foster sisters liking it hot,” referring to the fact that the bacterium grows at elevated temperatures on fatty acids only in syntrophic cultures with hydrogen-utilizing microorganisms])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Gram reaction-negative and gram-type-positive cells are generally rod shaped, obligately anaerobic, heterotrophic, and lipolytic and grow at elevated temperatures and moderately alkaline pH values.</s><s>Thermodynamically unfavorable substrates leading to hydrogen formation are utilized in syntrophic associations with H<sub>2</sub>-consuming microorganisms.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 43 to 44 mol%.</s><s>The lipolytic, fatty acid-degrading <i>T. lipolytica</i> is the type and, so far, only species in this genus.</s><s>On the basis of the 16s rDNA sequence the genus <i>Thermosyntropha</i> belongs to the family <i>Syntrophomonadaceae</i> (45)</s></p></content></protolog>