<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.202_nm.8020" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8020" rank="genus">Porphyromonas</organism><reference id="rid.202"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Oribaculum catoniae (Moore and Moore 1994) as Porphyromonas catoniae comb. nov. and emendation of the genus Porphyromonas.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>578</fpage><lpage>581</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-578</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590687</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Porphyromonas</i> Shah and Collins 1988.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description below is based on that of Shah and Collins (15) and data in references 1, 4, 7 through 10, and 14.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, nonmotile rods to coccobacilli.</s><s>Most cells in broth are small (0.5 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 3.5 μm), but occasionally longer cells (length, 4 to 6 μm) may be formed.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar plates are smooth (rarely rough), shiny, convex, and 1 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>The colonies of most species are pigmented because of protoheme production.</s><s>While the growth of most species is not affected by carbohydrates, some species are saccharolytic.</s><s>Nitrogenous substances such as Proteose Peptone, Trypticase, and yeast extract markedly enhance growth.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>The major fermentation products are usually <i>n</i>-butyric and acetic acids; lower levels of propionic, isobutyric, and isovaleric acids may also be produced.</s><s>Some species produce major amounts of propionic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Malate dehydrogenase and glutamate dehydrogenase are present; glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase are absent from most species.</s><s>Proteolytic activity is variable.</s><s>The strains have a limited ability to ferment amino acids such as aspartate and asparagine.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Starch and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains lysine as the diamino acid; 2-keto-3-deoxyoctulosonic acid is absent.</s><s>The principal respiratory quinones are unsaturated menaquinones with 9 or 10 isoprene units.</s><s>Both nonhydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present.</s><s>The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are predominantly methyl-branched-chain fatty acids.</s><s>iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> predominates in most species, although a few species contain comparable amounts of iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>The 3-hydroxylated fatty acids are generally straight-chain saturated fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base compositions range from 40 to 55 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Porphyromonas asaccharolytica</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>