<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4824_nm.1713" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1713" rank="genus">Massilia</organism><reference id="rid.4824"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>La Scola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birtles</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mallet</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Massilia timonae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from blood of an immunocompromised patient with cerebellar lesions.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>2847</fpage><lpage>2852</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9738031</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Massilia</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Massilia</i> (taken from the old Greek and Roman name for Marseille, Massilia, where our hospital is situated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative cells are straight rods that are 1.0 μm wide and 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Occasionally, filamentous cells are formed in old cultures and are especially formed at 37°C.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>The organism does not form spores.</s><s>A single polar flagellum is formed on each cell.</s><s>The organism is actively motile, especially in young cultures.</s><s>It is strictly aerobic and forms straw-colored colonies.</s><s>It has a tendency to form flocs and films in liquid medium without finger-like projections.</s><s>It is oxidase negative and catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is not formed from carbohydrates.</s><s>It is arginine dihydrolase positive, urease negative, esculin positive, and proteolytic on gelatin.</s><s>Denitrification does not occur.</s><s>Additional characteristics are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The moles percent G+C content of the DNA of the strain is 64.61 ± 1.78.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a culture of blood from a febrile patient with common variable immunodeficiency.</s><s>The type strain of <i>M. timonae</i> is strain UR/MT95, which has been deposited in the Collection de l'Institut Pasteur, Paris, France, as strain CIP 105350.</s><s>Its 16S rRNA gene sequence has been lodged within the GenBank sequence database under accession no. U54470.</s></p></content></protolog>