<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1168_nm.11837" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11837" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4002" rank="species">Clostridium purinolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.1168"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dürre</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersch</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andreesen</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of an adenine-utilizing, anaerobic sporeformer, Clostridium purinolyticum sp. nov.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>184</fpage><lpage>194</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-2-184</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium purinolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium purinolyticum</i> (pu.ri.no.ly'ti.cum. M.L. n. <i>purum uricum</i>, condensed as “<i>purin</i>,” a term proposed by E. Fischer for the basic ring system of uric acid; Gr. n. <i>lysis</i> decomposition; M.L. adj. <i>purinolyticum</i> decomposing the purine ring system)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 1.1 to 1.6 μm wide and 2.7 to 9.6 μm long.</s><s>Endospores spherical, 0.85 to 1.2 μm in diameter, terminally located, and cause swelling of the cell.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Motile by means of a few flagella.</s><s>Colonies nonpigmented, flat, circular, and 1 to 3 mm in diameter within 2 weeks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiology.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic; optimum temperature, 36°C; growth occurs at 18 and 42°C; pH range for growth, 6.5 to 9.0; optimum range, pH 7.3 to 7.8; chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>For growth, utilizes only purines, such as uric acid, 6-amino-2,8-dihydroxypurine, xanthine, 6,8-dihydroxypurine, guanine, isoguanine, hypoxanthine, adenine, 6-methylaminopurine, 2 -hydroxypurine, purine, adenosine, inosine, xanthosine, and glycine, and derivatives, such as formiminoglycine, benzoylglycine (hippurate), glycylglycine, glycylglycylglycine, glycylleucine, and 4-aminoimidazole-5-carboxamide.</s><s>Depending on the strain, the ability to grow with purine and some glycine derivatives may be lost (strain PD-1), but at least adenine is still attacked (strain AAM-1).</s><s>Selenite, bicarbonate, and thiamine generally required; yeast extract stimulatory and required for growth on glycine.</s><s>Acetate, formate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and NH<sub>3</sub> are products.</s><s>Hydrogen, acetoin, diacetyl, 2,3-butanediol, indole, and sulfide not produced.</s><s>Nitrate and sulfate not reduced, but CO<sub>2</sub> reduced to acetate.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin, starch, and esculin does not occur.</s><s>No betahemolysis.</s><s>Catalase, lipase, lecithinase, and urease not produced.</s><s>Growth not influenced by the presence of 2% bile extract.</s><s>Guanine plus cytosine content of the DNA is 29.0 to 29.3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source.</s><s>Isolated from soils contaminated with chicken manure and from sewage sludge enriched with adenine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>WA-1.</s><s>This strain was isolated from a farm in Bovenden-Eddigehausen, Federal Republic of Germany.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, with the following addition: the guanine plus cytosine content of the DNA is 29.0 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The strain has been deposited in the DSM under the accession number 1384.</s></p></content></protolog>