<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3888_nm.4319" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4319" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4319" rank="species">Desulfitobacterium chlororespirans</organism><reference id="rid.3888"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sanford</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Löffler</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of Desulfitobacterium chlororespirans sp. nov., which grows by coupling the oxidation of lactate to the reductive dechlorination of 3-chloro-4-hydroxybenzoate.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>62</volume><fpage>3800</fpage><lpage>3808</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8837437</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfomonile chlororespirans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfomonile chlororespirans</i> (chlor.o.resp.i'.rans M. L. part. adj.; <i>chloro</i> referring to the group VII element chlorine; fr. L <i>respirare</i> to blow, breathe; <i>chlororespirans</i>, breathing chlorine, referring to the characteristic of coupling oxidation of electron donors to reductive removal of chlorines from various chlorophenolic compounds via a respiratory process used for obtaining energy for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slightly curved motile rods 3 to 5 μm long and 0.5 to 0.7 μm wide.</s><s>Terminally located spores appear in late growth, and cultures are resistant to heat treatment at 80°C.</s><s>Cells stain gram negative, but phylogenetically this organism is within the gram-positive <i>Desulfotomaculum</i> group.</s><s>Growth is obligately anaerobic, and sulfite, thiosulfate, sulfur and <i>ortho</i>-substituted polychlorophenolic compounds are used as electron acceptors. 3-Chloro-4-hydroxybenzoate is the best substrate for halorespiration.</s><s>Pyruvate, lactate, formate, butyrate, and H2 are used as electron donors.</s><s>Cells grow by partial oxidation of carbon substrates to acetate coupled to the reductive dechlorination of <i>ortho</i>-substituted chlorophenolic compounds.</s><s>Growth of cells on pyruvate alone is homoacetogenic.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 378C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.8 to 7.5.</s><s>Colonies grown on R2A agar medium are white, round, and smooth with a diameter of 1 to 2 mm after 1 week of growth.</s><s>The type strain is Co23.</s><s>It has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection.</s><s>This organism was isolated from a Michigan residential compost soil.</s></p></content></protolog>