<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6281_nm.3817" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3817" rank="genus">Arcobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6281"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rossau</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tytgat</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revision of Campylobacter, Helicobacter, and Wolinella taxonomy: emendation of generic descriptions and proposal of Arcobacter gen. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>88</fpage><lpage>103</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1704793</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arcobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arcobacter</i> (Ar'co.bac.ter. L. n. <i>arcus</i>, bow; Gr. n. <i>bacter</i>, rod; M. L. masc. n. <i>Arcobacter</i>, bow-shaped rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative nonsporeforming rods (width, 0.2 to 0.9 μm; length, 1 to 3 μm) that are usually curved, S shaped, or helical.</s><s>Motile (with a darting, corkscrewlike motion) by means of a single polar, unsheathed flagellum.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15,30, and 37°C; no growth occurs at 42°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs under microaerophilic conditions (3 to 10% O<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Hydrogen is not required for microaerophilic growth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1 and 2% NaCl and 1% (wt/vol) pteridine vibriostatic compound 0/129.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 1% glycine and 0.1% 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium chloride.</s><s>The strains have oxidase and catalase activities and reduce nitrate.</s><s>Negative reactions in methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Carbohydrates are neither fermented nor oxidized.</s><s>Organic and amino acids are utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Hippurate, esculin, starch, and DNA are not hydrolyzed; gelatin is not liquified.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Menaquinone 6 and a second atypical menaquinone 6, the identity of which remains to be established, are the major respiratory quinones.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from root-associated sediments and roots of salt march plants, from aborted fetuses of several species of farm animals, and from various other animal and human sources.</s><s>Pathogenicity is unknown.</s><s>The type species is <i>Arcobacter nitrofigilis</i> comb. nov.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 28 to 31 mol% G+C.</s></p></content></protolog>