<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12881_nm.22691" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22691" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22691" rank="species">Flavobacterium chungbukense</organism><reference id="rid.12881"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>A.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhee</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>D.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium chungbukense sp. nov., isolated from soil</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2734</fpage><lpage>2739</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028563-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21186289</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium chungbukense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium chungbukense</em> (chung.bu.ken′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>chungbukense</em> of or belonging to Chungbuk, a province in Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, strictly aerobic, non-motile, rod-shaped, approximately 0.4–0.6 µm in diameter and 8.0–15.0 µm in length.</s><s>Gliding motility is absent.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, smooth and convex with entire margins after 3 days of incubation at 25 °C on TSA.</s><s>Growth occurs on TSA, R2A and NA, but not on MA or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C (optimum, 25 °C), at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0) and in the presence of 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0–1 %).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities are present.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Congo red is not adsorbed by colonies.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrogen.</s><s>Indole production, glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase activity are absent (API 20NE).</s><s>Starch, skimmed milk, gelatin, aesculin and DNA are hydrolysed.</s><s>Chitin, pectin, urea, CMC and agar are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, cellobiose, maltose, melezitose, melibiose and sucrose, but not from d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or inositol.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, l-arabinose, l-proline, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycogen, maltose, rhamnose and salicin, but does not utilize d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-ribose, dl-lactate, l-alanine, l-serine, l-histidine, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, 5-ketogluconate, adipate, caprate, malic acid, phenylacetic acid, citrate, potassium gluconate, propionate, valerate, inositol, itaconate, suberate, malonate or acetate (API 20NE and API ID32 GN).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase and β-glucuronidase activities are absent (API ZYM).</s><s>Antagonistic to <em>L. monocytogenes</em> and <em>S. aureus</em>.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin, spectinomycin and streptomycin, but sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin G and tetracycline.</s><s>Menaquinone-6 (MK-6) is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;11 %) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CS100<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 15048<sup>T</sup> = JCM 17386<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in Cheongju, Chungbuk, Republic of Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>