<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2927_nm.2074" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2074" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2074" rank="species">Chromatium glycolicum</organism><reference id="rid.2927"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Caumette</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matheron</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chromatium glycolicum sp. nov., a moderately halophilic purple sulfur bacterium that uses glycolate as substrate</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>167</volume><fpage>11</fpage><lpage>18</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s002030050410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9000336</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Chromatium glycolicum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Chromatium glycolicum</i> (gly.co'li.cum. L.adj., related to glycolate; M.L. n.adj., related to the ability to use glycolate as substrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight-to-slightly curved rods, 0.8–1 μm wide and 2–4 μm long.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells motile by polar flagella.</s><s>Color of cell suspension is pinkish-red.</s><s>Photosynthetic membrane system of the vesicular type.</s><s>Contains bacteriochlorophyll a (BChl <i>a</i>), spirilloxanthin and anhydrorhodovibrin as major carotenoids, and small amounts of rhodopin, lycopene, and rhodovibrin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron donors for photoautotrophic growth: hydrogen, hydrogen sulfide, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, and sulfite.</s><s>Globules of elemental sulfur are stored inside the cells.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and hydrogen carbonate, glycolate, glycerol, fumarate, and succinate are photoassimilated.</s><s>Formate, acetate, pyruvate, and casamino acids are slightly photoassimilated.</s><s>Chemolithotrophic growth with sulfide and thiosulfate; chemo-organotrophic growth under micro-oxic conditions in the dark with glycolate; not capable of assimilatory sulfate reduction.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal pH: 7.2–7.4; pH range: 6.2–9.0.</s><s>Optimal temperature: 30–35° C; no growth above 40° C.</s><s>Salinity range between 2 and 20% NaCl; optimal salinity at 5–6% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition: 66.3 ± 0.2 mol% G+C (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: anoxic mud, sediments, and microbial mats exposed to light in hypersaline environments such as coastal lagoons subject to evaporative water losses, with salt concentrations of approximately 6–20%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Chromatium glycolicum</i> strain SL 3201 isolated from a benthic microbial mat in Solar Lake (Sinai) and deposited with the German Collection of Microorganisms (DSM) under the number DSM 11080 and with the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 700202.</s></p></content></protolog>