<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12722_nm.22489" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22489" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22489" rank="species">Shinella daejeonensis</organism><reference id="rid.12722"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>S.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Shinella daejeonensis sp. nov., a nitrate-reducing bacterium isolated from sludge of a leachate treatment plant</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2123</fpage><lpage>2128</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026435-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870886</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Shinella daejeonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Shinella daejeonensis</em> (da.e.je.o.nen′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>daejeonensis</em> pertaining to Daejeon, a city in South Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, aerobic, motile, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–34 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth occurs on NA, R2A agar, TSA, LB agar and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Nitrogen fixation is negative.</s><s>Aesculin, casein, chitin, HE-cellulose, starch, xylan and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>In API ID 32 GN, API 20NE and API 50 CH tests, acetate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-adonitol, l-alanine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-fucose, d-galactose, gluconate (weakly), d-glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, d-lyxose, malate (weakly), maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-proline, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol and d-xylose are utilized for growth, but adipate, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabitol, arbutin, caprate, cellobiose, citrate, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fructose, d-fucose, gentiobiose, glycogen, l-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, inulin, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactate, malonate, melezitose, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, phenylacetate, propionate, raffinose, salicin, l-sorbose, starch, suberate, d-tagatose, valerate and l-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>In API ZYM and API 20E tests, positive for esterase (C4), β-galactosidase, gelatinase, α-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase esterase (C8) and trypsin, but negative for acid phosphatase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, α-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, lipase (C14), lysine decarboxylase, α-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease and valine arylamidase.</s><s>In API 20E tests, acid is produced from l-arabinose but not from amygdalin, d-glucose, inositol, d-mannitol, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or sucrose; production of H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are negative.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-10 is the predominant respiratory lipoquinone and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> are the major cellular fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MJ02<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22450<sup>T</sup> = JCM 16236<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sludge of the aerobic treatment tanks of a municipal leachate treatment plant located in Daejeon, South Korea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>