<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7258_nm.5160" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5160" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5160" rank="species">Ammoniphilus oxalaticus</organism><reference id="rid.7258"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zaitsev</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsitko</surname><given-names>I.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uotila</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>New aerobic ammonium-dependent obligately oxalotrophic bacteria: description of Ammoniphilus oxalaticus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Ammoniphilus oxalivorans gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>151</fpage><lpage>163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-151</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542085</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ammoniphilus oxalaticus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ammoniphilus oxalaticus</i> (o.xa.la'ti.cus. M.L. adj. <i>oxalaticus</i> pertaining to oxalate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight short or long slightly curved rods 1.0-8.0 μm x 0.6-1.1 μm in size, occurring singly, in pairs, in short or long chains.</s><s>Endospores are oval, centrally or subterminally formed, in non-swollen, slightly swollen or swollen sporangia, moderately heat-resistant to 80°C.</s><s>On agar medium (4-8 d) colonies are light brown or bright beige, convex, circular form with entire margin and smooth surface or mucoid, up to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Some strains grow poorly at 0.03 M NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup> and no growth occurs at ≤0.02 M NH<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Obligate oxalotroph.</s><s>Growth occurs up to 100 g ammonium oxalate l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Good growth on 540 g ammonium oxalate l<sup>-1</sup>, poor growth at the concentration of 34 g l<sup>-1</sup> and no growth ≤2 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Some strains can use glyoxylate as the sole organic source for carbon and energy.</s><s>Weak growth occurs on mixtures of formate and glyoxylate or methanol and glyoxylate.</s><s>No growth occurs with other organic acids, sugars or alcohols.</s><s>Mesophilic, the optimum temperature for growth is 28-30°C.</s><s>Most strains grow at 10-40°C, pH 6.8-9.5, and are tolerant to 4% NaCl.</s><s>Some strains slowly hydrolyse starch, gelatin and urea.</s><s>All strains form H<sub>2</sub>S from cysteine but not from thiosulfate.</s><s>Nitrates, nitrites or urea are not utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate to nitrite or N<sub>2</sub>; no requirement for vitamins; no production of indole.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are 12-methyl tetradecanoic (8-15 %), cis-hexadec-9-enoic (28-36 %) and hexadecanoic acids (22-29%).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45-46 mol %.</s><s>The type strain RAOx-1 was isolated from the rhizosphere of sorrel (<i>Rumex acetosa</i>), and is deposited in the DSMZ-Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 11538, and in the University of Helsinki HAMBI Collection as strain HAMBI 2283.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight short or long slightly curved rods 1.0-3.8 μm x 0.6-1-1 μm in size which occur singly or in pairs with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Cells in young cultures are Gram-negative, in the mid exponential growth are Gram-positive, and in old cultures the Gram reaction is variable.</s><s>Poor growth occurs at 0.05 M NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup> and no growth occurs at ≤0.04 M.</s><s>Glyoxylate does not support growth as the sole organic source for carbon and energy.</s><s>Good growth on ≥5g ammonium oxalate l<sup>-1</sup>, poor growth on 4 g l<sup>-1</sup>, and no growth on ≤3 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Minimum doubling time is 2 h.</s><s>Growth occurs at 14°C but not at 10°C.</s><s>Oxalate is oxidized by oxalyl-CoA decarboxylase and formate dehydrogenase (dye-linked).</s><s>Assimilation of oxalate proceeds by the serine pathway.</s><s>The Krebs cycle is incomplete at the level of α-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase.</s><s>The glyoxylate bypass does not function.</s><s>Ammonium is assimilated by reductive amination of keto acids.</s><s>Tolerant to 4% of NaCl.</s><s>Urease is not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 46 mol %.</s><s>The other properties of this strain are the same as the properties described above for the species.</s></p></content></protolog>