<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8293_nm.14144" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14144" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14144" rank="species">Zoogloea caeni</organism><reference id="rid.8293"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Zoogloea caeni sp. nov., a floc-forming bacterium isolated from activated sludge.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>526</fpage><lpage>530</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65670-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244434</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Zoogloea caeni</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Zoogloea caeni</em> (cae′ni. L. gen. n. <em>caeni</em> of mud, referring to the isolation of the type strain from activated sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on R2A agar are white, glistening, translucent, raised and circular with entire margins.</s><s>Cells are facultatively aerobic, Gram-negative, short rods (about 0.6–0.9 μm wide and 1.1–2.0 μm long) that are motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction to nitrogen gas and for nitrogen fixation.</s><s>Growth occurs optimally at 25–30 °C and pH 6.5–7.5.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Hydrolyses Tween 20 and gelatin, but not tyrosine, aesculin, casein, Tween 80 or starch.</s><s>Produces acid from d-lactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-galactose, d-mannitol and arbutin, but not from raffinose, l-arabinose, melibiose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose or salicin.</s><s>Negative for indole production and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, d-mannose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but not lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for valine arylamidase and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Contains a large amount of phosphatidylethanolamine as the major polar lipid.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is ubiquinone-8 (Q-8).</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.9–65.0 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EMB43<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22084<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19389<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge of a domestic wastewater treatment plant.</s><s>EMB61 is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>